Aaagh!
- Careful, Doctor!
- It's all right.
I think. I think it's all right now.
Yes. You see.
It's just a mock-up, a model.
Don't touch that!
That gun may be wired up too.
- It's a trap.
- No, I don't think so.
It's a testing room for weapons.
This is a purely robotic Cyberman.
There's no human material in it at all.
It's a target for weapons.
Let's get back to the control room
with this poor fellow.
What's that?
(JAMIE) Some wee creature
I found on the floor.
It's a fossil.
Victoria, be careful!
Let me see that.
Yes, it's certainly inactive,
but it's not a fossil.
Wait a minute.
Yes. Here we are.
Yes.
It's a Cybermat.
What's a Cybermat?
It's one of those.
I'd leave it alone if I were you./
I just don't understand this code.
The sequence doesn't make sense.
You, a logician, can't understand it?
- You must.
- But in the time we have...
We have plenty of time.
You will see.
- Lay him down there.
- What has happened to him?
There's been an accident.
He's been shot.
Right. We're all here.
Would you all sit down for a moment?
Toberman?
Mr Klieg?
Leave me alone.
Can't you see I'm working?
Have you forgotten
the purpose of this expedition?
This directly concerns my expedition.
Kindly take your place.
Right.
I'll come straight to the point.
I've reluctantly decided to abandon
the expedition and return to Earth.
- It's impossible!
- I feel just as strongly about it.
This expedition has been
my dream for many years.
Some, like Mr Viner,
said more preparation was needed -
more men and equipment.
I did not heed their warnings,
and the result is that two have died.
I'm sorry, but we must leave
at the first available conjunction.
We'll take back
all we can for further study.
But that is my decision
and that is what we must do.
- I insist that...!
- My decision is final!
We leave when the north hemisphere
is properly tangential,
which will be at 18.42.
Ah, Captain Hopper.
Can you blast off at 18.42?
No.
I beg your pardon.
Did I hear you right?
You are paid to take orders.
Not impossible ones.
It's the fuel pumps.
Someone has balled-up the lot.
- What?
- Or someTHING.
Whatever it is, it's nearly wrecked
our chances of leaving this planet./
There's no doubt about it.
The major workings lie below.
There are metal caverns
down there, all interconnected.
If only we can get down to them.
That's it! I've got it!
Finally, a Boolean function
of symbolic logic.
- Logical, yes, but...
- Everything yields to logic.
- Our basic assumption.
- Really.
Six, cap, B4...
if and only if C
is cap function of 2A.
I think perhaps your logic
is wearing a little thin.
I must have made a mistake.
I'll do it again carefully.
Six, cap, B4...
if and only if C...
is cap faction of... Ah, that's it!
2F, not 2A.
(WHIRRING)
I've done it! I've done it!
- Congratulations!
- But, Doctor, you...
Excellent. Now to work.
It'll be extremely cold.
We shall need to put on warm clothing.
Mr Viner, would you get the anoraks?
- Are we all going down?
- There's safety in numbers.
- The women as well?
- They will stay up here.
In case of trouble,
contact the rocket.
- I'm coming with you.
- But my dear young lady...
- You heard me, Professor.
- Victoria.
You will be much safer up here.
- But, Doctor...
- And much more use to us.
- I don't see...
- By keeping an eye on things.
Please.
- All right.
- Thank you.
(PARRY) If we're all ready,
I shall lead the descent.
Be ready to go back
the instant I give the word.
- You know what to do?
- The hatch?
Mr Toberman?
He stays with me.
Then I stay here too.
Of course. I am being selfish.
His strength will be useful to you.
He must go down.
Go down, Toberman.
Remember what I said.
Be very careful.
(KAFTAN) It seems
we are left alone to wait.
Captain Hopper brought food
from the rocket. You would like some?
Rather! I'm ravenous./
We've no time to linger!
It's extremely cold down here,
even with these anoraks.
(JAMIE) You obviously knew
what to expect.
Well, which way do we go?
I don't know. Let's try this one.
Yes.
Hey, what on Earth?!
(PARRY) Behold, gentlemen,
the tombs of the Cybermen.
(JAMIE)
Tombs? I don't see any tombs.
There, Jamie.
Frozen forever.
All their evil
locked away with them.
And so it must remain.
Like a gigantic honeycomb.
Like bees waiting for the signal
to arise from their winter sleep.
A signal they are never
going to get.
We'd better get busy. Everything
must be recorded. It's too cold...
Unless we find some way
to warm things up.
You have hardly touched your coffee.
It must be cold by now.
You would like some more?
No, thank you. I'm much warmer now.
That's good.
I...
feel so sleepy.
(WHIRRING)
(CLANG)
- What was that?
- It sounded like the hatch.
It's closed!
What's the use?
We're trapped down here now.
We'll never survive in this cold.
Better get back.
Well?
It's closed.
What are they playing at up there?
Maybe it wasn't them. Where's Jamie?
He went up the ladder to try it.
Professor. Professor,
listen to me, for heaven's sake!
The hatch is down.
We're trapped down here.
But some of my party
are up there. Are you sure?
Of course. You know how heavy it is.
It's down now.
We must do something!
I give us a couple of hours
in here at most.
Mr Klieg doesn't seem
to be very worried.
No, I'm not, Doctor.
It won't open
and I can't make them hear.
There is an easy way
out of our situation.
- You've found something?
- You forget logic.
If it closes,
it can be opened - from here.
Conveniently labelled
in symbolic logic, I notice.
Right. Are we ready?
I shall now operate the sequence.
If it is the opening device.
It's an opening device
of some kind, Doctor.
I don't know
how you can be so blasted calm!
I'll see if it works.
Go ahead!
Nothing happening out here!
It doesn't work.
Water!
- It's getting warmer.
- The ice is melting.
Hey, look behind you!
Look!
Look at the honeycomb.
There's something inside.
They're... They're Cybermen.
Jamie, come back!
It is them.
Gentlemen, they are perfect.
This is unique in archaeology.
No!
No! They're moving!
We must shut it down.
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING WINDS DOWN)
What are you doing?
Keep away from that!
No.
- What are you doing?
- Keep away!
- Keep away from those controls.
- No!
Viner!
Viner. You've killed him!
- He's mad.
- Jamie!
Haydon dead, now Viner.
What kind of man are you?
Back! Keep back!
Let's see what happens.
As the Professor says, this is
a unique archaeological event.
It would be such a pity to miss it.
(LOUD WHIRRING)/
Doctor, I have a feeling
that man's planned it all.
He knew
that wouldn't open the hatch.
- So did I, Jamie.
- You knew?
I wanted to know what he was up to.
- And now you know, Doctor.
- We know nothing.
This is the action of a lunatic.
Lunatic? Not at all, Professor.
A necessary detail, that's all.
But why?
Logic, my dear Professor,
logic and power.
On Earth,
the Brotherhood of Logicians
is the greatest man intelligence
ever assembled.
But that's not enough.
We need power -
power to put our ability
into action.
The Cybermen have this power.
I have come to find it and use it.
So that was your motive
in financing my expedition!
Precisely. Your lack
of administration made it ideal.
You think the Cybermen
will help you?
Of course.
I shall be their resurrector.
Look!
- Keep still!
- Behind you!
That thing! It's come alive!
You are so simple. You expect to
take me in with a trick like that!
It's true! Look!
- Will nothing keep you still?
- Will you please look?!
(BEEPING)
Any more trouble
and I'll take drastic steps.
We won't allow
a little girl to interfere!
Aaagh!
(BEEPING WINDS DOWN...)
(..AND STOPS)
What is it?
I think it's their leader,
their Controller, Jamie.
(CONTROLLER) You belong to us.
You shall be like us.