(GUNSHOT)
- Doctor!
- Sh!
Doctor...
Sin!
Where's Litefoot?
He went out. He said he'd seen
a Chinaman outside the window.
And you jumped through it!
- Something like that.
- Stay here!
Leela!
Leela, no! Don't!
Leela...
- Ice!
- The sheer criminal effrontery!
Things are coming to a pretty pass
when ruffians will attack
a man in his own home!
Well, they WERE Chinese ruffians.
- I wonder what they intended?
- Robbery?
Well, there are some valuable things here.
That K'ang-hsi vase, for instance.
My family brought that back
from Peking. Or that Chinese puzzle box.
It doesn't open. A chap spent a week
looking for a secret spring.
- Fused molecules.
- No, lacquered bronze!
Extraordinary! It's from this planet!
- A parting gift from the emperor.
- Technology this advanced?
Ah! Got it!
- That's the answer!
- What are you raving about, Doctor?
- Weng-Chiang!
- Weng-Chiang?
I do hope that girl Leela isn't in danger.
(WENG-CHIANG)
You will explain yourself, Li H'sen!
I will not tolerate failure!
- There has been no failure, lord.
- Then where is the time cabinet?
The house is marked.
When night returns, my brothers will strike!
I put no trust in your dockyard riffraff!
Lord, for your glory, they would die willingly!
Opium-soddened scum! Strike!
(CLANGING GONG)
Lord, I promise you shall have
the great cabinet of Weng-Chiang
- before another dawn.
- I had better!
I grow weary of this hole in the ground!
- You are safe here, lord.
- Safe?! It is a trap,
and I was seen returning to it!
- Tonight?
- Yes! And now he knows where I am,
- he will be back!
- Who?
By your description, the one you failed to kill!
The Doctor!
- Haven't you slept?
- Sleep is for tortoises.
- Any news of Miss Leela?
- Not yet.
- Should we inform the police?
- No. They already have nine missing girls.
Yes, but missing
under very different circumstances!
No. I think I know what they were used for,
and I can't imagine a more grisly fate.
- He's a blackguard!
- Who is?
I don't know, but some vampire
stalks this city at night - he's a blackguard!
I've got to find his lair
and I haven't got an hour to lose. Look.
Yes, yes, the Doctor is a danger,
and he was brought to my door
by your blundering!
You see what it means, Li H'sen?
He will die!
The list of your failures is growing!
I must be ready to move quickly -
I need strength!
- I will bring a girl, lord.
- One will not be enough this time.
I need two fresh young donors,
and I need them at once!
- It is not easy at this hour, lord.
- No excuses!
Get them!
I've been trying to trace
the line of the sewers.
That's the Thames, this is the line of the Fleet,
and that is the Palace Theatre.
I'm beginning to see what you're getting at!
Good.
(WOMAN) Ta, ducks!
(SHE GASPS)
- Pleasant are the dreams of morning.
- You gave me a turn, dearie!
Fresh as dew and bright with promise.
Yeah, well, that's how
you might see it, Mr Ching-Ching,
but all I want is a pair
of smoked kippers, a cup of rosie,
and put me plates up for a few hours, savvy?
Budding lotus of the dawn,
despicable Chang has other ideas.
I can tell you what to do with your ideas!
You will come with me.
Await my return.
(LAUGHTER)
(THEY LAUGH)
The spell of the shaman!
Come!
I said come!
You painted drabs! My master must feed!
Professor...
..you don't happen to have
an elephant gun, do you?
- Elephants?!
- Mmm.
Why on earth do you want an elephant gun?
We're about to embark
on a very dangerous mission.
Well, I've a Chinese fowling piece
if that's any good.
- Used for duck mainly.
- Made in Birmingham -
that's the main requirement.
Could you get me a boat?
I imagine so. What is the purpose of all this?
To find the confluence
of the Thames and the Fleet, Professor.
- And then?
- And then we shall see.
(CLIP-CLOPPING OF HOOVES)
There it is - fifty yards ahead!
Sit down, Doctor! The man knows these waters.
I've always enjoyed messing about in boats.
This entire enterprise is
extremely rash and ill-considered!
I've got a lantern and a pair of waders
and the most fearsome piece
of hand artillery in England!
- What could possibly go wrong?
- Well, that for a start!
It hasn't been fired for fifty years.
It will probably explode in your face!
Explode? Unthinkable.
It was made in Birmingham!
Tie up over there, skipper.
- Where did you get them?
- Are they unsuitable, lord?
They're not the best, but they'll do.
They're young. Their life essence is still strong.
Oh! This one has muscles like a horse!
I took what I could find, lord.
I have given you knowledge!
I have made you a leader among your fellows!
All I ask in for in return
is a few contemptible slatterns
- who will never be missed!
- But they ARE missed, lord!
And because your need is so great,
- I've had to move unwisely.
- Unwisely?
I took this one
from the rooms above. Nobody saw,
- but it will bring the police here.
- It is of no consequence.
Once I have the time cabinet,
I can move from here.
- Put her in the distillation chamber.
- Yes, lord.
Leave me to my work!
I shall not keep you waiting long!
(LITEFOOT) All right, Doctor?
(DOCTOR) All right, Professor!
- I'll wait for you for two hours.
- Yes, no more.
- If I'm still in here at high tide, don't bother!
- Good luck!
(HUMMING WHINE)
My beauties, find her!
She will wish she had died here!
(ECHOING SCREECH)
(ECHOING SCREECHES AND SQUEALS)
Hey, you! What's your business here?
- Business? Where the devil am I?
- Oh, you wouldn't be knowing (?)
What happened to me last night?
Can't remember a thing.
If anything's missing,
I'll remember you sure enough!
- Now get out of here.
- Get your hands off of me! I'm a lady!
- What's the trouble, Casey?
- No trouble, Mr Jago.
I'm just seeing this ''lady'' off the premises.
Oh, my lord! It was him! It was him!
Mr Chang? What are you talking about?
Quick! Let me out! Let me go!
Another case of the screaming oopizootics!
I'll bear that in mind.
It might have some relevance
to the matter in hand.
- What matter?
- The investigation, Casey -
these missing females!
I've made the acquaintance
of a very high-up gentleman,
an amateur investigator
who's been called in by the Yard -
Scotland Yard -
- and I am assisting him.
- No!
I am. He told me to watch, Casey,
and I am watching - everywhere!
You incompetent fool!
She was a tigress!
She substituted herself
for the woman I had found.
The police must be closing in.
My rats will dispose of her,
but you, Li H'sen,
have made too many mistakes.
That girl... She was with a doctor.
It is not the police, it is he who sent her!
Vacant excuses! You have failed me!
You know that until I have the time cabinet,
I can never be whole again!
I can never escape from this hideous condition!
Yet, knowing this, you still failed me!
Lord, hear me. I would
lay down my life in your service!
You are dismissed, Li H'sen!
I can no longer leave my fate
to your blundering hands!
Great one, let me find this Doctor.
Let me strike him down
for the harm he has done you!
Do not beg. You have proved unworthy! Go!
- I await your commands, lord.
- Go!
(HE GROANS)
(HUMMING WHINE)
(GASPS AND GROANS)
(ECHOING ROAR)
Aagh! Aagh!