(WHOOSHING)
These clothes are ridiculous!
Why must I wear them?
(DOCTOR) If you walk
around Victorian London in skins,
you'll frighten the horses.
Anyway, we don't want
to be conspicuous, do we?
(BLARING FOGHORN)
A swamp creature! That was its attack cry!
No, it was a ship on the river.
We can't be far away.
- From where?
- From where we're going.
You make me wear strange clothes,
you tell me nothing -
- you are trying to annoy me!
- I'm trying to teach you, Leela.
Surely you'd like to see how your ancestors
enjoyed themselves? Splendid.
That's why I'm taking you to the theatre.
Li H'sen Chang... Hmm, pity.
I'd rather hoped we'd catch Little Tich!
Never mind. If we hurry,
we'll just catch the second house.
(BLARING FOGHORN)
Mr Chang, wonderful!
Words fail me, sir! Words quite fail me!
You are most generous.
- (MAN) Hey, you!
- Where's my Emma?
- You're not allowed in here!
- Out of my way. It's him I want!
- Your Emma?
She come in here and ain't been seen since!
- What's happened to her?
- Call the stage hands!
It's all right, Mr Jago.
Please, come with me.
- Your wife?
- Emma Buller.
Don't deny she was here,
'cause I saw her with my own eyes!
Many ladies come to theatre. Why should...?
Not round the side door, they don't!
Now, look, I was passing in my cab
and I saw her plain,
and I know it was you she was calling on!
She's been acting queer
ever since you put the 'fluence on her,
so don't come the innocent!
In my country we have saying,
''Man who goes too quickly may step in bear trap.''
Right, I'm getting the peelers!
(LAPPING WATER)
(CRUNCHING FOOTSTEPS)
The Talons of Weng Chiang
(Whopix fan edit)
- What's the name of the tribe here?
- Cockneys.
(MAN SCREAMS)
(LEELA) The sound of death!
You stay here.
Excuse me, can I help you?
(MAN) Hold you there!
- What's all this?
- Touch me and I'll break your arm!
- Don't be foolish, miss.
- Keep back, Doctor! Blue guards!
- Good evening, constable.
- You know this young female, sir?
Yes, we were attacked by this little man
and four other little men.
When I got here, he was being
strangled with his own pigtail, sir.
Really? Girlish enthusiasm, officer?
You might call it that, sir.
I call it making an affray.
I must ask you to come
down the station with me.
Get your tail pinned on!
Linens up in five minutes.
Casey! Have you got the oopizootics coming on?
Mr Jago, I've seen it!
- I've seen it again!
- Be quiet! I told you before!
Horrible, horrible, it was! A great skull
coming at me out of the dark!
Quiet! Threadbare in Carey Street I'll be,
if people think there's anything
wrong with this theatre!
- Chains clanking!
- You've been drinking!
- Not a drop, sir!
- Well, it's time you started!
Now, pull yourself together, man!
I ain't never going down that cellar again!
There I was, fixing the trap,
when this apparition rose up in front of me!
- Hideous, it was, hideous!
- That's enough!
- It's your imagination!
- Never!
A cat must be trapped down there
making noises.
Tell you what I'll do, Casey,
I'll come down with you this evening,
and we'll have a good look round. How's that?
It was no cat, Mr Jago! I seen it!
Please, Casey, remember, mum's the word!
Good of you to come so prompt, sir.
Not at all, Sergeant. I'm always
happy to be of service to the police.
- What can I do for you this time?
- A complaint against this man, sir.
This lady and gentleman
swear they saw him, with others,
carrying a body, sir.
- Indeed?
- A European body, as I understand.
- What happened to the others?
- They got away.
- I caught this one.
- YOU caught him? Remarkable!
- Don't I know you?
- I think not.
- I've seen you somewhere before!
- I understand. We all look the same.
Are you Chinese? Yes, that's it.
We must have... No, I haven't been
in China for 400 years.
Are you taking this matter seriously, Sergeant?
We are, sir. Will you question the man, sir?
Very well.
Can I have paper and pencil, please, Sergeant?
Certainly, sir.
Got it! Li H'sen Chang,
the Master of Magic and Mesmerism!
Show us a trick!
Aagh!
Very good! Very good!
(LAUGHS)
I think he's dead, sir.
- How did you do it?
- I did nothing.
What are you suggesting?
- Scorpion venom.
- Scorpion venom?
Highly concentrated scorpion venom.
It killed him almost instantly.
- The Tong of the Black Scorpion.
- Don't know it, sir.
One of the most dangerous
criminal organisations in the world.
- Do you agree, Li H'sen Chang?
- You seem remarkably well-informed, Doctor.
Alas, I know nothing of these matters.
Most regrettable incident.
- Goodnight, Sergeant.
- Thank you, sir.
- I'm sure we shall meet again.
- Yes.
Perhaps under more pleasant circumstances.
Well, I don't know what to do about this lot!
Organise a post-mortem.
- I want an analysis of the organs.
- You want what, sir?
If the Tong of the Black Scorpion's
here in London,
- you need my help. Do as I say now!
- Yes, sir.
Faster, man! Faster!
Missing Girls Mystery, 8th Victim
Twinkle, twinkle, out in front!
Eh?
- Gallery lights still burning.
- I'll see to them now.
- Everyone gone?
- Aye, just locked up.
- I hope those girls go straight home.
- That they will, sir.
- There are nine missing now.
- Some fella was blaming Chang
for some girl's disappearance!
They've fenced off the streets -
mostly in this area.
What do you think's happened to them?
Nothing good, Casey, that's a stone certainty!
The papers say it could be Jolly Jack again.
- Jolly Jack?
- The Ripper, Mr Jago.
- Who the devil are you, sir?
- I'm the Doctor, come to help you.
When I need anyone's help
in pathology, I'll ask for it!
The constable suggested a drowning.
He was fished from the river,
but he wasn't drowned.
- Those marks suggest an animal.
- Exactly what I think,
but which animal leaves mutilations like those?
Chisel-like incisors - a rodent?
That's impossible. Look at the size of them.
Have you established the cause of death?
That's another curious thing -
all this happened after death.
He was killed by a knife blow to the heart.
- Are those his clothes?
- Yes, sir.
- I'm taking them for examination.
- Hold that.
He was carrying no personal documents,
but this indicates he was a licensed cab driver.
We can identify him by his number.
Doctor, those are the clothes
the man we saw was wearing!
- What do you think of these?
- Some sort of hair.
- Yes, I think they're rat hairs.
- Rat hairs?! Do you know what you're saying?
- Of course I know what I'm saying.
It's three inches long -
hairs on a rat are only a quarter of an inch.
Interesting, isn't it,