Syncro:
F.B Cavalcante
Just keep the door covered.
Janice, have you got a screwdriver?
Hello, Doctor Arnold?
No, Winslet, it's Janice.
Doctor Sal's
a little tied up at the moment.
- Tell him not now, Winslet.
- Not now, Winslet.
Wait a minute.
Doctor Arnold specifically asked me
to find any other containers with
the same serial number as the one
that contained that sphere thing.
Said it was very important.
Now I've been doing that
over and above everything
else I'm supposed
to be doing down here.
I've given it my full attention.
Taken me the best part of two weeks.
And, as a matter of
fact, I have found a
large number of crates
with the same code.
- Triple A stroke RH stroke 2961.
- Thank you, Winslet. No time.
Some of them have the letters...
A, U, T O, N.
Winslet, not now.
I have a satellite downlink,
an expensive satellite downlink,
due any...
- Oh God, I'm tired.
- We could always use some of next week's
- satellite window.
- You must be joking.
I'm going to beat
this thing if kills me.
- I can't believe you used Meccano.
- Nothing wrong with that.
Ah, here we go.
- Anything?
- Still just background radiation.
Let's see if I can filter out some
to the extraneous stuff.
Ah, nobody loves you.
Janice, get your notepad.
Note the time.
My God, what have I done?
Perhaps we should shut it off now.
It's picked up on something.
Or something's picked up on it.
It's having a conversation.
It's transmitting.
Terminating the satellite link.
That's it.
Janice, keep away!
Sincro:
F.B Cavalcante
Doctor Arnold.
- Code Seven now on site.
- Protocol one nine zero.
All non-essential
personnel are evacuated
to safe house with
full decontamination.
Listen, do you have
any idea what...
Heard those nasty rumours
about containment teams?
You don't think.
They'll be here any minute now.
- Winslet?
- What?
- I'm sorry I said you had bad breath.
- When?
When did you have bad breath,
or when did I say it?
- Doesn't matter.
- Don't move!
The laboratory's been secured, sir.
If you'd like to come this way.
This is where it was.
Dead?
Dead.
Make a preliminary examination.
The usual tests.
Open your box of tricks.
Did you know her?
Do you think we could
put our hands down now?
Doctor Sally Arnold,
Facility director and head of research?
Pleased to meet you.
May I ask...
- And who is that?
- Winslet. Graham Winslet, archivist.
Non-essential. What are you
doing here, Mister Winslet?
- You should have been evacuated.
- I'm afraid I wasn't ready in time.
- Oh.
- Sorry.
Sorry.
All right, lads.
You'd better let them have a general
sniff around, Ramsay.
- Is there a guard on the main entrance?
- Already taken care of.
Diligent as always, Ramsay.
I hope you didn't
burn your clothes.
It would be such a waste.
Is this yours, Doctor.
Yes. Useful when
I'm working late.
Which is most nights.
Particle traces on here?
What about the woman?
Massive localised
energy release.
Knocked out her
entire nervous system.
- Did the thing just explode?
- No. If it just exploded, there'd
- be more debris left.
- What are you saying?
That it did something a bit
cleverer than just exploding.
My name is Lockwood.
I am the head
of this containment team.
This is a code seven situation,
so your death certificates have
already been prepared by UNIT.
With luck, we won't find it
necessary to issue them.
This is Doctor Daniel Matthews,
my assistant.
Let me remind you that under the terms of
your contract with UNIT,
you're obliged to give me the fullest
cooperation during this investigation.
Mister Winslet, perhaps you'd like
to go and put your clothes back on...
and wait in your office.
Right.
Did you think my men were going
to shoot you?
At one point, yes,
it did cross my mind.
You thought you'd glimpsed
the forbidden fruit,
that we were here to stop
the truth getting out.
Something like that.
Perhaps we are here to
stop something getting out.
Was she a friend?
I knew her too.
It was years ago.
She's in shock.
She's no use to me at the moment.
Take care of her,
Doctor Matthews.
I feel stupid.
It's just shock.
Yes.
Carry on.
You've worked here for
six years, according to your records.
Very fastidious,
not a great socialiser.
Seven years.
Seven. Yes.
How come you didn't
make it to the safe house?
- I told you, I wasn't ready in
- In time. Yes, I know.
- But why weren't you ready in time?
- I don't know.
- Not like you.
- How would you know?
Not like your personality profile.
On the computer at  UNIT HQ.
Geneva.
Been there?
Geneva?
No.
I can't believe you used Meccano.
Perhaps we should shut it off now.
- All right?
- Fine. Thanks.
You should finish your tea.
It's hot and sweet.
It's good for shock.
How did you know Janice?
Oh, at university.
Did you like her?
It was a long time ago.
Is your Mister Lockwood always so cold?
Lockwood?
He's a breed apart.
But I've worked with  him long
enough to know he's the best there is.
I see.
Do you have any idea
what's happened here?
-Yes, we have plenty of ideas.
-Like what?
Oh, need to know, is it?
Why is Lockwood so convinced
there's no contamination risk?
I mean, that thing exploded.
I don't know what was inside it.
If you didn't know what was inside
it, why did you subject it to transmissions
from UNIT's most powerful
deep-space scanning satellites?
Because...
Because it was the only course
of relevant experimentation left.
I'd drawn a blank with the damn thing,
thought it was dead.
I tried every test I could think of.
That is my job, Doctor Matthews.
Assess and catalogue.
I knew it was of extra-terrestrial origin.
Wasn't just a meteor.
It appeared to be manufactured,
so I speculated...
- Oh, you speculated.
- Yes.
We don't exactly have information
here at our fingertips, I'm afraid.
This place was a sort of forgotten
Aladdin's Cave until about five years ago.
It was a mess.
Mountains of old paperwork.
Winslet hasn't even got a
tenth of the way through it.
We're working blind-folded most of.
Are you saying you know more about it?
Where do you get
your information?
I think you're ready
to speak to Lockwood.
Are we in danger?
It's possible.
So where were you
when it all happened?
Storage bay one,
you said just now.
- Yes.
- And you heard the alarm,
and you thought I
think I'll just stay
here and pick my
nose, is that it?
- No, no.
- Well then, what?
Doctor Arnold was
conducting her experiment
in her laboratory on
this alien artefact,
serial code triple A stroke RH stroke 2961,
and she asked me to find any other containers
- with that code.
- Because she thought there might
- be more of them?
- Or anything that would help her identify
- what she was dealing with.
- She wasn't dealing with anything,
Mister Winslet. She was
tampering with the
unknown, which is always
pretty dangerous.
Did you find any other crates with the same
code on them, by the way?
- No.
- Greyhound One to Greyhound Leader.
-Greyhound Leader.
-We have a problem.
- Same as the woman?
- I should say so.
- Mister Lockwood, what is going on?
- Just Lockwood. No Mister.
What is going on?
Exits are already secured.
- What are we looking for?
- I don't know, exactly.
Whatever it is, it can't be very big.
- Well, he didn't see it coming.
- Where is it going?
Well, presuming it started here
Oh, let's presume.
- Too many variables give me a headache.
- It's going through the storage bays,
whatever it is you're talking about. Look.
Well, what are you talking about?
Carry on, Ramsay, and see that Doctor
Arnold is kept out of harm's way.
What have we got?
We haven't got any of the right
equipment, for a start.
This was a code seven,
contamination risk.
Yes. Bit of a
balls-up, isn't it.
I should have twigged
there was no danger
of contamination the
moment I saw the code.
- Triple A
- RH 2961.
Seems no one here knew
what it meant.
But I didn't expect it to turn
into a bug hunt either.
- This is something new.
- Should we call for back-up?
To pick over our remains.
Great sense of
humour, Lockwood.
Great.
Sorry.
What did he say?
- Who?
- This Lockwood.
- Not much.
What do you think of him?
I think he's a bit high-handed.
Sorry about Janice.
We've got to find a way to track
the damn thing.
There's nothing feasible with the
level of equipment we've got here.
What is it they say
about a bad workman?
Oh, you're calling
me a bad workman.
What do you want to do, Dan?
Join the search.
See what else has got hidden away here,
what it might be after.
Our esteemed Doctor Sally Arnold
apparently instructed Mister Personality
Winslet to conduct a thorough search
for anything else with the same code.
But would he draw back?
I still thinkit's worth double-checking.
I never trusted the brain cell
count in research establishments.
All right, Have Ramsay bring Sally
Arnold to her laboratory.
I shall be waiting to give
her my charm offensive.
Doctor Arnold?
Come with me, please.
- You just sit tight, Mister Winters.
- Winslet. Graham Winslet. Archivist.
Whatever.
So he's finally deigned to speak with
me, has he?
- Who would that be, Doctor?
- Your boss, Lockwood.
I believe he does want a word with
you, yes, Doctor.
I suppose all this is pretty routine
for you, Sergeant.
- That's right, Doctor.
- Where exactly are you taking me?
- Your laboratory, Doctor.
- This is the long way.
Come on,
I'll show you a short cut.
Do sit down.
What did you make of
these symbols?
What did I make of them?
I've never seen anything like them.
All right, all right.
Did you think, oops, dear me,
what have I done?
Because I'd like to put to you
that is what you should have been thinking,
given that something is now
crawling around the building
apparently with the intention
of wiping out my team.
- Something? What is this something?
-That.
You mean it didn't just
vaporise when it exploded.
Doctor Sal is thinking.
Doctor Sal, that's what all
your chums call you, isn't it?
The insightful UNIT research scientist?
Gifted, highly qualified?
A working class comprehensive
school girl who ended up
with degrees in medicine,
physics, chemistry and biology.
I see you've read my file.
You're a bit of a maverick in the
scientific community.
Not afraid to put forward
new and untested ideas.
I suppose that accounts
for the stupidity of your actions here.
- It's easy to be wise with hindsight.
- Wisdom does not come into it.
Some excrement has hit
the fan, and you, Doctor
Sal, were the idiot who
turned the fan on.
I was doing my job.
It's a job which
I happen to consider important.
I can't help it if UNIT
doesn't fund us properly.
I work with the best information
that I have available to me.
In my opinion, underfunding of this
facility makes it a dangerous liability.
However, these are not
matters for mere slaves
of the UNIT bureaucracy
like ourselves.
I'm here to pick up the pieces.
I'm your alien artefact
serial code triple A RH 2961.
You connect me up to the
widest range of deep-space signals
available to mankind.
Why?
Because it hadn't
responded to any other kind of test.
God save us from mavericks.
You can test a gun all you like, but it doesn't
work until you pull the trigger.
You're saying I pulled the trigger?
It recognised one of the signals
from out there in deep space.
It came alive
and received instructions.
Now, what kind of an
instruction is please vaporise?
Not a very friendly one.
And this artefact was
undoubtedly talking to a friend,
so perhaps it was
instructed to do something else.
So you're saying it atomised in order
to reform itself into
something that could move?
And kill.
You saw nothing.
I saw a flash.
I heard Janice and I blacked out.
It's the mobility that's important.
It's going somewhere.
It wants something.
That'll be us in the shit, then.
Are there any other artefacts in
the warehouse like this one?
I don't know. Maybe. I asked Winslet
to look for anything with the same coding.
- Yes, I know.
- You obviously know what it was.
- Is. Yes, I'm afraid I do.
- Well?
It's an energy unit.
It's part of the Nestene Consciousness.
It has an affinity for plastic.
It's hostile, and God
help us if you have
any more artefacts coded
triple A RH 2961.
- Greyhound Five to Greyhound One.
- Receiving.
There's no radio contact with
Greyhound Four.
Winslet's office.
Check it out and report back.
Greyhound Leader.
Greyhound Leader, come in.
Please. Over
Go ahead, Dan.
We've found a crate
coded triple  A RH 2961.
-And it's marked Auton.
-Auton.
- Is that the only one?
- So far.
Has the crate been opened?
- No.
- Any sign of activity?
- Where are you?
- Storage bay one.
- Keep an eye out for more.
I'm on my way down.
Out.
You recognised that word. How?
Auton.
I remember Winslet saying it
over the phone just before.
He'd found some
crates marked Auton.
- He told me he didn't find anything.
- I didn't pay much attention at the time,
but I distinctly
remember him saying it.
- Stay here.
- Wait a minute!
What is going on?
- What is Auton?
- It's none of your concern.
Isn't it? I am right in thinking you
blame me for all this, aren't I?
Well, if it's my fault,
then I at least think
I have the right to
know what Auton is.
Autons are plastic automata
which can be controlled by the
Nestene Consciousness.
They're deadly and
virtually indestructible,
and it seems you've got
one in your storage bay, Doctor Sal.
Storage bay one?
Let's go.
Doctor Matthews?
Security door.
- Dan?
- Here.
I suppose you didn't
know about this, either.
We're probably looking at top-grade
signal shielding here.
How do we get it open?
The question is,
do we want to get it open?
Retina scan lock.
It's bound to have your retina print
on its memory.
But what about the entry codes?
I don't suppose you have
the code book for this?
I didn't even know it was here.
Can you do it?
We have to know
what we're dealing with.
Ramsay, I'd like some of your men here,
just to be on the safe side.
Sir.
This is Greyhound One
to Greyhound Six and Seven.
Report to Storage bay one immediately.
- Sergeant.
- Defensive positions.
What are you expecting?
You know that danger you were
asking me about earlier?
Keep them peeled, lads.
Keep them peeled.
Another one.
Was the first one just like this?
Identical.
Why?
What's the matter?
I'm not sure.
There's something different.
Not quite what I expected.
A metamorphosis?
The same as before.
Something's communicating with it.
The other energy unit.
We've got to get out of here.
Now!
Take this.
All right, Ramsay.
They're not after a conversation.
Open fire!
We're not going to get
out of this alive, are we?
I'm open to suggestions.
Why not? Let's try it.
- Ramsay?
- Go! Go! Go! Go!
No, this way.
No, no, this way.
This way,
Doctor Dan!
Here.
They're jamming us.
-Which way is the exit?
-Over this way.
Poor bastard.
He's still alive.
They must have copied him.
That's what they do.
They're using the real Winslet...
s a source of information,
like a template.
Lockwood tell you this?
So they could copy anyone.
We'd never know the difference.
Move it.
This is the only way to the exit.
They've got us trapped.
And what is this thing?
I don't know, but I've got a good
feeling about it.
Can you get us to your laboratory?
Er, yes.
We can cut through here.
Barricade the door.
Help me with this.
Hold it, hold it.
Couldn't you stop them?
-Not a chance.
-Have they taken the exits?
-Yes.
-Shit.
Lockwood...
Lockwood!
Just resting my eyes.
As your grandmother used to say.
How did you know that?
Your psychoanalysis tests.
We're all on the
great UNIT database.
Not even our personalities
is safe from trespass.
Has anyone ever told you you're a very
bitter, cynical,
person, Lockwood?
Don't presume to psychoanalyse me.
That's one degree you
don't have, Doctor Sal.
Only my friends call me that.
Then I'll refrain.
What do they want?
I suspect they want what's in that
tank in that sealed chamber.
Which is?
Would you take a look at this?
There must be some simple
reason why it isn't working.
And in answer to your question,
the thing in the tank is a mystery to me;
As yet.
Well, it looks like some
sort of transmitter but...
Okay, it's not as bad as it looks.
How does it look?
I feel like I've
had a shave with a cheese grater.
Off the wall humour in the face of
excruciating pain?
We'll make a soldier of you yet,
Doctor Dan.
Lockwood.
Bloody place is crawling with them.
Do you think Lockwood made it?
Yeah.
He's indestructible, isn't he?
What about the others?
Didn't stand a chance.
Oh Christ, I think
I'm going into shock.
Oh shit...
Ramsay.
How the hell are we
going to get out of this one?
Hello?
Whatever this is, it's got a
flat battery,
so I'm recharging it, all right?
Oh for God's sake, Lockwood.
Doctor!
Doctor Arnold!
Doctor, are you in there?
Winslet, where the hell have you been?
Hiding, Doctor.
Those dummies.
What is going on?
Everyone out here is dead.
It's me you want.
Kill her and you'll
have to kill me.
You're very perceptive, Lockwood.
Something different about you.
In some ways you're quite like us.
They've captured L
ockwood and that Doctor.
Best you don't move.
Do you know how many
times he's saved my life?
We both know how much pain
he goes through for us.
He wouldn't let us down, would he?
What are you going to do with it
when you've got it?
That sad remnant in there.
Just a bit of slurry, isn't it?
Left-over scrapings
from a body you
tried to create
yourself decades ago.
I expect it's got a
bit of mildew...
You will open the retina scan door.
Wel...
Don't you wish you'd been
a little more pleasant to me?
What?
If I don't help him, he's probably
going to kill you.
Right?
I can't say I really care.
Of course, then he'll kill me.
Then what will you do?
Cut my head off and
use my retina print?
You still won't
have the code.
You are like us.
You're linked to something.
What does he mean?
You should be attending to your
battery charger...
Doctor Sal.
- Come with me.
- We're not leaving him.
Yes, you are,
if you want to save him.
Leave them.
They're unimportant.
My God, it works.
What the hell is that?
I've got no idea.
Lockwood...
UNIT's creature.
You cannot resist us.
You can fight,
but you can't win.
Soon.
Soon all the chaos
will be over...
and you'll be at one...
with us.
Marvellous.
The return of the maverick.
Who the...
what the hell are you?
Think how many
people you've killed.
Why'd you do it?
Because that's what we do.
Don't do it.
Don't go in there.
It's too dangerous.
Just keep the door covered.
We'll lock it...
Get the experts
to deal with this thing.
Maybe find out some
of its weaknesses for next time.
Next time?
They've tried before.
They'll try...
My God.
Bloody hell.
Where does that lead?
Straight to the surface.
Call for back-up.
Greyhound One.
Not a bad bit of workmanship,
Doctor John Smith.
Just returned from
the outlying area, sir.
How far did you go?
We estimated a fifty mile radius.
Moorland, mainly.
A few farmhouses,
cottages, and suchlike.
Nothing?
Not a trace.
You've done a good job, Ramsay.
- I can ask for no more.
-Pack up and go.
-Sir.
See you back at base, sir.
You're a good chap, Ramsay.
I used to think your sort only
existed in black and white war films.
Always salutes when he can't think
of anything to say...
Have you noticed?
How's your face?
It's a life-enriching experience.
We found particle traces of the
Nestene creature in the external air vents.
It's out there somewhere.
Put it in the bin, Sal.
Memories can eat away at you,
if you let them.
Come to escort me to my debriefing?
- Yes.
I also came to thank you.
Thank me for being the
idiot who threw excrement
at the fan, or whatever
it was you said?
For being insightful...
gifted, a bit of a maverick.
You saved my life, Doctor Sal.
I think I'm going to
enjoy working with you.
- Working?
- Yes.
High-handed of me, I know,
but I've had you reassigned...
to my team.
I'm not sure I know
what to think about that.
You're saying I have no choice.
Wretched, isn't it?
I don't think  I'm ready
for your kind of work.
Why not?
I caused everything
that happened here.
- I killed all those people...
- It was out there...
waiting to happen.
You made a mistake.
We all do that.
A mistake?
Yes.
We can never
know the future...
but we mustn't
let the past haunt us.