Syncro:
F.B Cavalcante
Greyhound Seven to Trap One.
Proceeding as scheduled.
Should reach checkpoint
seven at oh four fifty. Over.
Understood.
Out.
Talkative, aren't they?
Bloody hell.
Greyhound Seven to Trap One.
Over.
Come in please. Over.
What the hell's that?
Greyhound Seven to Trap One.
Obstruction on road.
Please advise.
Over.
Another cock-up.
Just in case.
Mike, I think there's someone here round
the back of the truck.
Mike.
Dave!
Don't move.
Don't move or I fire.
Congratulations,
Colonel Wilson.
It is regrettable.
It is, Colonel Wilson,
a balls-up of the most
staggering magnitude.
Doctor Arnold.
-What's going on?
-It seems we've lost the Autons.
What?
How?
It was a covert operation.
An unmarked vehicle.
No escort.
What, a lorry load of Autons?
I thought they'd all been incinerated.
That was our recommendation
two years ago.
Someone, apparently,
had a different idea.
They were being transported to a
classified location
for further research.
Further?
We spent six months dissecting one.
We made a full report.
So how do you propose to get them
back, Colonel?
Back from where?
Look, what exactly happened?
We're not exactly sure.
I sent a back-up unit
immediately, but when
they arrived there was
no sign of the truck.
We've given the civilian
authorities a description,
the number plate, and
orders not to approach,
but as yet we've heard nothing.
In short, Colonel Wilson,
you've lost a bunch of
deadly alien killing machines.
Lockwood?
Lockwood, are you ready yet?
Yes.
Yes, just coming.
You know, I was just beginning to hope
that our escaped Nestene creature from the
warehouse might just have
curled up and died somewhere.
Are we assuming it's behind all this?
Reclaiming it's minions?
Possibly, but how did it
know where to find them?
Maybe they just came
into range by chance?
You all right, Lockwood?
Sorry, Sal.
I haven't been sleeping too well lately.
Right, Colonel.
I take it you're up to speed on the whole
Auton issue, yes?
Nestene energy unit reactivation
at the warehouse two years ago.
Auton assumes the likeness of senior
Archivist Graham Winslet,
absorbs two energy units,
attempts a few faltering
steps at world domination,
then reconstitutes into
a blob and scarpers
when the odd on success start to look bad.
I've read the file.
You must understand that
I'm not here to tread on anybody's toes.
But I do have my orders.
Direct from Geneva.
I have my own team, and I've been appointed
head of this investigation.
Why?
That's your signature.
On a transportation
docket for all artefacts
coded triple A stroke
RH stroke 2961.
You ordered the
relocation of those Autons.
Geneva has ordered that you,
Lockwood, join us.
Your role will be to provide any specialist
information my own scientific adviser may
I want the exclusion of
my containment team from
this investigation on the
record, need access to. Colonel.
Of course.
And I insist that Doctor Arnold
accompanies me.
Her work in the field of
Nestene technology is unparalleled.
That won't be necessary.
The car's waiting.
We're late.
Thank you, Colonel.
I'll be with you in a moment.
Did you issue that order?
No.
Something's going on.
But what?
What are you going to do?
Obey orders.
Have you got one of these, Sal?
Ramsay!
It's nice to see one friendly face at least.
You two know each other, then.
Yes, sir.
I was assigned to the original
warehouse containment team.
Any reports on the missing truck?
Not as yet, sir, but tracks suggest
it went back the way it came.
-It's good to see you again, Ramsay.
-And you, sir.
Are Doctor Arnold  and
Doctor Matthews still with you?
Dan's been digging up alien artefacts
in Africa for the last six months,
but Sal's still putting up with me.
Why isn't she here with you?
This is Wilson's show.
There was something in it.
Brilliant.
Something... powerful.
Something alive.
And how did you deduce that,
young lady?
Lockwood, this is Natasha Alexander,
my scientific advisor.
Really.
Well?
I felt it.
So did you, didn't you.
This is Lockwood.
Priority code 8954B.
Relay me to containment HQ, please.
Morning, Sal.
Hi.
How's it going?
Thought you might
have gone back to bed.
What have you got for me?
I'm scanning some kind of sheet
left at the scene of the crime.
Are you getting this?
Yes, receiving your transmission.
Just cross-referencing.
Oh, match's up.
Trace of radiation typical of
Nestene energy readings.
Thought so.
Ramsay, have a
sample of this sheet
sent back to Sal for analysis.
Sergeant Ramsay
says hello, by the way, Sal.
Hello, Sal?
So he does.
Hello, James.
Sir.
Let me know when
you've got something, Sal.
Will do.
Bye.
Sorry, old chap.
Can't work without back-up.
Hope you don't mind.
What's your assessment?
Nestene energy unit
put here by someone.
Energy unit activates Autons in truck.
Autons kill your men...
And drive off in truck.
-Where to?
-Well...
If we can find out
where the sheet's from,
we may find out where
the energy unit came from,
and perhaps where
the Autons have gone.
Not necessarily.
No, not necessarily, Colonel.
But since your truck seems to have vanished
off the face of the Earth,
I've resorted to
grasping at straws.
Who do you think put the
energy unit there?
What a bizarre question, young lady.
If I knew that, I wouldn't be
groping around here.
Well, if you have any more flashes
of insight, do let me know.
Come on, Corporal.
Shift it.
You knew that energy unit had been
here before you checked.
Oh, yes?
And how long have you been psychic?
Only since birth.
So you read my mind.
No.
It was written all over your face.
I think I'll wait in the car.
Will everything
be all right now they've arrived?
Yes, of course it will, Daron.
What did you want to see me about, Vicar?
Daron... you were always the first.
You were always the one
with the most fervour.
You led the way for the others.
Am I to be the one?
Yes, of course, Daron.
But there is one thing
I must ask of you.
You mean... you mean
to prove myself worthy.
Yes.
Are you willing?
There's nothing I won't do.
Good, good.
Because there are those
among our community,
mercifully few, I'm glad to say,
who simply do not believe.
Oh, they'll come around, Vicar.
-I'm sure of it.
-Time is short, Daron.
We have opened our hearts to
these souls and they have refused us.
That refusal has led them
straight into the hands of Satan.
Now that our disciples have arrived,
these servants of the devil...
must be struck down.
You know who they are, don't you?
And all you have
to do is think of them,
and they will be delivered from evil.
Priority code 8954B.
Secure line.
Get me containment HQ, please.
Sal?
Hi.
What's up?
I want you to find out all you can
on Natasha Alexander.
-Why?
-Because...
All I'm getting
is a brick wall.
-But that's not possible.
-I know.
It seems someone doesn't
want me to know about this.
Well, there's nothing on the standard
personnel register.
It could mean she's pretty important.
Keep looking for me...
-Would you?
-Yes.
Yeah, okay.
Oh, by the way, I may have something for you
on that sheet sample.
Yes?
Well, it's old, that's for sure.
It doesn't conform to any types
manufactured within the last ten years.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, you're not going to like this.
Try me.
Do you think you can work with him?
Oh, yes.
He's not going to make it easy for me,
but we're going to get along just fine.
You are clear about
your orders, Natasha?
Quite clear, Colonel.
Those are the possible points of
origin for the sheet.
This is going to mean an increase
in manpower.
-Can't we narrow it down?
-Afraid not.
Those are all the locations
where that make of sheet
has been available within
a hundred mile radius.
This is ridiculous.
Just because the sheet comes
from one area doesn't
mean to say that's where
the truck has gone.
No, but it's a start.
And I do think you need at least to
make a start, Colonel Wilson.
You've got a feeling about that sheet,
haven't you, Lockwood.
No.
Is someone going to drive me home?
You will give me a call,
won't you, Colonel,
when you've come up
with something useful.
I'll get in the car.
Again.
Can't wait to get
away from you, can he?
Give me a map.
Sorry to interrupt.
You're not going back
to containment HQ, Lockwood.
We're going to be working together.
It's not my choice.
And it's certainly not
your choice, I know.
But you and I don't
have any choice, do we?
That's something the
stwo of us have in common.
They recruited me as a child.
Parents didn't want me,
couldn't cope with their psychic daughter.
Couldn't lie to me, you see,
and I kept blowing all
the fuses in the house
every time I was smacked
and sent to my room.
UNIT's been my life.
Yes, you and I have a
lot in common, Lockwood.
Take a look at these locations.
-Now what?
-Simple psychic trick.
My party piece.
Remember what you were
thinking when you first saw that sheet?
-I wasn't thinking anything.
-Remember.
Sentinel Island.
No, not just bad dreams.
It's over.
Is it?
She'll come round.
I know she will.
I promise.
I swear it.
Of course she will.
Why don't you go and bring her to me?
Go on.
That's the one.
Seconded from Naval Intelligence boys.
That should do the trick.
After all, we don't want to go charging in
like the D-day landings.
This could all be a wild goose chase.
It isn't.
Yes, well...
UNIT High Command won't
get the British government's permission for
a full-scale assault on Sentinel
without concrete evidence.
-Did we get the AT36?
-Yes, sir.
It's a prototype but fully tested.
All the men have been issued with the new
high-powered ammunition.
No reports of any trouble from
the island, sir. Not a peep.
All the same, we need to land
somewhere quiet, uninhabited.
Shouldn't be too difficult.
There's only one village on the island.
Few outlying houses.
There should do.
-Very well. Carry on, Sergeant.
-Sir.
All right, lads, let's get a move on.
-Have you seen Lockwood?
-Yes.
Well, where is he?
Making a few discoveries,
I should imagine.
-Ah, Sentinel Island, Got it.
-Interesting?
-You into ley lines?
-What?
Ley lines.
There's one that runs
right through the island.
So there is.
And there are some
ancient burial grounds.
You think the creature from the warehouse
is on this island?
Yes, I do.
Anything on this Alexander woman?
I'm looking at her record now.
Natasha Alexander.
-She's a psychic.
-I know. What else?
From the Internal Security Division.
Lockwood?
Yes?
You know what the ISD do, don't you?
Yes.
Well, are they investigating
you or what?
Perhaps.
Lockwood, what's happened?
What, have you, I mean, why
would they be investigating you?
-Do they know the truth about you?
-Bound to, I suppose.
Something's going on, isn't it?
Sal, I remember.
I did authorise the
transport of those Autons.
-Lockwood.
-I have to go, Sal. Bye.
Doctor Arnold.
You'd better send them in.
Charlie, it's me.
-Is it safe?
-Yes.
What happened?
Did you call the mainland?
Did the police take the vicar away?
What's
It's all right.
Everything's going to be all right.
You see, Charlie?
Oh, my God.
I have a new member for our congregation.
Thank you, Daron.
-There's no need to be afraid, Charlie.
-Who the hell are you?
What are you doing here,
you murdering.
What have you done to Daron?
A strong young mind.
Just what we need.
Some do resist more than others.
Personally, I blame
it on your rather
expensive university education.
No simple faith.
You see?
You can't fight it.
This is something far
older than mankind itself.
It's been waiting.
Now it's calling to you for help,
and you
won't want to refuse.
Beautiful, isn't it?
-Seems quiet enough.
-Well?
-What do you think?
-I think this is Colonel Wilson's show,
and you, Miss Alexander,
are his scientific advisor.
I'm only here at Geneva's insistence.
Ramsay, have the pilot
drop anchor, get
the men on deck and
prepare the dinghies.
Sir.
Let us pray.
Don't tell me.
You've a feeling
we're being watched.
Ramsay, take one man and scout ahead.
-Stay in contact.
-Sir.
Hargreaves, you're with me.
The soldiers must not interfere.
Greyhound One to Greyhound Leader.
Greyhound Leader.
Go ahead.
No sign of anything suspicious.
Steep incline ahead.
Heavy woodland on top.
Band of the Coldstream Guards could be in
there for all we know.
All right, Greyhound One.
Find a way up but
exercise extreme caution.
We have entered woodland
and will hold this position. Over.
Take cover.
Lockwood!
What is it?
Autons.
Greyhound One.
What's happening, over?
Greyhound Leader.
Autons firing from cover.
Hargreaves is dead.
Request covering fire.
This is Greyhound Leader to all Greyhounds.
Covering fire.
Cease fire.
Are you all right, Ramsay?
Just like old times, Lockwood.
What's the situation, Sergeant?
They can see us.
We can't see them.
They've got us pinned down.
We must assess the
strength of their force.
Do not allow them to leave.
Leave her.
-She's not important now.
-I have to go to her.
You've experienced the rapture.
You belong with us now.
No.
We can't make it back to the boat,
they'll cut us down.
We need reinforcements.
This is Greyhound Leader
to Broadsword.
Greyhound Leader
calling Broadsword.
Urgent assistance required.
Do you read me?
You're wasting your time, Colonel.
The last thing they're going to let us do
is call for the cavalry.
The AT36.
Let's show them we mean business.
Davis, prepare the AT36.
-Do we know if this thing works?
-Precisely.
It's strange they haven't
moved in for the kill yet.
All we need now is a target.
Greyhound Four reports movement, sir.
Stand by.
Peek-a-boo,
you plastic bastard.
Davis, fire.
Yes!
This isn't solving anything.
We've got to find some answers.
Haven't you got any?
You knew they'd be here.
Yes, I suppose I did.
Autons are controlled
by the Nestene Consciousness.
We know a damaged
fragment of that escaped
from a top security
warehouse two years ago.
That fragment, that creature,
must be on this island.
If we can find out what it's doing here, we
might at least be half-way to stopping it.
At the moment, we're falling
right into its trap by
participating in a pointless
shoot-out we can't win.
All quiet on the Western Front.
It seems they're not
intending to annihilate us.
What is it?
Lockwood!
Sir.
Where the hell are they going?
-Ramsay, get them back here.
-Yes, sir.
What the hell are you doing?
This place is crawling with Autons.
-One of the locals.
-Perhaps with some answers.
How did you know?
Oh, Lockwood.
Lockwood.
Down!
No!
We've got to get out of here.
The, the church.
Something...
Beneath the church.
What is it?
They've cut off our retreat.
We can't get back to the others.
Come on.
Got any more shots
in that thing, Davis?
Three, sir.
Greyhound Leader
to Greyhound One.
Where are you?
Greyhound Leader,
say again.
Heavy interference.
I'm afraid the signals
it's using to control
the Autons are jamming
our transmissions.
It's?
Let me get this straight.
Are we still dealing with the blob that got
out of the air vents two years ago?
How did it get here?
Your guess is as good as mine.
Something beneath the church.
What?
That's what that girl said,
before she died.
What's under the church?
What's the matter?
Can't you read my mind?
The idea of not being in control
really upsets you, doesn't it?
No. What really upsets me...
is the idea of being investigated
by the Internal Security Division.
You're with the ISD?
And you're investigating him?
And she's apparently psychic.
When that girl looked at you,
she saw whatever she
thinks is under the church here.
Wait a minute.
Why are you investigating Lockwood?
He's UNIT's best operative.
We're investigating
him because his...
special abilities...
are a two-way street.
Did you think your
dreams would be exempt?
Dreams?
There must have been
a moment of contact,
when somehow the
Nestene Consciousness
has gained a foot-hold in your mind.
I have to know if
it's just taken up
lodgings or whether
it's the landlord.
You're mixing your metaphors.
Don't you think we'd better
investigate this church...
before Colonel Wilson is
obliged to make his last stand?
Well, if the church is the centre
of their operations,
that's where we've got to go.
We knock out the blob,
we stop the Autons, right?
Right.
Come on.
Of course...
if I am working
for the other side,
I may not even be aware of it.
Had you thought of that one,
Miss Alexander?
Oh, yes.
Ramsay...
I want you to go back,
get Wilson and the rest of the men.
No way.
Don't argue...
Just go.
What is it?
Come on.
Lockwood.
UNIT's creature.
At last.
O come, all ye faithful.
Well?
Sense of...
Joy...
Overwhelming rapture.
Then there's confusion...
And loss...
And fear.
Oh, well, that
explains everything.
Thank you.
Perhaps if you hadn't shut yourself
away all your life,
obsessed by your own uniqueness,
you might be able to admit
some of those things yourself.
I've seen them...
In black and white.
Maybe if you could be
honest with yourself
we might  find out what the
Nestene Consciousness is trying to achieve.
What's the matte...
No sarcastic come-back
at the ready?
No.
You've been betrayed by
your own people, Lockwood,
treated as an outsider.
But for the first time in your life,
you feel as if you
belong to...
Something.
I think this is the moment when
you make a run for it, Miss Alexander.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Why have you brought me here?
Oh, I think you know.
You should have left when
you had the chance.
I'm keeping an eye on you.
Your leaving was not an option...
Natasha Alexander.
In your own way, you might be as
helpful to us as Lockwood.
What do you mean?
Our good people of the island here...
Are as devoted to us...
as they can be...
but their mental energies are,
without exception I'm
afraid, rather modest.
It's been a long,
laborious job,
but we're
nearly there.
All we need now is...
A little push...
From your...
excellently nurtured mental powers,
Miss Alexander...
And Lockwood's special knowledge.
And what special
knowledge would that be?
Still resisting.
Very commendable,
Lockwood...
but pointless.
When we last met,
a seed was
planted in your mind.
Your very...
very special mind, Lockwood.
You're too kind.
It's been...
Germinating...
and you don't
want to stop it...
Do you.
What's under this church?
What has always been...
Since long before
the dawn of Mankind.
As Lockwood will tell you,
we have been...
Colonising other planets...
for a thousand million years.
We Nestenes visited this world...
and many others...
Long before
intelligent life evolved.
We made...
Investments...
For the future.
Consequently, this ground
has always been...
Feared...
Revered...
Worshipped!
Many of these sites do survive,
but none so
perfectly intact...
As this.
Lockwood, you've got
to listen to me.
He belongs to us now.
And so will you.
We are awakening one
of the surviving Nestene creatures.
A beacon waiting to be ignited.
Through it we shall
bring the  entire
Nestene Consciousness to Earth.
Opposition will be...
-Impossible.
-Lockwood, can't you see what you're doing?
With Lockwood's knowledge of all UNIT's
plans for combating alien invasion...
We will be...
Invincible.
No!
You said it would be
me leading the prayer.
That I would
bring him back to us.
Are you all right?
We've succeeded, Lockwood.
It won't be long before
contact is established.
The entire Nestene Consciousness?
Lockwood, you've got to stop it.
They're uploading every scrap
of information you have access to.
You're going to leave the
Earth open to invasion.
They'll destroy us all!
But not Lockwood.
He'll live on in the Consciousness.
He'll belong.
He's nothing in
common with you...
Or the rest
of your race.
What the hell happened here?
Get down.
Davis, prepare to give
it your last shot.
Don't shoot.
Sergeant, where the
hell have you been?
We've got to move fast, sir.
Lockwood and Natasha are in trouble.
They can't be.
What sort of trouble?
That kind of trouble.
Listen to me,
you stubborn old bastard.
Don't let that
smooth-talking piece
of plastic let you
wallow in self-pity.
Look into my mind.
I know what it's like
to be the outsider...
but we make
ourselves outsiders.
The trick is to let people in.
Lockwood,
I'm letting you in.
You've got to stop...
What have you done?
What have I done?
You're not off the hook yet.
I haven't finished my investigation.
-All right?
-Thank you.
Have you finished
your investigation?
No.
I'll leave you to it, then.
He's the soul of discretion.
Where did that creature go?
It hasn't gone, has it?
Lockwood, what have you done?
Whose side are you on?