Sincro: wyxchari
The humans have been told to begin the test.
Any delay will result in death.
There will be no delay!
Mollie, Mollie. Mr. McCrimmon has been kidnapped! It means the end of us unless we can find him quickly.
Straw.
I beg your pardon?
A piece of straw.
Had a cosy little sleep, young swell?
Lively, is it? Maybe you'd like to sleep again? I've got Mr. Nod here.
He'll have you snorin' as good as ever.
What do you want?
I'm to be well paid. Have no fear of that.
Oh, and for what? I don't know you.
This your man, sir?
Toby! What in Hades have you done?
Why, I, uh... brought 'im from the house, like you said.
I said nothing of the kind.
Well ya did, sir! Honest ya did. A guinea ya promised me. I... I done what ya said. You don't get outta payin'.
Be careful how you speak to me, Toby!
There's your money. Get out!
Where's Toby?
You just sent him about his business. Look, what's the matter? Are you all right?
Where's Victoria Waterfield?
I don't know.
Yes, you do.
I tell you, I don't even know her!
You're in the house, a friend of Maxtible's. You must know!
No, listen, I'm te...
Ha, I must apologize for that villain Toby. He was telling lies, of course. I shall escort you to the house.
Uh, You... you... you just asked me about Victoria Waterfield.
Now, she's in Paris. I'm afraid I haven't introduced myself - Arthur Terrall.
Well, never mind about that. Did you or did you not ask that man to knock me on the head and bring me in here?
I, oh...
...certainly not!
Oh.
Doctor, oh. I see you're in good hands now. I won't detain you any further. Good day, Doctor.
Oh, good day to you.
He's mad. Stark, staring mad!
Yes, I know. I was listening. Let's have a look at that head of yours. Come along.
Look, it's all right, Doctor. One minute he says this, the next minute he says that. Can you make it out, Doctor? I'm knocked on the head and I'm brought in here. Then that man Terrall enters and denies having ordered the other man to do it. Well, then he changes, and starts asking about Victoria Waterfield and in the next breath, he tells me she's in Paris!
I know what's happened to Victoria.
What has?
She's a prisoner of the Daleks.
Hurry!
Why am I being moved? Are you taking me back to my father?
No, you are being moved. Pick up your cover. Follow. Do not be afraid.
You are not to be exterminated.
Do not delay.
Move.
You've warned him - told him about the Daleks?
Yes, of course I did!
But you were expressly told...
Oh, fiddlesticks!
Bosh! Jamie will cooperate. You may be certain of that.
Are you sure?
Yes, perfectly sure. Jamie will do everything he is asked to do. Now come along, we must go and find Maxtible.
The female human being has been moved.
Everything is prepared.
The testing equipment is ready?
I think you will be pleased with the man I've had specially brought from London. Ah, he works in my house.
Show me!
You will understand that he is rather simple. He's quite dumb, but, uh... that has its advantages for us. His mind is, how shall I say, undeveloped. He will not understand you, the Daleks. Uh, I mean he will be terrified of you.
Show me.
Ohh, I beg your pardon, uh...
Kemel!
Will you come with me? I want you to stand here. No, no, no, no, no, face the cabinet. Good.
Now, bend that.
Excellent Kemel, excellent. Now, you'll help me with these stools.
Now, Kemel. One blow. Break the plank!
Very good Kemel. I'm very pleased with you. Now you can put on your jacket.
Come over here. Now, I want you to listen carefully. See this man?
Now, I'm going to take you to a place that I want you to guard, and this young man will try and get past you and you are not to let him. Do you understand? Oh, he's an evil villain, Kemel, a cutthroat who would gladly murder us all in our beds, if he could. You will remember this man, hmm?
Right. Well, you come with me and I will direct you.
You wait here. This is the entrance to the south wing of my house, and through here will pass the man I showed you in the picture. The door itself is an obstacle.
No, no, wait!
Now, if he gets through here, you will deal with him. Go now.
We do not trust you.
Then we're quits, aren't we?
But we have your time machine.
Yes.
So, you will obey us.
They want the "Human Factor", is that right?
Yes, that is what they want.
Very complex. And you want to introduce this "human factor" into the race of Daleks?
Yes, the conquest of humanity has eluded us. The Daleks must know why.
But, why choose Jamie for this test?
His travelling with you makes him unique.
But why him? Why not me?
Request denied.
Why?
You have travelled too much through time. You are more than human.
I see.
What is this?
They have been brought from the Dalek planet.
Skaro!
Yes, their life force is dormant. Before it is activated, we want...
You want the "human factor" introduced. I see.
You will obey us!
I will make up my own mind!
Do not antagonize them, Doctor. They will destroy your time machine!
And if I agree, it means the creation of a race of super-Daleks!
My TARDIS... I have no choice, do I? Very well. I agree.
The human being with you must not be aware of the trial.
I quite understand.
Make him begin the test!
What must Jamie do?
Attempt to rescue Waterfield's daughter.
There we are, sir.
Thank you, Mollie.
Arthur, I'd like you to meet Mr. McCrimmon.
May I ask what you are doing in this house?
I was just about to ask you the same thing.
Oh, you gentlemen have been introduced?
Aye, we've met.
It seems, Ruth, your father has the oddest collection of house guests these days.
Now Arthur, please!
You must forgive him, Mr. McCrimmon.
Ah, it's becoming a habit.
I don't care for insolence.
Well, I'm not keen on arrogance myself!
Why, you bite at each other as if you were old enemies!
I'm sorry if I seem rude.
Come, I want you to be friends. Won't you be so, to please me?
Arthur... Arthur, what is it? Excuse me. Arthur! What's the matter?
Sir?
Yes?! Oh, I wish you'd call me Jamie.
Oh, I couldn't do that sir. What would the master say?
Oh, who cares! Ah, What can I do for you?
If you'd tell me where your bags are, sir - yours and the Doctor's - I'll have them taken up to your room.
Aye. well, Mollie...
Listen to me, "have them taken. " I dare say I'll be doin' it meself!
You see, we didn't have time to pick up the luggage. It'll be following.
Oh.
Why do you say that you'll be doing it yourself?
Well, they do say, sir, that the house is haunted. Mr. Kitson, the butler, left, and cook and the two footmen are complainin' again.
Haunted?
Mmm. But, I've never heard anything sir. I sleep like a log and always have.
Aye. well, I'm glad you've got over the fright you had.
Oh, yes, that horrible man. Miss Ruth said it was all a game, but I dunno sir. I've never fainted before, sir. Truly I haven't.
Not "sir", "Jamie"!
Tell me about Arthur Terrall.
Miss Ruth's fiancé, sir?
Aye.
Oh, oh, he's a kind man, sir. Usually.
Usually?
Mmm. Well, when he's a bit odd or his temper's up, as it has been lately, I says to meself "Inkerman" and then it's all right.
"Inkerman"?
Yes sir. 'e was out in the Crimea, 'e was. They do say Mr. Terrall was wounded out there. Do you know, my uncle was killed at Inkerman, sir. So, you see, I do know what it's like with soldiers.
Oh... oh, I'm sorry sir. I didn't mean to... Well cook said to me that if I did some dusting it would be all right. Oh, you won't tell the master, will you? That I... Ah, ah... Thank you. Sorry sir.
Sorry Mollie. Never mind, Mollie. That will do. Yes, Mollie, thank you very much. It's all right, Mollie. I wouldn't dream of telling him. Thank you very much, Bye-bye.
Hmm, you'll have to brush up on your history. I can't be around to cover up for you all the time.
Now then, in the Crimean War, the English, the French and the Turks fought the Russians...
Oh, forget about all that!
Oh, I thought you'd be interested. I watched the Charge of the Light Brigade. Magnificent folly...
Look, where've you been?
Oh, just looking around.
Aye. What for? The TARDIS?!
Jamie, you're in a temper!
Oh, am I? Is that bad then? Does that mean I won't be co-operative - I won't do everything I'm told?
What was that?
I overheard you and Waterfield!
You were eavesdropping!
Well, whatever it is, I don't like what you're doing.
Now you listen to me...!
No, Doctor, you're forgetting the TARDIS was stolen and a man was murdered! Now, how am I supposed to tell when I see you as friendly as you like with the murderer!
Waterfield did not murder that man!
All right then, but he stole the TARDIS and that still makes him a thief!
The Daleks forced him to!
The Daleks! You keep telling me about the Daleks, and I haven't even seen one! You're always on about them, but where are they?!
Now you listen to me...!
No, you'll not get round me this time, Doctor. You're up to something with Waterfield and Maxtible. Now what is it? Some scientific invention?!
Oh, here's your friend.
Just a little argument.
I heard voices raised.
That's not all you'll hear!
Jamie seems to think that I'm lying to him.
Well, aren't you?!
He doesn't believe the Daleks are here.
It's the truth.
Aye, the truth you told Arthur Terrall, maybe - that your daughter was in Paris!
I had to tell him that.
So, you've got another story to tell me?
I tell you that the Daleks are holding my daughter prisoner in the south wing of this house, Mr. McCrimmon.
Then why don't you try and get her back, eh?! What are you doing?!
Well, what can I do? Now, be... be fair Jamie. Waterfield's tied hand and foot because of his daughter and we're tied hand and foot because of the TARDIS!
Aye, and that's all you can think about, isn't it? The TARDIS. Well, you can all stand around doing nothing. I'm sick to death of it!
Now just where are you going?
To be by myself for a bit. Do you mind?
No, not a bit. But, one word of warning. Don't you try to be a one-man army. You leave well alone. I won't have you ruining everything trying to rescue Victoria Waterfield. Now, you understand?!
Well, are you sure you didn't go a little too far, Doctor?
Adding a little fuel to the fire. Tell Maxtible that I'll be along to his laboratory shortly.
Oh, very well, Doctor. If you're sure.
Oh yes, quite sure. Once our young friend has cooled his heels a bit, he'll launch off on his own. And you dropped the hint about the south wing beautifully.
Well, what is it? You wanted to see me?
Very good of you to talk to me, gov'nor.
Well, never mind all that. I'll give you two minutes, no more.
I want me rights. No more, no less.
What do you mean, "rights"?
'alf a guinea, you gave me, and it ain't what we said.
You were lucky to get anything.
That ain't fair!
You'll get no more from me. I warn you! Keep away from this house, and this property. Find the nearest road to London and take it!
Oh, yeah, London, sir. Yeah, I daresay I could earn something for me stories there.
Stories?
Oh, I won't detain an important gentleman like yourself. Like as not me two minutes is up anyway.
What do you mean, "stories"?
Ah, it's all right, sir. I'll take a stroll to London...
Don't play with me!
Get off me! If you must know, there's plenty who'd pay to hear what I've got to tell 'em.
Indeed.
Yeah. You blows too hot and cold for me - tellin' me this one minute and that the next, and not payin' up.
You know nothing.
Don't I though?
Hmm. Who'd believe you anyway?
Pay me off, and there's the end of it!
Oh, blackmail is it?! Get out!
Maybe I don't know much to tell, but I'll wager I'll find something in the house that's worth me trouble. So, I'll say thank ya, Mr. Terrall, sir!
It's only me, Mollie!
It's over here, sir. I took it from the master's study.
It's marvellous. Thank you!
'ere, is this what you wanted?
Perfect, yes. Let's see, umm... this is the south wing here?
Yes sir, but it's been closed off.
Completely?
Oh, no sir. Only 'cause of some repairs about a twelve-month back. But the door may be locked.
Can you show me?
All right. What're you gonna do, sir?
Off to hunt a few wee ghosties, Mollie.
Every single one of Jamie's reactions will be recorded on these Dalek machines?
And then transformed into thought patterns on silver wire. A wonderful creation!
It is for you, Doctor, to select the major feelings to make up this "human factor".
Oh, yes. I quite understand.
We can rely on the Doctor to give us all cooperation.
We shall watch your every move.
I'm sure you will. And every step of Jamie's progress will be covered?
Yes.
The young human being is on his way.
Then the recording machines can be set in action.
Here!
Yes, sir. I once remember the master stepping away from here. When he saw me, he was very cross and told me to keep away.
I see.
What was that? What was that?!
That was no ghost, Mollie, that's for sure. That was a human voice!
Oh, sir!
Look Mollie, take the candle and go back to your room. Will you do that?
Yes sir.
Now, do you want me to see you safely there?
No, no. I'll be all right.
Hello. Who are you?