Sincro: wyxchari
Hello? Who are you?
It took courage to fight Maxtible's Turkish wrestler.
The Daleks are afraid of nothing and no one.
But Jamie saved the Turk's life.
Human weakness.
If he hadn't, he would have died in that room of yours. If you want the Human Factor, a part of it must include mercy.
What... what is he doing here?
A common thief, come to see what he could steal. No mystery here.
The intruder was destroyed.
Well, what... what are we to do? Where is the Doctor? He must be told.
No.
Why not?
Obey me!
Waterfield, I... I... I beg of you, do not antagonize the, um... hmm...
...our friends.
Oh, why do you consistently avoid reality, Maxtible? Another man has died. Can't you grasp that fact?
You will hide the remains of the dead human intruder.
No!
That is an order!
We must do as they say, Waterfield. We... we... we cannot anger them.
Here. Wrap the body in this.
No.
We must! Have you lost your mind? Don't you want to see your daughter again?
Th... there's no end to this. The hands of the Devil.
Dispose of the body. Obey!
Waterfield, what is the matter with you? We are not to blame for everything that has happened. No English judge or jury would find it in their hearts to convict us of one solitary thing.
It will never come to that.
And what may that remark mean?
I have one purpose only: to see my daughter out of the hands of those foul monsters. When that is achieved, I shall confess my part in all that has happened.
Y... You must help me.
I am at your heels, my dear sir.
That's better, thank you. Aye, you're an odd one. I'll say that. Aye, well, I... I suppose we're both a a bit touched, eh? Knocking each other about the place and saving one another's lives.
You don't say much, do you?
Oh, I see. You can't talk? Aye. Well, you're a sight better than a number of people I know who can. I wonder what your name is?
Kemel? Well, I'm Jamie.
He... hey, what is that?! Now come on now. None of that. We're to be friends. Do you hear? Friends.
Aye.
"V.W." I know, Victoria Waterfield.
Oh, Miss Waterfield gave you the flower? You like her?
Of course. Then what are we fighting for?
Do you not know what I'm doing here, Kemel? Victoria Waterfield is being held a prisoner here somewhere.
Together? Aye, we'll go together. There's no one I'd rather have with me.
What was that? Did you hear it?
Control your nerves.
But there was a noise.
Waterfield, go back to the house.
Hmm? Oh, we have a task to perform.
Waterfield, I am sick to death of you.
What?
I take you into my house, you and your daughter - provide for you.
Yes, I know everything that you've done.
Small thanks do I get for it! I did not bring these terrible creatures here deliberately, you know that. Am I to blame for everything?
No, no.
No, it is your daughter they have kidnapped. One moment, you beg me to do everything I can to rescue her; next moment, you blame me.
Yes. I... I don't mean it like that. It's the price. First Kennedy, now this fellow. How many people must die so that my daughter can live?
We are not the murderers!
No, just the silent partners. But we're equally to blame because we stand by and do nothing.
Go back to the house, Waterfield. I... I understand you are under a stress. You... you try and get some sleep.
Sleep? I've not had one good night's rest since this started.
There. You go back to your room. Near the end now. You've done enough.
What... what are you doing?
Waterfield does not die yet!
He says he will confess everything!
Go back to the laboratory. I will dispose of the body. You will obey. You will obey!
Wait. Never mind about those, Kemel, unless they catch sight of us. We seem to be going in the right direction.
Down!
We do not trust you. What thoughts are you using now?
Human beings have five senses: sight, hearing, taste, smell and touch. But there is instinct too. And Jamie used instinct to avoid your trap.
Name?
Victoria.
Louder.
Victoria! Victoria Waterfield! You know my name!
Silence. Inspection is over. Return to your room.
She's very beautiful, Kemel.
What are you going to do with that?
You'll attack the Daleks - draw them off down the corridor, while I go up there and rescue her somehow? It's too dangerous, Kemel. Besides, needs two of us up there. But how?
What is the significance of this thought pattern?
Suicidal attacks to gain an objective. Postulate. Self-preservation is a strong human factor. Jamie and his new friend are determined to succeed. But finding the girl is only part. Getting her away is another.
You'll come in here, Mollie, and explain yourself.
Oh... Oh, sir... Please, sir... You're hurting me!
Now, what is this hysterical nonsense?
But sir, I heard Miss Victoria's voice!
Did she say how the weather was in Paris? That's where she is, Mollie.
Well, I know that sir, but I heard her speaking.
Where?
I was walking past the big fireplace in the hall sir, and her voice sort of... floated out of it.
Will you explain how you could possibly hear Miss Waterfield's voice when she's in Paris?!
I know it can't be, sir, but I heard her, as plain as anything.
What were you doing in the hall?
Oh, well. I wasn't doing anything wrong, sir.
What were you doing in this part of the house at this hour?!
Oh, I don't know.
You do know, and you'll tell me!
Arthur!
I found this child creeping about the corridors.
I haven't done anything.
Be quiet!
Yes sir.
She's miles from her room - should have been in bed an hour since!
Did you have extra work this morning?
Yes, Miss Ruth. I do.
You're a liar!
Well, I haven't done anything, Miss. I haven't took nothing.
Arthur, the poor child's frightened out of her skin after this.
She's nothing but play acting. She's a mean, sniveling little minx.
But I haven't done anything. I haven't.
Go to the sitting room and wait there. Mr. Maxtible will decide what to do with you.
But sir, I...
Do as you are told!
Mollie, it's all right. Everything will be all right.
Arthur, tell me what's wrong.
Wrong? Why should something be wrong?
Has my father influenced you in some way?
No, not your father.
Come away with me please! I somehow feel if we delay, it will be too late.
I can't go. Not yet.
I have done everything you have asked me to. You wanted an agency here on Earth to plan and prepare things for you. I have been that agency. Will you please tell those who give you orders that I am getting tired of waiting.
Do you threaten the Daleks?
Oh, surely threatening is not necessary. We have a... a partnership - an understanding.
You have obeyed us.
You have a strange way of putting things. I prefer to say that you have asked for certain services. I have, uh... provided those services punctually and efficiently. Now you really must look to your side of the bargain. It is not beyond me to ruin the entire enterprise.
Oh, oh, oh, ho!
Do not threaten! Obey!
Yes, very well! I understand!
Obey the Daleks.
No. Please... Please wait!
The secret... the secret. You promised to give it to me! That is why I have done all this!
The Daleks know many secrets. You will learn the most important.
I must not be frightened of them. It's just their way. Th... They're different people - alien. But they will tell me! Of course they will!
Father!
Ruth, I told you not to come in here - under any circumstances.
Father, I simply had to. I heard you speaking to someone and there's no one here. And Arthur is involved in some way.
Oh, Arthur. Yes.
Why has he become so changed? And Victoria Waterfield - where is she?
My child, these are questions that I cannot answer. But, my dear, I will tell you one thing - one thing only, and then perhaps you may understand why there are secrets to be kept.
You see this?
What is it?
A piece of ordinary metal of very little value, would you not say so?
I suppose so.
What does it weigh? A few pounds? Five, six, shall we say? For centuries now, men have searched for the greatest secret of all. Some say it was known to the ancient alchemists. Some say that the secret never existed at all. But still, the stories and the rumours, and the search goes on!
What secret?!
The transmutation of metal into gold. Changing metal into gold. Now, perhaps, do you begin to understand a little? To possess such a secret would mean power and influence beyond all imagination. And I am about to discover this secret. Nothing will stop me. Nothing! Nobody!
Name?
Victoria.
Louder!
Victoria Waterfield!
Inspection is over. Return to your room.
Well, that's fixed that one.
Look out, the rail's going to break!
Miss Waterfield? Can you open the door? We've come to get you.