Sincro: wyxchari
It's a game, Jamie! They're playing a game!
A rather amusing little game, don't you think so Jamie.
We've done it! Maxtible, they've got the "Human Factor". We've done it! What are they doing now? Look, they're all joining in. They're playing train!
Train, train, train, train.
Oh... oh, now what is it? Oh, we're on the roundabout. They're playing roundabout. Oh, I'm getting dizzy. Oh dear. Oh, oh, ho, ho, oh. I'm dizzy! Oh, ho, ho. I'm dizzy.
Diz-yy, diz-yy, dizzy Doctor.
Maxtible, do you hear that? They've got a sense of humour!
I'm glad you are so easily amused.
Well, I congratulate you, Doctor. They are almost human.
They are!
And I will now leave you to your little game.
Oh, thank you.
Well, how old are they now, Doctor - mentally?
Oh, they're just young children, but they'll grow up very fast - within a matter of hours. Now, uh... come here all of you. Come along, gather round. Come here. Now then, come along, come along.
Who is this?
Oh, this is Jamie. He's a friend.
Friend. Hello, friend.
Well, say hello Jamie.
Hello.
You know what a friend is, don't you? It's somebody who... who likes you - who wants to help you and share with you.
There we are.
What have you done?
I have given you all names. Alpha, Beta and Omega.
Alpha, Beta, Omega. Alpha, Beta, Omega. Alpha, Beta, Omega.
Yes, yes, yes. now... now, this is Jamie and I am Doctor. We are friends.
Friends, friends, Jamie, Doctor, friends, friends. We must go now. We are called.
Go? Go where? What do you mean, "go"?
All Daleks are ordered to return to Skaro.
Return to Skaro? But, that's the Dalek planet.
Friend.
But if the Daleks are returning to Skaro, where's Victoria?
Victoria! We left her in the secret passage. Come on - follow me!
I assure you, my dear Waterfield, Victoria is perfectly safe.
But where is she?
The Daleks have released her.
Released?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Well, then, where is she?
She's probably lying down. Ruth will be taking care of her. You may be sure of that.
Not Ruth, no. I saw her and Mollie helping Arthur Terrall into a dog-cart not half an hour since.
Ruth and Terrall?
Yes. Surely you knew they were leaving?
Oh, yes, yes, indeed, yes. It, it slipped my memory. Umm... As you see, I'm going for a little trip myself. I... No doubt, I shall join them. Well, possibly she's, ah... taking a stroll in the garden. Go along and see. Go along and see.
Yes
Well, go along man! Go along and see. Find your Victoria.
Stupid, stupid girl.
What are you doing?
Merely, ah... looking.
Do not touch the instrument.
What is that box for?
Do not question. You have your orders.
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes. To... To bring the Doctor and his companion to you here for our little trip.
Yes
And then... The secret - you will give it to me?
Yes.
The formula - the transmutation formula.
Yes. Obey your order. Do not delay.
Doctor, Doctor! Doctor!
Oh, Waterfield, how I'm delighted you've come back. Now will you please go and find the Doctor and his companion Jamie and bring them here to me? It is a matter of some urgency.
Maxtible?
Oh, what is it?
What have you "arranged" with the Daleks?
The Daleks; nothing.
What formula did they promise you?
No formula whatever.
What are you doing? You've sold yourself to them, haven't you?
You fool!
Yes, I'm a fool - a fool not to have realised before that it was you who brought this misery down on us.
You, you never did understand anything, did you? Well, metal into gold. That's what the Daleks are going to give me. Now do you begin to understand? The secret of the transmutation of metal into gold.
Do you imagine I care about that?! Where is Victoria?
I've not the remotest idea.
Yes, you have, and you're going to tell me!
Get your hands off my throat. Let go of me! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Oh.
Oh, what are you doing?
Where is the Doctor?
Well, I had no time to bring him.
Hurry. That is an order.
What is that box for? Will you tell me?
We are destroying this area.
But you can't do that. Turn it off! You cannot destroy my house!
Bring the Doctor. Obey! Immediately!
But, uh... the secret. If you destroy my laboratory, the secret is useless! You promised me. They must be out of their minds! Destroy my laboratory? the very idea. Well, well. But, oh, goodness gracious me, only two minutes. Doctor, Doctor, Doctor, Doctor, Doctor. Oh, you fool.
All Daleks return to Skaro.
And the prisoners?
They are already in transit.
Doc... Dalek... Doctor.
Waterfield, what's happened to you?
Doc... Doctor, Daleks are going to destroy... house. Can't turn it off.
But, this is a time switch.
Well, if you can't turn it off, surely...
No, wait a minute. Eighty-nine, eighty-eight, eighty-seven. Just about a minute, that's all we've got.
Well, toss it out the window then.
This isn't a firework. We'd have to toss this half a mile. We'll have to follow the Daleks to Skaro. Jamie, open the doors. Come along.
Doctor, Doctor.
Doctor, they're locked. They won't budge!
Cupboard in the alcove. The time machine.
Time machine! Jamie, give me a hand. Come on. Quickly. Quickly. Here, now... Here, take this.
Now the other one. Steady.
Right. Now, where's Victoria?
Quick Jamie, the time switch!
Twenty-eight, Doctor. Hey, Doctor, Kemel must have dropped this.
Jamie!
We'll find Victoria and Kemel too.
Dear Kemel. Oh, there. Are any of the others here?
The Daleks?
You will wait here.
Oh, Mr. Maxtible.
Oh, what are you doing here?
Don't know. Nor even where here may be.
Oh, we've been transported to the Dalek planet, my dear. To Skaro.
I don't understand you.
A little journey through space.
They've taken us somewhere. Is that what you mean? Away from your house?
Oh, far away. Far, far away.
But why? What do they want?
Well, I know why I am here. But why you are here, I have not the faintest idea.
You seem to understand them. Ask them.
Don't be foolish, girl. I shall do no such thing.
And where's my father?
I do not know. I'm not a nursemaid to your father.
Follow me.
Of course, I shall do my best for you. The matter is really entirely out of my hands.
It's no good. He won't help us. Don't worry Kemel, I shall protect you. I shall see they do you no harm. Yes, I suppose it was a bit silly. Think so? Wish I did.
Oh well. Maybe between us we can fight them. We must face it out together.
And that is the Dalek city?
Yes, it is.
I've scouted around, but I can't see any water.
Oh, please don't bother. I feel much better.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Come along then. We must get along.
You mean just walk into the city?
Oh, no Jamie. The city is all around us. At least, um, it's beneath us. Come along.
How long have you known that's there?
Not a sound. I think the Daleks are in for a little surprise.
Where is the Doctor?
I had no time to get him.
No time?
I was told my house was going to be destroyed. Why?
You did not bring the Doctor?!
Everything I possess is in that house. Everything. What right had you or anyone to destroy it? All these years of labour, all these years of research - destroyed through this caprice of yours. My laboratory - the only real thing in the whole of my existence - destroyed. I, Theodore Maxtible, made a bargain with you, and I demand to know... ah, ah!
Rights? Rights? Rights? Rights? You have disobeyed a Dalek command. You must obey the Dalek command.
Exterminate. Destroy.
I swear... I swear... I swear it's not my fault. I swear it's not my fault. I... No!
Move.
What's happening? What are you going to do with me?
Obey. Move.
These humans are still here.
Then other humans are inside the city.
"Other humans inside the city", Kemel! Listen!
Emergency. Emergency. Human beings detected in city! Emergency! Emergency!
Maybe it's Jamie and the Doctor. Oh, Kemel, there's a chance. A chance.
Intruders detected. Emergency! Emergency! Human beings detected in city. Emergency! Emergency! Intruders detected. All Daleks to observation stations. Repeat. All Daleks to observation stations. Emergency!
Stop! What is that mark?
That is my name.
Name?
The Doctor gave it to me.
Doctor?
Yes. He is my friend.
Follow me.
Remain here.
What is happening? Do you know? They say there are other human beings in the city.
No. No thank you.
Why don't you answer me, you little fool. No one can help you here. No one but me.
Silence. Follow me. You, wait.
I can't see anything.
Move.
Where are you taking me?
Oh, what are they doing to him?
You follow. You will wait.
I'll do as you say.
Move forward, alone.
That was a human voice, I tell you.
Perhaps it was, Jamie
We must go more quickly.
Victoria. That was Victoria's voice.
You can't. Where are you running to? Well, you mustn't. You'll go over the edge!
Doctor, I am your friend.
One of your experiments, Doctor. For a moment I thought we were done for!
What is your name?
Omega.
Oh, I see.
I have come to lead you.
Thank you.
Oh, careful.
Oh, ah... I'm all right. Oh, thank you. Ah, lead on.
Follow me.
What was that screaming?
A prisoner.
Where?
Follow me. I will show you.
What are you doing?
Think I don't know my own mark? That wasn't the real Omega at all.
Up to all sorts of tricks, aren't they?
Oh, please. We must reach my daughter.
I tell you, they forced me. They threatened to kill us all. First of all, they ordered me to scream and I was to make you do the same.
And you had to do as you were told?
I tell you, they threatened to kill me.
You came up behind me in the dark and twisted my arm.
And what else could I do?
Oh, if only I'd realised. Why do you think they wanted us to scream like that?
I've no idea.
You know perfectly well. There are other people in the city. They wanted to draw them on. Trap them. Oh, if only I could have thought quickly. Oh, Kemel.
No, no. I don't like the look of this. Back the way we came.
Follow me.
Doctor!
Look at the size of that thing.
So, you are the Doctor?
We meet at last. I wondered if we ever would.
The experiment is over.
Yes, I have implanted the "Human Factor" in the three Daleks that you gave me... When I say run, run!
Speak louder.
Promise me, Jamie. I was merely telling my friend that the day of the Daleks is coming to an end.
Explain.
It's very simple. Somewhere in the Dalek race there are three Daleks with the "Human Factor" Gradually, they will come to question. They will persuade other Daleks to question. You will have a rebellion on your planet!
NO!
I say, yes. I've beaten you and I don't care what you do to me now.
Silence. The "Human Factor" showed us what the "Dalek Factor" was.
What?
Well, what does that mean?
Without knowing, you have shown the Daleks what their own strength is.
While you were doing one thing, they were really making you do another.
The "Human Factor" is useless.
You still have those three Daleks to contend with.
They will be impregnated with the "Dalek Factor". Your discovery, but your work is not over.
I won't work for you!
You will obey!
What is the "Dalek Factor"?
You want me to guess? It means to obey, to fight, to destroy, to exterminate. I won't do it.
Watch!
The TARDIS, Doctor!
You will take the "Dalek Factor. " You will spread it to the entire history of Earth!