The Tomb of the Cybermen
(Whopix fan edit)
Stand by. Everybody down.
to open the doors.
Miss Kaftan, I must remind you
that I am the leader of the...
- What happened?  - I don't know.
Well, one thing for sure, he's not going to
collect 50 pounds from you or anybody else.
- Quiet. Quiet a minute.  - What's that?
Sounded like an engine.
(WHOOSHING)
- Something came down there! Behind that ...
- OK, Viner. Slow down.
- I'll take care of this. Jim!
- OK. I've got it!
(LOW VOICES)
Hold it right there, friend.
If you put it like that, I certainly will.
Hear that, Professor? English.
(PARRY) Yes. All right, Hopper.
Thank you.
Who are you and where are you from?
And you'd better have a good story.
Maybe you'll not get one.
Listen, fella.
We're not playing games.
- You'd better listen to him.
- What's been happening over here?
He was killed the moment you men  appeared.
Ah. And you think we did it?
Oh no, I can assure you, we had nothing
to do with the death of this man.
He appears to have been electrocuted.
Trying to open these doors, perhaps?
- He seems to know all the answers.
- A wiseguy!
I think this fellow must be
a member of a rival expedition.
(DOCTOR) Expedition?
We've tried to keep it secret.
Unsuccessfully, now it appears.
Archaeologist written all over him.
- Really? Does it show?  - You see?
It's impossible to keep a secret
in the scientific world.
- Doctor, what do you mean?
- Tell them, go on, Doctor, tell them.
No, not until they tell us
the purpose of their expedition.
This is an archaeological expedition.
We are searching the universe
for the last remains of the Cybermen.
Cybermen? You mean to say they came from here?
Of course. Telos was their home.
This is the entrance to their city.
We know they died out centuries ago,
what we don't know is why they died out.
Callum, Rogers! Get him back to the rocket.
I'll be with you in a minute.
That's that. Are you coming back
to the rocket with me, Professor?
- What for?
- You're not going on with this, are you?
I don't know if these people had
anything to do with it or not,
but one of my men was just been killed.
You're not paying that kind of money.
- Yes, I suppose that's quite true.
- You think it over.
Come on, let's go.
We'll wait for you at the ship.
The problem, I take it,
is to open these doors, right?
- Ha! Brilliant.  - That is the problem.
And we would prefer it, if you return
to wherever you came from.
- Not very friendly, are they?
- Do as he says.
That became impossible the moment
that name was mentioned - Cybermen.
Cybermen? What are they?
I knew they're here on the same quest!
No one would come here for any other reason?
- We must stay!  - Doctor!
Must we? I don't like
the look of those things at all.
We shall stay and help you with your research.
Perhaps we don't want help.
That's just it. You obviously do.
Now I'm sure we can agree.
- I can open those doors for you.
- It's our problem!
Can I suggest you take this ridiculous
expedition of yours off this planet!
It seems to me we have
as much right here as you have.
Of course you have!
Mr Klieg, must I remind you again...
that you do not speak for this expedition?
I am its leader.
You and Miss Kaftan
are only here on sufferance.
- Thank you. And whose money is paying
for the hire of that rocket?
- (KAFTAN) Mine!
I thought I made it clear
that your financial support...
did not entitle you to a say
in the running of this expedition!
Of course. It was quite clear.
Was it not, Eric?
Of course.
No one questions your leadership.
Good. That's all settled.
- And now we shall open these doors.
- What...?
- Careful, man!  - Doctor!
Perfectly safe now.
- You'll be killed!  - Don't touch him!
- It's beyond my strength.
- Let me, Doctor.
I've not had much exercise lately.
Quite. I think here is a gentleman
who could open these doors for us.
He is my servant.
I will not have him risk his life.
Surely it was just for such a contingency like this
that you insisted we bring him with us.
There's no danger now.
Unless he's afraid.
No, no. He's not afraid.
- Come on.  - No. Wait!
I would be very careful in there
if I were you.
Why weren't Toberman killed?
Why weren't you killed?
The poor fellow who died drained
all the electricity out of his body.
It's perfectly safe to go in now.
We're wasting time.
Of course. After you, Professor.
But I'd still...
I'd still be very careful if I were you.
Very careful indeed.
Come on. Let's join them.
Come on, Victoria.
You look very nice in that dress.
Thank you.
Don't you think it's a bit...?
Short? I shouldn't worry.
Look at Jamie's.
I'll have you know that... Oh, aye.
Come along. Let's go and see
what the others are doing.
(VICTORIA)
Mercy! Just look at this place.
These controls are of earlier dynasties.
Not so early. Look, John...
I'm quite capable of making
my own deductions! Thank you.
All right.
Be careful. There might be danger.
Don't worry, with Toberman to guard me.
What is more important is
to keep an eye on these strangers.
- I tried to...!
- Do not raise your voice.
You will achieve nothing by shouting.
You look after the Doctor
and I will watch the girl.
- And the Scots boy?
- Leave him to Toberman.
Eh, Toberman?
- But you will be careful and discreet. Understand?
- I understand.
- Did you ever see the like of it, Doctor?
- Not exactly, Jamie, but very nearly.
(PARRY) Now that we're all here...
Now that we're all here, we'd better
take stock of the situation.
This appears to be a dead end.
The only way out is through that hatch.
- Are there no doors?
- No. Apart from the entrance.
- And the other two, of course.
- Two other doors?
Yes. One in that section
and one in that section over there.
Activated, I imagine, by this
simple logical system here.
Here we are, I think.
(BLEEPING)
Yes, splendid! A simple logical gate.
Doctor, you seem to be
very familiar with this place.
Not really. It's all based on symbolic logic.
The same as you use in computers.
The opening mechanism of this door -
an OR gate, as you call it.
Yes, I can see that, but how did you know
in the first place?
I use my own special technique.
Really? And may we know what that is?
Keeping my eyes open
and my mouth shut.
We are too many to explore together.
I think we'd better divide up.
If you, Mr Viner, would take that door with...
- Jamie.  - Jamie and Mr Haydon.
Mr Klieg, the Doctor and myself
will be a party.
- What about us?
- I think the women should better to remain here.
Rubbish! We can make a party.
Certainly. With Toberman to guard us,
we need fear no one.
Mr Klieg, will you take them with you?
- I prefer to stay here.  - As you wish.
Mr Viner, will you go along with the women?
- If you like.
- Get back to the spacecraft by 16.30.
You all know the temperature drop at night,
so we'll meet back here at 16.25.
If anyone is missing...
that gives us an hour to look for them
before we have to leave.
Come on then. We might as well
try that opening over there.
We'd better keep close together.
I'm all right, thank you.
- Come on, Jamie.  - Right.
Now to concentrate on this, whatever it is.
This hatch must lead somewhere
and there must be
some opening mechanism.
What was that about
symbolic logic? Any ideas?
No, not really.
I think it's time
we gave Mr Klieg a chance
to show off his archaeological skills.
Come on. Right in.
Where's Toberman?
I sent him to join the others.
We do not need protection
now that you are with us.
Yes. Well, shall we commence?
Everything must be carefully
measured and recorded.
What is this room?
I don't know. Possibly this is
where the Cybermen are made.
I wonder what this is.
Do you mind? You're in my way.
Just go over there.
Oh, fiddle!
Could this not be the purpose of the room?
Yes?
A Cyberman would stand
in that form and be...
Well, revitalised.
Yes, that's reasonable.
These projectors probably meant to fire in
some neuro-electric potential.
That's it. I think you're right.
Revitalising is just what I need.
Mercy! The Cybermen
must have been giants!/
Well?
The basis of this code
is binary to digital conversion,
with an intervening step involving
a sort of Whitehead logic.
When this Bourrier series is complete,
then there is no more to be done.
- Yes, but why do it at all?
- Really, Doctor?
For an archaeologist, you seem to
be curiously lacking in curiosity.
Some things are better left undone
and I have a feeling this is one of them.
What do you mean by that?
- It's all too easy, isn't it?  - Easy?
I wouldn't call this an easy survey. Would you?
Everything is designed to keep their secrets,
whatever they are, insoluble.
Insoluble? Oh, I wouldn't say that.
Take this mathematical sequence for example.
I'm really no nearer to its solution.
I've tried every combination.
It's hardly call that easy.
Yes. Well, what you've done here
is mostly right.
- Thank you (!)
- You see, any progressive series
can be converted into binary notation.
If you take the sum of the integrets
and express the result as a power series,
then the indices show the basic binary blocks.
Only I wouldn't do it if I were you.
Oh, I really wouldn't do it.
Of course! You're right!
(LOW HUMMING)
Look! Sum between limits of one and 91
integral into power series... Yes, yes!
Then you differentiate...
You fool! Why couldn't you leave it alone?
- What's happening?  - I don't know.
Perhaps the Cybermen aren't as
quite dormant as you imagine.
Yes, we must find out
what's happened to the others.
- Is that all?  - Aye.
All except this big button here.
What does that do?
I'm not sure, but we'll find out.
I'm going to trace the source
of these shapes.
There must be a projector somewhere.
- When I give the word, press the button.
- The big one?
Yes. Maybe it works in conjunction with the others.
- Right. Ready when you are.
- OK. Go ahead.
- Jamie, don't touch that control!
- I already have.
- What's the matter, Doctor?
- Which one was it?
Which one what?