Can we not make a run for it,
Doctor?
No. We wouldn't reach the ladder.
It's too risky.
What can we do?
Play for time.
Wait for our chance. Leave it to me.
Excuse me? May I ask a question?
Why did you submit yourself
to freezing?
You don't have to answer that.
To survive.
Our history computer
has full details of you.
Oh? How?
We know of your intelligence.
Oh. Thank you very much.
Ah, yes. The lunar surface.
Our machinery had stopped
and our supply of replacements
been depleted.
So that's why
you attacked the moonbase.
You had destroyed our first planet
and we were becoming extinct.
What does capturing us do?
You'll still become extinct.
We will survive.
You will become the first
of a new race of Cybermen.
You will return to Earth
and control it.
But we're humans. We're not like you.
You will be.
Oh. No. Keep away!
Keep away!
Keep away...!/
It's very quiet down there.
Yeah. Too quiet.
- Something must have happened.
- How long they been down?
About an hour.
That's too long. I'm going down./
You are a logician.
Our race is also logical.
You will be the leader
of the new race.
You will listen
to my proposals, then?
Yes. We will listen.
But first you will be altered.
Altered?
You have fear.
We will eliminate fear
from your brain.
Yes. You will be the first.
And you will be the next.
No! No! Aagh!
You will be like us.
To die is unnecessary.
You will be frozen
and placed in our tombs
until we are ready to use you.
Your lives will be suspended.
Prepare the tombs.
They really mean it.
They're going to freeze us.
- Not me.
- No, they're coming back.
Come on, you guys. Run for it!/
Jamie!
Look at that smoke.
(JAMIE) Victoria!
Come on, Mr Parry. Come on, quick!
The Cybermen!
They're right behind us.
When the Doctor's up,
close the hatch!
- OK!
- Stand by!
Oh! Aagh! He's got my leg!
Doctor, come on!
- Come on!
- It's no use.
Jim, close the hatch!
(CALLUM) Got him!
(BANGING)
It was horrible. It was so strong!
It's all right.
You're all right now.
That was a near thing.
Is anyone missing?
Yes. Klieg and Toberman -
they're still down there!/
Don't open it.
It may be the Cybermen.
No. No, it's too soft.
- It must be Toberman and Klieg.
- You're crazy.
We can't leave them down there
even if they are killers.
They're probably frozen by now.
You must let them up.
They must be saved.
Yes, they're more dangerous
down there than up here.
What? OK. Jim?
Right.
(KNOCKING)
Let her go.
Excuse me, please.
Shut it! Shut it quick!
- Where's Toberman?
- They've got him.
Still think you can form an alliance
with the Cybermen?
If only I'd been
in a stronger position to bargain.
- You must be out of your mind.
- You're in no position to bargain.
What are we going to do with them?
I'd feel happier
if they weren't in here.
What about the testing room?
Good idea.
- Callum!
- Right.
Mr Klieg?
Miss Kaftan./
These humanoids are not like us.
They still have fear.
Place the Cybermats on the runway.
Cybermats will attack.
Oh!
I'm on your side, remember?
Hey, why didn't you wake me?
I should have been on watch
half an hour ago.
- I thought you should rest.
- Why me?
No reason really.
Oh, I think I know.
Was it because I'm...?
Well, if you are 450 years old,
you need a great deal of sleep.
Well, that's very considerate
of you, Victoria,
but, between you and me,
I'm really quite lively actually -
all things being considered.
Are you happy with us, Victoria?
Yes, I am.
At least, I would be
if my father were here.
Yes, I know.
I wonder what he'd think
if he could see me now.
You miss him very much, don't you?
It's only when I close my eyes.
I can still see him standing there.
Before those horrible
Dalek creatures came to the house.
He was a very kind man.
I shall never forget him. Never.
No, of course you won't.
But, you know, the memory of him
won't always be a sad one.
I think it will.
You can't understand,
being so ancient.
- Eh?
- I mean old.
You probably
can't remember your family.
Oh, yes, I can when I want to.
That's the point.
I have to really want to
bring them back in front of my eyes.
The rest of the time
they sleep in my mind and I forget.
And so will you. Oh, yes, you will.
You'll find there's so much else
to think about, to remember.
Our lives are different
to anybody else's.
That's the exciting thing.
There's nobody in the universe
can do what we're doing.
You must get some sleep,
and let this poor old man
stay awake.
Jamie, Victoria, Callum, wake up!
- Wake up!
- What is it?
Callum. Callum.
(VICTORIA) Those terrible things.
Don't move, Callum. Don't move.
Get back to the controls,
all of you.
Don't make any sudden movements.
Parry, wake up.
Don't panic.
Come back with us. Steady.
We'll all go in the other room
and lock them out.
Aagh!
Let's get out of here.
The main doors.
No!
Oh! Oh, Doctor, we're trapped!
Back against the controls,
everybody.
Here.
Give me a hand, quick.
Lay this down on the ground.
Come on!
- Doctor?
- Come on!
Let's blast the filthy things!
You're wasting your time. There are
too many of them! Come back!
- There you are.
- What are those creatures?
Well, they're...
They're a form of metallic life.
They home
on human brainwaves and attack.
Urgh!
Are they safe now?
Quite safe now. The power cable
generated an electrical field
that confused
their tiny metal minds.
They've had a complete
metal breakdown.
- Ooh.
- I'm so sorry, Jamie.
What about Klieg and Kaftan?
They've probably been attacked.
- The testing room.
- Come on. Mind your feet.
Most ingenious, Doctor.
Now let's see
what you can do against this.
Watch out, Doctor!