You may have been on duty all night, Fewsham,
but that's no excuse for slipping up!
- They weren't major hold-ups.
- Kelly was going mad on Earth Control!
She would!
It's my head in the noose as well, you know!
I know! I'm sorry.
Oh, all right.
All right, go on. You'd better get back to Earth.
(WAILING BEEP)
Now what?!
It has no air locks.
- Who's there?
- No one.
Then how come the air locks are in use?
(MAN SCREAMS IN TERROR)
Phipps! What's happened?
Come on, man!
(TERRIFIED SCREAM)
Close the door!
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
Don't move, anybody!
Harvey, don't!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
The Seeds of Death
No! I refuse!
(RASPING WHISPER)
You will be wise to co-operate at once,
otherwise you will be destroyed!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Well, I suppose that leaves me
no alternative.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Don't do it, sir!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Silence!
There's a certain element of risk.
(RASPING WHISPER)
You are wasting time!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER)
What is happening?
I'm afraid there's been a fault.
The circuit's overloaded.
Very unfortunate.
(RASPING WHISPER)
You deliberately sabotaged this apparatus!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(JAMIE) Hey! Quite a place, isn't it?
(DOCTOR) Oh, my word!
- Look at the size of this one, Doc!
- Yes!
(ZOE) Oh, Doctor, look!
Doctor, look.
- Now, Zoe...
- (BEEPING)
What's that?
(MAN) Travel Mat is the ultimate form of travel.
Control centre is the moon, serving all major cities on Earth.
Travel Mat is an instantaneous means of travel,
and transports raw materials and food to all parts of the world.
(JAMIE) Travel Mat? Sounds like a flying carpet!
Travel Mat uses the principle of dematerialisation at the point of departure,
and rematerialisation at the point of arrival.
Departure and arrival are almost instantaneous.
Faster than light!
The system is automated and fool-proofed against power failure.
Well, we have our own system, thank you, only it isn't foolproof!
Jamie, I think that's just a tiny bit...
You saw what happened to your superior.
You would do well to co-operate.
Killing him didn't do you any good.
- Would you do as I ask?
- There is nothing I can do!
- You do not want to die?
- I'm not that good enough a technician!
- It needs an expert!
- But you are second in command.
- Yes, but...
- You must have certain abilities.
- You must know what needs to be done.
- In theory, yes.
Then you will do it!
He'll only make it worse!
What is their status here?
Maintenance. Second-class technicians.
- The person you need is at Earth Control.
- Without her, it can't be done!
- Who is this specialist?
- Miss Kelly, technical co-ordinator.
But we can't reach her. T-Mat is not working.
- But you have a video link.
- Osgood wrecked that, too!
So, there is no means to communicate with Earth?
No, you've cut us off completely!
In that case, you are useless!
You will all be destroyed!
There's the emergency T-Mat link!
It only operates from here to Earth!
Then you will activate the apparatus...
..at once!
- It's damaged, too!
- The technicians will help repair it.
- We won't help you. Neither will he!
- Then he will die!
No more money, no more facilities.
A life's work abandoned thanks to T-Mat!
Very short-sighted of the government to put all their eggs in one basket!
You still haven't told me who you are and why you're here!
(WAILING BLEEP)
That's the main door alarm! What's going on?
Professor Daniel Eldred, well, well, well!
Radnor, come to see how your spies are getting on?
I'm sorry? We've not met. My name's Radnor. This is Miss Kelly.
Oh, how do you do?
This is Zoe, Jamie, and I'm the Doctor.
Don't pretend you don't know them!
I can assure you I've never met them before in my life.
I see. I find three strangers prowling around.
and by the merest coincidence, you turn up on their heels!
I merely wanted a chat with a very old friend.
Well, you've done without a chat for a good many years.
Old times. Friendships don't die.
Our friendship ended the day that you walked out of my laboratory to join T-Mat!
Different men, different careers!
Yes, but you knew which career would be financed by government funds!
You could have come over.
Yes, and worked as Miss Kelly's assistant perhaps
You know I respect your work. We would have welcomed you.
I prefer rockets, obsolete as they are!
Not so obsolete as all that, eh? We don't miss very much, you know.
- You've been spying on me!
- No, we stopped that a long time ago.
What's wrong with running a private museum?
Nothing, but you're doing rather more than that
What if I am? What's wrong with having a hobby?
Rather more than a hobby -
preparing an ion rocket
for an unauthorised journey into space!
All right, so you know.
What do you intend to do?
- My dear fellow, help you, of course!
- What?
You can make your trip
- as long as it's to the moon.
- Why the moon?
There's a minor fault developed at T-Mat Control at Moonbase.
- It has to be put right.
- I thought T-Mat was infallible!
It will be eventually, but we are unable to reach the moon.
Except by out-of-date rocket! Oh, that's perfect!
You need me after all (!)
I thought you'd like the idea,
and a large sum of government funds wouldn't come amiss, would they?
Now, how soon can you be ready to...blast off?
Well, come on, it's urgent! Can you give me an approximate ETD?
I could, but I won't.
Why? There are no strings!
I'm just telling you that I refuse!
- Right, that should do it.
- I'll switch on the power.
You fools! When they find out, we'll all be killed!
Moonbase to T-Mat Reception Earth.
Moonbase to Earth.
Emergency! Emergency!
You can't refuse because of an out-of-date rocket programme!
- Commander Radnor.
- Excuse me.
Radnor. Emergency message from Moonbase linking through now.
Commander Radnor, Miss Kelly...
..we are in desperate trouble! Osgood is dead and we are...
Locke! Locke!
Guard!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)