It's hopeless, Doctor!
You'll never get that thing going again!
完全没希望啊, 博士！你没法搞定那个东西 fixme
I'm not so sure, Jamie. After all,
it's only the controls that are damaged.
我可不这么认为, Jamie．毕竟, 被毁坏的只有控制开关
The workings are all right.
主体还是没事的
If we can bypass the controls...
如果我们能绕过这些控制开关
Have you got your knife on you?
Lend it me, will you? Be careful.
你身上带着刀吗？借我一下, 好吗．小心一点
Thank you. There we are.
Now, what have we got here?
谢谢．这些好啦．现在, 看看情况怎么样了？
Ah, yes... Yes, yes.
啊, 对了...对, 对
Yes, well, it's just a question
of sorting this lot out. That's all.
是了, 好啦, 现在就是搞明白这个东西的问题了, 仅此而已
All is prepared, Grand Marshal.
都准备好了, 大元帅
I shall return to our ship to finalise invasion plans.
我将返回我们的飞船, 准备最后的入侵计划
Right, now then, Zoe, let's see what happens
when we try to connect these two together.
好了, 现在, Zoe, 我们来看看我们把这两个东西连在一起, 会发生什么
No, I don't think so somehow!
不, 我觉得不是这样！
What about these two?
这两个怎么样？
Ah! That's better! I think I've succeeded /?
啊！好多了！我觉得我已经成功了
in re-establishing one of these rain circuits, Jamie.
造雨线路已经重新连起来了, Jamie
Well, it's not raining yet!
但是, 还没有下雨啊！
Oh, Jamie! Weather Control is a very difficult technology.
哦, Jamie！气象控制是一项很难的技术
You can't expect immediate results.
你不能指望马上有结果
- Are you sure you're getting it right?
- Yeah, I hope so, Zoe.
- 你确定你搞对了吗？  - 是, 我期望是, Zoe
Just have to hope for the best. That's all.
只能期望能有最好结果, 就这样了
I must get on as there's another little job I want to do.
我必须得继续了, 还有另外一件小事我想要住做
We should have some nice heavy rain before long!
不久以后我们就会有漂亮的大雨了！
- Ah, there we are!
- Yes, the satellite.
- 啊, 我们来了  - 是的, 卫星
(ELDRED) Isn't that a beautiful sight!
这个景观是不是很漂亮！
We've finished and installed the homing device.
It's working perfectly.
我们已经制作完成了引导装置, 并安装上去了, 工作得相当好
Doctor, I know we're sending up a false signal,
博士, 我知道我们送上去了一个假的讯号
but aren't some of the Martian ships bound to follow the right one?
但就不会有一些火星飞船会收到正确的讯号吗？
There isn't going to be a right one,
there's going to be only ours, the wrong one,
不会有正确的讯号的, 只会有我们的讯号, 错误的这个
and that's going to lead the entire Martian fleet
into an orbit round the sun!
它会把整个火星舰队引导为沿着太阳轨道飞行！
- What about Slaar's signal?
- Obviously that has to be stopped.
- 那 Slaar 的讯号会怎么样？ - 显然, 它会被停掉
- But how?
- Well, as soon as that satellite is up
- 怎么停掉？  - 哦, 一旦卫星上天
I shall T-Mat myself to the moon
and destroy their homing device.
我就会用 T-Mat 把自己传送到月球上, 毁了他们的引导设备
- They'll kill you on sight!
- No, I don't think so.
- 他们一看见你就会杀了你的！  - 不, 我不这么想
I rigged up an interesting device here.
我这里拼凑了一对很有意思的设备
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(KELLY) There it is. It's in orbit.
那就是了, 它进轨道了
We're picking up the aliens' homing signal from the moon.
我们识别到外星人在月球上发出的引导讯号了
That means their invasion fleet is getting closer.
There's no time to lose.
那意味着他们的入侵舰队已经接近了．没时间可以浪费了
Are you quite clear? As soon as
I have succeeded destroying their signal,
你清楚了吗？一旦我成功破坏了他们的讯号
you must activate our signal in the satellite.
你必须激活我们在卫星上的讯号
- We'll be ready.
- Right, then I'll be off.
- 我们会准备好的  - 好, 那我启程了
- Doctor, do be careful, won't you?
- Don't worry, Zoe, I will.
- 博士, 千万小心, 好吗？  - 别担心, Zoe, 我会的
- Are you ready, Miss Kelly?
- Doctor, our control of T-Mat hasn't been tested!
- 准备好了吗, Kelly 小姐？  - 博士, 我们 T-Mat 控制还没有测试过
Then now's the time to test it!
那现在就是测试它的时候！
(TRILLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(SIGNAL GETS LOUDER)
(SIGNAL GETS QUIETER)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(SLAAR) No.
不
You...
你...
..over there.
..过去
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
I ordered you to be destroyed!
我命令过要消灭你的！
Well, you weren't very successful, were you?
但是, 你并不是太成功, 是吧？
Destroy that weapon!
消灭那个武器！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
What is your purpose in coming here?
你来这里的目的是什么？
You don't expect me to tell you that, do you?
你没指望我会告诉你吧, 对吗？
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
The directional beam is still operative.
牵引光速仍然在工作
Yes. I'm afraid you were a little too quick for me.
是的, 我担心你动作太快了 fixme
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Are you capable of operating the T-Mat mechanism?
你有能力操作 T-Mat 装置吗？
Oh, no. I don't think I...
哦, 不, 我觉得不行...
Well, yes, perhaps I could get the hang of it.
哦, 可以, 也许我会找到窍门的
As long as you can be useful to us, you can live,
只要你对我们有用, 你就可以活着
but this time, there will be no escape.
但这一次, 你不可能逃走了
You will familiarise yourself with the T-Mat controls.
你先让自己熟悉一下 T-Mat 控制开关
Oh, thank you very much!
哦, 非常感谢！
You will not touch the controls until I give the order.
在我下命令之前, 你不可碰这些开关
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
- (KELLY) It's operating perfectly!
- Shoulf we wait till the Doctor got back?
The moon signal has disappeared, hasn't it?
That may be too atmospheric. As all we know
they're transmitting as strongly as ever.
The moon signal was strong enough before the Doctor left.
- He must have succeeded.
- Then why hasn't he come back?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
When our Warriors arrive,
you will transmit them to Earth
under my direction.
Yes. They haven't arrived yet.
Something still might go wrong.
- Nothing can go wrong now!
- There's many a slip between the cup and the lip.
If anything does go wrong,
you will be the first to die.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
Scan closer!
If they are going to divert,
it should happen any moment now!
They're changing course!
I think you're right!
They're all following the satellite signal!
The Doctor must succeeded!
He must turned off the Martians' signal.
What's happening up there, then?
Why hasn't he come back?
Don't worry, Jamie. A squad of Security guards
armed with flame throwers are on their way here now.
- As soon as they get here, we'll T-Mat them to the moon.
- They'll be too late!
- You'll just have to be patient!
- I'm sick of being patient!
(WHISPERS) Zoe.
- That T-Mat thing, do you know how it works?
- I think so. Why?
- Could you T-Mat me back to the moon?
- Oh, no, Jamie, shouldn't you...
Look, Either the Doctor's all right,
in which case we've no reason to worry
or he's in danger and he needs my help!
You have failed us, Slaar!
We shall all die!
We're being pulled into the orbit of the sun!
This is impossible!
The signal! There is no power!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You did this!
Yes. That signal has been going
no further than this control room.
But they were receiving my signal!
Not your signal - ours.
You sent a signal...
..from Earth?
We sent up a satellite.
That signal has sent your fleet into a false orbit!
The heat of the sun will kill them!
You have destroyed our entire fleet!
You tried to destroy an entire world.
Earth will still die!
The fungus will take the oxygen from your atmosphere!
I'm afraid you've failed there, too.
We can destroy the fungus.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Kill him!
DOCTOR!
Jamie! Look out!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
Creag an tuire!
Jamie! The light terminal!
Well done, Jamie!
Oh, goodness me! Jamie, thank you very much!
Now then, we must T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
(THUNDERCLAP)
(COMPUTER) Widespread rainfall throughout the country.
Some flooding but none serious.
Fungus rapidly disappearing.
Weather Control Bureau coming back into operation.
World food shortages partially relieved,
now T-Mats are becoming operational again.
Message to Commander Radnor from the Security Council
of the United Nations -
-  Congratulations.
- All right. Just discontinue report.
So you DID know what you were doing
at the Weather Control Bureau!
Zoe, of course I did.
Well, it took long enough to work!
Well, the rain seems dispose of the fungus well enough.
Now the next thing to do is to get T-Mat fully operational again.
Yes, when Moon Relay is repaired, we must check over
the equipment and build in safeguards.
From now on, T-Mat must be entirely controlled from Earth.
Oh, surely you've learned not to put all your eggs in one basket!
T-Mat itself is perfectly effective!
You need a secondary transportation system,
a fleet of rockets on permanent stand by!
- There's no need to go to such lengths.
- It's a question of common sense!
I'm sure the Doctor will agree with me! Doctor...
(JAMIE) You didn't have to make it
rain as hard as all that!
Oh, Jamie, some of you is just never satisfied!
- What did you rush us back here for?
- Oh, you know, questions and explanations are very difficult. Come on!
- Where are we going now?
- It's no good asking him.
He's no more idea than the man in the moon!
I heard that, Jamie! Come on!