Hello, Moonbase! Can you hear me?
Yes!
Yes, I can hear you loud and clear!
What part of Earth are you speaking from?
(DOCTOR) We're in a rocket orbiting the moon.
A rocket? But that's impossible!
I can assure you it's not impossible!
What is your emergency?
What's happening on Moonbase?
We've been invaded! Aliens have taken over!
Put that cover back on.
T-Mat to Earth and report to Commander Radnor.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Stop!
You will remain here!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
These aliens he described...
- Yes, Ice Warriors!
- What?
Jamie and I have met them before.
They come from the planet Mars.
- What do they want?
- Mars is a dying planet.
- They want a new home.
- Why the moon?
- It's a stepping stone.
- They're Ice Warriors?
Yes, you know, Mars is a cold planet
and they've adapted to that.
It's heat they can't stand.
We should just about be coming into range now.
Hello, Moonbase.
(RASPING WHISPER)
You will remain here!
That's the lot. The whole system's
completely operational again.
- We can now send to any city in the world?
- Yes, anywhere with a T-Mat centre.
- Fewsham, Do you realise what you're doing?!
- I'm trying to save our lives!
We're in no position to argue!
Why do you want control of T-Mat?
If you invade the Earth,
you'll fight the armed forces
of the entire world. You'll never succeed.
- There'll be too much resistance.
- There will be no resistance!
What will happen to us?
You will remain alive as long as you are useful.
You'll never get any help from me.
When the time comes, you will do
exactly what you are told...
..or die!
Hello?
- Who are you?
- Oh!
- Mr Phipps, I presume?
- Yes, but where did you come from?
From the rocket. We were talking on the radio.
- Are the others here too?
- Yeah, They're still in the rocket.
- How many Ice Warriors are there?
- Those creatures you mean?
- Not many, but they're deadly.
- They have their weak points.
Look, they've killed everybody here,
except Fewsham, who's helping them.
I see. Well, there's only one thing for it.
- We shall have to destroy T-Mat.
You will shortly dispatch a cargo
to certain cities on Earth.
Cargo? What sort of cargo?
That's an Ice Warrior's. It's got Miss Kelly, but how...?
Run!
Oh!
Stop!
(RASPING WHISPER)
You must be destroyed!
You've got no orders to kill me!
Your leader will want to speak to me!
Humans are our enemies!
But I can be useful to you, like Fewsham!
Your leader will be angry with you
if you kill me! I'm a genius!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Genius!
You will come with me!
The prisoner Kelly has escaped.
This human was in the corridors.
Who are you? Where are you from?
I might ask you the same question!
You will find the human Kelly
and bring her back here!
- Who is this man?
- He's not one of the crew.
He must have just arrived here.
Impossible - we control T-Mat.
How did you get here?
Our resources are not limited
to T-Mat, you know!
- You arrived by space craft?
- Rockets haven't been used for years.
Then you are lying!
You have been concealed here all the time.
(DOCTOR) But you can't be sure
of that, can you, hmm?
The people of the Earth
may be preparing a whole fleet
of rockets to defend themselves with!
(ICE WARRIOR)
No, Earth relies entirely on T-Mat.
There is no defence against our plans.
And what are your plans? Invasion by T-Mat?
There are too few of you to conquer all Earth.
(ICE WARRIOR) The Grand Marshall
has ordered the seeds to be prepared!
- You are to receive your instructions.
- Then guard the humans.
If they try to escape, kill them!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Why are you helping them?
I've seen what they can do!
Do you know what is in that container?
All I know is they want me to send
something to Earth by T-Mat.
- I suppose that's what's in it.
- I shall have to look inside,
and you are going to help me!
- The Doctor's been captured?
- There was nothing we could do.
- We had a job to reach here ourselves.
- Aye. So did we!
Are you sure the Ice Warriors don't know about this place?
One dit but I got him with a booby trap fixed to the solar energy power line.
It looks those things are invulnerable!
- No, the Doctor said they can't stand heat.
- That's right!
The heating controlled from the Centre.
We can turn up the heating.
But how can we get there? Ice Warriors are patrolling those corridors.
Aye, Yes I know. The maintenance tunnel's over here!
(WHISPERS)
All right, Fewsham, now!
I can't! They'll kill us both!
- You've got to help me!
- I can't, I daren't.
Very well, I shall do it by myself.
If I am caught, which is most likely,
we will both get killed.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Do not move!
I was ordered to prepare
the controls for transmission. I’ve got to check that everything is in order.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Return to where you were!
(FEWSHAM) But this is most important!
If you are trying to escape, I shall destroy you!
I'm not trying to escape!
Go back to where you were!
All right! All right!
Wait!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Open it!
I said, ''Open it''!
What are these things?
They look like seed pods.
(CHOKING COUGH)
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
What's happened to him?
Is he dead?
We can get through it here then. Turn the heating up, knock the Warriors out
- We can rescue the Doctor.
- And T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
- But T-Mat's broken down.
- I repaired it.
Can we get this cover off?
- This part of the
base has been disused for ages. It's rusted. It will take some time.
The Doctor may not have much time.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You will prepare to activate the cubicle and transmit to London.
Obey!
Activate!
(TRILLING HUM)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
Commander Radnor! T-Mat is working.
- Working? Kelly must have got through!
- Splendid!
What is it?
It's alive!