Stop him!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Hunt that man! He must not escape!
Can we not help them? We can use the Tardis!
To go to the moon? We'd probably
overshoot by a few million years!
Yes, or by a few million miles!
The Tardis is not suited to short-range travel.
Still, we should help them if we can.
- Aye.
- Yes.
- I could get your rocket to the moon.
- You?
Yes, I have considerable experience
in space travel.
That's splendid! Thank you!
- But the rocket is not ready!
- Perhaps you overestimate the difficulty.
How much more work is required?
It needs fuel
and a complete computerised check.
- I can order that.
- No! The risk is too great!
If there was some other way,
- I wouldn't even consider such a risk!
- No!
(COMPUTER) Commander Radnor
Radnor. Go ahead.
T-Mat receptions -
New York, Moscow, Tokyo -
express great concern over continued hold-up.
Medical shipments and food
awaiting transit to Asiatic centres.
Position desperate, Calcutta.
Instructions awaited.
- That's your answer!
- Well, we want to help!
You don't understand! It's suicide!
Listen, if this fault lasts much longer,
there's going to be worldwide chaos,
and world population is at stake.
Infallible T-Mat,
putting the world in jeopardy (?)
All right, I admit it.
Now this man has to risk his life for you!
No, not for me, for thousands
of people all over the world
who will die if we don't take this risk!
I'm sorry but I've got no alternative.
- Miss Kelly.
- Sir.
I want all technical personnel working on this.
I want that rocket prepared for launching!
Yes, Commander.
We'd be grateful for your help.
If that rocket's to reach the moon safely,
you'll need a miracle!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Continue the search!
He must not escape!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Commander.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
Is it wise letting these people crew the rocket?
What's the alternative?
We gave up training astronauts years ago.
- Who are they?
- Eldred's crazy friends, I imagine,
- but the Doctor knows his space travel.
- How can you be sure?
He and the girl know
more about space flight than Eldred.
- What about the boy?
- I'm not sure about him.
(RASPING WHISPER)
The emergency link with Earth,
- is it ready yet?
- I've nearly finished.
- Do not make any mistakes!
- I'm not an expert!
- But you will do it?
- Yes!
Commander, I think I should go
as crew on the rocket.
Don't be ridiculous, you're too valuable here!
How can T-Mat be repaired if I'm not there?
- What about (one of) the technicians (who was already over) there?
- Osgood's dead.
- Yes, well, what about Fewsham?
- He's incapable of doing it! I think I) should go!
No! You're the only one
who really understands T-Mat.
I can't have you risking your life!
But (yet you are perfectly prepared to) allow them to risk theirs!
Don't worry, (Miss Kelly) we'll be perfectly all right!
But I don't see what good
just this emergency link can be.
Even if you had a gigantic army of warriors,
you couldn't send them all to conquer Earth.
(RASPING WHISPER)
We do not need an army.
Earth will be ours for the taking...
(HISSING BREATHING)
..very soon!
- Doctor...
- Yes?
Final check on procedure after you land.
Yes, (I know) we're to re-establish video link with the Earth.
That's right.
When we can see what's wrong,
you can do the rest
under Miss Kelly's supervision.
Right. We're ready when you are.
12...
10...
nine...eight...seven...
..six...five...four...three...
..two...one.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
It's done.
- The emergency link will work now.
- Excellent!
- What are you going to do?
- Do not ask questions!
Activate the link.
- On receive only.
- Receive?
But aren't you going to...?
Activate the link on receive at once!
- (KELLY) You've double-checked?
- Yes, the fault is on Moonbase.
Are you able to effect repairs over video?
the fault is not too major.
- And if they get there with the rocket!
- They'll get there.
You can't even be sure the rocket's still in one piece!
Miss Kelly!
The emergency T-Mat link to Moon Control is activating!
Is someone coming through?
No, it's on send.
Moonbase has managed
to make a temporary repair.
Have a full emergency kit waiting.
- I'll join you as soon as possible.
- Yes, Miss Kelly. Standing by.
Where are you are going?
If we can send, it's the only thing I can do.
You dont know) what conditions are like up there!
I know all too well what are like down here
Commander, you've stopped me once.
Don't try it again, otherwise
I shall have to go above your head.
- She's after your job, Julian!
- Miss Kelly!
(TRILLING TONE)
- Thank heavens you've come!
- What happened?
Osgood, it must have been space madness.
He just went berserk!
Osgood? But he'd be the last man,
I'd have thought!
- So did we.
- Where are the others?
When Osgood fused the controls,
Locke tried to stop him.
- Osgood killed him.
- This is fantastic!
- What about Phipps?
- He's injured and under sedation.
- And you?
- There's nothing wrong with me.
You look frightened.
If you'd seen Osgood die, wouldn't you be?
How did he die?
His body's outside.
He just went out.
Without a pressure suit? I see.
Open all control sections and computer links.
Fewsham, what are you doing?
I'd best switch off the emergency link.
- It could easily burn itself out.
- Sensible.
It will prevent Commander Radnor sending a security guard
to drag me back to Earth!
(RASPING WHISPER)
The other human is still free. Find him!
He must not interfere with our plans!
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! How do you read me?
Emergency! Can you hear me?