The Tomb of the Cybermen
(Whopix fan edit)
Stand by. Everybody down.
to open the doors.
Miss Kaftan, I must remind you
that I am the leader of the...
- What happened?  - I don't know.
Well, one thing for sure, he's not going to
collect 50 pounds from you or anybody else.
- Quiet. Quiet a minute.  - What's that?
Sounded like an engine.
(WHOOSHING)
- Something came down there! Behind that ...
- OK, Viner. Slow down.
- I'll take care of this. Jim!
- OK. I've got it!
(LOW VOICES)
Hold it right there, friend.
If you put it like that, I certainly will.
Hear that, Professor? English.
(PARRY) Yes. All right, Hopper.
Thank you.
Who are you and where are you from?
And you'd better have a good story.
Maybe you'll not get one.
Listen, fella.
We're not playing games.
- You'd better listen to him.
- What's been happening over here?
He was killed the moment you men  appeared.
Ah. And you think we did it?
Oh no, I can assure you, we had nothing
to do with the death of this man.
He appears to have been electrocuted.
Trying to open these doors, perhaps?
- He seems to know all the answers.
- A wiseguy!
I think this fellow must be
a member of a rival expedition.
(DOCTOR) Expedition?
We've tried to keep it secret.
Unsuccessfully, now it appears.
Archaeologist written all over him.
- Really? Does it show?  - You see?
It's impossible to keep a secret
in the scientific world.
- Doctor, what do you mean?
- Tell them, go on, Doctor, tell them.
No, not until they tell us
the purpose of their expedition.
This is an archaeological expedition.
We are searching the universe
for the last remains of the Cybermen.
Cybermen? You mean to say they came from here?
Of course. Telos was their home.
This is the entrance to their city.
We know they died out centuries ago,
what we don't know is why they died out.
Callum, Rogers! Get him back to the rocket.
I'll be with you in a minute.
That's that. Are you coming back
to the rocket with me, Professor?
- What for?
- You're not going on with this, are you?
I don't know if these people had
anything to do with it or not,
but one of my men was just been killed.
You're not paying that kind of money.
- Yes, I suppose that's quite true.
- You think it over.
Come on, let's go.
We'll wait for you at the ship.
The problem, I take it,
is to open these doors, right?
- Ha! Brilliant.  - That is the problem.
And we would prefer it, if you return
to wherever you came from.
- Not very friendly, are they?
- Do as he says.
That became impossible the moment
that name was mentioned - Cybermen.
Cybermen? What are they?
I knew they're here on the same quest!
No one would come here for any other reason?
- We must stay!  - Doctor!
Must we? I don't like
the look of those things at all.
We shall stay and help you with your research.
Perhaps we don't want help.
That's just it. You obviously do.
Now I'm sure we can agree.
- I can open those doors for you.
- It's our problem!
Can I suggest you take this ridiculous
expedition of yours off this planet!
It seems to me we have
as much right here as you have.
Of course you have!
Mr Klieg, must I remind you again...
that you do not speak for this expedition?
I am its leader.
You and Miss Kaftan
are only here on sufferance.
- Thank you. And whose money is paying
for the hire of that rocket?
- (KAFTAN) Mine!
I thought I made it clear
that your financial support...
did not entitle you to a say
in the running of this expedition!
Of course. It was quite clear.
Was it not, Eric?
Of course.
No one questions your leadership.
Good. That's all settled.
- And now we shall open these doors.
- What...?
- Careful, man!  - Doctor!
Perfectly safe now.
- You'll be killed!  - Don't touch him!
- It's beyond my strength.
- Let me, Doctor.
I've not had much exercise lately.
Quite. I think here is a gentleman
who could open these doors for us.
He is my servant.
I will not have him risk his life.
Surely it was just for such a contingency like this
that you insisted we bring him with us.
There's no danger now.
Unless he's afraid.
No, no. He's not afraid.
- Come on.  - No. Wait!
I would be very careful in there
if I were you.
Why weren't Toberman killed?
Why weren't you killed?
The poor fellow who died drained
all the electricity out of his body.
It's perfectly safe to go in now.
We're wasting time.
Of course. After you, Professor.
But I'd still...
I'd still be very careful if I were you.
Very careful indeed.
Come on. Let's join them.
Come on, Victoria.
You look very nice in that dress.
Thank you.
Don't you think it's a bit...?
Short? I shouldn't worry.
Look at Jamie's.
I'll have you know that... Oh, aye.
Come along. Let's go and see
what the others are doing.
(VICTORIA)
Mercy! Just look at this place.
These controls are of earlier dynasties.
Not so early. Look, John...
I'm quite capable of making
my own deductions! Thank you.
All right.
Be careful. There might be danger.
Don't worry, with Toberman to guard me.
What is more important is
to keep an eye on these strangers.
- I tried to...!
- Do not raise your voice.
You will achieve nothing by shouting.
You look after the Doctor
and I will watch the girl.
- And the Scots boy?
- Leave him to Toberman.
Eh, Toberman?
- But you will be careful and discreet. Understand?
- I understand.
- Did you ever see the like of it, Doctor?
- Not exactly, Jamie, but very nearly.
(PARRY) Now that we're all here...
Now that we're all here, we'd better
take stock of the situation.
This appears to be a dead end.
The only way out is through that hatch.
- Are there no doors?
- No. Apart from the entrance.
- And the other two, of course.
- Two other doors?
Yes. One in that section
and one in that section over there.
Activated, I imagine, by this
simple logical system here.
Here we are, I think.
(BLEEPING)
Yes, splendid! A simple logical gate.
Doctor, you seem to be
very familiar with this place.
Not really. It's all based on symbolic logic.
The same as you use in computers.
The opening mechanism of this door -
an OR gate, as you call it.
Yes, I can see that, but how did you know
in the first place?
I use my own special technique.
Really? And may we know what that is?
Keeping my eyes open
and my mouth shut.
We are too many to explore together.
I think we'd better divide up.
If you, Mr Viner, would take that door with...
- Jamie.  - Jamie and Mr Haydon.
Mr Klieg, the Doctor and myself
will be a party.
- What about us?
- I think the women should better to remain here.
Rubbish! We can make a party.
Certainly. With Toberman to guard us,
we need fear no one.
Mr Klieg, will you take them with you?
- I prefer to stay here.  - As you wish.
Mr Viner, will you go along with the women?
- If you like.
- Get back to the spacecraft by 16.30.
You all know the temperature drop at night,
so we'll meet back here at 16.25.
If anyone is missing...
that gives us an hour to look for them
before we have to leave.
Come on then. We might as well
try that opening over there.
We'd better keep close together.
I'm all right, thank you.
- Come on, Jamie.  - Right.
Now to concentrate on this, whatever it is.
This hatch must lead somewhere
and there must be
some opening mechanism.
What was that about
symbolic logic? Any ideas?
No, not really.
I think it's time
we gave Mr Klieg a chance
to show off his archaeological skills.
Come on. Right in.
Where's Toberman?
I sent him to join the others.
We do not need protection
now that you are with us.
Yes. Well, shall we commence?
Everything must be carefully
measured and recorded.
What is this room?
I don't know. Possibly this is
where the Cybermen are made.
I wonder what this is.
Do you mind? You're in my way.
Just go over there.
Oh, fiddle!
Could this not be the purpose of the room?
Yes?
A Cyberman would stand
in that form and be...
Well, revitalised.
Yes, that's reasonable.
These projectors probably meant to fire in
some neuro-electric potential.
That's it. I think you're right.
Revitalising is just what I need.
Mercy! The Cybermen
must have been giants!/
Well?
The basis of this code
is binary to digital conversion,
with an intervening step involving
a sort of Whitehead logic.
When this Bourrier series is complete,
then there is no more to be done.
- Yes, but why do it at all?
- Really, Doctor?
For an archaeologist, you seem to
be curiously lacking in curiosity.
Some things are better left undone
and I have a feeling this is one of them.
What do you mean by that?
- It's all too easy, isn't it?  - Easy?
I wouldn't call this an easy survey. Would you?
Everything is designed to keep their secrets,
whatever they are, insoluble.
Insoluble? Oh, I wouldn't say that.
Take this mathematical sequence for example.
I'm really no nearer to its solution.
I've tried every combination.
It's hardly call that easy.
Yes. Well, what you've done here
is mostly right.
- Thank you (!)
- You see, any progressive series
can be converted into binary notation.
If you take the sum of the integrets
and express the result as a power series,
then the indices show the basic binary blocks.
Only I wouldn't do it if I were you.
Oh, I really wouldn't do it.
Of course! You're right!
(LOW HUMMING)
Look! Sum between limits of one and 91
integral into power series... Yes, yes!
Then you differentiate...
You fool! Why couldn't you leave it alone?
- What's happening?  - I don't know.
Perhaps the Cybermen aren't as
quite dormant as you imagine.
Yes, we must find out
what's happened to the others.
- Is that all?  - Aye.
All except this big button here.
What does that do?
I'm not sure, but we'll find out.
I'm going to trace the source
of these shapes.
There must be a projector somewhere.
- When I give the word, press the button.
- The big one?
Yes. Maybe it works in conjunction with the others.
- Right. Ready when you are.
- OK. Go ahead.
- Jamie, don't touch that control!
- I already have.
- What's the matter, Doctor?
- Which one was it?
Which one what?
Aaagh!
- Careful, Doctor!
- It's all right.
I think. I think it's all right now.
Yes. You see.
It's just a mock-up, a model.
Don't touch that!
That gun may be wired up too.
- It's a trap.
- No, I don't think so.
It's a testing room for weapons.
This is a purely robotic Cyberman.
There's no human material in it at all.
It's a target for weapons.
Let's get back to the control room
with this poor fellow.
What's that?
(JAMIE) Some wee creature
I found on the floor.
It's a fossil.
Victoria, be careful!
Let me see that.
Yes, it's certainly inactive,
but it's not a fossil.
Wait a minute.
Yes. Here we are.
Yes.
It's a Cybermat.
What's a Cybermat?
It's one of those.
I'd leave it alone if I were you./
I just don't understand this code.
The sequence doesn't make sense.
You, a logician, can't understand it?
- You must.
- But in the time we have...
We have plenty of time.
You will see.
- Lay him down there.
- What has happened to him?
There's been an accident.
He's been shot.
Right. We're all here.
Would you all sit down for a moment?
Toberman?
Mr Klieg?
Leave me alone.
Can't you see I'm working?
Have you forgotten
the purpose of this expedition?
This directly concerns my expedition.
Kindly take your place.
Right.
I'll come straight to the point.
I've reluctantly decided to abandon
the expedition and return to Earth.
- It's impossible!
- I feel just as strongly about it.
This expedition has been
my dream for many years.
Some, like Mr Viner,
said more preparation was needed -
more men and equipment.
I did not heed their warnings,
and the result is that two have died.
I'm sorry, but we must leave
at the first available conjunction.
We'll take back
all we can for further study.
But that is my decision
and that is what we must do.
- I insist that...!
- My decision is final!
We leave when the north hemisphere
is properly tangential,
which will be at 18.42.
Ah, Captain Hopper.
Can you blast off at 18.42?
No.
I beg your pardon.
Did I hear you right?
You are paid to take orders.
Not impossible ones.
It's the fuel pumps.
Someone has balled-up the lot.
- What?
- Or someTHING.
Whatever it is, it's nearly wrecked
our chances of leaving this planet./
There's no doubt about it.
The major workings lie below.
There are metal caverns
down there, all interconnected.
If only we can get down to them.
That's it! I've got it!
Finally, a Boolean function
of symbolic logic.
- Logical, yes, but...
- Everything yields to logic.
- Our basic assumption.
- Really.
Six, cap, B4...
if and only if C
is cap function of 2A.
I think perhaps your logic
is wearing a little thin.
I must have made a mistake.
I'll do it again carefully.
Six, cap, B4...
if and only if C...
is cap faction of... Ah, that's it!
2F, not 2A.
(WHIRRING)
I've done it! I've done it!
- Congratulations!
- But, Doctor, you...
Excellent. Now to work.
It'll be extremely cold.
We shall need to put on warm clothing.
Mr Viner, would you get the anoraks?
- Are we all going down?
- There's safety in numbers.
- The women as well?
- They will stay up here.
In case of trouble,
contact the rocket.
- I'm coming with you.
- But my dear young lady...
- You heard me, Professor.
- Victoria.
You will be much safer up here.
- But, Doctor...
- And much more use to us.
- I don't see...
- By keeping an eye on things.
Please.
- All right.
- Thank you.
(PARRY) If we're all ready,
I shall lead the descent.
Be ready to go back
the instant I give the word.
- You know what to do?
- The hatch?
Mr Toberman?
He stays with me.
Then I stay here too.
Of course. I am being selfish.
His strength will be useful to you.
He must go down.
Go down, Toberman.
Remember what I said.
Be very careful.
(KAFTAN) It seems
we are left alone to wait.
Captain Hopper brought food
from the rocket. You would like some?
Rather! I'm ravenous./
We've no time to linger!
It's extremely cold down here,
even with these anoraks.
(JAMIE) You obviously knew
what to expect.
Well, which way do we go?
I don't know. Let's try this one.
Yes.
Hey, what on Earth?!
(PARRY) Behold, gentlemen,
the tombs of the Cybermen.
(JAMIE)
Tombs? I don't see any tombs.
There, Jamie.
Frozen forever.
All their evil
locked away with them.
And so it must remain.
Like a gigantic honeycomb.
Like bees waiting for the signal
to arise from their winter sleep.
A signal they are never
going to get.
We'd better get busy. Everything
must be recorded. It's too cold...
Unless we find some way
to warm things up.
You have hardly touched your coffee.
It must be cold by now.
You would like some more?
No, thank you. I'm much warmer now.
That's good.
I...
feel so sleepy.
(WHIRRING)
(CLANG)
- What was that?
- It sounded like the hatch.
It's closed!
What's the use?
We're trapped down here now.
We'll never survive in this cold.
Better get back.
Well?
It's closed.
What are they playing at up there?
Maybe it wasn't them. Where's Jamie?
He went up the ladder to try it.
Professor. Professor,
listen to me, for heaven's sake!
The hatch is down.
We're trapped down here.
But some of my party
are up there. Are you sure?
Of course. You know how heavy it is.
It's down now.
We must do something!
I give us a couple of hours
in here at most.
Mr Klieg doesn't seem
to be very worried.
No, I'm not, Doctor.
It won't open
and I can't make them hear.
There is an easy way
out of our situation.
- You've found something?
- You forget logic.
If it closes,
it can be opened - from here.
Conveniently labelled
in symbolic logic, I notice.
Right. Are we ready?
I shall now operate the sequence.
If it is the opening device.
It's an opening device
of some kind, Doctor.
I don't know
how you can be so blasted calm!
I'll see if it works.
Go ahead!
Nothing happening out here!
It doesn't work.
Water!
- It's getting warmer.
- The ice is melting.
Hey, look behind you!
Look!
Look at the honeycomb.
There's something inside.
They're... They're Cybermen.
Jamie, come back!
It is them.
Gentlemen, they are perfect.
This is unique in archaeology.
No!
No! They're moving!
We must shut it down.
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING WINDS DOWN)
What are you doing?
Keep away from that!
No.
- What are you doing?
- Keep away!
- Keep away from those controls.
- No!
Viner!
Viner. You've killed him!
- He's mad.
- Jamie!
Haydon dead, now Viner.
What kind of man are you?
Back! Keep back!
Let's see what happens.
As the Professor says, this is
a unique archaeological event.
It would be such a pity to miss it.
(LOUD WHIRRING)/
Doctor, I have a feeling
that man's planned it all.
He knew
that wouldn't open the hatch.
- So did I, Jamie.
- You knew?
I wanted to know what he was up to.
- And now you know, Doctor.
- We know nothing.
This is the action of a lunatic.
Lunatic? Not at all, Professor.
A necessary detail, that's all.
But why?
Logic, my dear Professor,
logic and power.
On Earth,
the Brotherhood of Logicians
is the greatest man intelligence
ever assembled.
But that's not enough.
We need power -
power to put our ability
into action.
The Cybermen have this power.
I have come to find it and use it.
So that was your motive
in financing my expedition!
Precisely. Your lack
of administration made it ideal.
You think the Cybermen
will help you?
Of course.
I shall be their resurrector.
Look!
- Keep still!
- Behind you!
That thing! It's come alive!
You are so simple. You expect to
take me in with a trick like that!
It's true! Look!
- Will nothing keep you still?
- Will you please look?!
(BEEPING)
Any more trouble
and I'll take drastic steps.
We won't allow
a little girl to interfere!
Aaagh!
(BEEPING WINDS DOWN...)
(..AND STOPS)
What is it?
I think it's their leader,
their Controller, Jamie.
(CONTROLLER) You belong to us.
You shall be like us.
Can we not make a run for it,
Doctor?
No. We wouldn't reach the ladder.
It's too risky.
What can we do?
Play for time.
Wait for our chance. Leave it to me.
Excuse me? May I ask a question?
Why did you submit yourself
to freezing?
You don't have to answer that.
To survive.
Our history computer
has full details of you.
Oh? How?
We know of your intelligence.
Oh. Thank you very much.
Ah, yes. The lunar surface.
Our machinery had stopped
and our supply of replacements
been depleted.
So that's why
you attacked the moonbase.
You had destroyed our first planet
and we were becoming extinct.
What does capturing us do?
You'll still become extinct.
We will survive.
You will become the first
of a new race of Cybermen.
You will return to Earth
and control it.
But we're humans. We're not like you.
You will be.
Oh. No. Keep away!
Keep away!
Keep away...!/
It's very quiet down there.
Yeah. Too quiet.
- Something must have happened.
- How long they been down?
About an hour.
That's too long. I'm going down./
You are a logician.
Our race is also logical.
You will be the leader
of the new race.
You will listen
to my proposals, then?
Yes. We will listen.
But first you will be altered.
Altered?
You have fear.
We will eliminate fear
from your brain.
Yes. You will be the first.
And you will be the next.
No! No! Aagh!
You will be like us.
To die is unnecessary.
You will be frozen
and placed in our tombs
until we are ready to use you.
Your lives will be suspended.
Prepare the tombs.
They really mean it.
They're going to freeze us.
- Not me.
- No, they're coming back.
Come on, you guys. Run for it!/
Jamie!
Look at that smoke.
(JAMIE) Victoria!
Come on, Mr Parry. Come on, quick!
The Cybermen!
They're right behind us.
When the Doctor's up,
close the hatch!
- OK!
- Stand by!
Oh! Aagh! He's got my leg!
Doctor, come on!
- Come on!
- It's no use.
Jim, close the hatch!
(CALLUM) Got him!
(BANGING)
It was horrible. It was so strong!
It's all right.
You're all right now.
That was a near thing.
Is anyone missing?
Yes. Klieg and Toberman -
they're still down there!/
Don't open it.
It may be the Cybermen.
No. No, it's too soft.
- It must be Toberman and Klieg.
- You're crazy.
We can't leave them down there
even if they are killers.
They're probably frozen by now.
You must let them up.
They must be saved.
Yes, they're more dangerous
down there than up here.
What? OK. Jim?
Right.
(KNOCKING)
Let her go.
Excuse me, please.
Shut it! Shut it quick!
- Where's Toberman?
- They've got him.
Still think you can form an alliance
with the Cybermen?
If only I'd been
in a stronger position to bargain.
- You must be out of your mind.
- You're in no position to bargain.
What are we going to do with them?
I'd feel happier
if they weren't in here.
What about the testing room?
Good idea.
- Callum!
- Right.
Mr Klieg?
Miss Kaftan./
These humanoids are not like us.
They still have fear.
Place the Cybermats on the runway.
Cybermats will attack.
Oh!
I'm on your side, remember?
Hey, why didn't you wake me?
I should have been on watch
half an hour ago.
- I thought you should rest.
- Why me?
No reason really.
Oh, I think I know.
Was it because I'm...?
Well, if you are 450 years old,
you need a great deal of sleep.
Well, that's very considerate
of you, Victoria,
but, between you and me,
I'm really quite lively actually -
all things being considered.
Are you happy with us, Victoria?
Yes, I am.
At least, I would be
if my father were here.
Yes, I know.
I wonder what he'd think
if he could see me now.
You miss him very much, don't you?
It's only when I close my eyes.
I can still see him standing there.
Before those horrible
Dalek creatures came to the house.
He was a very kind man.
I shall never forget him. Never.
No, of course you won't.
But, you know, the memory of him
won't always be a sad one.
I think it will.
You can't understand,
being so ancient.
- Eh?
- I mean old.
You probably
can't remember your family.
Oh, yes, I can when I want to.
That's the point.
I have to really want to
bring them back in front of my eyes.
The rest of the time
they sleep in my mind and I forget.
And so will you. Oh, yes, you will.
You'll find there's so much else
to think about, to remember.
Our lives are different
to anybody else's.
That's the exciting thing.
There's nobody in the universe
can do what we're doing.
You must get some sleep,
and let this poor old man
stay awake.
Jamie, Victoria, Callum, wake up!
- Wake up!
- What is it?
Callum. Callum.
(VICTORIA) Those terrible things.
Don't move, Callum. Don't move.
Get back to the controls,
all of you.
Don't make any sudden movements.
Parry, wake up.
Don't panic.
Come back with us. Steady.
We'll all go in the other room
and lock them out.
Aagh!
Let's get out of here.
The main doors.
No!
Oh! Oh, Doctor, we're trapped!
Back against the controls,
everybody.
Here.
Give me a hand, quick.
Lay this down on the ground.
Come on!
- Doctor?
- Come on!
Let's blast the filthy things!
You're wasting your time. There are
too many of them! Come back!
- There you are.
- What are those creatures?
Well, they're...
They're a form of metallic life.
They home
on human brainwaves and attack.
Urgh!
Are they safe now?
Quite safe now. The power cable
generated an electrical field
that confused
their tiny metal minds.
They've had a complete
metal breakdown.
- Ooh.
- I'm so sorry, Jamie.
What about Klieg and Kaftan?
They've probably been attacked.
- The testing room.
- Come on. Mind your feet.
Most ingenious, Doctor.
Now let's see
what you can do against this.
Watch out, Doctor!
The humanoids
must first be destroyed.
You will re-enter cells
to conserve energy.
Keep back!
Your gun.
You've killed him, you murderer.
No. He is fortunate. I spared him.
- You missed him.
- Silence! I could have killed him.
- Shall I kill them now?
- No, that will not be necessary.
The Cybermen
will have a use for them.
You will make excellent
experimental specimens.
Oh, let me help him, please!
No tricks.
Still think you can bargain
with the Cybermen?
Certainly. This time on our terms.
I wish to speak to the Controller.
I wish to speak to the Controller!
He is now prepared.
Release him.
They're coming.
Now, gentlemen, you will see how
I shall use the power of the Cybermen.
Use, maybe, but you'll never
control the Cybermen.
- Behind you.
- Stop!
You know what this can do to you.
Toberman, it is good
that you are back.
Watch them.
- Doctor, he seems er...
- Yes, Jamie, yes.
I shall let you be revitalised.
To survive, it must be now.
Come forward. Slowly.
- Be careful.
- Leave this to me.
You are absolutely crazy
to trust them!
You think so?
Then perhaps you and your colleagues
had better join him. Go on. Go on!
- The girl stays with us.
- No!
She is our hostage.
Close the hatch.
You seem to be in trouble.
The energy...
levels...are...low.
We...will...survive.
You will help us.
You will...help...us...
Yes. Yes, certainly.
- Jamie, Professor.
- You're not going to help them?
You can't support these creatures!
I think it best. Come on.
Come along.
That's it.
Do...you...understand...
the...machine?
Yes. One moment.
Have you taken leave of your senses?
Let's help Victoria.
In a moment, Jamie.
(DOCTOR) Are you ready?
We will survive.
We will sur...
Now, where would you rather
have him - in or out of there?
Oh, I see what you mean.
Only we must make sure
that he stays in there.
Do you really believe you can bargain
with those terrible Cybermen?
That is our concern, not yours.
I'm talking to him, not you.
They will have to agree to our plan.
We shouldn't have touched it.
Turn it off. It's out of control.
(NOISE DIES DOWN)
It's taken over.
I think not.
There must be some sort
of internal timing mechanism.
Jamie, I hope you made
those ropes secure.
The King of Beasties
couldnae get out of that.
Jamie, remind me to give you
a lesson in tying knots.
What do you hope to gain from this?
- That does not concern you.
- They might as well know.
We are going to build
a better world.
(CALLUM) Better? But who for?
I told you to watch the door.
Aagh!
Toberman.
Victoria.
- You have done well.
- Toberman!
Silence.
He is now under our control.
Open the tombs.
No.
You have broken your promise.
Cybermen do not promise.
Such ideas have no value.
Open.
No.
That gun will not harm me.
Aagh!
Look what they've done.
You are not like them. You're a man
like us. You must help us.
He has killed Kaftan.
You must help us.
You will report to the surface.
(UNINTELLIGIBLE NOISES)
Jamie, the hatch!
The gun, Jamie!
There's another one!
(CRASHING)
Are there any more?
No. I'll close the hatch.
Wait a minute.
We'd better go down there.
- Not again!
- It's the only way to make sure.
- I'll go too.
- No. Stay and look after Victoria.
I'll take somebody else.
Toberman.
You see what these creatures
have done to you?
They've tried to make you like them.
Do you understand?
They've tried to make you
their slave. They want to use you.
They are evil. Think of Kaftan.
- Evil!
- They must be destroyed, you see.
Evil must be destroyed.
Now, come.
Destroyed!
Come on.
Come on!
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
- Doctor, the gun.
- I shan't need that.
Should have taken it.
- Aagh!
- Poor Mr Callum. How are you?
I can't move my arm.
Move quietly.
They're all dormant, see?
Evil!
No! Quietly. They're only asleep.
They're not frozen yet.
You watch them. I have things to do.
Now, let me see.
Yes.
The cryostat! You're freezing them!
Klieg!
No! You'll wake them up!
That is exactly my intention.
You still don't understand, do you?
Their Controller is dead.
Now I shall control them.
They will do what I say.
You see, Doctor.
Yours is the privilege
to witness for the first time
the union between mass power
and my absolute intelligence.
Who is that?
Come out.
Come out or I shall kill this man!
Oh, it's you.
Go to that wall, all of you.
All of you!
No.
I have a better idea,
a much better idea.
I shall leave you to the Cybermen.
I'm sure
they'll have some use for you.
Or parts of you!
(KLIEG SCREAMS)
Quick, Jamie!
These two levers together.
- I can't shift this one.
- What? Trip that first.
Last time they were frozen
for five centuries.
This time it must be forever.
Oh, Doctor!
Here we are, Victoria,
safe and sound. Close the hatch.
There we are.
Now then.
The best thing about a machine
that makes sense -
you can very easily
make it turn out nonsense.
- I think you'd better go outside.
- What are you going to do?
I'm going
to re-electrify the main doors.
Only this time I'm going to include
the hatch and the control panel.
Anyone touching any of them
will get a considerable shock.
A fatal one. Now, everyone outside.
Please take him with you.
I shall be glad to see him outside.
There we are. That's done.
We just have to close the main doors
and the circuit is complete.
Thank goodness for that.
Doctor.
Doctor!
Jamie...
You go that way. I'll go this way.
That gives us more of a chance.
When I say run, run.
Run!
Quickly!
Stop! We'll get a shock.
We must find something to insulate.
That shoring timber.
Hurry up!
Hurry up, he's coming!
We must keep him inside
or all our work will be wasted.
- I can't hold mine!
- You must!
Toberman!
We must survive.
You are evil.
- Toberman, come away!
- You'll get killed, man!
They shall never pass Toberman.
The door is closed.