Sincro: wyxchari
What the...?
Day of the Daleks
Doctor, why don't you take a break?
It's maddening, you know. So nearly there.
If I could only cut out their override
on the dematerialisation circuit.
Let me see those figures.
Doctor?
I thought the TARDIS was working again.
What gave you that idea?
Oh, being dragged off to an alien planet
five hundred years in the future, for example.
Oh, you know - all that business
with the miners and the colonists.
My dear Jo, the TARDIS was being operated then under
remote control by the High Council of the Time Lords.
Well, if it worked for them...
I don't want it to work for them.
I want it to work for me.
No-one's going to turn me into
an interplanetary puppet.
Yes, of course. Why didn't I think of that before?
Yes, of course. I remember now.
Look, don't worry, my dear. I know you're alarmed but you needn't be.
Yes, well I think that should do it. Why on Earth I never realised that...
Oh no! What are you doing here?
Well, I'm not here. Don't worry.
Well, that is, in a sense, er, I am here,
but, erm, you are not there.
Er... yes, well, it's a bit difficult
to explain really.
This won't do at all!
We can't have two of us running about.
Yes, well don't worry. It will all sor...
Doctor! What happened?
Well, it's a very complicated thing - time - Jo.
Once you've begun tampering with it,
the oddest things start happening.
But there was another you and another... me.
Well, where've they gone?
Back into their own time stream, of course.
Or do I mean forward?
But, Doctor, I don't understand...
Look, Jo. Don't worry about it. It was a freak
affect. It's very unlikely to happen again.
Hold that and give me those papers.
Ah, Doctor. Glad you're still here.
I need your help.
Sorry, Brigadier. I'm busy.
Yeah, so am I, Doctor, so am I. Now then,
you've heard of Sir Reginald Styles?
No, can't say that I have.
Well isn't he the chief representative at the UN?
That's right - key figure at the latest
summit conference.
My dear chap, I'm a scientist. Not a politician.
You know, Doctor, if you... didn't spend so much time
tinkering around with this wretched contraption,
you'd realise just how bad
the international situation's become.
Humans are always squabbling over something, Brigadier.
Yes, well, this particular squabble looks like
ending up in a third world war.
The Chinese delegation have refused to attend.
Without them, the conference can't even begin.
Now Styles is flying to Peking in a few hours.
There's just a chance that he can persuade them to change their minds.
All right, Brigadier. So what's his problem?
Well, he was working late last night,
down at Auderly...
Where's that?
Auderly, Miss Grant, is a Government owned country house
about fifty miles north of London where the conference is due to be held.
Oh.
He suddenly started behaving... rather oddly.
Seemed to think that someone was trying to assassinate him.
Any idea who?
Some sort of "ghost" apparently.
He said somebody attacked him and vanished.
And you're absolutely certain that he used the word "ghost"?
Oh yes. But afterwards he...
Miss Paget! What's going on here?!
These people are from UNIT, sir.
Who asked them to come here?
I did - because of what happened yesterday.
Nothing happened yesterday.
There seems to have been some sort of incident,
Sir Reginald?
Nothing of any importance.
Well, if you could tell us what happened?
I was working late. I must have dropped off.
Freak gust of wind, blew some papers off my desk,
I woke up rather confused,
I was picking up the papers when Miss Paget came in.
But you did mention ghosts.
Did I? Must have been having a nightmare.
But the French windows were shut. I closed them before I went to bed.
Then I must have opened them!
Did you, er, did you also make
those marks on the floor over there?
Muddy feet, Sir Reginald. Someone was in here, you know.
Are you accusing me of lying, sir?!
Sir Reginald, you've obviously been under considerable
strain recently. Were you feeling at all unwell last night?
I felt, and feel, perfectly well.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I've a lot to do.
I'm due at the airport in an hour.
You've no objection to my men searching the grounds?
None at all. Though I really don't know
what you hope to find.
Sergeant!
Ah, he's in a bad way, poor chap.
You'd better get him to the hospital.
Captain Yates...
Right away, sir.
This is a new one on me.
What do you make of it, Doctor?
I'm not sure...
Sir?
What've you got there, Benton?
No idea, sir.
It was hidden about fifty feet inside the tunnel.
Have you seen this before?
Really Brigadier! What sort of games are you playing?
It's not a game, sir. It's our duty to protect you!
I don't need your protection!
Sir Reginald, we've just found a very severely
injured man down by the canal tunnel.
Oh really? And what did he look like?
Thirty-fiveish, average build. He was wearing
a sort of guerilla combat suit.
And carrying that gun.
I am very sorry, gentlemen, but I have rather more important
things on my mind at the moment. If you'll excuse me?
I've arranged an escort to take you to the airport, sir.
Thank you, but it shouldn't be necessary.
I'm sorry, sir, but I think it will!
Oh, if you insist.
I'd like to get that gun down to the laboratory
and run a few tests on it.
Well, basically it's a form of ultra-sonic disintegrator.
You mean a ray gun?
That's right, Jo, I mean a ray gun.
Only it's far more sophisticated than any weapon
yet invented on Earth. Now take a look at this.
Quite an effective little weapon, eh?
Doctor, you say this wasn't made on Earth.
Do you mean it comes from another planet?
Well that was my theory at first, yes.
But the metallurgical analysis shows that the,
er, iron constituent is very much of this world./32.8
In fact, it was mined not very far from here - North Wales.
How do you explain that?
Do you believe in ghosts, Brigadier?
Let's be serious, Doctor.
I am.
Oh, come along, Doctor, come along.
Oh, my mistake. I was forgetting
the unimaginative nature of the military mind.
But we saw a couple of "Amicus Seperatus"
a few moments ago, didn't we, Jo?
Did we?
Yes, here in this laboratory.
Oh, you mean when we...
Mind you, they were manifestations
of a much more benevolent kind.
None of your clanking chains and chilly fingers!
But ghosts, none the less.
That was because you were playing around
with the time mechanism on the TARDIS, wasn't it?
Still can't get it to work, eh?
Well, I can't get this thing to work, either.
But this is a form of, er, of time machine of a very crude kind.
How do you know?
Come over here. Look at this.
Now what do you think that is?
Ooh, it's a... mini-dematerialisation circuit.
Top of the class, Jo.
Now then, pop this in here, like that.
Now, as far as I can gather,
when you push this button, it should...
Good grief! It's working!
Sir?
What is it?
Time transmitter in operation, sir.
Twentieth Century Zone.
Can you fix the space-time coordinates?
Do be careful, Doctor!
All right, Jo, all right.
Well?
No good, sir. There was a transference,
I think, but the machine's cut out completely.
Continue scanning - and next time
you had better be more efficient!
Report!
Yes, I see. All right, sergeant.  You'd better
report back to Captain Yates. Goodbye.
That was Benton. He was in the ambulance
with the man we found.
Well?
Well according to him, that man just...
vanished, faded away - like a ghost.
Oh no!
Well, Doctor, what now?
Well, everything that happens seems to
centre round Styles' house.
Obviously.
And whoever tried to harm him will probably try again.
Jo, how would you like to spend the night
in a haunted house?
Wake up, Jo.
It's all right. It's morning.
Nothing's happened?
No, nothing at all.
Jo! Jo!
Please! Turn that machine off
- or they'll kill all of us! Please!
Sir?
Yes?
We've picked up that time transmitter again.
You're sure?
Yes, sir. Same frequency, same time...
time zone. Much stronger now.
Right. I want the exact space-time co-ordinates
so whatever happens, don't lose it!
What is your report?
We have a fix on the time transfer device.
It is operating again in the twentieth century
time zone and it must be them.
You have obtained the space-time co-ordinates?
We're trying now. The trace is much stronger
this time. There is every chance...
You must not fail!
Security forces are standing by. If we do get
the co-ordinates, what are your instructions?
Whoever is operating the time machine
is an enemy of the Daleks.
All enemies of the Daleks must be destroyed!
Exterminate them!