Get back! Get back!
Please! Wait! I've got to talk to you!
Keep away!
Exterminate!
_ or you'll be caught in the time field!
We warned you.
Yes, yes, so you did.
This may come as a shock to you, but you've just
travelled two hundred years through time.
Thank you. But I'm probably more familiar
with the concept of time travel than you are.
Now wait a minute. Before the time transference,
I saw a Dalek.
You know of the Daleks?
Indeed I do. I know them only too well.
They've been my bitterest enemy for many years.
Then you're a fool to have let yourself be brought here!
Look, I came here in order to find Miss Jo Grant.
I told you, she's probably dead.
But as long as there's a chance...
Come on, Anat.
Wait a minute - what is my best way of finding her?
That's your problem.
We can't just leave him!
I can - come!
Run, Doctor - run!/
Report!
The security guards have combed the tunnels.
They've found nothing.
You have failed the Daleks! You will be punished!
The fault is not mine! Your security guards let them get away.
- Those creatures are useless!
- They are loyal to the Daleks.
As loyal as they are stupid!
They will never be a match for human guerillas.
No one can succeed who opposes the Daleks.
For every guerilla cell that you destroy,
another one springs up.
They have stolen your time machines and copied them.
They steal your weapons, your explosives.
These criminals will be exterminated.
The Daleks will destroy them.
If only you would let me
recruit more human security guards...
Humans are treacherous and unreliable!
Not all humans. I have served you faithfully.
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
Obey without question!
Very well. There was one... curious thing.
The girl referred to a companion in her own time zone.
She called him... "the Doctor".
Doctor?! Did you say "Doctor"?!
He appears to have got through to our time.
He was seen by the guards.
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks!
He must be found at once and exterminated!
Don't gloss over it, Anat, we failed!
We had no choice once our plan was known to them.
If you'd listened to me, we still could have done what was needed.
We did all we could!
Monia, our orders were to eliminate Styles, right?
Yes, but you failed.
We could have succeeded.
Then why didn't you?
He wasn't there! Security guards found us.
But Anat went soft.
Be quiet.
The trouble with you, Boaz is...
Both of you! We have to think now.
The situation is different.
As I see it, it's exactly the same -
we still have a job to do.
No. There may be other ways.
I've had a report from one of our contacts.
A girl has been captured.
They're holding her prisoner at the control centre.
The same girl - the one who operated
the time module at Styles' house?
It fits your description.
Well, at least she's alive.
In the hands of the Daleks? She won't live long.
Can she tell them anything?
Nothing of importance.
Have they picked up that Doctor yet?
Not yet. It's only a matter of time.
Move! Move! Come along there, you scum!
Move! Come along there, move! Move! Go on!
Well?
Been captured. Taken for processing.
We must rescue him.
Rescue him? Are you mad?! From there?
I say we must!
Suicide.
Are you afraid?
Me? Of course I am. I'm not a fool.
What is he to us?
We have fresh information from
one of our contacts at control centre.
He is the sworn enemy of the Daleks.
He is the one man they're afraid of - don't you see?
It's our only hope. If we don't act quickly,
it may be too late.
You are the Doctor! You are an enemy of the Daleks!
Now you are in our power! You will be exterminated!
You will be exterminated! You will be exterminated!