Sincro: wyxchari
This is a preliminary warning. Preliminary warning. Prepare
phase one base evacuation procedure. Phase one evacuation.
...determine the extent of
breakdown factor in ionisation...
Why has the ioniser been allowed
to deteriorate to danger level?
There was a power stoppage.
I've done all I can to boost it.
Well it can't be allowed
to fall any lower.
We still have time to evacuate.
We will certainly not evacuate.
We've beaten its tantrums before.
It's falling again.
Well hold it... steady
I can't.
Switch the stabilising circuits
through to the computer.
I have, it's still not holding!
All circuits, woman, all circuits!
We're nearly there.
There's not enough power.
It's slowing down.
Maybe it'll hold there.
I doubt it.
Well, at least it gives us time.
We need Scientist Penley.
He is no longer a member of this
post. You will make this machine work.
Yes, Leader Clent.
That's better.
Emergency evacuation phasing set?
Yes.
loniser state fault check?
Reactor safety sequence
in operation. Good.
You'll make an organiser
first class yet, Miss Garrett.
I only follow your
example, Leader Clent.
What is the latest report
from all other ioniser bases?
All bases are in phase. America: glaciers held. Australasia: glaciers
held. South Africa: glaciers held. Asia: some improvement claimed.
They would!
Britannicus Base, Europe: slipping
out of phase. Glacial advance imminent.
If we fail, the whole program for
glacier containment is in danger.
I'm fully aware of that fact.
But in two hours, the
ioniser will be useless.
And then the glaciers will move again... 5000 years
of history... crushed beneath a moving mountain of ice.
Phase two evacuation. Emergency. Phase two
evacuation. Red state emergency. Red state emergency.
Priority override.
Yes, of course. But
Penley was the expert.
I've had enough of experts.
Their crazy ideas. Where's Arden?
Still at the ice face, completing
the instrumentation project.
Well, hasn't he been warned?
We couldn't get through...
Well we have to tell him, immediately!
I cannot lose any more men!
Leader Clent to Scientist Arden
at glacier face, come in Arden!
Walters, through here. Now clear that...
Sir. Get your drill ready, Davis.
Sir!
Yes?
Come quickly, Sir!
I could swear there's something inside.
Oh, not another mastodon.
Well look for yourself, Sir.
Is it a man?
Perhaps it's an animal.
Well we'll soon find out.
Davis, the heavy drill.
Yes Sir.
Base calling, Sir.
What do they want?
There's nothing coming through. Poor
reception. I suppose they might...
They'll have to wait. This is
more important. Come on Davis.
Well what are we going to do, Sir?
Do? Excavate. This could
be a brilliant discovery.
But Sir
- the computerised schedule! We must stick to that.
Oh, must we?
Leader Clent will be furious, Sir.
Well that's just too bad. For once we'll
do something on our own account, eh?
There's not much base can do about it Sir,
after all, we can't even ask permission, can we?
Come on Davis, hurry man!
Arden, for heavens sake
man, come in! This is urgent!
_ again. _ is decreasing. Not
far from total disintegration.
Arrgh!
What's the matter?
You're on my head!
Careful!
Come on, Victoria. Give me your hand.
It was a blind landing.
Is that what you call it?
Well no broken bones.
Hey, look at the snow.
Oh no, not again! Tibet was bad enough, but I think
you've put us down just further up the mountain!
Well let's see, shall we? Very careful, I'm
going to get out. It's quite a long drop.
Come on Victoria, that's right.
Hey, looks like a great
big wall of ice. Look!
Ooohhh!
What is it?
You're on my hand!
But Doctor, look.
Yes, that's not ice, that's plastic.
Yes and, see how smooth
it is, and curved.
It's a dome. A protective dome.
It's so big. Can't see the end
of it. Wonder what's inside.
Don't worry, those alarms weren't meant
for us. I wonder what's wrong, though.
Ach, that's their problem. Come on.
Leader Clent! The video!
Arden has made contact.
Arden! Can you hear me?
Yes. What is it?
You must return to base immediately.
Well don't panic. I've almost finished setting
up the seismograph probe. Davis hurry up.
Well... the ioniser's nearly
at disintegration point.
Oooh, I wonder if
Penley's ears are burning.
It's not a laughing matter,
man! You know what it means.
Yes, cold weather ahead. I
thought it felt a bit nippy.
There'll be a full enquiry into
your delay, you realise that.
Yes, and I've got a very good reason.
A fantastic discovery, in the ice.
Your task was to set up movement probes in
the ice, not indulge in amateur archaeology.
This is a man!
Well, congratulations. Makes a change
from fossils. Now leave it and return.
I'm bringing the body back with me.
Arden.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
There seems to some interference.
Arden!
Oh, Doctor, it's just like my home.
I know!
Red state emergency. Evacuation phase three. Phase three evacuate.
Transport section leaders report now. Phase three evacuation.
Something's wrong.
Seems safe enough.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you. Excuse me Miss, I'm Jamie McCrimmon,
do you think you could tell us where we are?
She doesn't want to know, Jamie.
Hey, this says we're on
evacuation flight seven.
Yes, rather inhospitable,
we've only just arrived!
Mmm.
Hey, and this tag, it
says I'm a scavenger!
And yours does too!
Hey, we're not beggars!
Hush Jamie.
What is it Doctor?
Sounds like electronic machinery, like a
computer. There's something wrong with it's pitch.
Oh no. Now look, it might be
dangerous, now let's leave it.
No.
Doctor.
Let's go in.
Oh, there's something very wrong here.
Now is _ still out of phase?...
Seven-two point four...
Seven-two point four? That's bad.
Now balance those gauges, Miss
Henry. 17 degrees out from normal.
17 degrees? Well this is serious!
One-three-seven-nine,
now...
Who the blazes are you? Get
these scavengers out of here!
We're not scavengers!
Out of here!
No! In two minutes 38 seconds, you're going to
have an almighty explosion! The readings say so!
Well how do you possibly know that, I haven't even, I
haven't even processed them through the computer yet!
I don't need a computer!
If he's right it's
already too late to escape!
No it isn't, it doesn't have
to happen, if you'll excuse me.
Cut out the reactor!
There's insufficient power for that.
Well a quick short burst then
from the reactor unit, now.
Off!
Now link the circuit,
with the reactor link.
Now, bring in the computer stabiliser.
Yes, yes, that should hold it steady. It's a, it's not a
perfect job, mind you. You ought to get an expert in, you know.
How did you... It was all bluff, wasn't
it, that two minutes 38 seconds to danger?
Oh no, it was near enough
correct, give or take a second.
Rubbish.
Check it on your
precious computer, then.
Miss Garrett, do so.
loniser fall rate: seven-two point four, ion compensator: minus
one-seven degrees, ion flow rate: one-three-seven-nine. Assessment please.
Immediate emergency. In two minutes
37 seconds, the reactor will explode.
Well a second out. We...
can't all be perfect.
We're at half power now, Leader Clent!
Why even Penley couldn't have done
better. Where on earth did you spring from?
It doesn't matter, look...
Are you alright?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, no no no no. It's nothing, it's
just um, it's just an emergency _ and 10 hour duty spell.
The vibro-chair.
Yes, you're right. Um, contact the Medi-Control Centre the moment
there's a further _ We'll talk at the same time, come with me.
Ask him where we are!
A giant among prehistoric men.
See the kind of armour he's got on?
Yes, that's rather strange. He looks pre-Viking. But no such
civilisation existed in prehistoric times before the first ice age.
Ha! Proper "Ice Warrior", isn't he, Sir?
I reckon Leader Clent will be interested.
Yes. What'll the mighty
computer make of it, eh?
Sir, hadn't we better get back
while the weather still holds?
Good point Walters. Davis, try bringing
the air-sled a little closer, will you?
What are they up to?
Arden's found something in the ice. Something
to take back to Clent. It won't be appreciated.
Ar, they ought to leave way alone.
Arden was always a researcher. He wanted
to be an archaeologist when I knew him.
Archaeology. What good's that?
It's good to know things,
even when they're dead.
Nothing's sacred to you, is it?
I only ask questions, it's
in my character I suppose.
Ar, you swore you'd give all that up.
Discovery's as exciting to me as the hunt is to you. But with Clent,
he uses scientists' craniums as stepping stones for his ambitions.
Ar, that's about all
you lot are fit for...
Well we're not totally useless, surely?
To me you are. Come on, we've got to
move. Leave them to... stupid games.
Avalanche! Come on!
Where's Davis?
Storr! Come on! Avalanche!
Storr, are you alright?
Penley...
What's the damage?
My arm. It's gone I think.
Broken?
Feels like it.
Well you're lucky. There's one down there
who's staying on the mountain for good.
They'll... they'll come looking for him. We must move out a
bit. Unless you fancy trying to turn me over to your friends.
Six weeks ago they were my friends,
but not anymore. Can you walk?
Aye. Just you try and keep up. Come on.
All clear, Sir.
Yes, but how 'bout Davis?
I'll go look for him.
Well let's hope he's safe. With another
man gone, Clent'll skin me alive.
Well if he gets too difficult, you can
always set your warrior on him, eh Sir?
But you've no valid proof
of your qualifications?
Look, aren't we wasting time?
If you want our help, why
not tell us all about it?
All about it? All about what?
Where have you been all these years?
Well, er, as a matter of fact, we've, we've been
in retreat. In, in Tibet. We are sanctifiers.
Oh, I see. In Tibet. Well if you'll take a simple test,
I'll soon know if you're up to our scientific standards.
I see, and er, if I fail?
You'll be evacuated with the
other scavengers in due course.
Oh, where to?
The African rehabilitation
centres, of course.
Oh no, not Africa.
Very well, fire away.
I present you a problem.
Yes.
All the major continents are threatened with
destruction, under the glaciers of the second ice age.
Oh.
How would you halt the ice surge, and turn the climate
back to normal? 45 seconds, starting from... now.
Oh, er, ahem, er, possible causes,
er, the reversal of the magnetic field.
No such change has occurred.
Um, interstellar clouds,
er, obscuring the suns rays.
An excessive burst of sunspot activity.
A severe shift of the
Earth's angle of rotation.
Come on Doctor.
There aren't that many alternatives.
Gigantic heat loss, eh? Er.
I asked for an answer, not a
question. Twelve seconds left.
Oh. Er. Oh well. Ahem. In that case the answer's simple. A severe drop
in the carbon dioxide level in the Earth's lower atmosphere. Is that it?
I would use ionisation.
Well, is he right?
Yes, he is.
But I still don't understand.
Well the carbon dioxide level in the Earth's atmosphere helps retain
the suns heat. Take that gas away, and there's a sudden freeze up.
Oh, where does the gas go to?
Well...
You know how efficient our civilisation is, thanks to the direction of the great world computer. And you also know how we conquered the problem of world famine a
century ago by artificial food. On the land that was once used to grow the food we needed, we built up-to-date living units, to house the ever-increasing population.
Up to date?
Well there were exceptions, of course. I mean this house was classified as being historic
interest. So, the amount of growing plants on the planet, was reduced to an absolute minimum.
No plants, no carbon dioxide.
Then suddenly, one year,
there was no spring.
Even then it wasn't understood. Not
until the ice-caps began to advance.
Er, but er, what's this ioniser?
Um, Miss Garrett.
lonisation is a method of intensifying the suns
heat onto the Earth, but into particular areas.
Yeah, it's like a
magnifying glass, Jamie.
Oh, aye.
You mean you can melt glaciers
and change the weather?
Um, when certain
difficulties are overcome.
Precise control is not easy.
We can't afford to make mistakes. lonisation can
produce temperatures intense enough to melt rock.
Only by maintaining a perfect balance
can we prevent widespread flooding.
Can't your computers solve
the problem of control?
Of course they can!
Well?
When the input data is complete
they will give us the solution.
Oh, I see. And when will that be?
Soon Doctor, soon.
What's the position now?
Well we're barely holding the glacier in check. Now
there you see a world map of the situation at the moment.
And there you see what's, erm, going on in our sector. But if we fail, then not only will Europe be
swallowed up, but the balance of power will be ruined, and the whole world program will, will go under.
And the glaciers will win.
My senior scientist Penley, is missing. I think you have the
capabilities to join us here. This great mission. Will you help us?
Well I, I'm willing to try.
Jolly good. Jolly good. Er, Miss Garrett will give you some
background information. You've worked with computers, I presume?
Er, only when I have to.
Well Miss Garrett is our computer
specialist, she'll help you.
Oh, I'll try and remember that.
Here we are completely computerised.
Oh never mind.
Every decision is checked, to eliminate risk of failure. Because of
course, all decisions, all actions, must conform to the common good.
This way, gentlemen, this way. Right.
Now do be careful. 'Round
here. Steady with her.
Is this... your full co-operation, Arden?
How do you expect us to carry out this...
Great heavens.
Yes, I thought you'd be impressed Clent.
Right chaps, lets have him over here...
This way, this way...
What is it?
It looks like a Viking
warrior. Look at the helmet.
Frozen for centuries in the ice.
Perfectly preserved. Hm, that's odd though.
What? Who are you?
An addition to our staff,
Arden. What's odd Doctor?
Well the helmet, it's wrong. When this man was
frozen to death only primitive cavemen existed.
Well I say it's an undiscovered
civilisation. Think of the implications!
Well whatever the implications, it must still take second place to out ioniser project.
We have our daily planning conference in three minutes fifteen seconds, exactly.
Come along Arden! Play with
your toy after the meeting.
Well, what's supposed to happen, Doctor?
You see this fellow Arden has set the electricity so that
the ice melts very slowly, allowing for the resistance.
It's working quite quickly.
Well, I suspect there are some
impurities in the ice. I say.
Look at that.
What is it?
It's an electronic
connection. I'm sure of it.
It can't be.
Now you wait here, and,
and don't touch anything.
What's got into him all of a sudden?
I don't know. Scientists are
all alike, eureka and all that.
Aye. Could do with a go on this, maybe.
Er, Victoria.
What?
You see how those lassies were dressed?
Yes I did. And trust you to
think of something like that.
What? Couldn't help thinking about it.
Well I think it's disgusting,
wearing that kind of thing.
Oh, aye, so it is, so it is. You er, you
don't see yourself dressed like that then?
Jamie!
Oh, I'm sorry, it was just an idea.
We will now change the subject,
please. I want to look at this man.