Sincro: wyxchari
Ready to fire.
Not yet.
She has betrayed us.
She must be destroyed.
Let her talk first.
They will know our numbers.
They will also know she
is alive. She is a bait.
Victoria, tell us more
about the warriors.
Er, they're from Mars...
They're not important. Have you seen the
propulsion unit of the spacecraft, girl?
Oh, propulsion unit?
The engines!
Oh yes. They're busy repairing them now.
What kind are they?
It's vitally important.
I... I've no idea!
Well, reactor turbine? lon
jet? Anti-gravity? Think girl!
Can you describe them
to us, Victoria dear?
Yes, yes I think so.
Well hurry girl!
Look it isn't easy. Now I
have to have time to think...
Victoria? Victoria what's happened?
Are you alright? Answer me!
I'm alright.
It's the glacier. It's
moving all the time.
You're not hurt?
The engines, tell us about the engines!
She has told them enough. Bring her in.
Destroy her.
You are wrong Zondal. She must answer some questions first.
Why are they so interested in our engines? Why are they afraid?
There's... there's someone coming!
Victoria... Victoria. Can you
see the base from where you are?
Yes. Yes I can.
Do you think you can get back to it?
I can give it a try.
Well, get in contact again
as soon as you can! Good luck!
Yes.
This is an automatic
chemical dispenser is it not?
Yes.
How does it work?
Well, you choose the category of the article that you want
by, er, indicating it on one of these little chaps here.
Jolly good. And er, now you dial the
precise chemical formula that you want there.
May I? There's something
I need rather desperately.
Oh, what's that?
Water.
Indeed.
Ah, that's better. Now then,
let's see. Jamie has vanished.
Victoria's on her way back to the base.
And neither of them can help
us with our main problem.
An exact description of the
spacecrafts propulsion unit.
That will?
I will.
With the help of ammonium sulphide?
We know these creatures come from Mars, don't we? What
do we know about their planet's atmospheric conditions?
Chiefly nitrogen with
virtually no oxygen or hydrogen.
Then they're not going to enjoy this
little concoction much, are they?
What? You mean you plan to use
it as a kind of... toxic gas?
Well, if I'm going to an alien
spaceship it may come in handy.
Now don't be ridiculous.
We've lost Arden already.
Arden fell into a trap.
I know what to expect.
I, I, I refuse to allow you to go!
Splendid! You go instead then!
No one can be spared!
Least of all Leader Clent!
I can be spared. I've done all I can here. The ioniser
will work without me. I'll start getting ready then.
But if anything goes
wrong with the countdown!
Oh, you'll manage.
No!
It's as simple as this: someone has to get to the spacecraft, find out what sort of propulsion unit
it has, and bring the information back to you! Or we can't use the ioniser! Now, who better than me?
I've come to regard you as Penley's replacement. And,
um... alright, alright! But it's strictly under protest!
Thank you.
How will you get the
information back to us?
Ah. Now I don't suppose you have
a, a, a, a small radio transmitter?
No, our video links are the only communicators
available. Pure sound is no longer in use.
Oh, well you won't see
me, but you'll hear me.
As soon as I get to the glacier face I'll
switch it on and you'll overhear. I hope.
Is that all you're taking?
Why, what else do I need?
But the Warriors are armed!
But I'm not going to fight a duel.
But you must be in a
position to defend yourself!
They'll try to kill you out of hand!
Oh, I don't think so.
This is my defence.
But how can you rely on that? They've already
proved themselves to be utterly ruthless.
I think they'll listen to me.
You mean you're going to
let them take you prisoner?
That is exactly what I'm going to do.
I think he's gonna wake.
Pulse isn't too good.
His fever's gone.
Well, his body is young. It will heal.
Then, why you looking so worried?
I don't know yet. The weapons they used on him
- they're curious.
Aye, scientifically designed, of course.
This is no time for debates.
Aye, it's easily said. I'll
away and fetch a fresh drink.
You'll not keep me prisoner!
Stay still!
No get away out of it!
Storr!
Stop fighting!
You'll not keep me!
We're your friends!
We saved your life!
Oh, ooh.
Oh my head. Ah.
What you doing to me?
I'm going to try and ease your
pain with this tranquiliser pad.
I don't believe you!
Now you must trust us. We know about
your friend. We may be able to help.
Victoria? Well where is she?
In the alien spaceship.
Alien?
These warriors are not of
our time. Nor of this planet.
So, how would you know all that?
Ah, because he's a scientist. He can
produce an explanation for anything.
And you?
I'm a loyalist.
A loyalist!
Ah! They've told you have they?
Aye! But there's no time to talk.
I came here to rescue Victoria.
You're in no way...
Oh, just you try me.
Here give me a hand.
He's not as bad as you say Penley.
Your scientists aren't always right!
Ah ha! You hear that Penley!
But, your legs are still weak.
My legs! I can't feel my
- I can't stand!
Oh, is this what your
stupid drugs can do?
Don't be a fool, Storr. Of
course it's not the drugs.
Well what is it then?
Well their weapons must have
affected your central nervous system.
You mean I'm paralysed?
Where is the girl?
Turoc has not yet returned.
He must find her.
Why?
We need her to draw an
intelligent being from the base.
To find out the kind
of reactor they use.
Yes. Without the _ fuel
elements we are helpless.
And if they have them?
We shall take them.
Is the fuel completely run down?
If the scientists succeed
in melting the ice?
There will be floods.
No hope for our engines, then?
Or for us.
The gun is our only chance.
Help! Oh, somebody help
me! Ugh! Help! Somebody!
Arrgghh! Oh no! No! Oh please!
Help me somebody! Please help me!
Well, there's nothing more I can do for him.
That's the last of the tranquiliser pads.
Do ye... understand his illness?
No, and I've no way
of knowing the cause.
Well, there's one way we can save him.
How?
To befriend the aliens.
Oh don't be a fool Storr!
Oh they'll help us. I'll talk
to them. They'll understand.
But they're warriors, trained to kill.
Ach, only in self-defense, surely.
Oh rubbish no! We've got to
get the boy back to the base.
No!
For the boy's sake.
Oh, ye, ye, ye trying to trap me! There's no return for me to
the civilisation that Clent represents. This is where I stay.
Do you think the aliens are
any better? They killed Arden.
Ar, they were afraid.
They're ruthless, they
place no value on human life.
Well I'll talk to them. Someone has to.
We don't know what they're
capable of, or why they're here.
Well, I'll ask questions
first, then act.
It may be too late then.
We'll see.
No
- wait! Storr, look, you don't know what you're running into!
Now don't try and stop
me! You look after the boy.
Storr! Storr! Storr! Storr!
Can you hear me! Help! Oh! I'm trapped!
Oh, oh it's you again, is it?
Has anyone passed this way?
No. Are you looking for someone?
A rather ragged fellow. Like me.
No, nobody. Not even like me.
Then I'm too late.
There's nothing I can do.
Can I help you?
Well you've helped me once already. Why didn't
you give me away, or stop me at the base?
Well why should I? I don't
believe everything Clent tells me.
This boy. He's your friend.
You know where he is? Is he hurt?
Come this way.
Help me please!
Who are you?
Never mind about that now.
Would you release me please?
Wh, what happened?
I run away and the warrior
caught me. The ice fell...
You ran away? But why?
The warriors
- they're evil. They killed Arden. I think they want to destroy the base.
They are against the scientists?
I know, but they won't listen. They think
the ioniser is a weapon against them.
Ah, it's true. A weapon of destruction.
Only to destroy the ice.
Ah, it will destroy civilisation.
Anyway, thank you.
Uh.
Ah, where were you going?
Uh well, your friend, the boy.
Jamie! Jamie, he's
alive! Oh, is he alright?
Ah, he's desperately
ill. I'm going for help.
But where?
We'd better move out of here
- quickly!
Is it ready?
We are checking the motivator. Realign
harmonic frequencies to target points.
When do we attack the base?
Soon, Zondal, soon. Has Turoc returned?
Not yet Sir.
The ice, it is alive.
The spaceship!
Aye.
You came here on purpose?
Of course!
I'm not coming with you!
Oh, but you must! We must! You'll
- we'll be safe! They'll listen to me.
But they won't! You can't trust them.
Arh, they're against the scientists and
the ioniser. That's good enough for me!
Is that your reason?
I think that's wicked!
Ar, they'll understand.
Let go of me!
Oh!
Where's Turoc?
He... he was crushed by the ice.
Oh!
I give you your life. You run away.
Because of that, one of my men is dead!
Honestly, it wasn't my fault!
Take her inside.
You're not going to kill me are you?
My name is Storr. I'm
a scavenger. A loyalist.
You are from the base?
No, I'm against the scientists.
You know nothing of their machines?
No, I don't want to. Their intentions are
evil. I want to help you destroy the scientists.
You. What good are you to us?
Oh well, I know the land around
here. I've lived here all my life.
You are not a scientist.
Only a local native.
Useless and unnecessary.
Oh, but I want to help you!
Now, to question the girl.
There we are!
Good to see you again, Doctor.
Ah, won't be long before you're
on your feet again, Jamie.
How long?
Well, that depends. You've had some sort of shock
to your brain, it's affected your nervous system.
I will walk again, though?
Oh, yeah, of course you will. It's
just a matter of time, that's all.
Aye, well I'll take your word on that.
What can we do for him?
Well the base is the only
place he can be treated.
Yes I know that, but he
can't get there alone.
That's the glacier. It's
moving forward even faster.
Yes. It'll flatten this
place in no time at all.
Alright. I'll help you take him back.
Well that's just it, you see. I, I
can't go, there's something I must do.
Well you don't expect me to face Clent alone? That mouth-piece of
the computer? He's got a printed circuit where his heart should be!
He's a man with a mission. I don't
think he can afford to reject you.
Well that's not the point.
Anyway, what are you gonna do?
I must speak with the warriors.
No Doctor!
Well what can you do alone?
I have to see whether Victoria got away safely, and I must find out whether this
spacecraft is a danger to the ionisation program. I, I admit it won't be easy.
Doctor, if you go to the
warriors you'll be their prisoner!
Their guest I hope, Jamie.
Look Miss Garrett, look. The glacier's moving. That's the
fifth surge today. The ioniser just isn't holding it anymore.
But we daren't increase
power beyond the minimal.
Well I know the risk if the spaceship explodes. _ radioactivity
level. We'd only replace one disaster with an even greater one.
But you must make a decision soon.
No decision to be made yet! Computer can act only when given adequate
information. We still don't know enough about the alien reactor.
Suppose we never know? Suppose
the Doctor never returns?
We'll face that if and when we have to.
But you must have a
plan in mind, surely?
I'm pinning all my hopes on
the Doctor. He must succeed.
Here we go, Clent old
chap. Wish me luck.
Anyone at home?
Open up. Come on, open up, I say! Very well,
I shall count to ten. One... two... three... ah!
Who are you?
I never answer questions
until I'm addressed properly.
You will answer now.
Very well. You are standing in the airlock of this spacecraft. Unless you answer my
questions, within ten seconds I will take atmospheric pressure around you down to zero.
But if you do that my body will explode!
One... two... three... four...