It's a flying beastie!
Hey, you! Stop!
Scatter!
- The pilot said what?
- A police box on the runway.
A likely story! Tell him to get back into stack
and await further instructions.
Miss Rock, get the airport police.
Control. Sugar Delta X-ray.
Return to stack.
Police? Commandant here.
In-bound aircraft reports obstruction
on intersection of runways five and two.
Investigate and report back.
Police box
Jamie! Come over here with me.
Come on.
Just a minute.
Give me that envelope!
I would advise you to stop.
Agh!
Can you come quickly? Trouble.
Trouble? What happened?
The postcards. Someone found them.
Right.
All right, all right.
So you dumped it by number four hangar, but what was it?
It WAS a police box?
Get me the police chief.
All right. You can bring those planes down now.
- The obstruction's been cleared.
- Right, sir.
Do you think it was a practical joke, sir? Students or someone?
Well, whoever it was, they'll pay for it when I get my hands on them.
I won't have passengers' lives
endangered by practical jokers or anyone else.
Superintendent Reynolds?
I have the commandant for you.
The Chief of Police.
Listen, what's all this about a police box on the runway?
Oh... Well, security's
got to be tightened up all round!
He reports that four suspects were seen running away from it.
- Did they catch them?
- No!
Idiot of a policeman lost them.
They're miles away by now.
Get me Immigration.
Tell them to let me know
if any suspicious characters are seen there.
- There's Polly!
- Polly! Over here!
Doctor...
I've just seen a man killed!
- Hit by one of the beasties?
- No.
There were two men in there.
One of them had a gun,
and he shot the other one.
The murderer,  did he see you?
He chased me but I managed to lose him.
Could you find this hangar again?
Well, I think so...
I can remember the name.
It was Chameleon something or other.
- Where's Ben?
- We haven't seen him. Let's find this hangar.
The bloke with the gun will be looking for me.
We'll look after you. Now, come on.
- What about Ben?
- We'll find him. Come on.
- He found the postcards.
- His name?
I don't know. I caught him in the office.
He'd found evidence. I had to stop him.
You've killed Detective Inspector Gascoigne -
a policeman.
Do you think a parent sent him?
Possibly. It doesn't matter.
The important thing is
that nobody should find him.
Arrange disposal.
All right. Get it over here as quickly as possible.
- A container is on the way.
- Right.
Destroy this.
Why have you left those suitcases there?
The detective - he interrupted me.
Spencer!
Look.
The bloke came out of that door there.
Is it locked? Is anyone in there?
It's locked. There's nobody there.
This man who killed him.
Would you recognise him again?
Yes! He chased me. I'd recognise him anywhere.
Fool!
Polly, how would you say he was killed?
With a gun.
Can you describe it to me?
No. It was too far away. Why?
This man was electrocuted.
His clothes are all scorched.
It was definitely some kind of a gun, Doctor.
Maybe. But not one
that's been developed yet on this planet.
This man they call Doctor,
where does he get his knowledge?
He looks like a normal being.
More intelligent than most.
He's a threat to our operation.
- I'll kill him.
- No. Get the girl. She can identify you.
- We can deal with the man later.
- He may talk.
So?
Nobody will believe him.
We must report this to the authorities.
That man who chased us. We could find him maybe.
The policeman?
No, no, Jamie, we must find
the man in charge in this place.
What about him? We can't just leave him here.
There's nothing else we can do.
Now let's find the main airport building. Come on.
Are you sure this is the right way, Doctor?
It seems to lead to the main airport building.
- What happened to me?
- A temporary disablement.
You'll be back to normal any second now.
Up here.
- Where are you taking me?
- You'll see.
- I've got her.
- Excellent. Did anybody see you this time?
She was following behind her friends, but they didn't notice.
- They'll come looking for me.
- Sit down.
Murderers!
You'll have to show us some respect
and answer my questions.
- Which airline do you work for?
- I don't understand.
You must belong to an airline
or the airport authority to be in this area.
I've got nothing to do with the airport.
We'd just arrived. We were lost.
I was trying to find someone to help me,
and I saw him kill a man.
You say you'd just arrived? How did you get here?
We'll gain nothing by questioning her.
The important thing is that we've got her.
You don't think my friends
are just going to forget me like that, do you?
I don't understand it, Doctor. Polly's nowhere to be seen.
Something must have happened to her.
That's locked, Jamie.
There's nobody there.
I'm afraid we're wasting our time here, Jamie.
The sooner we find the authorities and tell it to them, the better. Come on.
Yes, you're right. Your friends ARE worried about you.
Then we shall have to do something
to stop them worrying.
This seems to be the way, Jamie.
Excuse me... We're looking
for someone in authority.
Just a moment, sir. All in good time.
Thank you, madam.
Now, sir. Your passport, please.
I've got no time for that.
We want to see someone in authority.
- I am in authority. Your passport, please.
We have something important to report.
Yes, sir, when you've found your passport.
Next one, please.
- What's a passport?
- Official mumbo-jumbo. Look!
We've just discovered a dead body out there.
Did you hear me?
Well, sir. If I were you, I'd inform the police.
Please tell me where we can find them.
There's probably a policeman in the main concourse.
- And where is that?
- Through this door and turn to your left.
Thank you, thank you very much. Come on, Jamie.
May I see your passport, sir?
We neither of us have passports!
Does that satisfy you?
I think you must be mistaken, sir.
You couldn't have got on the aircraft without passports.
- What aircraft?
- The one you arrived on, sir.
We didn't arrive on an aircraft.
Now, look here, this joke's gone far enough.
You know and I know
that you must have arrived on the last inbound flight
- which was flight 729 from Madri
- Tell him about the Tardis!
- What's that?
- It's the way we got here.
You gentlemen wouldn't know anything about a police box, would you?
That's what I'm saying! We're...
I really think that our mode of  conveyance is irrelevant.
The important thing is that we discovered a dead body out there!
And we want to report it to someone in authority!
I think you'll have plenty of opportunity
to see someone in authority.
- Well, thank you.  Thank you very much.
- Will you take a seat, over there
Give me the commandant, please.
Hello, sir. Jenkins here. Immigration desk five.
I've got two of your suspects here.
Anyone here?
There must be someone around. Anyone here?
Hello. Is Captain Blade about?
I don't know. I'm a bit lost.
Are you looking for me?
Yes, I have your flight schedules here. They're all in order.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- What do you want?
- I'm looking for the way out.
This is private property. Visitors are not welcome.
Do you belong to the airport staff?
Yeah. I started today.
I didn't mean to come in here. I got lost.
- Are you sure?
- Of course I am.
Are you going to direct me or not?
Yes, of course. Come on.
I'll show you the way.
You say this girl witnessed a murder?
- Yes. She saw the man killed!
He was electrocuted with a ray gun.
- A what?
- Oh, what does it matter what sort of gun.
The point is he was killed  and my friend saw it happen.
Where is she? I'd like to talk to her.
Well, that's another thing. She's vanished.
Oh, people who vanish, ray guns...
Is this some sort of joke?
You wouldn't think it a joke if you saw the body.
What flight did they come in on?
Well, sir, they came in with the passengers from
flight 729 from Madrid,
but they've no passports.
Perhaps you'd kindly explain
why you have no passports.
Oh, look, we're all wasting time!
Are you going to come and see that body,
or am I going to find someone who really is in charge in this place?
I am in charge of this place, thank you.
Now, you both accompany me to this hangar immediately.
Thank you! Thank you very much. At last!
- Tell Air Traffic Control where I am.
- Yes, sir.
Immigration desk five here.
Number One's just gone to the hangar area.
He wanted me to let you know.
As a matter of fact, he's just gone to look for a dead body.
Yes, It's gonna be one of those days, isn't it?
- Get her?
- She's being processed.
They can take another on the next flight.
Excellent.
The body - it's gone!
- You're quite you've got the right hangar?
- Aye. The name's up outside.
The body was lying just here.
Well, let's see what we HAVE got, shall we?
What exactly are you doing?
For the police, of course. The trouble is I can't tell them who he was.
- Some sort of mystery man, no doubt.
Yes, as a matter of fact he was.
There was nothing in his pockets to identify him.
- A man with nothing in his pockets
- Yes, I was rather surprised myself.
- Wait. There WAS one thing.
- What did he have in his pocket?
This.
- A postage stamp
- But it's Spanish and it hasn't been used.
I'm sure that'll make all the difference.
Exactly. Hello... This is interesting.
What have you found now?
It's burnt fibres.
What about this, Doctor?
This wasn't here before. It's a burn mark.
You're right, Jamie. It's quite new.
It's good to see someone is using their intelligence.
Oh, I've had enough of this! You two coming with me.
Definitely made by a ray gun.
Ray gun, burnt fibres, foreign stamps...
- Unused foreign stamps.
- All right, unused foreign stamps.
I must be as mad as you are, even to be listening to you!
- You know what they've done with it ? - Done with what?
The body. Somewhere there's a large packing case.
- Right behind you, Doctor!
- Can I help you?
- Are you connected with Chameleon Tours?
Yes. I'm Captain Blade - chief pilot.
These gentlemen think
there's an incident happened in here.
- An incident?
- Would you mind if we have a look in this packing case?
- May I ask who you are?
- I'm the commandant.
Yes, of course.
What do you expect to find?
A dead man.
How very interesting.
Plastic cups! Now I'm going to do
some investigating of my own.
I'm glad I've roused your interest!
Oh, you have. But what I'm going to investigate is you.
and why you're both here in the airport.
Thank you, Captain Blade Come on, you two. Out.
We'd better humour him.
Bring him down.
It's all right.
Will he survive?
If we hurry.
There you are.
We've got to get you to the airport building
and you'll be safe.
He's reaching suffocation point. Hurry.
- You didn't let me search properly.
- That hangar is leased to a private charter company.
I've have no right to search in there.
Now, will you kindly sit down and keep quiet?
Jenkins, get onto Superintendent Reynolds.
This is his job. These people are trespassing.
- I've just got another flight coming through.
- All right. I'll do it.
Doctor, look!
- Commandant, this is the girl I was telling you about.
- I beg your pardon?
Do you know these gentlemen?
- No. Why? Should I?
- According to them, they know you.
- Where have you been, Polly?
- Polly?
My name isn't Polly.
You must have made a mistake.
I've never seen them before in my life.