Somebody help me, please.
I'm suffocatingI
QuicklyI Somebody help me, pleaseI
Help meI PleaseI
Yeah, but what about me brother?
I'm afraid I've got something
more serious to look into first, Miss.
If this young man's telling the truth,
a colleague of mine's been murdered.
- Doctor, this man wants to talk to you.
- Oh, Who is he?
There you are, sir.
"Detective Inspector Crossland. Scotland Yard. "
- I told him everything.
- Have you ever seen that man?
He was in the Chameleon Tours hangar.
The Doctor's body. Where is it?
He... escaped.
His intelligence is far above normal beings.
Above YOURS, perhaps
I must leave. The flight to Zurich
is ready to take off.
You will remain here.
- For what purpose?
- To atone for your incompetence.
The Doctor must die, and you must do it.
All right then, Doctor, we'll go and see the commandant.
I want him to hear your story.
Well, he wasn't very impressed with it the last time.
This time, he's gonna believe you.
Well, if you think so.
Jamie, stay here and keep an eye on the kiosk.
We shan't be long.
Don't worry about your brother, Miss.
We'll find him for you.
- A fat lot of good that inspector's going to be!
- But he believes us.
Oh, year, but that doesn't mean to say he's going to do anything.
I think I'll go and have a look round that Chameleon hangar.
- Not by yourself.
- Well, I suppose it would be better if I had a man with me.
Aye. If only the Doctor hadn't told me
to watch this place.
- Oh, do you always do everything you're told?
- No, but the Doctor trusts me.
Yeah, that's your trouble, isn't it!
All right, stay here.
After all, they can only murder me. Ta-ra.
No, wait a minute.
I don't suppose anything will happen here, do you?
- Since they closed the kiosk, so it's hardly likely.
- And we won't be long, will we?
Well, that depends on what we find. Come on, kid.
In any case, you need me
to show you the way there!
All right, all right.
I'll accept that you found a body,
but I still want to know where you come from
and why you have no passport.
- Surely that's unimportant?
- It is not unimportant to break the law!
Sir, I think we'll have to let him tell us in his own way.
Very well. Make it brief.
Thank you. I have just carried out a search
of the Chameleon Tours hangar.
In a packing case, I found the body of a man.
You never told me that, Doctor.
Another dead man?
No, he was in a stupefied state, a sort of coma.
- Who's this one?
- I don't know his name.
But I have a feeling he's one of your employees.
- Oh, indeed?
- In fact, I think he may be in here.
Taxi, following southern taxi way
for departure runway 27...
- Do you know what this is?
- It looks like a fountain pen to me.
Things are not always what they seem.
Careful! It's dangerous.
- Chameleon Tours aren't what they seem either.
- What's your theory?
I'm afraid you won't believe it
when you hear it....
First, Inspector Gascoigne
was murdered with a ray gun.
- A ray gun?
- A weapon that has not yet been developed on this Earth.
- Oh, really!
- You see, I knew you wouldn't believe it.
No, now be patient, sir.
We are trying to understand you.
Very well. Next, I believe Chameleon Tours
to be merely a front - a cover.
For what?
For the mass kidnapping of young people.
And is all this supposed
to be taking place in my airport?
- Yes. At this very moment.
- That's quite enough!
Can't you take that fellow into custody?
Well, I'm very sorry, sir, but you know he hasn't broken any law.
except for this immigration business,
and that's not my responsibility.
- Brian Briggs IS your responsibility!
- Who is he?
He's a young man who went on the Chameleon tour and vanished.
Come on Doctor, wait a minute.
We're not certain of that yet.
Well, he's nowhere to be found,
and neither are my two friends,
which proves my point - Chameleon Tours
are a cover for the abducting of young people.
And just where do you think they're taking them?
Well, in view of the facts that I've already presented
the ray gun, this pen,
and one or two other things -
I think we're dealing with people who are not from this planet
That hardly answers my que...
What did you say?!
- You see, I knew you wouldn't believe me.
- This is absolute arrant nonsense!
Look, Doctor, I think you ought to
produce some evidence to support all this.
- Evidence? What about this pen?
- A pen! Do you call that evidence?
I'll demonstrate it for you.
Excuse me.
- Would you mind helping us?
- I don't understand.
Could you hold this cup out in front of you?
Very well.
- Perhaps you've seen one of these before?
- No. Agh!
It's turned to ice!
Do you call that arrant nonsense?
"Dear Mum and Dad.
Have arrived safely in the Black Forest."
"Will write again soon. Love, Tim. "
"Dear Dad, I... "
"Dear Mum... "
Jamie!
Jamie! Look what I've found.
There must be 50 postcards here.
That should make that inspector do something.
You're right, and I know where to find him.
You're a brave wee lassie.
No time to greet now.
Get off! I've got something in me eye. Come on.
Where are we going?
The commandant's office.
Doctor, here are the remaining flight schedules
for Chameleon Tours you wanted.
- What a nasty little device.
- I'd better get that checked over, sir.
- What the devil...
- Samantha, down here.
- Postcards! Look.
- I will not have my control room invaded!
- Not even for these?
- What have you got there?
I think it's the further evidence
you required, Inspector.
Yes... Just as I thought.
- Where did you get these?
- In the office in that hangar.
- You see what they mean?
- All falling into a pattern.
This envelope is addressed to somewhere in Germany.
Yeah. "Dem Chameleon Reisen, Freiberg. "
That means Chameleon Tours.
Just what are you all talking about?
You see, they give out these cards,
and get the kids to write home to their parents
before they go.
The Chameleon Tours lot take the cards abroad
and THEY post them back to Britain.
So the parents think the children
have arrived safely.
Doctor, what do you think happens to them?
Now, now. This is all mere supposition!
Oh, to you, maybe, but one of those kids
happens to be my brother.
- Your brother?
- Aye, sir. This is the young lady whose brother's missing
and you see, she did get a card from him in Rome.
But why would anyone want
to abduct these young people?
Well, if we knew that,
we wouldn't be sitting here.
Inspector, can I have a word with you?
You don't think this fellow's
a little unbalanced, do you?
Oh maybe a wee bit unorthodox, sir.
But after all, he's given us the only lead we've got so far.
If you could just see your way to giving him a free hand.
- A free hand?
- Just to poke around a little bit, sir.
Do you think it's safe
to let the fellow roam around the airport?
You can rely on us to keep an eye on him, sir.
All right, but on your head be it.
I personally will investigate Chameleon Tours
then I'll report back to you if I've found out anything.
In the meantime, if you could keep everything
going as normal, you understand?
- We don't want them to get wind of anything.
- No, no, no, no, no.
Doctor, I'm giving you the freedom
of the airport for 12 hours, heaven help me.
At the end of that time,
I shall expect you back here with some real facts this time.
Thank you, Commandant.
- Did they believe the Doctor?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean?
- I think he suspects me.
He turned one of our own weapons on me.
Forced me to leave.
You fool. You should have stayed.
Now, we do not know
how much he has discovered.
Even if he has discovered the secret
of our mission, they won't believe him.
These Earth minds cannot stretch that far.
Of course, the truth is beyond their intelligence,
except for that Doctor.
I know where he is. I could kill him.
You're going to, but not at the risk of your own safety.
We still need you in Air Traffic Control.
Take this. Attach it to him.
When you're ready,
I shall activate the mechanism with this.
- That should put paid to him once and for all.
- Very well.
Don't delay.
I want him dead before Captain Blade returns.
Doctor...
-  I've made out a pass for you and your two friends.
- Thank you.
Excuse me, sir.
There's a Chameleon flight coming in now.
Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima
calling Gatwick Airport Control.
Gatwick Control
to Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
I will now give you your heading.
- How many flights do they use a day?
- Seven or eight.
- How many planes do they use?
- Four.
I could get their registration numbers
if you like. Why do you ask?
Eight flights a day and only four planes.
Is that normal?
Yes. They have a very quick turnaround.
I mean, after all they're only on short haul flights
You know, all the holiday centres.
Spain, Rome, Athens, the Black Forest.
- Jean, where's the file on winter schedules.
- Excuse me.
- Which is the Chameleon plane?
- Oh that one, sir.
Look, he's turning left at Dunsfold.
I shall hold him now over Epsom
until I can give him landing clearance.
- What's the range of your radar?
- 130 miles. Why?
- I wondered when this plane first appeared.
- I've no idea, sir.
We don't notice them until they start to call in.
Now excuse me a moment.
Gatwick Control
to Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
Climb to 10,000 feet and hold in
Epsom control zone to await landing clearance.
Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
Climbing to 10,000 feet and holding.
- How long do you hold them after take-off?
Once they've left Gatwick Control Zone,
we've finished with them.
I see. That means they might be anywhere.
Aren't you wasting your 12 hours
hanging around here, disturbing my people?
I don't think I've been wasting a minute,
but I'll go if you insist. Sam! Jamie!
- Sorry.
- It's all right. It's quite my fault.
- Haven't I met you somewhere before?
- I don't think so.
You must have a double!
- Excuse me, are you the manager?
- I'm looking after bookings. Can I help?
- I'd rather like to speak to the manager...
- Er...
- I'm a police officer.
- Is there some trouble?
- I'd prefer to speak to the person in charge.
- That's Captain Blade.
He's just returned from one flight, taking off for another.
- He's rather busy at the moment.
- Perhaps I could go out to the plane?
I'll have to see about that.
Just a moment, please.
A detective wants to see you.
Does he suspect anything?
I don't know.
All right. Send him over to the plane.
We'll deal with him.
Are you sure this is the right room, Doctor?
- Jamie, have you ever known me to be mistaken?
- Aye!
- Hey. Now watch out.
- What?
That's the wall the gas nozzles came out of.
There's nothing here now.
You're right.
That's clever, very clever.
Oh, well, it makes life simpler for us.
Now, the man I froze came from here somewhere.
- Aye, he would - a solid wall
- Somewhere in that solid wall, there's a door.
Aye, and we still haven't found Ben and Polly.
- What do you think's happened to them?
-  I don't know.
Perhaps if we find that door, we'll find them.
Come on. You take that end, I'll take this.
We must hurry.
Inspector's Crossland's keeping them busy at the moment,
but he'll be no match for them
if he presses them too far.
You'll find that the whole plane conforms strictly
to the international standards of air safety.
I can't think why anybody
would complain about us.
Did I say anyone had complained?
I'm not enquiring about safety.
My enquiries are about a missing boy.
A passenger on one of your flights.
And there's also the business of a colleague of mine,
Detective Inspector Gascoigne,
was last seen in your hangar.
He's believed to have been murdered.
That is indeed a serious matter.
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you to hold up this flight
a while, while I ask you some questions.
Would you mind coming to the commandant's office?
If you'll just excuse me for a moment, Inspector,
I have some arrangements to make.
- Excuse me, please.
- I'm sorry.
Captain Blade!
I shouldn't move any further if I were you.
This gun proved remarkably effective
in dealing with your colleague, Inspector Gascoigne.
- You killed him.
- Unfortunately, an error.
You Earth men are more use to us alive.
Sit down there.
That's better.
This Earth man is a particularly
fine specimen, don't you think?
- Perhaps the director himself.
- Exactly.
Whatever you two are planning for me,
I must warn you of the long arm of the British law.
I don't think it will reach where you're going.
Chameleon Flight 4-1-3 to Control.
Request start-up.
Jamie, look!
What's that, Doctor?
For someone who's not used
to the Earth's atmosphere.
Very interesting.
Ah! A TV monitor set. Let's see what we can see.
What's that?
It looks like a hospital.
Jamie, we're getting warmer - which is a change
from the last time I was here!
Come on. Let's see if there's
a first aid post in Gatwick airport.
- Shall we clear up the mess, Doctor?
- No.
Let's get along to the first aid post.
Oh, my back!
Jamie, my back!
Please take a barley sugar. Thank you.
You can unfasten your seat belts now. Thank you.
A barley sugar? Everything all right?
- All set.
- Good.
You wanted to know
what was the secret of Chameleon Tours.
Well, Inspector...
See for yourself.