Keep back, Victoria! I can't stop it.
Jamie, the roof!
- What are you doing?
- We have to stop it somehow!
- You'll bury us alive!
- It's our only chance. Get back!
Are you all right?
That horrible thing! What was it?
I don't know. Did you see what it did to my sword?
Broke it like a piece of wood!
No human's as strong as that.
What is this place?
And what are those?
Some sort of metal.
They're all glowing.
- Oh, let's get away from here, Jamie!
- Aye, if we can.
I don't think the tunnel's completely blocked. Come on.
Don't worry about that. It's quite dead.
- What's the matter?
- Look!
Come on!
- Come.
- About time, too!
- Come to release me, have you?
- No, sir.
Oh, well. First things first... what's your name?
- Thonmi. You must come with me.
- I see, Thonmi.
- After we've had a little chat.
- Khrisong will be waiting!
No, no. Just wait.
Nobody seems to want to listen to me,
and everyone is jumping to the wrong conclusions.
You seem to be a reasonable sort of chap.
What's going on here?
We are besieged. The Yeti have turned upon us.
- At least, that is what we thought until...
- Until I turned up. I see...
Every time I visit Detsen,
the monastery is in some sort of trouble.
You were here before?
That attack in 1630, what was the outcome?
You know something of our history.
- A little.
- That was also a dark period.
It was then our holy Ghanta was taken from us.
Oh, dear. Never mind.
I'm sure it'll turn up again.
- Legend tells us so, but...
- This chap Travers...
This chap Travers, what of him?
There is no time to talk.
Khrisong will be angry.
Yes, he may be angry,
but he's not the Abbot, is he?
- No.
- I don't think the Abbot will be angry...
... when he sees what I've brought with me.
What do you mean? Show me.
I want you to help me to get this to the Abbot.
Why this delay?
Seize him. Take him to the gate.
Abbot! The straw!
Follow me.
Victoria, the Tardis is that way!
I know, but we must warn the Doctor!
We don't even know where he is. Run!
Khrisong.
- Khrisong.
- Do not interfere, Rinchen.
Did we not decide to consult the Abbot Songsten?
We?
You mean YOU had decided.
- The time for talk is past.
- But Khrisong, the Abbot must...
Must I always consult the Abbot
before I take any decisive action?
Travers, don't you think
this has gone far enough?
- There's nothing I can do.
- What do you hope to gain?
- Time.
- Time?
You've killed my companion, left me single handed
but don't worry, you won't get another chance to get in my way.
I shall find the Yeti, with or without help.
- You can't possibly leave...
- Can't I?
You'll be quite  safe here,
and I know where you are. I'm going.
Don't worry. The monks won't harm you.
- They're men of peace.
- Men of peace?
You are asking us...
You are asking us to agree to murder.
No. Our hands will be clean.
After deliberately using him as bait?
You cannot be so ruthless.
Sapan, I believe that this man is, for some reason...
...trying to turn the Yeti into savage creatures.
- But what proof is there?
- You've heard the word of Travers.
He is an Englishman. A stranger.
He's a killer.
Let me tie him to the gate.
If the Yeti come to rescue him,
we will know the truth...
.. and my warriors will be waiting.
- But if he is innocent?
- My warriors will protect him.
Khrisong, there may be wisdom in what you say.
- All we ask is that you wait until...
- No!
I have done with waiting.
Bring him to the gate!
Master Abbot.
Abbot Songsten.
- Forgive me, Abbot.
- Thonmi!
- I am sorry, but...
- You know well that only I may enter here.
What is this?
Where did you get this?
Is it not the Ghanta that was lost?
It is, my son.
200 years or more, it has been lost to us.
How came you by it?
It is the master. Padmasambhava.
Do not be afraid.
Answer him.
A stranger brought it, master.
The DoctorI
So, he has returned
Bring the Ghanta to me, my son.
Both of you.
Do not be afraid, Thonmi.
Ralpachan, watch from the window there.
You, the other window.
Any attempt to rescue you
will now be highly dangerous for you.
Look, nobody IS going to rescue me,
least of all an Abominable Snowman!
Hasn't it occurred to you, that innocent or guilty
that whatever's been killing your monks might very well kill me?
If you are innocent, then let us hope
that we will have the time to rescue you.
- I think we've shaken it off.
- Have we? Oh, good.
Come on. It can't be much further.
- Listen!
- What is it?
Something's coming. Come on!
Hey,  who the devil are you? What are you doing here?
We're on the way to the monastery.
Are you indeed?
You're a strange pair to find roaming around these mountains.
- You aren't anything to do with that newspaper fellow, I suppose?
- What do you mean?
He says he's a doctor. but I know what he's really after.
- Have you seen him?
- Yes, I've seen him.
Is he all right?
Yes, he's quite all right.
So, you're going to the monastery, are you? Good.
I think you'll find those lamas have quite a welcome waiting for you.
The Doctor said there would be.
- Did he, now?
- I wouldn't go that way if I were you.
- Wouldn't you?
- There's something up there.
A great hairy beastie.
- Where?
- In a cave.
- A cave? Have you found their cave?
- Aye.
- Will you show me where it is?
- Oh, no
No, we couldn't go back there, not with Victoria.
Now look here, young fellow, stop playing games with me.
I know that
you and that Doctor fellow are after the Yeti.
Yeti? What's he talking about?
You mean you're not part of some press expedition?
- Expedition?
- We're not part of anything.
- We're just visiting the monastery.
- But the cave...
If you want to tangle with that beastie,
I'll show you the cave.
- You will?
- After you've shown us how to get to the monastery.
I've nothing to lose, I suppose.
All right. Come with me.
Tell me, my son.
Is the Doctor alone?
Yes, master.
We are grateful
for the return of the holy Ghanta.
The Doctor is our friend.
He must be treated with respect and kindness.
Thonmi...
You will go to Khrisong.
Tell him the Abbot orders the release of the Doctor.
Go now.
Remember, these words were spoken by the Abbot here.
You will forget that you have entered this room,
or that you have spoken to me.
Therefore, Songsten,
we must make certain that Doctor
learns nothing of what is happening.
He is a man of great knowledge
and intelligence,
but he may not show sympathy
for the powers that guide us.
He may even seek to hinder the Great Plan.
It might be wise
if he departs as soon as possible.
Khidom, In the rocks! Did you see something?
Something is coming, Khrisong! The Yeti!
Oh, no!
Be ready to kill them!
Jamie! Victoria! Keep back!
Keep back! They'll kill you!
Keep away! Get away!
You see? I was right.
Khrisong! It was all a mistake.
Doctor!
I've talked to these youngsters.
I'm sorry. This is not the man that attacked me.
- Seize them.
- What's going on?
I told you to keep away. He's led you into a trap!
- No, Doctor...
- Silence!
Who are these people?
- They're friends of his.
- Then they shall act as hostages also.
- Where have you been?
- With the Abbot. We must release him.
This stranger has brought back to us
the holy Ghanta that was lost.
We must treat him with respect and kindness.
These are the words of our Abbot.
- Is this true?
- Of course.
Then why did you not tell me?
You'd already accused me of murder.
You were hardly in the right frame of mind to listen...
...to my story of how I came by the bell, now where you?
Oh, please.
This wasn't the welcome I expected, you know!
As for you, Travers...
It is well to remember
that nothing must disturb our preparations.
There is little time left now.
How, if the Doctor will not go...
His life could be in great danger.
He has been a good friend in the past.
It would be ill if the life
of such a one became imperilled.
- You found this in the cave?
- Aye.
- There were lots of them.
- What do you think it is?
I've no idea. This creature, what was it like?
It was huge, and all covered with hair.
Like a sort of bear.
- It attacked us.
- It sounds like your Abominable Snowman.
- They wouldn't attack anyone.
- No, I always thought so.
They're shy, elusive creatures.
Why do you think it's taken me
so long to track them down?
What made this? I wonder what it's for.
Oh, well... I'd like to see one of these creatures.
It was horrible.
It was buried under tons of rock,
yet it still got up and came after us.
- Like a nightmare.
- Fear makes us imagine all sorts of things.
Including creatures that don't seem to be flesh and blood.
- Khrisong! Khrisong
- What? What's the matter?
- Come quickly!
- What is it?
- He must have seen something.
- Look!
There they are at last! Yeti! After all these years!
Ralpachan,stand watch at the wall.
Pletu, I want two men either side of here.
Thonmi, come with me.
Look, they're magnificent!
Just as I thought they'd be.
Do you really think they'll attack?
I don't know. They have never been this close before.
They won't attack anyone.
They're timid. You'll see.
Yes, but if they do, do you think could you capture one?
I would like to examine one.
- Examine it? Aye, we'll wrap it up for you
- Thank you, Jamie.
Thonmi, come. We must see to the defences.
Boy, open the gates.
If you want to capture one of these beasties,
I have an idea that might just work.
Victoria, this is one of those instances
where discretion is the better part of valour.
Jamie has an idea. Come along.
Have no fear.
Now that the holy Ghanta
has been returned to us, all will be well.
What if the Yeti do attack?
Have faith, Rinchen.
Khrisong and his warriors will protect us.
Khrisong is a rash man.
He was so sure that this Doctor
was a threat to us.
I can assure you I am not.
I hope this is going to work.
Are you ready up there? Catch!
- There is one coming!
- Aye, one's enough.
The others don't seem to be moving.
Keep it back. I'm not ready for it yet.
That's it. Stand by. Here it comes.
Now!
Right, haul on the rope, quick. Quick with the net!
Pull hard that way!
Wait.
- It's dead.
- Aye.
Why aren't the others attacking?
They're going!
Good! Let's get this one inside.
You were right about one thing, Victoria.
This creature certainly doesn't seem to be flesh and blood.
It's not your Abominable Snowman either, Travers.
- It's metal.
- That's incredible!
- What is it?
- A devil's warrior.
No, I don't think so. It's more like a robot.
A robot? Don't let your imagination
run away with you!
Why has it stopped?
Wait a minute... Wait a minute!
- Nothing there.
- No.
But there has been!