Sincro: wyxchari
Come in, my child. You have no alternative.
Do not be afraid.
Are... are you?
I am Padmasambhava.
I'm sorry to intrude. I know this room
is meant to be private, but...
You need my help. Is that not so?
Oh yes. Please, the Doctor...
One moment child.
- But...   - Shh.
What is it?
The courtyard is empty.
Courtyard?
I must do what I am compelled to do.
What's that?
Come closer.
Look. See.
It's one of those
horrible creatures.
- A Yeti.  - Indeed.
But you have not seen it.
She must have had some reason,
I mean why would she run off like that?
Her motives were not clear to me, Mr Jamie.
Oh headstrong, that's what she is.
No... no... no!
All right, Travers, you're quite safe.
- Doctor?   - Yes.
What happened? Oh, my head.
Just relax, you're safe, in the monastery.
Monastery?
What happened? Where did you go to?
Was it the Yeti?
No, no, not the Yeti. It was a...
Something else, it was a light.
A blinding... white light and a noise...
A piercing noise that went through my head...
I couldn't stand it...
Then I... I can't remember anymore.
You spoke of a pyramid.
Pyramid?
Yes, at the gates when you returned.
Pyramid? No, no.
I left the monastery, then um... then...
It's no use, my mind's a complete blank.
You just rest.
- Ah!   - What is it?
No !
We are taught that it is better
to share a memory of fear.
Evil. A feeling of evil.
- Like um... shadow on my mind.   - Yes.
I felt as though I was going to drown.
But where did this happen?
I... I don't know, I can't remember.
Oh, I'm tired, so tired.
You just rest, you'll feel better.
Poor fellow he's completely exhausted.
- What does he mean a shadow...?
- Wait. We'll just let him sleep.
What could it be, this evil of which he speaks?
What was that?
The Yeti! The Yeti!
Khrisong, what's happening?
The yeti have broken in! You are safe here.
But Victoria, where is she?
Who can tell? But she will be found.
She must be stopped.
Doctor, is there nothing we can do?
- Khrisong
- Forgive me, Songsten,
I have failed to defend the monastery.
Failed? No. This disaster was written.
Man cannot alter his destiny.
I should have obeyed you, my Abbot.
My desire to fight these creatures was foolish,
but I will defend you with my life.
Abbot, I fear for Rinchen's safety.
- Is he not here?  - No.
He would not seek safety.
He is so sure that the girl is responsible.
- He is still searching for her?  - Yes.
- Find her!
- If it is not too late.
The Yeti! They are turning back.
Then you are safe for the moment.
Ralpachan, come with me.
Stop! Stop!
She-devil, wherever you are, call off these monsters.
Spare us!
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Aaahhh!
He's dead.
The monastery of Detsen is accursed.
Now it is complete. Now the monks will leave.
By nightfall the monastery will be emptied,
the mountain yours.
Will this then be your final command?
Will you then be content?
I do not understand,
but I will continue to serve.
And now we must consider the problem
of you and your friends.
The Doctor is not easily frightened,
like my poor monks.
Therefore my child you will assist me.
Together we will make sure that he leaves.
Come closer.
This is what you will do.
This is the courtyard and
we are here, to the south.
- I see Thomni, so here lies north.
- That is so.
What are those readings again, Jamie
- Jamie, the readings?  - What? What?
- The readings?
- I'm sorry, I was thinking of Victoria.
Yes I know, but there is
nothing we can do about her.
- Two ninety-seven, Doctor.
- Two ninety-seven.
Now that will give us a bearing roughly there.
Does your science help us, Doctor?
No! We want another bearing, say, from there.
And where those two cross,
that'll be where the transmissions are coming from.
- But that won't tell us why.   - Why?
Yes, what is the purpose behind all this.
That's what we have to find out, eh Jamie?
- Doctor?   - Are you feeling better?
Better? What are we doing in here? What's happened?
You had a spot of trouble on the mountain.
- Trouble?
- Aye, with the Yeti no doubt.
Funny, I don't remember.
Sorry, I'm a bit confused.
Well you sounded it, with
all that talk about...
Yes, I'm... I'm sure it'll
all come back to you in time.
Yes, with the headache I've got, no wonder I ...
... can't remember anything.
I think I'll get a bit of fresh air.
Why is this door locked?
Do not blame yourself, Khrisong, death is inevitable.
Sambhutar, Ghentan, take up our brother.
We will take him with us on our journey.
There will be a time to mourn our brother.
Put to the test I ran and hid like a mountain rabbit.
I'm not fit to be called a warrior.
We must lead out our brothers
before more of them are destroyed.
Gather what is needed, my brothers.
Soon it will
be the hour for meditation, then we must depart.
What of the strangers, master Abbott?
They will be taken with us to a place of safety.
But the girl is lost.
Khrisong and his warriors will find her.
And the Master? What of Padmasambhava?
His powers are great, he will remain.
The holy ghanta.
- Child, how came you...?  - Shh!
She has entered the Sanctum.
- Then let me...  - Silence.
See, she is about to speak.
- This is a time of much danger.
- Padmasambhava
I have chosen to speak to you myself
through the lips of this maiden.
She bears the holy ghanta.
Bear it away to safe keeping.
Treat this child with kindness.
She and the strangers are innocent
of any malice towards you.
Their wish is but to help you against the Yeti.
But in my wisdom I tell you there is no help.
Detsen must be abandoned.
When the wind destroys the nest,
so the bird will build another.
- But what of you Master.  - Go.
With my blessing.
- But Master.  - Do not question.
I will remain here to the end.
Will a day come for our return to Detsen?
Take her to rest.
Ralpachan, release the strangers.
Bid them make ready.
It is time for prayer. The last time at Detsen.
Come, my brothers.
You are released.
I should jolly well think so!
What the devil do you think you're up to!
You must prepare to leave with us.
I shall have a short few words to say
to the Abbot before I go anywhere.
Never mind about that! Have you found Victoria yet?
- She is safe. Khrisong is with her.
- Ah good.
Are you recovered? Child?
There you are, I've been worried sick.
Where have you been?
Victoria? What have you done to her?
Doctor! Doctor, I think she's ill!
Let me see.
- Doctor!   - Yes, Victoria.
There is great danger. You must take me away!
Take me away! Take me away!
Yes, yes of course.
Victoria, what's happened? Tell us?
What's the matter with her?
Victoria, it's me, Jamie.
- How long has she been like this?
- Doctor!
- Yes, Victoria.
- There is great danger.
You must take me away!
Take me away! Take me away!
The child is still in a state of trance.
Still! What do you mean?
She spoke to us with the voice of the Master.
Then she did reach the holy sanctum.
What are you talking about?
She was certain that Padmasambhava
would recognise the Doctor.
- Recognise the Doctor?
- Yes he has been here before.
But that was three hundred years ago.
It's the same man!
Khrisong, the Abbot Songsten wishes us
to join our brothers in prayer.
Very well. You will prepare
to leave. Get Mr Travers ready.
He is in the courtyard.
Come, Thomni, to prayer.
Khrisong, will you forgive me?
We have both of us strayed
from the path of obedience.
Jamie, there is something I have to do.
Right. Hey why are we whispering?
It's my voice. She reacts to my voice.
Oh it's that hypnotism thing.
Can you not do anything about it?
Yes I can, but I need more information now.
- You wait here.
- Where are you going?
I'm going to see a very old friend.
Oh Intelligence. You promised to release me,
yet still I feel your grasp upon this frail body. Why?
What is happening? This was not your plan.
But if you continue to expand.
I have brought the world to its end.
Come in, Doctor.
Good to look upon your face again? So many years...
Padmasambhava, so it's true.
I have been kept alive so many years,
but now our time left is very very short.
Listen carefully, perhaps you can...
Kept alive? I don't understand.
- I didn't know, I didn't realise...
- What?
Try to tell me.
Intelligence... formless in space...
I astral travelled...
I see, you've made mental contact with this intelligence.
It used my mind... it controls my body...
- But why?  - Experiment...
Wished material form.
Ah yes, it said... I believed... experiment...
but now... help... you must help me.
Yes, of course I will help you. But...
But first you must tell me things.
Why are the monks been driven away?
What is the purpose of these robots, the Yeti?
Where is their control?
Padmasambhava? Padmasambhava?
I wish there was something I could do.
- What on earth was that?
- Oh, it was just an idea.
Doctor! There is great danger.
You must take me away!
Take me away! Take me away!
You've got to do something.
Did you find out what you wanted to know?
Not about Victoria, no.
But I found some very interesting clues
- ... as to what's been happening.
- Oh, never mind about that!
It's Victoria you ought to be worrying about.
Yes. Yes, you're quite right.
Victoria must come first.
Trouble is I really need more information.
However, I'll just have to take a chance.
It may just be simple post hypnotic suggestion.
- On the other hand...   - Yes?
It may be something worse.
What if it is?
Well let's just hope it isn't.
- Victoria.
- Doctor! There is great danger.
- You must take me away! ...  - Yes, Victoria.
Listen to me.  You've been taken away.
You're no longer in the monastery.
You're safe in the TARDIS.
Now do you understand. You're safe... in the TARDIS.
Yes. Look at me. Look at my eyes.
You're feeling tired, very sleepy.
Drift away, let yourself drift away into sleep.
Deeper... deeper... sleep...
sleep... sleep... sleep.
- Oh, not you Jamie!   - Aye, what?
So far so good.
Hey. I never knew you could do
that sort of thing.
No, neither did the person who hypnotised Victoria.
What now?
Well, I'm tempted to ask her what happened,
but I don't think I dare probe too deeply.
The important thing is to get rid of this implanted fear.
- It's growing every minute.
- What if you can't?
We shall just have to do as she asks and take her away.
- If we don't...  - Yes?
- She'll go out of her mind.   - What?
Well, that's the object of the exercise,
to get us away from the monastery.
But I'm not beaten that easily.
- Hey, you're taking an awful risk!
- I know what I'm doing, Jamie.
Victoria. Now, Victoria, you can hear my voice, can't you?
- Yes.  - Oh, good.
Now I'm going to take you a little way back in the past, Victoria.
You are in the cell with Thomni.
- Do you understand?  - Yes.
Good. Now you're going to forget everything after that.
You went to sleep. Is that clear?
- Umm.  - Good.
Jamie and I have come back to the monastery
and you are in the meeting room with us.
You're feeling happy, but a little tired.
Do you understand?
- Yes.  - Good.
Now when I count three, you're going to wake up.
One... two... three.
Oh, ooh. Ooh dear, I must have dropped off.
Yes, I believe you did. I've got work to do.
What are you grinning at?
Travers!
- Travers!  - Yes, Doctor.
- How are you feeling?
- Oh, much better thanks.
Look, I've been taking a look up the mountain.
Those robots are still there.
They're just standing, not moving. I don't like it!
Yes, I think things are coming to a head.
What are they up to? What are they waiting for?
Instructions!
Travers, can you remember any more of
what happened to you on the mountain?
I'm afraid not, my mind's a complete blank.
Are you prepared to risk it again?
- I thought we're supposed to clear out.
- Yes well,
the monks are, but I want to get back up the mountain.
One more bearing and I shall know where the control centre is.
- I see, you want me to help you.
- Yes, if you will.
What about your young friends?
Well they're leaving with the monks,
but I want to get out of here before anyone sees us. Will you help?
- All right, I'm on.
- Oh, good, come on.
What's the matter?
I don't know. I've got a feeling I've done this before.
Now, what do you want me to do?
I want you to stay here and take some readings.
Those Yeti are not transmitting.
I'm going over there to stir things up a bit.
I don't understand that thing, you'd better let me go.
Oh no, it's far too dangerous.
I can't ask you to take that sort of risk.
Rot, I can take care of myself.
Now, wish me luck.
No wait!
That's odd.
You got your readings? Because if you've got the reading...
Yes.
What's up?
- Is there any sign?
- No, every room is empty.
Mr. Travers and the Doctor are nowhere to be found.
It's as you wished. The monastery is deserted.
This is well. I will ask a final blessing
of our Master, Padmasambhava,
then we will depart.
- Padmasambhava.
- Try not to think about it.
- I.. I.. I think...  - Doctor!
Khrisong, I have found the control.
It is too late, Doctor, I can no longer help you.
But you don't understand!
It's here! In the monastery.
What? That's impossible!
But the monastery is empty, we are all here.
Are we? Are we all here?
- The Master!   - Songsten is with him!
Then he is in great danger!
Stay where you are. All of you.
I remember.
Songsten, the Yeti, on the mountain.
- Yes, yes, it's all coming back to me.
- Tell us.
There was ... this cave...