Sincro: wyxchari
Oh no! Thomni! Help, Thomni!
Run, Miss Victoria, run! Fetch Khrisong.
The Yeti! The Yeti! Fetch help! Where's Khrisong?
But where is Thomni? What has happened?
He's in there. He's coming, now hurry!
- Khrisong, the Yeti, it is alive!   - What!
It's true Khrisong! Quick, it's coming, do something!
Get back! Get back!
Ralpachan, help him! Get him! Get up!
We can't stop it! Get a net!
No, we must destroy it!
What's the matter, Doctor?
Oh, I'm just taking a breather, that's all.
You've heard something?
No, no, nothing.
Well come on then!
Listen.
Nothing.
Yes, that's what's worrying me. It's too quite.
We've not seen a sign of the Yeti
since we left those three back there.
Aye, well lets just be grateful and get to the TARDIS.
I don't like it. There's something happening on this mountain.
I can feel it.
Hey, you're giving me the willies. Come on.
Look, Doctor!
Thought we'd been too lucky.
What now?
I don't know. We've got to get to the TARDIS somehow.
Aye, well you can't frighten one of those things away.
No.
I wonder what he's waiting for?
Um.
Well he couldn't have known we were coming.
It's a robot, Jamie. It merely follows instructions.
Who's giving them?
That we shall have to find out, won't we?
Get down, Doctor!
Oh, Great Intelligence, have I served you well?
After so many years, can I feel the grip of your power loosen?
How long before your great experiment begins and I can rest?
So soon? I am not sorry. What of the others?
It will be done. Songsten is making final preparations.
Yes.
Have you thought up some clever plan, Doctor?
Yes, Jamie, I believe I have.
What are you going to do?
Bung a rock at it.
Oh be serious, Doctor!
Jamie, I am.
Hey no, Doctor!
There you are, you see? Just as I thought.
It can't see and it can't feel. Come on.
Don't be daft, Doctor.
Well it's quite all right, Jamie.
It's like those three back there,
it's either switched off or not receiving. Come along.
Are you sure it's quite safe?
Well quite frankly no, Jamie.
But there's only one way of finding out.
Don't, Doctor, you might switch it on.
No I don't think so, Jamie.
Yes, just as I thought. Now then.
Now, Jamie, will you hold this flap open for me please. Thank you.
Hey you're taking an awful risk, Doctor.
Well I'm glad that's over. Catch!
Hey I just thought of something, Doctor.
The man that made these robots is very clever, right?
- Yes.
- And yet we were able to walk right up to it...
... and put it out of action just like that!
- You mean why didn't they build in some sort of protective device?
- Aye.
Well perhaps they didn't think it was necessary.
I mean look at him.
Would you walk up to a creature like that
with just a screwdriver in your hand?
- No I would not.  - No there you are.
I'm really rather pleased with myself.
Aaahh!
Have you not found it yet?
Yes, Jamie. Sorry, I'm just coming.
Hey Doctor! Look!
Ah, splendid! Splendid, it's sending out signal.
That's just what we wanted.
Hey Doctor, you'll have to help me, I'll let go!
Oh no, you mustn't do that. Jamie, no!
It's no use, I'll have to let go.
Whatever happens, you mustn't let go Jamie!
It's no use, Doctor!
No!
Jamie get a rock!
- What?  - A rock!
Put it in the hole in its chest!
You all right, Doctor?
Yes, I'm all right. Just a bit puffed, that's all.
Jamie, these things are programmed to return to their Yetis!
That one that disappeared in the monastery!
- That wasn't taken!  - It moved itself!
It could have got to the Yeti! The one we captured. Come on!
You deliberately disobeyed my orders!
- It was the only sensible thing to do...
- Be silent!
If you had not opened the gate the creature would not have escaped.
Khrisong, you know we couldn't stop it.
You'd have been killed!
Anyway it was my idea to open the gates.
Was it? Was it also your idea to breath life into the Yeti?
What do you mean?
Were you not with the creature when it came to life?
- Yes, but...
- You think that she was...
- Who else could have done this?
- Oh, this is foolish!
- Continue, Rinchen.  - The creature was here, dead.
What reason had you to enter this room?
- I was hiding.  - Hiding? Why?
For what purpose?
Speak!
- She means no harm...  - Be silent!
Your young warrior seems too anxious to protect this stranger.
- What are they plotting, these two?  -  No!
You do not understand!
Where is your authority, Khrisong,
... that your warriors forget their allegiance?
Lock them up!
- Hey Doctor!  - What is it?
It's started again! The signal's started.
No! No that's another sort of signal.
Jamie, I've just picked up another signal!
Oh, Doctor, let's get to the monastery.
You said you do all your tracking from there.
- Jamie, you don't seem to understand.
- Oh don't I though!
While you're fiddling with that thing,
this sphere is calling up all the Yeti in creation.
What a perfect opportunity to trace the main transmitter.
A perfect opportunity to get ourselves killed.
I wish the Doctor would come back.
This... a... Doctor, is he your guardian?
I suppose he is in a way.
He is a good man?
I think so.
Tell me, Miss Victoria, how did he come by our holy bell?
I don't really know. Why?
It disappeared three hundred years ago.
- Oh stolen, you mean?
- No it was given to a stranger,
... for safe keeping during a time of trouble. It was never returned.
A stranger? Of course, the Doctor.
They're one and the same man.
- But three hundred years?
- Oh dear. Well I know this sounds silly...
but the Doctor can travel through time and space.
He has a machine you see and... and well...
I don't really understand it myself.
- It's rather difficult to explain.
- There is no need, I understand perfectly.
- You do?
- Yes. You see, it is said that our Master, Padmasambhava,
... can free himself from his earthly body and travel great distances.
Oh!
This can only be obtained after many years
of strict discipline and self training.
You mean... that you might be able to do that sort of thing?
Perhaps, one day.
Rinchen, where is Songsten?
No one has seen him for many hours.
He will be with Padmasambhava.
Padmasambhava?
- To seek guidance.
- Or is it to escape his responsibilities?
- Khrisong, you should not say such things.
- Why not?
Has anyone seen Padmasambhava?
Ralpachan! Inform me when the Doctor returns!
Khrisong would be wise not to voice such thoughts.
Perhaps, but brave men are impatient. And he is no fool.
Sleep, Ralpachan. You have not seen me.
You have not opened the gate. No one has entered.
When I leave the courtyard you will not know that you have slept.
You have done well, Songsten.
Already the Great Intelligence begins to take on material form.
But it demands more. It must expand.
THAT IS WHY YOU AND OUR BROTHERS MUST DEPART FROM THIS PLACE.
Leave the monastery, Master. I understand.
- And the strangers?
- The strangers, oh yes.
I will tell you how to deal with them... if they return.
- I wish this thing would keep quiet.
- Not much further.
- Well, we were expecting it.
- Now what do we do?
Trapped!  -
Jamie, give me the sphere. Give me the box.
- What now?  - Follow me slowly.
Jamie, when I say run, run.
Run like the wind. Don't worry about me.
- Doctor...  - Now, Jamie, please.
- No heroics, Jamie.   - But surely, Doctor...
Now Jamie! Run! Run!
I know what I'm doing - I hope!
It worked!
It's no use, Miss Victoria.
Even if Padmasambhava would consent to see us, we can't get out.
Can't? We haven't even tried.
Thank you, Ralpachan.
I am sorry about this, Thomni.
Oh, good. I am thirsty.
Urgh! A funny taste.
- Oh, Ralpachan, has the Doctor... oah!
- Miss Victoria, what is it?
No, no, no don't touch it. The drink. No... oah!
Miss Victoria!
I will fetch some water. Stay close to her, Thomni.
Miss Victoria.
Miss Victoria!
I'm sorry, Thomni.
And in his wisdom our Master, Padmasambhava,
has given me his guidance.
We must all leave the monastery.
It is impossible for us to defeat the Yeti.
- But there may be a way. The Doctor...
- No my son, they are invincible.
They will destroy us all.
Therefore in order to avoid further bloodshed it has been decided...
Songsten, I have just been informed that the Doctor has returned.
He brings with him equipment which will help us to defeat these monsters!
- Khrisong, the Master...  - The Master?
My apologies, Abbot. I have felt the strength of these Yeti...
but still I will not meekly turn away. I mean to fight!
Brothers, Khrisong thinks only of our safety, we know,
but in this matter he has been led astray.
He has forgotten his vow of obedience.
- In due time he will realise his...
- Master Abbot,
The girl has escaped. She tricked us by feigning sickness.
- She is a devil women!
- She must be found.
Find her, my brothers!
We had no defence against it,
yet it just walked through the gates.
Doctor, we must act quickly or the Abbot will prevent us.
- Yes, but is Victoria all right?
- I did as you asked, she is locked up.
- Is this your equipment?  - Yes.
Stand aside!
- Travers!  - Thank heavens!
Doctor... up there... the pyramid.
- Well what's he saying?
- Shh! Go on. Go on.
The pyramid... it's a...
Seize them! Seize the strangers!
Khrisong, the girl has escaped. She is a devil woman!
Victoria! Hey what's happened?
- Take these people to...  - No!
These people can help us. Besides this man is ill.
I cannot allow it!
Khrisong, you will obey.
- Take them.  - No, but...
- Where is Victoria?
- Doctor, what did he mean 'a devil woman'?
- What is this about Victoria? Where is she?
- Where are you taking us?
- I cannot allow this!  - You cannot allow?
These are the orders of our Master, you must obey.
But these people can help us!
The Master tells us that there is no help against the Yeti.
- He tells us to leave.  - We will not leave!
Khrisong, do not defy me.
Find the girl. Instruct your warriors.
Go after them Sapan.
Advise me Padmasambhava.
Khrisong turns his warriors away from the path of obedience
I hear, Songsten, and I understand.
Well if they will not be lead,
then they must be driven from the monastery.
This is what you must do.
I understand, Master.
Help them search for the girl. Go quickly!
Come in, my child,
Come in...
...You have no alternative.