Sincro: wyxchari
Aahh!
John?
John, where are you?
Aahh! Aahh!
I don't believe it! Marvellous!
After all this time.
Oh, what's so marvellous about that?
Well don't you see, Jamie, its the Himalayas!
And I do
believe we're in exactly the right... now wait a minute.
The Hima- what?
Shh, Shh.
The Himalayas, Jamie. They're mountains.
Aye I can see that. Hey is it the Earth, Doctor?
I don't fancy another tangle down the Cybermen's tomb.
No, no. Shh, Jamie, Shh! Yes of course it's the Earth.
Yes... yes I think I'm right... yes...
Where are these mountains?
Don't you know where the Himalayas are?
They're in India. Well at least I think so...
Yes, that's it! I knew it! I knew it! It's incredible.
Right! No, no, not India.
This is Tibet. That's where we are, Tibet.
Now, there's no time to be lost.
Come along, Jamie, we must find the ghanta.
The what?
The ghanta, the ghanta. I put it here somewhere.
Come along, Jamie, help me.
Hey what am I supposed to be looking for?
I told you it's...
Good Lord, I haven't seen that for years.
Oh, that's the ghanta then?
No, no, no, no. It's a...
Well... whatever it is... it's nice to see it again.
Oh.
Thank you. Come along, Victoria.
Hey, Doctor, would you look at these.
- You never told me you had these.
- No, Jamie.
Hey I could fix those easily.
Yes I was afraid of that.
Jamie, you're getting as bad as the Doctor.
Come along, help me find the ghanta.
It would help us considerably
if we knew what we were looking for.
- Ghanta!
- But what is it?
Oh, what is it, you don't
know. Oh, it's a bell.
Oh, it's a bell, Jamie.
Oh, a bell. Oh, well now we
know what we're looking for.
Yes, it's a Tibetan bell, actually. A holy relic.
This one is quite small,
it has a dragon on it.
And it has rather an interesting history, it was... Oh!
Ah ha, yes I'll have that.
Ah ha, yes, it's just the thing for this climate.
You might as well find yourselves something while you're about it.
- How do I look?
- Doctor, you look beautiful.
Yes, I thought I might.
I think I'll go and have a scout around.
Now you two find the bell, it's very important.
Oh, but why do you want it?
Because down there it's going to
guarantee us the welcome of a lifetime!
- Down there?
- Oh, don't ask me.
When you've been with the Doctor as long as I have,
you begin to realise you don't know what he's talking about.
We better find this bell of his.
Wait a minute, Jamie.
Hey come and give us a hand.
I want to see where the Doctor's gone.
Now if I turn this to the left... it should... a ha that's it.
Hey, now would you look at this.
Oh, that's marvellous. What...
- Hey, what's that?
- Where?
A great sort of hairy beastie. Turn the thing back.
No, to the right.
- I am!
- Downwards. That's it, there!
Oh no, my mistake.
The great
hairy beastie, it's the Doctor.
Yes, ah, yes.
A monastery!
Aye, that will be where he's gone.
I wonder why he wouldn't take us?
You can never tell with the Doctor.
Hey, just thought. Do they let lasses into monasteries?
I don't know. Oh, don't say that.
Oh never mind, I suppose he'll manage somehow.
Hey, shall we open it?
I don't think so, the Doctor may not like it.
Apart from climbing boots I really think
you ought to wear something warm.
I tell you I'm a Highlander, the cold doesn't affect me.
There's a great deal of difference
between the Highlands and the Himalayas, Jamie.
Aye, they're bigger.
Oh, there you are Doctor. I found
this bell thing you were looking for.
Oh, splendid, splendid.
Is the monastery far? Can we come too?
Mmm, yes. Oh, no.
One thing at a time,
Victoria. We must find this ghanta.
- Oh, here.
- Oh, um.
Is this where we're going, Detsen?
Um. Detsen, yes that's the name of the monastery, but
I'm afraid you're not going.
- Well not yet a while anyway.
- Doctor!
No, I think it would be better if I went alone.
You've seen something haven't you?
Would it not be better if I went with you?
Is there something dangerous then, Doctor?
Oh, good heavens no!
No, there's nothing for you to worry about.
Now you stay here with Jamie, inside,
and I'll be as quick as I can.
Oh ah, Doctor.
Oh, ha ha. I nearly forgot it.
Oh, I'm getting bored. Let's go outside.
No I don't think we should.
- All right I'll go by myself.
- Oh no you won't!
You won't leave me here by myself.
Oh come on, we needn't be long.
Aye, well just a quick look then.
Anybody here?
What can you see?
Come on, it's a marvellous view.
Aye, so it is. Now come away back.
- Why?
- Because the Doctor said that...
Well if you must know, I am cold.
Didn't I tell you. Now why don't you go and get that coat?
Because I'm not leaving you out here on your own, and that's final.
- Jamie, look!
- What is it?
Footprints. Look at the size of them.
Something's been walking around the TARDIS.
What could it be, Jamie, a bear?
Whatever it is, it's pretty big. We better get inside.
I'd like to find out what it is first. Wouldn't you?
Look we must be careful. This could be dangerous.
Wait while I get that sword.
Hello there.
Hello!
Where is everybody?
Oh, ah ha, there you are.
I thought...
I thought for one... moment.
What do you want here?
- I've come to...
- Look he's got my rucksack.
- Oh that. - You murderous devil!
Who is this man?
I don't know, but this is mine all right.
- But you said...
- Be silent.
You said it was a beast that attacked you.
Yes, but it was dark.
I remember all I could see was a vague shape, but I felt it's hair.
Well it's quite obvious now that it's this coat he's wearing.
Why did you attack this man?
Me! I haven't attacked anyone!
- I found the haversack on the mountain.
- He's lying!
- I also found a dead man!
- Yes you killed him!
Enough! Seize him.
- But you can't possibly...
- Silence.
This man accuses you of one crime,
but there have been many others.
If you are responsible, be sure you will be punished.
Take him away.
But this is ridiculous.
Why don't you listen to me?
Where are you taking me?
Watch him carefully, Khrisong, he's dangerous.
This is possible.
We do not know he is the attacker.
Of course he is! I've just said he's so.
Why then did he come here?
That, also, we shall discover.
The welcome of a life time?
Jamie, look!
Aye, that'll be where the beastie lives, right enough.
And it's as far as we're going.
Oh we can't turn back now.
We can and we will, it could be dangerous.
How do you know? It may be quite harmless.
With feet that size?
Well just a quick look inside.
Look, if that animal is dangerous
we could be walking into a trap.
- Oh but Jamie...
- No, we're going back, I mean it.
- Jamie. Look...
- Hey! Wait a minute.
Well what is it?
Look there, just inside the cave.
Where? I can't see anything.
It looks like a beam of wood.
Oh it can't be.
It might not be an animal's den after all.
I'm going to take a closer look.
- Oh but Jamie...
- Look, a wild animal's one thing...
...I'm not afraid of a man!
This is a man's work all right.
Oh let's go back, Jamie.
Jamie!
JAMIE!
Hey, come and a look at this.
Jamie, listen! There's something coming!
Get back.
Its a 100 foot drop outside that window.
There's no way out you know.
I didn't think there would be.
How did you track me down?
Track you down? I don't even know who you are.
Don't play the innocent with me! It won't work.
If it wasn't for my expedition you wouldn't be here.
Hmm. You're one of those wretched newspaper men.
Paper Men? I wish I know what you are talking about?
Oh yes! You laughed at me in the press didn't you.
"Travers - the mad anthropologist".
After that, even my own Society wouldn't finance me.
But I know they're here. Twenty years I've been searching.
Twenty years!
I've staked my reputation and every penny I own on this expedition.
Now, when I'm close to finding them, you want to steal my glory!
Just for the sake of a cheap headline.
Finding them? Finding what?
Don't pretend. They're here.
Somewhere on these mountains.
- What are?!
- You know!
The Yeti! The Abominable Snowmen!
Oh, it's not use, I can't shift it.
Perhaps there is another way out of here.
I'm gonna see what's down there.
Oh no! Don't! There may be more of them.
Aye, there might. That's why I want you to stay here.
Oh no...
Look, you're safe enough for the moment.
If you need me just yell your head off.
Don't worry, I will!
But it could have been the Yeti that attacked you.
Rubbish! The Yeti are timid creatures. They're shy...
- But...
- They're afraid of men.
But... Why me!? Why say I did it?
You want a clear field don't you.
I discovered the Yeti!
The honour's mine, but you want to take it from me.
Why, you even murdered my companion...
... just to get a cheap story for your newspaper.
- That is ridiculous.
- Is it?
Whoever killed your friend had enormous strength.
Yes?
Well, could I have done it? Well, could I?
No. I'm not going to discuss it any further.
There's work to be done. The expedition must go on!
Khrisong will find out the truth!
Travers! Travers, come back!
We have the word of the Englishman, Travers.
But how do we know he is telling the truth.
Why should he lie?
In any case, I am not so concerned with
the death of Travers's companion.
Four of our brothers have been slaughtered.
That is my concern.
Had we not agreed that the Yeti were responsible?
True, Rinchen. But have we not also wondered why?
They were so rarely seen, timid.
Then, suddenly they become savage...
Did we not wonder why?
Did we not wonder what or whom had brought this change?
And now, here is this stranger and Travers accuses him.
He may be a cause.
I ask you again. Let me put it to the truth. Now.
You are asking us to condemn
a man to certain death.
I am Chief Warrior. Is it not my duty to protect you?
But not by taking a man's life.
Yes, if it is necessary.
No! Only the Abbot can decide.
Songtsen alone can approve such measures.
It is time for prayer, my brothers.
Wait! We must decide now!
No, Khrisong. After our meditations
we will consult the Abbot.
This is foolishness! Time will be wasted!
Do they wish more of our brothers to die
before I'm allowed to take action.
- There is no other way.
- There is, for me.
Let them meditate. Let them consult.
I, Khrisong, will act!
Bring me the prisoner.
Jamie! Jamie, it's coming back!
Get back in there!
- Oh, is it safe?
- Aye. Now go on!
Stop!
Jamie, get back! It will kill you!