Sincro: wyxchari
Jamie, when you captured this creature,
you must have dislodged it's control unit.
Then it must still be lying out there.
Precisely!
Where are you going?
To have a look outside the gates.
I want that unit. Come on, Jamie.
- No! I will not allow it.
- But why not?
I trust no one to leave the monastery.
You say this creature is not a real Yeti.
- It's metal. It's been made.
- And sent against us. Why?
Why does someone wish harm to the monks of Detsen.
I will trust no stranger until these questions are answered.
Ah, but we're on your side! Have we not convinced you yet?
I am convinced of nothing.
The Doctor knows all about this sort of thing.
Why not let him help you?
Well if you don't trust us at least send Thomni,
or one of your other warriors.
No! I will not allow the gates to be opened!
- If you want us to help...
- I do not need your help!
Thomni, guard them!
Oh dear, a very obstinate man.
Yes, well that's that I suppose.
Nothing we can do about it now.
Um, well I... I think I'll just go
and get a bit of shut-eye. Good night all.
- Ralpachan.   - Yes, Khrisong.
Stand guard at the gate.
No one is to leave the monastery.
Be watchful, these Yeti are more dangerous than we thought.
- Khrisong.  - What is it? What do you want?
- Um, I want a word with you.   - Well?
Alone.
- Yes?  - Look I've been thinking.
Now that we've found out that...
... that these abominable snowmen are mechanical things...
- Well?  - Don't you see it means that I am right!
The real Yeti are there,
hiding up there somewhere in those mountains.
- This is no concern of mine.
- No, but Khrisong, wait.
I um... I want to go out there, after them.
That would be foolishness!
Look, I've always said that the real Yeti are harmless.
Now I must make a... find out for sure.
Otherwise the whole point of my expedition would be lost.
And those devil creatures would kill you.
Yes well, that's a chance I'll have to take.
- No! I will not allow it.
- But don't you see?
The real Yeti may be killed by these robots.
Look, I must go!
No, I forbid it!
Look I'm not one of your monks, you know?
You can't give me orders.
No. I've said that no one will leave.
Anyone may be controlling these monsters. Even you.
- Oh that's ridiculous...
- I have given my orders! Obey them!
Sir, I have no choice, I must obey Khrisong.
Do you not realise the man's a wee bit daffy?
Oh I wouldn't say that, Jamie.
He's just doing his duty, as he sees it.
But I think he is mistaken not to trust you.
There is much sense in what you say.
- Oh thank you, Thomni.  - Doctor
- Come here a moment.  - What is it?
The place you said where the control unit would go, it's round.
- Yes?   - Well I wonder if...
Jamie, you remember in that cave, we found that sphere.
Well don't you think it could go...
- Hey yes! I believe you're right...
- Yes, but I've thought of that.
But the thing was as light as a feather,
there couldn't have been anything inside it.
Unless...
- Where is it?
- Well I gave it to you. You were looking at it.
I remember, I put it down somewhere.
- The Buddha! The Buddha in the courtyard!
- I put it down by the Buddha!
Oh now please, Thomni, please!
- It's not here, Doctor.
- But I swear I put it down here by the Buddha.
- Aye, well its not here now.
- Somebody must have picked it up.
Oh dear.
Maybe that guard's taken it.
Aye, let's ask him.
No. Tact, Jamie. I'll handle this.
Hello guard, good evening.
Um, I wonder if you could help us.
I um... I left a... a silver sphere by the Buddha there.
Sphere? It's a shiny round thing.
It's most important. Have you taken it?
No, and if anyone had I should have seen them.
Ralpachan, who has passed through the courtyard?
Master Khrisong, but he touched nothing.
- No one else?  - The Englishman, Travers.
Travers? Are you sure he didn't pick it up?
I am sure. He spoke only to Khrisong and now he is gone.
Gone?
He said Khrisong had given him permission to leave.
But that's impossi...
- He has tricked you!
- Aye, he must have taken it!
- Yes, but why?
- Could he be the one that's doing it?
I wonder. Are you sure he didn't take the sphere with him?
- He took nothing!
- I'll find his room and search it.
- Right, Jamie.
- We must tell Khrisong what has happened.
Yes, yes. Travers, I can't believe
he has anything to do with these robots.
One thing's for certain, it couldn't have moved on its own.
How if the devil should breath life into it again?
My ghost trap will ward off the evil spirits.
Mmm, but to fetter it with chains is also wise.
The strangers say that this creature is not flesh and blood.
How can this be, does it not move?
- Strangers, do not believe them, Sapan.  - But see.
It is but armour, such as any warrior would wear.
The devil in his guile wears his armour
beneath the skin to protect his evil heart.
Such a being is against nature, it troubles me. Let us go.
What have you been doing, my brothers?
We have built a spirit trap about the monster, my Abbot.
This is well thought, Sapan, you are wise.
You should never have allowed this monster
to have been brought into the Monastery, Khrisong.
What I allow is my affair, Rinchen.
Gently, my son, gently.
I'm sorry, my Abbot. I try to guard my tongue,
but Rinchen finds much fault in me of late.
Harsh words are like blunted arrows.
It is the truth that makes them sharp.
I have tried to do my duty.
Under your guidance, the protection of the monastery lies in my hands.
I know, my son. You're task is a hard one.
And such is our adversary, that against such creatures that I must protect you.
The purpose of my life is nothing if I fail.
You know, my Abbot, that I willingly would
lay down my life for you and my brothers.
But can I combat this with mildness.
You must let me fight their strength with my strength.
Our ways are the ways of peace, Khrisong my son.
You, must not seek to change them.
I would fight to preserve them.
You must let me. There is no other way.
There is. It is merely obscured to our simple minds.
I shall seek guidance from the Master, Padmasambhava.
- Khrisong! Khrisong, I must speak with you.
- What is it?
- Have you given Travers permission to leave the monastery?
- Of course not!
- Well he's gone!  - How?
The guard at the gate said you'd given him permission.
Did he? Very well. Come with me.
- It's about time you let me help you.  - Help?
I want to make sure you don't disappear as well.
It's the Abbot, is he all right?
- Oh yes, he's in a trance. We must leave him now.
- Trance?
Yes, Master.
Who's he talking to?
The Master, Padmasambhava.
He's asking for spiritual guidance.
How?
I hear you, Master. I am coming.
Where's he going?
To the Holy Sanctum. To Padmasambhava.
- Let's follow him.
- No, no, no, it is forbidden!
No one but the Abbot may enter.
No one!
...And this should not have happened.
I hold you responsible, Ralpachan.
Oh well, what's done is done.
Ah, Jamie.
- Searched his room, but it's not there.  - I see.
Khrisong, you must see that it is vital
that I examine one of these control units.
The one that Jamie bought down from the mountains has disappeared.
Someone is trying to stop us learning the truth.
You must let us outside to find the other one!
Oh, look...
Very well. I will go.
No! No, Victoria, we mustn't.
- I only want to see where he's going.
- I told you,
The Sanctum. No one is allowed to go there.
Please, let us go back.
You mean to say you've lived here
all this time and never been in there.
- Yes.  - You are funny.
- Aren't you the tinniest bit curious?   - No.
And you've never seen this... Master?
Never.
Don't you want to know what he looks like?
- Oh, sure you do. Come on.
- No! Miss Victoria,
Can't you understand that it is impossible?
- I don't see...  - No you do not!
It is forbidden. And I have been brought up on the path of obedience.
Very well.
But I'll get there somehow.
- Hasn't he found it yet?  - No.
- No. Khrisong, can I give you a hand?
- Stay where you are!
Far better if the Yeti had not been brought into the monastery.
I'm sorry, Master, I could not prevent it.
The Doctor is wise. His eyes are not closed in ignorance.
If he is not ignorant perhaps he might assist you with your plan.
But his mind is on a complex plane. It is hard to fathom.
There is a chance he will oppose what we have to do.
NO. WE MUST CONTINUE WITH THE WORK, ALONE.
I MUST NOW MAKE SURE OUR PLAN IS IMPERILLED NO MORE.
I've found it!
- Khrisong! Behind you! Yeti!   - Come in!
- No!   - Don't be a fool!
Don't be a fool, they're on top of you!
Quick get him inside!
They came to get their ball back.
It would seem that the Yeti have caused some little upset at the gates.
However their work is accomplished.
Now, Songsten, observe.
These three Yeti are waiting for you.
Take this pyramid I have prepared. Take it to the caves.
Then the Great Intelligence will focus upon this planet.
Soon it will begin to grow and at last take on physical form.
At last its wanderings in space will be at an end.
My work will then be done.
Go now, Songsten, do as I have asked.
NOTHING MUST INTERFERE.
These creatures are indeed fearsome.
Aye, you were lucky you weren't killed.
But why did they just turn and leave?
They had us at their mercy, why?
They didn't come to fight. They came for the sphere.
Are you sure?
Pretty sure. They didn't want me to examine it.
You talk of these creatures as if they were human, with a human's brain.
That sphere is like a brain. They had to get it back.
Yes, and that Yeti we caught in the net.
Well that could have been after the sphere we found in the cave.
I'd still like to know what happened to that one.
This sound that you heard.
It came from the sphere, I swear it.
- Some sort of signal, do you think?  - Yes, could be.
- Anyway, its a help.   - How can this help?
Well with the right sort of equipment,
these signals can be tracked.
You mean you can find out where the Yeti
are getting there instructions from?
- Yes, Jamie.  - Where can we find such equipment?
We've got to get back to the TARDIS.
This equipment. You have it?
Yes. But it's outside there on the mountain
Then, you must go for it.
You mean you'll let us go?
I have no choice. I have failed.
My warriors are powerless. I must trust you.
Come on, let's get my coat.
Oh. Oh, they're not back yet. I think I'll go and find them.
- No need for you to come.
- I think it would be better if I came with you.
Afraid I may go somewhere that I shouldn't.
Oh, come on then. I don't want to stay in here with that thing.
Thomni, it were well that you went to Khrisong...
- Where is he?  - In the courtyard.
I will go to him. Oh, Sapan, would you care for our guest, please?
Jamie and the Doctor... are they all right?
Rest easily my child.
- They are in...  - They are very well.
There is no need for this child to worry. Is it not so, Rinchen?
You're keeping something from me.
My child, I have told you nothing but truth.
Your friends are busy helping our brothers.
- Sapan, we have duties to perform.  - True.
We must leave you. It might be wiser to join Thomni
in the courtyard. Excuse us please.
You are not well, Khrisong. You should be resting.
There can be no rest for me while this creature is here.
- But it is dead, what harm can it do us now?
- Even so, wiser to destroy it.
Rinchen or the Doctor, who is right. I do not know any longer.
Khrisong you must guard this child.
Sapan sent her to you in the courtyard,
yet I found her near the Sanctum.
I didn't mean any harm.
For her own good, it would be safer
if she were closely guarded.
When I have passed through the gate you will awake.
You have seen nothing.
I suppose everyone thinks I'm a nuisance.
- Is that it?
- We are concerned for your safety, as you well know.
You're not really going to lock me up in this beastly room, are you?
No, I don't think that will be necessary.
But you must promise to behave and not cause trouble.
What do you mean?
I think perhaps you are a little too inquisitive, Miss Victoria.
Me? I just don't like mysteries.
- Your Master, for instance, Padma...
- I have told you there are some things...
- ... that you should not ask!
- Oh all right, I'm sorry. All right.
Look do we have to stay here? Can't I go and find the Doctor?
The Doctor? But he's gone.
- Gone? Gone where?  - To the mountain.
I thought you knew. Did Sapan not tell you?
I knew he was keeping something from me.
- I've a good mind to go after them.
- That would be foolish!
Don't worry, I'm not really serious.
Oh please forgive me, I'm being a very bad host.
- Would you care for some food?  - No thank you.
Um, yes. Perhaps on second thoughts I will.
They're not moving.
They can't have seen us, Doctor.
Perhaps they're switched off. I wonder...
Don't be a fool, Doctor. No point in taking chances.
Let's get to the TARDIS while we can.
Yes, perhaps you're right.
Oh no! Miss Victoria!
Ralpachan, the girl, did she go out?
What did you want, Thomni?
I went for food, now she has disappeared.
- Fool!  - I think she went after the Doctor.
No one has passed Ralpachan.
Then she must still be in the monastery.
Find her.
Where? Where could she...?
Miss Victoria!
It were better that you were not found in here, my child.
Who's that?
The monks will look upon your presence here as sacrilege.
Go quickly.
Victoria!
Miss Victoria, where are you?
Miss Victoria!
My son, what is the matter?
Oh, Sapan, the girl, I can't find her.
- I think she may have...   - Aahhh!
Miss Victoria!
Oh.