Sincro: wyxchari
It was Songsten who took this pyramid into the cave?
That's right.
- And the Yeti never harmed him?   - No.
Songsten. He's the link I've been looking for.
But Khrisong is with Songsten now.
Then he is in danger!
Songsten, danger! You are in great danger!
Come away from this place!
What madness is this?
KHRISONG, WHENCE CAME YOU BY SUCH FOOLISH THOUGHTS?
Don't try and frighten me! Who are you?
I demand to know what is happening!
Demand? You are in the presence of the Master.
Yes, a master who controls the Yeti. What is hidden in there?
Forgive him Master.
Of course, but our brother must not be allowed to depart
in the knowledge that I am other than what I am.
Songsten!
Why do you put him in a trance?
You understand, Songsten?
I understand, Master.
You may enter, Khrisong.
One moment! You may not take weapons into the presence of the Master.
ARE YOU AFRAID?
Waahh!
You have done well, Songsten.
You will now...
Why are you making me do this? Why?
Release me... I beg of you... I am...
SONGSTEN, YOU WILL NOW GO FORTH WITH THE MONKS.
YOU WILL NEVER RETURN.
Yes, Master.
Khrisong, where are you?
- Khrisong!   - What has happened?
We're too late.
What have you done to Khrisong?
What have we done? Well that's a bit cool, I must say.
You have killed him!
- I...?   - SONGSTEN, KILL THEM!
Jamie, grab hold of him! His hands!
Quick, get him out of here!
Doctor!
It's all right, lie still, I'll get help.
Too late, my time has come. Closer.
My brothers... they are not... to blame Songsten...
- He was... in a trance.
- I understand
- Now just try...
- Go!
Leave.. leave me..
My brothers! My brothers, Khrisong is dead.
- Dead?
- By whose hand?
By the hand of our Abbot, Songsten.
- This cannot be.
- Aye, it's true enough.
No. What reason would he have to do such a vile thing?
Obviously he thought Khrisong knew too much.
Songsten, is this true?
Aaah!
- Keep back!
- Do not interfere, stranger!
- No, leave him alone, there's been enough killing...
- Oh, Jamie, no!
Wait! Wait, my brothers, this is no time for rashness.
He is quite right!
He is quite right! You listen to him.
- Well?
- Kill them... kill them...
Look, is this our Abbot who loves peace.
Surely you can see he was made to kill Khrisong.
He is a helpless puppet!
But I saw him on the mountain, he was leading the Yeti!
Yes, but by command, unknowingly.
Thomni is right, Songsten is merely a puppet.
Who has done this to him?
- Is it you?
- No!
I tell you I saw Songsten change. He was put in a trance, by the Master.
Have a care what you say.
Now listen to me, all of you. Your Abbot is not responsible!
But neither is Padmasambhava, he too is controlled.
Now do as you'd planned. Leave the monastery, there is great evil here.
No Doctor, you're wrong. The evil is on the mountains.
It's that hideous thing in the caves.
Wherever it may be, what can we do to overcome such a force?
My brothers, let us obey the Doctor.
- What of you, Doctor?
- I will stay here, Thomni.
Oh, me too.
- Why?
- I have to.
This things that's here, this evil, it will spread.
It has to be stopped and I think I can do it.
Thomni, will you help me? It will be dangerous.
- You can rid us of this evil?
- Yes, I think I can.
And if we succeed the monks will be able to return.
Then of course I will help.
Doctor, you're not going to send me away with the monks, are you?
- Yes, Victoria, I think it best.
- Well, I won't go.
No, I didn't think you would.
Hey Doctor! Songsten, he's unconscious.
- Sapan, tend our Abbot.
- No! Wait.
There are things I have to find out and only Songsten can tell me.
What makes you so sure he's going to do that?
Sit him down here, Jamie. Over there.
The Doctor's got it wrong. I've seen that thing in the cave.
That's what we've got to destroy.
The Doctor thinks the evil is in here...
I know, I've seen it, he hasn't.
He said himself that Padmasambhava was being controlled.
And it's that thing that's doing it. I'm going to get at it.
Are you coming with me?
- Very well!
- Good man, come on.
What do you plan to do?
I don't quite know yet. Get to that cave...
The pyramid's the answer...
I just have to take a shot at it with this. Come on.
And the Yeti?
They were designed to serve the Intelligence.
I see. Now this intelligence, ah, it is confined to the cave?
- No.
- No?
It has broken its promise. Now it demands the whole mountain.
I see. Now, Songsten, I want you to help me.
I want to help you.
Now these Yeti, they are controlled?
Yes, by Padmasambhava.
Yes, but the control units, they were made somehow, somewhere?
The Master laboured for nearly two hundred years.
With the help of the Intelligence he built the creatures and the other wonderful machines.
These small Yeti models, their movements must be mirrored by the real robots?
- True.
- But there must be a controller.
A machine that gives out the orders. Now, where is that control?
The sanctum.
But I have seen the sanctum?
Throne. Behind the throne there lies a hidden room.
How do I get into it?
Songsten, how do I get into it?
A close one. Heading towards the monastery.
Should we not return?
No, now we've come this far. Let's push on. Come on.
Take care of him, Sapan.
I will. He has suffered much.
Is it time to leave?
Now as soon as the monks have left, we must get into that control room.
How do we get past Padma-thingme?
I'll deal with him. But remember, as soon as we're in the sanctum...
...whatever happens, Thomni and you must smash the controls!
What do you mean, whatever happens'?
Padmasambhava will use super-normal powers if necessary.
For a start he will try to hypnotise you again.
Well how can I stop him?
Thomni, you better teach her the 'Jewel of the Lotus Prayer'.
It'll give her something to concentrate on.
Yes, Doctor.
Jamie, where is Travers?
- Travers?
- Well he's not here.
Perhaps he's deserted us.
No, I don't somehow think he's done that, but I'd like to know what he's up to.
Well we're going the right way, there's some sort of path along here.
Look! What is it?
It's that hideous light from the cave. It's spreading all over the mountain.
It's blinding me. How can we reach the pyramid?
We can't. It's too late for that now I'm afraid.
But it will engulf the monastery.
Doctor, why will you not accept the aid of our warrior brothers?
Because they are needed to guard you and the lamas, Sapan.
Besides brave hearts will not suffice for this battle.
Protect them Thomni. We shall pray for you.
Thank you. Don't worry, everything will be all right.
When it's all over you can come back. I hope.
Now don't forget, I will go into the sanctum first
and deal with Padmasambhava.
And, as soon as it's safe, make for the curtain behind the throne.
That's where the control room is!
When we have destroyed the machine what will happen?
I haven't the faintest idea.
What?
Don't worry, Jamie, it's going to be all right.
Hey, we might all be blown to smithereens!
What am I supposed to do?
Well nothing I hope, but one of us just might need help.
Are we ready? Come on.
What shall we do?
Looks as though we're well and truly cooked.
Look! There, below us, torches. The monks must have left.
Yes, but has the Doctor?
How can we tell, we are trapped.
I don't know.
We cannot enter the monastery.
Looks as though... we'll just have to sit tight.
Can we not try and join my brothers?
No! The Doctor may still be in there. I'm sure he is.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WHY DID YOU NOT HEED MY WARNING?
YOU ARE STUBBORN, DOCTOR.
Who are you?
YOU KNOW WELL IT IS I THE MASTER, PADMASAMBHAVA, WHO SPEAKS.
Oh no it isn't. I know Padmasambhava, he's my friend.
Where have you come from? Why are you using his body in this fashion?
SUCH AS A BRAIN AS YOURS IS TOO SMALL TO GRASP MY PURPOSE.
Too small?
I AM MUCH POWER.
Much power? Just a...
Simple levitation, a childish trick.
Now stop playing games and open these doors.
Or are you afraid to meet me face to face?
YOU ARE RASH.
Now anything can happen now, just trust me and above all don't panic.
Aah Oh!
No! No! The Doctor said to wait!
Now!
Come on, Thomni!
Quickly! Into the control room, smash the controls!
To work, Thomni!
Doctor, he's bringing the Yeti in!
Victoria, Victoria, I can't hold him!
The models... knock over the models!
No, Victoria, don't let him!
Jewel of the Lotus'! Om mane padme hum... Om mane padme hum...
Om mane padme hum... Om mane padme hum...
At last! Come on.
Om mane padme hum.
Oh it's no good, I can't move.
You've got to!
I... I can't!
Jamie! Jamie!
Jamie! Yeti's coming!
Yeti?
But we have destroyed the machines.
Well there must be something else that controls them.
The control unit, of course the sphere!
ONE STROKE OF FORTUNE WILL NOT SAVE YOU.
STUPID MAN, DID YOU NOT FEEL ENOUGH OF MY POWER WHEN YOU MET ME IN THE CAVE?
- The cave?
- The cave!
Jamie, there was a pyramid in the cave!
- There's one here too.
- Destroy it!
Noooo!
Look at him.
At last peace... Thank you, Doctor...
Goodbye old friend.
You all right, Doctor?
Yes, Jamie, it worked.
The Intelligence is destroyed.
Yes, well it a... was most decidedly tricky for a minute or two.
Yes, Thomni, you can signal the monks, they can return.
Doctor, are you trying to tell me that
that old man was responsible for all this?
- The Yeti? The cave?
- Oh no, no, no.
He was just a tool in the hands of a monstrous brain.
It wasn't his fault.
It's horrible, let's get away from here.
Aye, come on.
Please Doctor, our Abbot will be most grieved
that he did not thank you personally. Will you not wait?
Ah no, Thomni, we're anxious to get back to the TARD...
We're anxious to get back.
Goodbye, Doctor.
I'll see them safely up the mountain.
Goodbye, Thomni.
Goodbye.
Bye, Thomni.
Aye, well those things won't bother us anymore, Doctor.
Those horrible things.
Ah, they were clever machines.
Almost a pity to have had them destroyed.
Well at least you'll have something to take home from your expedition, Mr Travers.
I suppose so.
But nobody would believe me, they'd think I'd had it made.
No, I'm afraid the expedition's over now.
Oh Doctor, look!
- Oh no!
- It can't be!
A Yeti! A real Yeti! At last!
'scuse the haste. Goodbye and all that. Mustn't lose this one.
Do you think he'll ever find his abominable snowman, Doctor?
Well that we shall never know, Jamie.
What's the matter with you, are you cold or something?
Oh it's all right for you in your home-made Yeti kit.
Yes, I suppose there is a little bit of a nip in the air.
A nip! A nip, just look at my knees, they're bright blue.
A horrible sight.
Could you not land us somewhere warmer next time?
Jamie, you never know, do you?