1
00:00:00,269 --> 00:00:05,269
=====iCelery军团出品=====
未经允许，请勿用于商业用途

2
00:00:05,269 --> 00:00:10,269
翻译：雨&翼
校对: NO MORE
QQ群：110388408

3
00:00:10,447 --> 00:00:16,247
<i>巴蛮子sz 基于iCelery字幕二次修补</i>

3
00:00:31,085 --> 00:00:32,085
Bristol?
Bristol?

4
00:00:36,413 --> 00:00:38,207
Bristol? 你还好吗？
Bristol? Are you alright?

5
00:00:39,689 --> 00:00:41,164
我觉得不可思议!
I feel marvelous!

6
00:00:41,420 --> 00:00:42,906
很好，很好，会没事的. 你很安全
Good, good, it'll pass. You're fit.

7
00:00:43,746 --> 00:00:44,876
你发现什么了？
What did you find out?

8
00:00:45,081 --> 00:00:47,966
很少, 不足以找到Skagra, 但已经吓得我不知所措了
Not much, not enough to locate Skagra, just enough to frighten me out of my wits.

9
00:00:48,189 --> 00:00:48,958
主人!
Master!

10
00:00:49,194 --> 00:00:51,220
K-9! 你为什么不回去......?
K-9! Why aren't you back at...?

11
00:01:00,346 --> 00:01:03,220
K-9, 阻挡它!
K-9, try and keep it back!

12
00:01:03,607 --> 00:01:05,707
我的能量快没了
Power supply at danger level.

13
00:01:15,858 --> 00:01:17,142
博士, 小心！
Doctor, look out!

14
00:01:38,900 --> 00:01:39,612
Bristol!
Bristol!

15
00:01:39,815 --> 00:01:40,281
是？
Yes?

16
00:01:40,532 --> 00:01:41,489
依然感觉奇妙吗？
Still feeling marvelous?

17
00:01:41,633 --> 00:01:42,170
是
Yes.

18
00:01:42,312 --> 00:01:45,743
很好. 给我十秒钟
Fine. Give me ten seconds.

19
00:01:48,929 --> 00:01:52,924
好，来这啊！来这啊！
Well, come on then! Come on then!

20
00:01:56,161 --> 00:01:58,962
博士, 快点！它要爆炸了！
Doctor, come on! It's going to blow up!

21
00:01:59,197 --> 00:02:00,525
危险, 博士, 危险
Danger, Doctor, Danger.

22
00:02:07,225 --> 00:02:07,825
博士！
Doctor！

23
00:02:18,006 --> 00:02:19,856
危险，博士，危险
Danger, Doctor, Danger.

24
00:02:40,281 --> 00:02:41,204
不！
No!

25
00:03:04,328 --> 00:03:05,087
它堵住了！
It's jammed!

26
00:03:18,145 --> 00:03:19,498
危险，博士,危险！
Danger, Doctor, Danger!

27
00:03:26,200 --> 00:03:31,785
我一边冲进 Skagra 的船，一边命令她迅速起飞, 立刻隐形
As I rushed into Skagra's ship, I ordered her to lift off and dematerialise immediately.

28
00:03:41,802 --> 00:03:43,899
我下定决心要找出来 Skagra 去了哪,
I was determined to find out where Skagra had gone,

29
00:03:43,899 --> 00:03:46,099
尽管这艘船拒绝告诉我
though the ship resisted telling me,

30
00:03:46,499 --> 00:03:49,099
于是我要求去 Skagra 的家
so I asked to be taken to Skagra's home.

31
00:03:49,299 --> 00:03:54,299
这艘船就遵从了. 很聪明, 不是吗？
The ship complied. Clever, eh?

32
00:03:57,793 --> 00:04:00,123
听着, 我根本不知道要做什么！
Look, I don't even know what I'm meant to be doing!

33
00:04:00,455 --> 00:04:03,059
我们必须让这个旧的巡视车重新动起来
We must get this old perambulator moving again.

34
00:04:03,280 --> 00:04:04,768
很好, 我碰了它一下, 它真的动了
Well, it certainly moved when I touched it.

35
00:04:06,041 --> 00:04:10,424
一个痉挛, 仅仅是一个痉挛. 我只希望它不是一个致命的痉挛
A spasm, a mere spasm. I only hope it wasn't a dying spasm.

36
00:04:11,380 --> 00:04:15,859
因为它让我们停留在一个荒谬的时间里, 
Because it has left us jammed between two irrational time interfaces,

37
00:04:15,860 --> 00:04:18,131
而且时间正在远离我们
and time is moving away from us.

38
00:04:19,491 --> 00:04:21,978
如果我们尝试解救我们自己, 
If we ever do manage to disentangle ourselves,

39
00:04:21,979 --> 00:04:25,546
我就不得不非常小心, 否则我就可能不再存在了
I'll have to be careful otherwise I shall cease to exist again.

40
00:04:25,812 --> 00:04:27,060
噢, 真的吗？
Oh really?

41
00:04:28,245 --> 00:04:29,518
现在按我说的做
Now do what I do.

42
00:04:29,745 --> 00:04:30,444
那是什么？
What's that?

43
00:04:30,649 --> 00:04:31,437
忘了它吧
Forget about it.

44
00:04:31,577 --> 00:04:33,008
说起来比做容易
That's easier said than done.

45
00:04:36,907 --> 00:04:40,110
这些 Salyvin 人是什么？
Who was this Salyavin person?

46
00:04:40,428 --> 00:04:45,167
Salyavin! 他是一个罪犯, 不过他的罪行被严重夸大了
Salyavin! He was a criminal whose exploits have been wildly exaggerated.

47
00:04:45,168 --> 00:04:49,512
他是一个性急的, 杰出的年轻人, 拥有独特的天赋
He was a hotheaded, brilliant young man with a peculiar talent.

48
00:04:50,400 --> 00:04:52,299
我不能修好它
I can't fix this.

49
00:04:52,711 --> 00:04:53,635
我能帮你吗？
Can I help?

50
00:04:53,901 --> 00:04:55,593
很难！太难了
Difficult! Very difficult.

51
00:04:55,594 --> 00:04:59,401
修复一个界面谐振器, 需要两个操作
To repair an interfacial resonator requires two operations

52
00:04:59,402 --> 00:05:02,814
它们必须完全同时进行
that must be performed absolutely simultaneously.

53
00:05:03,872 --> 00:05:07,188
说实话, 亲爱的, 我不觉得你具备这些知识
And to be honest, my dear, I don't think you have the knowledge.

54
00:05:07,954 --> 00:05:09,110
所以我们困住了？
So we're stuck?

55
00:05:09,425 --> 00:05:10,087
是的
Yes.

56
00:05:10,644 --> 00:05:12,810
我可以学的, 你要知道, 我学得很快
I could learn, you know. I'm very quick.

57
00:05:17,277 --> 00:05:18,546
怎么了？
What's the matter?

58
00:05:19,569 --> 00:05:22,474
听着, 认真听我说
Listen to me. Listen to me very carefully.

59
00:05:22,475 --> 00:05:29,115
我要做的事是你绝不能提及的, 这也是我唯一一次做这样的事
What I am about to do you are never to speak of, and this is the only time I will ever do it.

60
00:05:29,367 --> 00:05:30,421
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?

61
00:05:30,614 --> 00:05:31,409
你能给我承诺吗？
Do I have your promise?

62
00:05:31,757 --> 00:05:33,297
呃, 你要干嘛？
Well, what are you going to do?

63
00:05:33,478 --> 00:05:34,513
你能我给我承诺吗？！？！
Do I have your promise?!?!

64
00:05:34,741 --> 00:05:35,753
可以, 当然可以
Yes, yes alright.

65
00:05:36,227 --> 00:05:38,080
你手里拿着什么设备？
What is that piece of equipment you are holding in your hand?

66
00:05:38,246 --> 00:05:39,515
我根本不知道
I have absolutely no idea.

67
00:05:39,695 --> 00:05:40,273
很好
Good.

68
00:06:04,815 --> 00:06:09,216
现在, 这是什么设备？
Now, what is the piece of equipment?

69
00:06:09,505 --> 00:06:13,710
这个？这是一个概念性的几何继电器, 带有农艺触发器
This? It's a conceptual geometer relay, with an agronomic trigger,

70
00:06:13,711 --> 00:06:17,978
一个完全瘫痪的领域分离器, 但它并不重要
a totally defunct field separator, but it doesn't really matter.

71
00:06:18,198 --> 00:06:21,405
如果我们可以让界面共鸣器重新运作起来, 我们根本就不需要它
We can dispense with it if we can get that interfacial resonator working again.

72
00:06:21,623 --> 00:06:22,465
太棒了！
Splendid!

73
00:06:22,653 --> 00:06:23,895
恩, 就这么办吧, 怎么样？
Well, let's do that then, shall we?

74
00:06:39,726 --> 00:06:44,123
K-9, Chris 和我出现在货船上
K-9, Chris and I emerged inside the Carrier Ship

75
00:06:44,124 --> 00:06:46,152
跟 Skagra, Romana 以及许多 Krarg 面对面了
and face to face with Skagra, Romana and a multitude of Krargs.

76
00:06:47,022 --> 00:06:48,822
在球体的帮助下,
With the aid of the sphere,

77
00:06:48,823 --> 00:06:54,820
Skagra 想用一个思维统一整个宇宙 就像一个神一样
Skagra intend to merge the whole of creation into one single mind. One god-like entity.

78
00:06:55,364 --> 00:07:00,847
宇宙将会是 Skagra 的！当那些 Krarg 准备关起那些犯人时, 
The universe will be Skagra! As the Krargs prepared to lock up the prisoners,

79
00:07:00,848 --> 00:07:03,695
K-9, Chris 和我冲了出去
K-9, Chris and I made a break for it.

80
00:07:03,998 --> 00:07:06,361
Romana 被 Skagra 和 Krarg 支队的成员拖进了 TARDIS
Romana was dragged into the TARDIS by Skagra and a detachment of Krargs

81
00:07:06,362 --> 00:07:10,872
而我们其他几个则被其余生物追击
while the remainder of the creatures pursued my group.

82
00:07:11,208 --> 00:07:15,590
突然我发现了一个门, 决定藏起来
Suddenly I spotted a door and decided to take cover.

83
00:07:29,861 --> 00:07:31,531
Keightley!
Keightley!

84
00:07:31,814 --> 00:07:32,507
Chris?
Chris?

85
00:07:33,343 --> 00:07:34,348
要来杯茶吗？
Cup of tea?

86
00:07:34,894 --> 00:07:37,531
Krargs 开始试图闯入教授的房间
The Krargs started to break into the Professor's room.

87
00:07:39,328 --> 00:07:41,000
博士, 你喜欢我的 TARDIS 吗？
Doctor, how do you like my TARDIS?

88
00:07:41,348 --> 00:07:42,730
噢, 太棒了, 太棒了！
Oh, ace. Ace!

89
00:07:43,198 --> 00:07:45,707
这不是正式的, 他们不允许我拥有一台
It's strictly unofficial. I'm not really allowed one.

90
00:07:45,909 --> 00:07:49,532
是的, 与其把它藏起来, 不如直接生活在里面, 你这个老滑头
Yes, and there's no better way to hide it than by living in it, you old sly boots.

91
00:07:49,734 --> 00:07:51,009
你在这干嘛？
What are you doing here?

92
00:07:51,256 --> 00:07:54,991
我也想知道. 教授的房间怎么在这？
How am I'm suppose to know. What's the Professor room doing here?

93
00:07:55,191 --> 00:07:57,954
噢, 你问的好, 可这得问教授
Oh, you may well ask, but ask the Professor.

94
00:07:58,939 --> 00:08:00,189
博士, Skagra在哪？
Doctor, where is Skagra?

95
00:08:00,367 --> 00:08:02,649
嘘. 别这么大声, 他就在外面.
Shhh. Not so loud. He's right outside.

96
00:08:02,650 --> 00:08:05,719
而且他抓住了 Romana, 他得到了 TARDIS , 他得到了那本书, 我还以为你死了,  教授
He's got Romana, He got the TARDIS. He got the book. I thought you were dead, Professor.

97
00:08:05,915 --> 00:08:06,761
我也这么想
Yes, so did I.

98
00:08:06,915 --> 00:08:07,795
你说真的？
Did you really?

99
00:08:07,918 --> 00:08:13,065
听着博士, 如果 Skargra 得到了 TARDIS 和那本书, 他就可以去 Shada 了
Listen Doctor, if Skagra has the TARDIS and the book, he can get to Shada.

100
00:08:13,271 --> 00:08:14,674
Shada? Shada?
Shada? Shada?

101
00:08:14,875 --> 00:08:17,779
是的, 时间领主的监狱星球. 你可能已经忘了它
Yes, the Time Lords' prison planet. You've probably forgotten about it.

102
00:08:17,972 --> 00:08:18,913
我记性很好. 我从不会...
I never forget anything. I never...

103
00:08:19,064 --> 00:08:22,878
好吧. 我忘了. 那是时间领主的监狱星球
That's right. I have forgotten. The Time Lords' prison planet.

104
00:08:23,046 --> 00:08:29,707
为什么我现在忘了这个？对了, Salyavin 就被关在Shada
Now why would I have forgotten it? Of course, Salyavin was imprisoned on Shada.

105
00:08:31,424 --> 00:08:34,254
快问我谁是Salyavin
Ask me who Salyavin was.

106
00:08:34,418 --> 00:08:37,522
噢, 他是一个大罪犯, 几百年前被时间领主关进了监狱
Oh, he was a great criminal imprisoned centuries ago by the Time Lords.

107
00:08:37,666 --> 00:08:39,946
一个大罪犯, 拥有不同寻常的精神力量
A great criminal, unique mental powers.

108
00:08:39,947 --> 00:08:44,680
他有能力将他的想法投射到其他人的大脑里去, 是这样吗, 教授？
He had the capacity to project his mind into other minds. Didn't he Professor?

109
00:08:44,889 --> 00:08:45,935
这不是 Skagra 在做的吗？
Isn't this what Skagra doing?

110
00:08:46,070 --> 00:08:48,887
噢, 不不不. Skagra 则完全相反
Oh no, no, no, no. With Skagra, quite the opposite.

111
00:08:49,067 --> 00:08:53,294
Skagra有能力提取人的思维, 但没法把思维放到别人大脑里
Skagra had the capacity to take minds out of people, but he couldn't put minds into them.

112
00:08:53,641 --> 00:08:57,033
这就是为什么他需要 Salyavin 在他的球体里 这也是他要去 Shada 的原因
That's why he needs Salyavin in his sphere, and that's why he's going to Shada.

113
00:08:57,220 --> 00:08:58,344
当然
Of course.

114
00:08:58,488 --> 00:09:00,224
博士! 他不能去那儿
Doctor! He must not get there.

115
00:09:01,267 --> 00:09:04,427
在 TARDIS 里, Skagra 翻着书, 
In the TARDIS, Skagra turned the pages of the book,

116
00:09:04,428 --> 00:09:08,393
通过这样, 使太空船的中心柱体运作起来
activating the central column of the space-craft by doing so.

117
00:09:09,398 --> 00:09:14,317
Romana 面无表情地看着, 而飞船正驶向 Shada
While Romana watched impassively, the craft proceeded to Shada.

118
00:09:17,069 --> 00:09:20,947
如果球体里面有了 Skagra 和 Salyavin 的思维,  Skagra将变得无所不能
With Skagra's mind and Salyavin's mind in the sphere, Skagra will become omnipotent.

119
00:09:21,160 --> 00:09:24,195
什么, 你的意思是, 他可以随意进入宇宙中每个人的思维？
What, do you mean that he could just move himself into every mind in the Universe?

120
00:09:24,647 --> 00:09:29,317
是的, 最终会的, 这可能要上千年的时间. 但这都不是事儿
Yes, eventually, It might take thousands of years, but that wouldn't matter.

121
00:09:29,542 --> 00:09:32,118
一旦他的思维变得不朽, 它就会像病毒一样扩散
His mind would be immortal. It would spread like a disease.

122
00:09:32,328 --> 00:09:33,913
这只是一个理论, 不是吗？
It's quite a thought though isn't it?

123
00:09:33,914 --> 00:09:36,784
所有思维为同一个有机体工作, 成为一个思维
Every mind working together as a single organism, a single mind.

124
00:09:37,128 --> 00:09:40,458
Skagra的思维. 这不是一个好想法
Skagra's mind. Not a pleasant thought.

125
00:09:40,722 --> 00:09:42,354
博士, 我们必须阻止他达到 Shada...
Doctor, we got to stop him from getting to Shada...

126
00:09:42,511 --> 00:09:45,616
没错. 可怎么阻止？他已经上路了, 而我们还不知道路
Yes. But how? He got a start on us and we don't know the way.

127
00:09:45,968 --> 00:09:46,999
我们必须跟着他！
We must follow him！

128
00:09:47,161 --> 00:09:47,890
可怎么跟？
But how?

129
00:09:48,096 --> 00:09:49,440
和我们来的时候一样
The same way we arrived.

130
00:09:50,678 --> 00:09:53,463
你追踪了 TARDIS 时空轨迹！就是这样！
You followed the TARDIS' space-time trail! Of course!

131
00:09:57,221 --> 00:09:58,049
走吧！
Let's go!

132
00:10:02,809 --> 00:10:04,847
带着 Romana 和 Krargs, 
Taking Romana and the Krargs with him,

133
00:10:05,125 --> 00:10:09,487
Skagra 翻阅 Shada 的记录来寻找 Salyavin 的下落
Skagra searches the records of Shada to discover the whereabouts of Salyavin.

134
00:10:09,852 --> 00:10:17,261
成功了！他们动身前往T号厅的9号囚室, 甩开了记录中心的警卫
Success! They set off for in pursuit of Cabinet 9, Chamber T, leaving guards at the records centre.

135
00:10:17,956 --> 00:10:19,793
博士, 我们到了！
Doctor, we're arrived!

136
00:10:20,042 --> 00:10:20,996
很好！很好！
Good! Good!

137
00:10:21,187 --> 00:10:21,863
现在你们两个...
Now you two...

138
00:10:22,029 --> 00:10:22,503
恩？
Yes?

139
00:10:22,623 --> 00:10:23,300
待在这
Stay here.

140
00:10:23,400 --> 00:10:25,743
我现在没空解释了
I'm not at liberty to explain.

141
00:10:26,517 --> 00:10:31,277
K-9, 你可以一起来, 但不可以和 Krargs 纠缠
K-9, you can come along, but you're not to tangle with any Krargs,

142
00:10:31,480 --> 00:10:33,402
除非迫不得已
unless of course if you have to tangle with any Krargs.

143
00:10:33,583 --> 00:10:35,452
快！Skagra 已经到了
Hurry! Skagra will be here already.

144
00:10:35,597 --> 00:10:36,750
快来！快来！
Come on! Come on!

145
00:10:38,225 --> 00:10:41,771
貌似教授在某些时候, 能知道 Skagra 在想什么
The Professor seemed in some way able to know what was Skagra was thinking

146
00:10:42,018 --> 00:10:44,890
并坚决要求走某一条路
and insisted they head in a particular route.

147
00:10:45,412 --> 00:10:51,530
与此同时, Skagra 放出了囚室内的一些犯人. 他们开始蠢蠢欲动
Skagra meanwhile revitalised the prisoners cabinet. They began to stir.

148
00:10:52,491 --> 00:10:58,209
- 这几天过得好奇怪啊？- Chris？ - 我的意思是, 之前我还在国王巡游的路上骑车游玩
- How odd some days work out isn't it? - Chris? - I mean there I was, just cycling down King's Parade...

149
00:10:58,534 --> 00:11:00,796
Chris, 在教授身上有不寻常的事发生了...
Chris, there's something very strange about the Professor...

150
00:11:01,049 --> 00:11:02,192
为什么突然提教授？
Why single out the Professor?

151
00:11:02,345 --> 00:11:04,072
我想知道发生了什么
I want to know what's going on out there.

152
00:11:05,276 --> 00:11:06,642
Chris, 你不会丢下我吧...
Chris, you're not leaving to me...

153
00:11:06,784 --> 00:11:08,171
我只是不想被撇下
I just don't like getting left behind.

154
00:11:10,473 --> 00:11:15,289
我是说, 我们是来自地球, 但这并没有给任何人傲视我们的权利
I mean, just because we come from Earth doesn't give everyone the right to be patronising to us.

155
00:11:17,155 --> 00:11:19,931
恩, 当然啦, 所有这些使我们看上去像原始人
Well, admittedly, all this does make us look a bit primitive.

156
00:11:20,730 --> 00:11:22,817
对于它是如何运作的, 我没有一丁点头绪
I doesn't have even the faintest idea how it all works.

157
00:11:23,098 --> 00:11:24,026
我知道
I have.

158
00:11:25,490 --> 00:11:26,432
你知道？
You do?

159
00:11:26,611 --> 00:11:28,611
至少刚才那会儿我知道
At least I did a while ago.

160
00:11:30,104 --> 00:11:31,353
什么意思？
What do you mean?

161
00:11:31,540 --> 00:11:33,634
这就是我刚才一直想告诉你的
That's what I been trying to tell you all along.

162
00:11:33,929 --> 00:11:36,828
教授对我的思维做了一些什么事情...
Its something that the Professor did to me, to my mind...

163
00:11:37,975 --> 00:11:40,319
囚犯们从休眠中被唤醒
The prisoners were reviving from their sleep.

164
00:11:40,743 --> 00:11:42,907
Skafra 接近 9 号囚室, 激活了复苏信号
Skagra approached Cabinet 9 and activated the revival

165
00:11:43,080 --> 00:11:47,505
我和我的团队冲入了囚室
just as I and my group burst into the chamber.

166
00:11:47,813 --> 00:11:49,497
Skagra 警告我们退后 
Skagra warned us to keep back.

167
00:11:49,671 --> 00:11:53,217
他把手伸进柜子, 拉出一个可怜的替身
He reached into the cabinet and pulled out a pathetic dummy-like substitute.

168
00:11:54,010 --> 00:11:59,983
直到 Chronotis 解释他就是 Salyavin, Skagra的怒火才得以平息
Skagra's anger mounted until Professor Chronotis explained that HE was Salyavin.

169
00:12:01,301 --> 00:12:06,361
让我理一理, 你是说他... 就这样走进你的思维？
Let me just get this right. You say that he... Just "Walked into your mind."

170
00:12:07,272 --> 00:12:12,657
恩, 就像他闯进了我思维的前门, 然后就扰乱了我的思维
Well sort of. Just like he barged in the front door and shuffled my thoughts about.

171
00:12:13,015 --> 00:12:17,315
可是博士说那项能力是 Skagra 一直在寻找的, 那个不寻常的人才有的...
But the Doctor said was that ability was unique to the guy that Skagra's come here to find...

172
00:12:21,048 --> 00:12:26,155
站起来, Keightley. 来吧, 让我们看看到底怎么回事
On your feet, Keightley. Come on, let's see what's happening.

173
00:12:33,765 --> 00:12:38,975
Skagra 命令球体清空 Salayvin 的思维, 可是K-9把它炸成了碎片
Skagra ordered the sphere to drain Salayvin's mind but K-9 blasted it into pieces.

174
00:12:39,881 --> 00:12:45,680
碎片变成不同的小球, 而其中一个选择了那个老人
Each fragment reformed into another small sphere. One of which settled on the old man.

175
00:12:46,407 --> 00:12:48,638
Skagra很高兴
Skagra was exhilarated

176
00:12:49,424 --> 00:12:55,520
“你们应该看看宇宙思维的起始”, 他在小球聚集起来的时候大喊道
"You shall see the beginning of the universal mind" he cries as the spheres came together,

177
00:12:55,692 --> 00:12:57,889
大量能量喷涌而出
discharging vast amounts of energy.

178
00:12:58,102 --> 00:13:02,658
一些囚犯转身过来, 众多小球依附到他们身上
And then, each of them attach themselves to one of the prisoners who turned towards me.

179
00:13:03,136 --> 00:13:07,570
Chris 和 Clare 进入囚室, 这个年轻小伙子冲上去想帮忙
Chris and Clare entered the chamber and the young man rushed forward trying to help.

180
00:13:08,094 --> 00:13:10,740
一个球瞬间吸收了他的思维
A sphere absorbed his mind in an instant.

181
00:13:11,039 --> 00:13:16,535
囚犯们, 包括Chris, 带着威胁, 超过涌过来...
The prisoners, including Chris, marched menacing towards me...

