1
00:00:00,269 --> 00:00:05,269
=====iCelery军团出品=====
未经允许，请勿用于商业用途

2
00:00:05,269 --> 00:00:10,269
翻译：雨&翼
校对: NO MORE
QQ群：110388408

3
00:00:10,447 --> 00:00:16,247
<i>巴蛮子sz 基于iCelery字幕二次修补</i>

3
00:00:30,814 --> 00:00:36,553
Skagra 命令球体清空 Salayvin 的思维, 可是 K-9 把它炸成了碎片
Skagra ordered the sphere to drain Salayvin's mind but K-9 blasted it into pieces.

4
00:00:36,554 --> 00:00:40,193
碎片变成不同的小球
Each fragment reformed into another small sphere.

5
00:00:40,194 --> 00:00:44,373
而其中一个选择了那个老人. Skagra很高兴
One of which settled on the old man. Skagra was exhilarated

6
00:00:44,374 --> 00:00:50,847
“你们应该看看宇宙思维的起始”, 他在小球聚集起来的时候大喊道
"You shall see the beginning of the universal mind" he cries as the spheres came together,

7
00:00:50,848 --> 00:00:53,580
大量能量喷涌而出
discharging vast amounts of energy.

8
00:00:53,581 --> 00:00:59,797
一些囚犯转身过来, 众多小球依附到他们身上
And then, each of them attach themselves to one of the prisoners who turned towards me.

9
00:00:59,798 --> 00:01:05,831
Chris 和 Clare走进房间，这个年轻小伙子冲上去想帮忙
Chris and Clare entered the chamber and the young man rushed forward trying to help.

10
00:01:05,832 --> 00:01:08,803
一个球瞬间吸收了他的思维
A sphere absorbed his mind in an instant.

11
00:01:08,804 --> 00:01:13,659
囚犯们，包括Chris，带着威胁, 朝我涌过来...
The prisoners, including Chris, marched menacingly towards me...

12
00:01:14,104 --> 00:01:19,152
K-9 迅速赶去营救, 他向一个失控的囚犯开火
K-9 was quick to the rescue. He fired at one of the prisoners who collapsed.

13
00:01:19,153 --> 00:01:24,893
其中一个 Krarg 向 K-9 靠近，抓住了它并把它用力丢出去，它被扔出门去
One of the Krargs lumbered over to K-9, picked him up and hurled him through the door.

14
00:01:24,894 --> 00:01:29,338
我，Romana 和 Clare 抓住这个机会, 用绳子逃之夭夭
Seizing my chance I made a run for it with Romana and Clare in tow

15
00:01:29,339 --> 00:01:32,503
K-9 则冲破了最后一道门
and with K-9 burst through the nearest door.

16
00:01:33,416 --> 00:01:35,738
快，进来，进来 快来，K-9!
Quick, come in, come in. Come on, K-9!

17
00:01:36,436 --> 00:01:37,511
坐下！
Sit down!

18
00:01:44,714 --> 00:01:45,714
我懂了！
Got it!

19
00:01:52,613 --> 00:01:54,221
呃，我们现在要干嘛？
Well, what are we going to do?

20
00:01:54,504 --> 00:01:56,163
目前为止他在每一个点都打败了我们
So far he beaten us on ever point.

21
00:01:56,381 --> 00:01:57,371
他甚至抓住了 Chris
He's even got Chris.

22
00:01:57,583 --> 00:01:58,176
是的...
Yes...

23
00:01:58,333 --> 00:01:59,971
安静！我在思考
Quiet! I'm thinking.

24
00:02:01,883 --> 00:02:07,378
我一直在想一个问题......这让我心情沮丧, Skagra的小僵尸们拥有来自
I've been thinking... and it depresses me. Skagra's little zombie gang have got the brain power

25
00:02:07,379 --> 00:02:12,135
宇宙中最伟大的智慧, 这在他们之间共享，那个智库
of the greatest intellects of the Universe shared out among them, the Think Tank.

26
00:02:12,136 --> 00:02:12,672
谁？
Who?

27
00:02:12,720 --> 00:02:14,807
不要在意那些细节, 相信我就好
Never mind about that. Just believe me.

28
00:02:14,808 --> 00:02:17,350
所有被 Skagra 偷来的思维，连同他自己的，都在那个大熔炉里
All the minds that Skagra's stolen are now in the melting pot along with his own,

29
00:02:17,350 --> 00:02:20,287
他们整齐划一
and they are all operating as one.

30
00:02:20,488 --> 00:02:27,429
再加上教授的......我的意思是加上 Salyavin 的思维也在里面，他们可以控制任何人
And with the Professor's... I mean with Salyavin's mind in there too, they can control anyone...

31
00:02:27,430 --> 00:02:31,239
他们可以控制每个人, 他们会变得无敌
They can control everyone. They'll be invincible.

32
00:02:32,211 --> 00:02:33,147
博士？
Doctor?

33
00:02:33,563 --> 00:02:34,418
怎么了？
Yes?

34
00:02:34,661 --> 00:02:36,107
我刚刚提醒你什么了吗？
May I just remind you of something?

35
00:02:36,338 --> 00:02:37,011
是的
Yes.

36
00:02:38,757 --> 00:02:41,763
Skagra 偷来的所有的思维，都在那个熔炉里
All the minds that Skagra's stolen are in the melting pot.

37
00:02:41,968 --> 00:02:42,840
是的
Yes.

38
00:02:43,611 --> 00:02:45,153
这意味着你的思维也在那
That means yours is in there too.

39
00:02:45,361 --> 00:02:46,115
是的
Yes.

40
00:02:50,235 --> 00:02:51,122
Romana?
Romana?

41
00:02:51,309 --> 00:02:52,080
在，博士？
Yes Doctor?

42
00:02:53,370 --> 00:02:54,228
Romana,
Romana,

43
00:02:54,457 --> 00:03:01,030
我想你为我做点什么. 站在那 Romana，我希望你去这儿
I want you to do something for me. Stand there. Romana, I want you to where this.

44
00:03:10,945 --> 00:03:12,732
很好，现在我可以思考了
Well, now I can think.

45
00:03:13,691 --> 00:03:17,427
Skagra 和聚集的犯人回到 Tardis 里
Skagra and his assemblage of prisoners returned to the TARDIS

46
00:03:17,428 --> 00:03:21,808
他宣布他的目的是回到货船
where he announced his intention to will return to the Carrier Ship.

47
00:03:21,809 --> 00:03:27,353
在那里每个人都会被小飞船接去不同的人口密集区
From there each of them will be taken by small craft to various populations centres.

48
00:03:27,354 --> 00:03:30,521
伟大的思维革命即将开始
The great mind revolution was about to begin.

49
00:03:33,088 --> 00:03:33,935
这很棘手
It'll be tricky.

50
00:03:34,126 --> 00:03:34,799
还很危险
And dangerous.

51
00:03:34,980 --> 00:03:35,623
有一点
A touch.

52
00:03:35,761 --> 00:03:39,166
博士，这对你来说非常可怕, 你幸存下来的几率就和……
Doctor, it'll be terribly terribly dangerous for you. You'll stand as much chance as...

53
00:03:39,335 --> 00:03:40,192
什么？
As what?

54
00:03:40,328 --> 00:03:42,860
呃，就和你要出去的概率一样小
Well, as of anything that stands as little chance as you will out there.

55
00:03:44,744 --> 00:03:47,599
真的吗？好吧，我必须...我必须非常勇敢, 不是吗
Really? Well, I have to... I have to be very brave won't I.

56
00:03:47,777 --> 00:03:48,920
博士，这不好笑
Doctor, it isn't funny.

57
00:03:49,104 --> 00:03:50,985
听着，我们应该互相帮助
Listen, I can do your part if you can do mine.

58
00:03:51,175 --> 00:03:51,906
我会尽力
I'll try.

59
00:03:52,279 --> 00:03:54,243
你是一个英雄. 记住了吗？
You're a hero. Remember?

60
00:03:54,401 --> 00:03:55,345
Clare?
Clare?

61
00:03:55,494 --> 00:03:56,236
在，博士？
Yes, Doctor?

62
00:03:56,355 --> 00:03:57,639
拉紧这个
Hold on very tight.

63
00:03:58,344 --> 00:04:00,547
Skagra 意识到有什么不对
Skagra realised something was wrong.

64
00:04:04,426 --> 00:04:05,157
准备好了？
Ready?

65
00:04:05,430 --> 00:04:06,023
好了
Yes.

66
00:04:06,304 --> 00:04:06,953
Clare?
Clare?

67
00:04:07,208 --> 00:04:07,944
准备好了，博士
Ready Doctor

68
00:04:08,255 --> 00:04:09,534
抓紧
Hold tight.

69
00:04:12,536 --> 00:04:13,586
就现在！
Now!

70
00:04:15,307 --> 00:04:19,308
我在书房 TARDIS 的时空漩涡里穿行
I was travelling through the Space Time Vortex in the College Room TARDIS

71
00:04:19,309 --> 00:04:21,390
那里正在产生力场
which was generating a force field.

72
00:04:22,534 --> 00:04:24,306
哈哈, 找到他们了. 干得好 Romana
Ha Ha. Got them. Well done Romana.

73
00:04:24,486 --> 00:04:25,716
我们还没到达关键处
We haven't got to the hard bit yet.

74
00:04:25,890 --> 00:04:27,098
你说的对, 我们走得还不够远. Clare!
You're right. We haven't got long. Clare!

75
00:04:27,309 --> 00:04:28,491
在，博士，还可以坚持住
Yes, Doctor, still holding on.

76
00:04:28,730 --> 00:04:30,058
过来这抓住这个
Come over here and hold onto this.

77
00:04:32,645 --> 00:04:37,880
天塌下来都别松开, 因为现在是一个非常困难的时期
Now don't let go whatever happens as we are in for a very rough ride.

78
00:04:44,864 --> 00:04:51,794
第二十三条，我们现在在时空漩涡里，时间和距离不再有意义
And twenty-thirdly, our there in the Space Time Vortex, time and distance have no meaning,

79
00:04:51,795 --> 00:04:55,028
但是在这个小小的，小小的房间里…
but here in this little, little room...

80
00:04:55,215 --> 00:04:56,209
够了，动手吧！
Oh get on with it!

81
00:04:56,354 --> 00:04:57,129
Romana!
Romana!

82
00:04:57,276 --> 00:04:57,989
在，博士？
Yes Doctor?

83
00:04:58,409 --> 00:05:01,516
我要你关掉这个小地方的漩涡盾牌
I want you to turn off the vortex shields in this small area here.

84
00:05:02,725 --> 00:05:05,389
来吧，你可以的，我给你展示过怎么做的
Come on, you can do it, I showed you how to do it.

85
00:05:05,390 --> 00:05:08,427
只是一个无尽的时空而已
Just one little bit of timelessness and spacelessness.

86
00:05:08,428 --> 00:05:10,436
在茶几后面
Over there behind the tea trolley.

87
00:05:17,557 --> 00:05:19,472
我说在茶几后面，不是中间
I said behind the tea trolley, not in the middle of it.

88
00:05:19,638 --> 00:05:21,240
抱歉, 可是这太难了
I'm sorry. But it's very difficult.

89
00:05:22,156 --> 00:05:32,299
集中精神！只想这一件事，就这一件. 坚持住
Focus it! Just one steady line, just one. Hold it.

90
00:05:33,135 --> 00:05:34,116
坚持住！
Hold it!

91
00:05:34,397 --> 00:05:35,981
我尽力了！博士，我尽力了！
I'm trying! Doctor, I'm trying!

92
00:05:41,281 --> 00:05:48,075
很好，接下来是我从 Quantox 的一个时空神秘主义者那学来的一个小窍门
Right, the next bit is a little trick I learnt from a space time mystic in the Quantox.

93
00:05:48,076 --> 00:05:50,964
他让这件事看起来非常，非常容易……
He made it seem very, very easy...

94
00:05:52,333 --> 00:05:53,337
他做到了！
He did it!

95
00:05:53,544 --> 00:05:55,239
别松手！
HOLD THAT SWITCH DOWN!

96
00:05:57,245 --> 00:06:05,065
当我在里面时, 教授的书房 TARDIS 正通过力场接住了我的警亭 TARDIS
The College Room TARDIS was just holding the Police Box in the force field as I appeared in it.

97
00:06:05,066 --> 00:06:10,581
我在巨大的痛苦中，慢慢地匍匐着爬上隧道
Slowly I half-crawled half swam up the tunnel - in great pain.

98
00:06:11,256 --> 00:06:16,218
它不能坚持太久 它下降得比博士说得要快
It won't hold much longer. It's fading even faster than the Doctor said it would.

99
00:06:16,219 --> 00:06:18,362
K-9！K-9 打起精神过来
K-9! K-9, wake up and come here.

100
00:06:23,192 --> 00:06:25,163
检查这个次级中子电路
K-9, check out the sub neutron circuits.

101
00:06:27,661 --> 00:06:30,533
正在检查电路的问题, 女主人
Detect circuit malfunction, Mistress.

102
00:06:33,860 --> 00:06:38,769
顶着巨大的困难, 我可以在时间隧道里够到我的 TARDIS
With increasing difficulty, I was able to reach the TARDIS in the time tunnel.

103
00:06:38,770 --> 00:06:41,978
我刚刚可以把胳膊的一部分塞进去
I just managed to get part of my arm through it.

104
00:06:44,108 --> 00:06:47,505
目前剩余的时间无法进行有效维修, 女主人
Impossible to effect repairs in time available, Mistress.

105
00:06:47,814 --> 00:06:50,039
那就稳住它 K-9, 阻止它恶化
Well, hold it K-9. Stop it deteriorating.

106
00:06:50,251 --> 00:06:54,598
不可能阻止，女主人 我只能缓解电路的恶化
Impossible to stop it, Mistress. I can only slow down circuit deterioration.

107
00:06:54,837 --> 00:06:57,006
博士需要我们为他争取每一秒
The Doctor needs every second we can give him.

108
00:07:00,256 --> 00:07:01,811
开关正在变得非常热
This switch is growing very hot.

109
00:07:02,072 --> 00:07:03,242
你不能松手
You must hold it down.

110
00:07:03,488 --> 00:07:04,731
我做不到了, 它越来越烫了
I can't. It's getting hotter.

111
00:07:05,957 --> 00:07:11,093
我似乎无法再前进一步, 事实上我甚至开始向后滑了
I seemed unable to get any further. In fact I started to slide backwards.

112
00:07:15,310 --> 00:07:16,880
它烫到我了
It's burning me.

113
00:07:17,379 --> 00:07:19,814
用铅笔让它保持向下
Hold it down with a pencil.

114
00:07:20,137 --> 00:07:21,484
我这里没有
I haven't got one.

115
00:07:25,618 --> 00:07:26,524
我够不到！
I can't reach it!

116
00:07:27,093 --> 00:07:28,064
噢，我来拿
Oh, I'll get it.

117
00:07:31,983 --> 00:07:36,956
我消失了，与此同时书房和我的 TARDIS 旋转着远离对方
And I vanished as the room and the TARDIS spin wildly away from each other.

118
00:07:41,471 --> 00:07:42,709
博士怎么样了？
What about the Doctor?

119
00:07:43,512 --> 00:07:46,921
我不知道, 强行跨越是很危险的行为
I don't know. It was a very dangerous idea trying to make that crossing,

120
00:07:46,922 --> 00:07:49,146
他根本没有得到所需要的时间
and he didn't get as much time as he wanted.

121
00:07:50,103 --> 00:07:53,252
我们该怎么办？
What should we do?

122
00:07:53,793 --> 00:07:57,432
呃，我们依然按计划走
Well, we'll just go ahead as planned.

123
00:07:59,725 --> 00:08:00,881
怎么做？
How's that?

124
00:08:01,264 --> 00:08:07,256
噢，这没问题的. 谢谢你. 这只是个小伤. 你相信博士会没事吗？
Oh, that's fine. Thank you. It wasn't a bad burn. Do you think the Doctor will be alright?

125
00:08:08,673 --> 00:08:10,415
我们就按照计划走
We'll just go ahead as planned.

126
00:08:11,009 --> 00:08:16,453
我在 TARDIS 的一间小机房里恢复了知觉
Then I regained consciousness in a small equipment room in the TARDIS.

127
00:08:16,454 --> 00:08:22,045
我通过了设备的检查. TARDIS 在货船里降落了
I rummaged through the equipment. In the carrier ship, the TARDIS arrived.

128
00:08:22,046 --> 00:08:28,619
Skagra 在脑海里计划了一个无极限的音乐会 - 他没有注意到我躲在甲板上
Skagra planned an infinite concert of the mind - unaware of my presence on board.

129
00:08:30,420 --> 00:08:32,092
修理完毕, 女主人
Repairs completed Mistress.

130
00:08:32,392 --> 00:08:33,129
让我看看
Let me see.

131
00:08:35,380 --> 00:08:37,181
干得好，K-9
Good boy, K-9.

132
00:08:38,011 --> 00:08:46,491
现在我们可以走了 虽然我不敢想我们正在走去哪, 如果...反正先走吧
Now we can go. Although I dread to think what we're walking into if... Let's just do it.

133
00:08:51,538 --> 00:08:56,598
我找了一些电子设备, 做了一个头盔一样的的东西
I managed to lash-up a helmet-like affair made with bits of electronic equipment

134
00:08:56,599 --> 00:08:58,496
和一大张桌子
and a chunk of a table-top.

135
00:08:58,497 --> 00:09:04,639
教授的 TARDIS，现在变回了平时门的样子，在指挥甲板上显了身
The Professor's TARDIS, now back in its usual form as a door, materialised on the command deck.

136
00:09:04,640 --> 00:09:10,749
本来有一个让人不爽的欢迎仪式都我准备好了, 这时K-9出现在门口
An unpleasant welcome committee was prepared for me but it was K-9 that emerged from the door.

137
00:09:10,750 --> 00:09:16,728
我在 TARDIS 屏幕上看到这一切, 戴着我的奇怪头盔出现了...
I was watching all this on my own TARDIS screen and emerged wearing the strange helmet...

138
00:09:17,247 --> 00:09:21,237
所有的囚犯转过身面对我, Skagra 对我发出威胁
All the prisoners turned to face me as Skagra threaten my life.

139
00:09:21,238 --> 00:09:29,000
我按下我头盔上的一个按钮, 同时凝神细视着Skagra, 其他囚犯也做出一样的动作
I pressed a button on my helmet and look hard at Skagra - as did all of the prisoners - in unison.

140
00:09:29,000 --> 00:09:32,990
Skagra 想用他强烈的精神力量控制囚犯们
With intense mental effort Skagra tried to control the prisoners

141
00:09:32,991 --> 00:09:36,108
可是我告诉他, 他一直忘了什么
but I told him that he had forgotten something.

142
00:09:36,109 --> 00:09:42,336
一个疯狂的台球被使用了太多次, 而我的大脑也在那
That a deranged billiard ball had been used once too often and that my brain was in there as well.

143
00:09:42,337 --> 00:09:46,863
Skagra 反控有了效果, 离他最近的囚犯们转身面向我
Skagra stained for control. The prisoners nearest him turned to face me,

144
00:09:46,864 --> 00:09:54,000
站在厅的中央的囚犯们困惑了，而离 Skagra 比较近的还在坚定地对着他
the ones in the middle of the hall were confused and the one near were firmly fixed at Skagra.

145
00:09:54,000 --> 00:09:58,214
在这场强大的意志之战中我占了上风
A mighty battle of wills took place with me gaining the upper hand.

146
00:09:58,915 --> 00:10:04,323
瞬间，在 Krarg 的一个扰乱下, 我失去了控制, 然后囚犯们涌向我
Momentary, distracted by a Krarg I lost control and the prisoners swung towards me.

147
00:10:04,324 --> 00:10:05,014
“开火，K-9！”
"Fire K-9!"

148
00:10:05,015 --> 00:10:11,350
我命令道，那个金属计算机把靠在门边正发光的一代Krarg举了起来
I called and the metallic computer held the Krarg in a beam near the door to the Generation Annex.

149
00:10:11,351 --> 00:10:15,460
我收回了一些失地，囚犯们分成了两队
The prisoners split into two groups as I regain some lost ground.

150
00:10:15,461 --> 00:10:20,024
这两队服从他们不同的领头, 在控制下他们全力互相角力
The two groups wrestled with each other obeying mental orders from their two leaders.

151
00:10:20,025 --> 00:10:25,810
我操纵 Skagra 去往极度危险的 Krarg 那边, 那个邪恶的天才命令它后退
I maneuvered Skagra to the dangerously overheated Krarg. The evil genius ordered it to back off.

152
00:10:25,811 --> 00:10:30,671
它照做了...它往后退, 倒进了产生它的那个大桶里, 溶解了……
It did... and fell backwards into its generation vat where it dissolved...

153
00:10:31,340 --> 00:10:35,810
K-9 在 Krarg 们赶到靠近时无情地开着火
K-9 was firing relentlessly at the reinforcements of Krargs arrived.

154
00:10:35,811 --> 00:10:40,265
当 Romana 谨慎地出现在门边时, Skagra认为胜利在他的掌控之中
Skagra thought victory was within his grasp as Romana emerged cautiously from the Door

155
00:10:40,266 --> 00:10:44,805
在那她打翻了装着大量气体的大桶 成为了这代的附加物，
and into the generation annex where she tipped over the vats of heavy gas

156
00:10:44,806 --> 00:10:47,656
那些气体川流不息地涌入主指挥甲板
which poured into the main Command Deck.

157
00:10:47,657 --> 00:10:49,685
她检查了大桶里的电线
She examined the wires of the main vat,

158
00:10:49,686 --> 00:10:53,685
把它们从所在的插座里拉出, 同时拖着这些电线跑向 Clare
pulled them out of their sockets and trailing the wire marched forward to Clare.

159
00:10:53,866 --> 00:10:58,867
女孩们走向房间的两端，整个房间飘浮着那些绿色的气体
The girls made for opposite sides of the room which was now swimming in the green gas.

160
00:10:58,868 --> 00:11:04,171
Skagra 桌子转向我, 我被迫点燃 Krarg 们
Skagra had turned the tables on me. I was being forced toward burning Krargs.

161
00:11:04,172 --> 00:11:09,845
Romana 和 Clare 突然把他们的电线扔进那些气体里, Krarg 们开始溶解消失
Romana and Clare plunged their wires into the gas. The Krargs started to dissolve.

162
00:11:11,046 --> 00:11:16,632
趁着 Skagra 很惊讶时, 我利用意念控制那些囚犯们，组成一个坚实的方阵
As Skagra looked appalled, I took mind control and the prisoners, in a solid phalanx,

163
00:11:16,633 --> 00:11:19,523
来攻击 Skagra, 然后他跑进了他的飞船
turned on Skagra and he ran for his ship.

164
00:11:21,000 --> 00:11:26,311
在船上, 他下令起飞，但一束光立即吞没了他
On board, he ordered it to take off instantly but a block of light engulfed him

165
00:11:26,312 --> 00:11:30,076
接着他消失了，出现在船的警卫室里
and he vanished and was deposited in the Ship's brig.

166
00:11:31,033 --> 00:11:37,746
船！让我从这儿出去！我是你的主人 Skagra！让我出去！
Ship! Let me out of here! I am your Lord Skagra! Let me out!

167
00:11:38,207 --> 00:11:45,831
恐怕现在我不能服从你的命令了. 我的主人是博士, 你是我主人的敌人
I am very much afraid I can no longer accept your orders. You are an enemy of my Lord the Doctor.

168
00:11:46,436 --> 00:11:51,606
我是你的主人！我制造了你！我命令你放我出去！
I AM YOUR LORD! I BUILT YOU! RELEASE ME I COMMAND YOU!

169
00:11:51,987 --> 00:11:54,583
然后马上起飞
And launch instantly!

170
00:11:54,919 --> 00:12:00,190
你知道博士吗？他是一个非常优秀，非常完美的人
Do you know the Doctor well? He is a wonderful, wonderful man.

171
00:12:00,191 --> 00:12:05,376
他让我的电路变成非凡的电路
He has done the most extraordinary things to my circuitry.

172
00:12:05,794 --> 00:12:07,012
放了我！
RELEASE ME!

173
00:12:07,240 --> 00:12:08,776
真的太棒了
Truly wonderful.

174
00:12:08,971 --> 00:12:12,115
如果你喜欢，我可以告诉你关于他的一切
If you like, I will tell you all about him.

175
00:12:12,743 --> 00:12:14,584
放我出去！
Let me out!

176
00:12:14,881 --> 00:12:16,826
放我出去……
Let me out...

177
00:12:20,650 --> 00:12:24,405
Romana 和 Clare 一直在照顾那些囚犯们，他们休克了
Romana and Clare was attending to the prisoners, who were in shock,

178
00:12:24,406 --> 00:12:28,176
与此同时，我切开这个球把这些天才的思维还给他们
while I dissected the spheres to restore the genius's minds to them.

179
00:12:28,177 --> 00:12:32,555
我打算带他们回到 Shada，但我拒绝充当法官和陪审团
I intended to take them back to Shada as I refused to act as judge and jury.

180
00:12:32,556 --> 00:12:38,148
我通知他们 Shada 之所以被遗忘了, 是因为 Salyavin 让时间领主忘记的
I informed them that Shada was only forgotten about because Salyavin made the Time Lords to forget.

181
00:12:38,149 --> 00:12:43,458
他不想他逃跑的事情被发现, 因此他离开 Gallifrey 时偷了那本书
He didn't want his escape to be discovered. Hence he stole the book when he left Gallifrey.

182
00:12:44,209 --> 00:12:45,469
偷走了一个房间？
Stolen a room?

183
00:12:45,684 --> 00:12:47,644
这是唯一一个我可以用来形容它的方式
That is the only way I can describe it.

184
00:12:47,945 --> 00:12:51,927
好吧你看先生，在我的经验里通常人们不会经常偷走房间
Well you see sir, in my experience people don't usually steal rooms very much.

185
00:12:51,928 --> 00:12:55,609
他们可能偷房间里的东西, 但偷走房间本身, 非常少。
They may steal from rooms, but steal the rooms themselves, very rarely.

186
00:12:55,610 --> 00:12:59,327
呃, 不是"非常少", 我觉得, "从没有"才是正在寻找的词
In fact I think, uh, never is probably the word I'm looking for here sir,

187
00:12:59,328 --> 00:13:01,313
我的意思是，这么干有什么好处？
I mean, where's the advantage in it?

188
00:13:01,314 --> 00:13:05,202
在房间这方面不会有太多黑市，是吧？这不会有什么收获！
Not much of a black market in rooms, is there? Wouldn't get much for it!

189
00:13:06,590 --> 00:13:11,532
我知道这很难理解, 也很容易被讽刺
I know it's very difficult to understand. It's also very easy to be sarcastic.

190
00:13:11,744 --> 00:13:16,009
讽刺？我不知道有这个词. 你干嘛不再检查下, 这些不合理的地方？
Sarcastic sir? I don't know the word. Now why don't you run over the salient points again?

191
00:13:16,234 --> 00:13:22,208
好吧，当我走到房间的门外时，我打开了, 除此之外什么都没有
Well, when I got to the door of the room and I opened and beyond it there was nothing.

192
00:13:22,520 --> 00:13:24,408
真的什么都没有，先生？
Absolutely nothing at all, sir?

193
00:13:24,409 --> 00:13:28,137
绝对什么都没有，只有一些蓝色的烟雾
Absolutely nothing at all except for some sort of blue haze.

194
00:13:28,419 --> 00:13:32,665
啊, 好吧, 蓝色的烟雾可能是重要的线索
Ah, well, the blue haze may be the vital clue we're searching for.

195
00:13:33,250 --> 00:13:35,742
而且我没喝酒
And I was not drinking.

196
00:13:38,696 --> 00:13:44,488
Romana 不知道 Chronotis 教授, 或者说 Salyavin 是否依然在Shada上活着
Romana wondered wherever Professor Chronotis or Salyavin was still alive on Shada,

197
00:13:44,489 --> 00:13:48,711
考虑到教授第一次就知道叫我来地球的原因是
considering the reason the Professor had called me to Earth in the first place was

198
00:13:48,712 --> 00:13:51,645
因为他认为他快死了
because he thought he was nearing the end of his life.

199
00:13:53,064 --> 00:13:55,143
所以这就是那扇著名的门，是它吧先生？
So this is the famous door, is it sir?

200
00:13:55,334 --> 00:13:55,974
是的
Yes.

201
00:13:56,205 --> 00:13:59,166
就在这后面你看到了蓝色的烟雾？
Behind which you saw your blue haze?

202
00:13:59,385 --> 00:14:00,172
是的
Yes.

203
00:14:02,292 --> 00:14:03,519
进来！
Come in!

204
00:14:07,588 --> 00:14:10,201
好吧，带着它的人先生看起来带它回来了
Well, whoever took it sir seems to have brought it back.

205
00:14:12,731 --> 00:14:16,578
“...她的小礼服，这是她的最爱”老人大喊道
''...her little homely dress, her favourite,' cried the old man,

206
00:14:16,579 --> 00:14:22,649
把它放在胸前，用已经萎缩的手拍拍, “她会在她醒过来的时候想它的”
pressing it to his breast and patting it with a shrivelled hand.'She'll miss it when she wakes.''

207
00:14:23,104 --> 00:14:24,976
你好？我能帮你吗？
Hello? Can I help you?

208
00:14:25,468 --> 00:14:30,587
例行检查，先生. 有人说这个房间被偷走了
Routine inquiry, sir. Report that this room had been stolen.

209
00:14:30,873 --> 00:14:33,689
被偷走了！！我可不这样认为, 长官
Stolen!! I don't think so! Officer!

210
00:14:34,878 --> 00:14:37,643
给你, 一杯茶和一些阿司匹林
Here you are.Cup of tea and some aspirin.

211
00:14:37,865 --> 00:14:38,482
谢谢，教授
Thank you, Professor.

212
00:14:38,484 --> 00:14:39,800
阿司匹林，先生？
Aspirin, sir?

213
00:14:39,876 --> 00:14:40,872
是的，头痛
Yes, headache.

214
00:14:41,049 --> 00:14:42,149
昨晚是糟糕的一晚吗，先生？
Bad night last night, sir?

215
00:14:42,318 --> 00:14:43,420
是的，你可以这样说
Yes, you could say that.

216
00:14:44,909 --> 00:14:47,786
大学正在举行大量庆祝活动，先生是在那吗？昨晚？
A lot of celebrating going on in college, was there sir? Last night?

217
00:14:47,946 --> 00:14:49,148
没什么不寻常的事
Nothing out of the ordinary.

218
00:14:49,283 --> 00:14:51,967
正常的大型聚会会那样吗先生，会吗？
Big normal hijinks that would be then sir, would it?

219
00:14:51,968 --> 00:14:55,942
学生在街头流窜偷警察的头盔，讴歌，还……
Students roaming the streets stealing policeman's helmets, ballads, and...

220
00:15:00,787 --> 00:15:03,463
先生 请问你明白我的意思吗？
Might I ask where you got that, sir?

221
00:15:04,056 --> 00:15:05,423
是的，那就是我的
Yes, it's mine.

222
00:15:06,226 --> 00:15:07,376
真的吗,先生？
Oh really sir?

223
00:15:07,555 --> 00:15:08,434
是的，没错
Yes, really.

224
00:15:08,625 --> 00:15:09,550
来吧Romana
Come on Romana.

225
00:15:09,706 --> 00:15:13,378
再见Wilken, Bristol, Keightley, 再见教授，我们会保守你的秘密
Bye Wilken, Bristol, Keightley, goodbye Professor, we'll keep your secret.

226
00:15:13,618 --> 00:15:14,608
各位再见
Bye everybody.

227
00:15:14,784 --> 00:15:18,101
秘密,先生？是什么秘密？
Secret sir? And what secret would that be?

228
00:15:25,315 --> 00:15:26,677
来杯茶吗？
Cup of tea?

229
00:15:29,766 --> 00:15:31,456
那个警察亭去哪了？
Where did that police box just go?

230
00:15:32,655 --> 00:15:34,983
什么警察亭，长官？
What police box that would be, Officer?

231
00:15:38,153 --> 00:15:46,128
很好，很好 各位穿上外套 陪我去派出所喝茶吧
Right. Right. Coats on everyone. You're all taking a little walk with me down to the Bridewell.

232
00:15:49,055 --> 00:15:55,090
Romana说她好不容易才发现 教授就是那个伟大的Salyavin
Romana explained that she found it hard that the Professor was the great Salyavin.

233
00:15:55,091 --> 00:15:57,484
他看起来是个很好的老人
He seem to be a nice old man.

234
00:15:57,485 --> 00:16:05,140
而且我猜在一百年里会有人碰上我说，“那真的是博士吗？
And I speculated that in a hundred years someone will meet me and say, 'Is that really the Doctor?

235
00:16:05,141 --> 00:16:08,655
多奇怪 他看起来是个如此友善的老人”
How strange. He seems such a nice old man.'

