(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
JO: Ogrons!
You, come.
What's next?
SECRETARY: The Historical Monuments
Preservation Society
wants you to address their
annual meeting on the 10th of January.
Mmm. Clashes with a cabinet meeting.
Um, express apologies.
Congratulate them on their good work.
And there's an inquiry reporting
on the anti-Draconian riots
in Peking last week.
The petitioners seek your support
for compensation.
(PRESIDENT SIGHING)
Pass that onto the Treasury
with my recommendation.
All claims to be
sympathetically considered.
-Anything else?
-General Williams requires an interview.
-He says it's extremely urgent.
-I see.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(GUN FIRING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Get down.
That was close.
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
SECRETARY: General Williams
to see you, madam.
Will you ask him to come in, please.
(BUZZER BUZZING)
(DOOR OPENING)
Vanished. The Draconian kidnappers
have completely disappeared.
No trace of them at all.
-Have some wine?
-Thank you.
Well, at least they didn't
get away with it.
Those two traitors are back in their
cell and that's where they'll stay.
The time has come for extreme measures.
I know. You want me to
break off diplomatic relations.
I want more than that.
This is a military situation.
We should attack now.
No. I will not be responsible
for starting a war.
There is one thing worse than war,
Madam President and that is defeat.
You must think of your own position.
-What about my position?
-If you're not seen to act decisively
against the Draconians,
you can and will be replaced.
(SCOFFING)
By you perhaps?
We used to be friends once.
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
I know what's happened
has changed all that,
but do you really think I'd betray you?
No. No. I've never doubted you.
I'm sorry.
There are certain
senior officers who feel
that a military dictatorship is needed.
Your political opponents
are clamouring for war.
You must act now
or they will bring you down.
I shall break off diplomatic relations.
The Draconian Ambassador and his staff
will be expelled from this planet.
I shall inform the Emperor that
his actions will no longer be tolerated.
But unless you give me conclusive
evidence about their intentions,
I shall not strike the first blow.
The proof you need is in the minds
of those two traitors.
We shall have to use the mind probe.
Not on the girl.
-Perhaps I can make her see reason.
-I doubt that.
I prefer to put my faith
in the mind probe.
WILLIAMS: Well, Doctor,
shall we try again?
You can suit yourself.
But I warn you,
you're wasting your time.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Are you a member of
the Draconian Secret Service?
No.
No change in the rhythm, sir.
He must be telling the truth.
How did you get on the cargo ship?
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
I came here in my own ship, the TARDIS.
-TARDIS?
-Yes, my own spaceship.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Why did you help the Draconians
attack the cargo ship?
DOCTOR: I didn't.
In any case, it wasn't the Draconians,
it was the Ogrons.
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
Your machine can't be working properly.
Or else he's controlling it.
We've checked all the circuits, sir.
Those are his thoughts.
We know this man is a Draconian agent.
He must be lying.
Perhaps he's already
been brainwashed, sir.
But as far as he's concerned,
what he's telling us is the truth.
Then we must break through
his conditioning.
Unless you tell me the truth,
the real truth,
I shall be forced to use
increased power.
I wouldn't do that, old man.
I know these machines.
They aren't awfully reliable, you know?
You'd do better to worry about
the effects on your mind.
There's just no telling some people,
is there, my dear?
Step up the power.
Increase to 12.
Now!
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Are you an agent of the Draconians?
-DOCTOR: No.
-When do they plan to attack us?
They don't.
-How did you board the cargo ship?
-Through the TARDIS.
Who first recruited you
to serve the Draconians?
-No one.
-WILLIAMS: Who are the other
-Draconian agents on Earth?
-I don't know.
WILLIAMS: The truth, man.
I want the truth.
-I'm telling you the truth.
-WILLIAMS: I will get the truth.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(MIND PROBE SPARKING)
Doctor, are you sure you're all right?
Mmm-hmm, apart from a bit of a headache.
I like the new outfit.
Who are you fighting tonight?
(JO CHUCKLING)
What happened to you, anyway?
Oh, they kept going on at me to confess.
Yeah, it's awkward, isn't it?
Well, they've made up
their minds, you see.
They'll only believe us if we tell them
what they want to hear.
It's a pity really that the Ogrons
didn't succeed in kidnapping us.
Perhaps we should have
been more helpful.
-Why?
-Well, if they had succeeded,
presumably they'd have taken us
to where the TARDIS is.
(SIGHING) I'm sorry, Jo,
but I'm afraid another kidnapping
attempt is our only ray of hope.
So, we just sit around here waiting for
those jolly old Ogrons to turn up again?
(CHUCKLING) That's about it, yes.
The President wants to see you.
Get moving.
Not you. You.
This maybe your chance. Good luck.
-See you later.
-Bye.
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm giving you a final chance
to tell me the truth.
Madam President,
I've been telling you the truth
for some considerable time
but you just won't believe me.
I can't think why you chose
to work for the Draconians.
But whatever it is, I'll double
any offer they've made to you.
That's very generous of you, madam,
but you'd only be buying information
that doesn't exist.
You leave me no alternative.
Under the powers invested in me
by the Special Security Act,
I'm sending you to
the Lunar Penal Colony.
What, without a trial?
Without even a chance to state my case?
So, you're just tucking me
quietly away, are you?
What about my companion?
She will remain here.
I have hopes that, away
from your influence,
I might be able to make her
see the error of her ways.
But you will see that
she comes to no harm?
We are not barbarians.
If you want to help her,
why don't you tell me
where she comes from?
I'd like to inform her family.
I'd like to, madam.
I really would, but there's nothing
that I can say that you'd believe.
May I say goodbye to her?
No! You'll be leaving immediately
for the penal colony.
We're putting you where your Draconian
friends will be unable to reach you.
Over there.
Get in line and face the front!
Face the front!
(PATEL SIGHING)
What did they get you for?
Oh, it's a long story.
I don't think you'd believe me
even if I told you.
You are a political, aren't you?
-Not particularly, no.
-Oh, come off it!
Only politicals get sent to the Moon,
none of your common criminals.
Have you got many
political prisoners here?
Thousands. Well, I mean,
criticise the government
and you're for it, aren't you?
You a member of the Peace Party?
Well, you might put it like that, yes.
Yes, I tried to stop a war.
Me too. I tried to sabotage
a military base.
Did you? How long is your sentence?
Sen... Where have you been?
There are no sentences.
Once they send you to the Moon,
it's forever.
(DOOR OPENING)
-No talking!
-Get in line!
What have you got in there?
-Nothing.
-Show me.
Chocolate.
My allowance from the remand prison.
No chocolate allowed here.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Now that's stealing, you know.
That's what I'm in for.
Got a troublemaker, have we?
-I'll remember you.
-Good, I'm glad to hear it.
LUNAR GUARD: Attention!
CROSS: New arrivals, sir.
I'm the Governor of this penal colony.
There's one rule here,
you do as you're told.
If you behave yourselves,
you'll be reasonably treated,
but you have no rights
and there is no means of escape.
You'll do well to remember that
you're here for the rest of your lives.
Why is that man not in uniform?
Don't know, sir.
That's how they sent him.
Special security prisoner.
-See he's kitted out immediately.
-Sir.
We won't be staying here forever,
you know!
The Peace Party will win one day.
Very well, Cross,
I'll leave them to you.
Sir.
That's probably the last time
you'll see the Governor.
But you'll see me every day.
Now I run a nice,
quiet, tidy section here.
Any trouble,
it's a black mark on my records,
so there's never any trouble, got it?
Look, don't you realise
you're one of us?
We're all prisoners here!
Victims of the system!
Belt up, you!
You, kit out that man. Come with me.
I thought you said
there were no common criminals here?
(PATEL SIGHING)
Cross is a trusty.
They are all hardcore criminals
specially imported from other prisons.
Professor Dale?
You were on our youth committee,
were you not?
(LAUGHING) That's right, sir.
Oh, we met last year,
just before your arrest.
Well, you'll find yourself in
very good company here, my boy.
I sometimes think there are more
members of the Peace Party up here
than back on Earth.
(PATEL LAUGHING)
Don't any of you ever try to escape?
Escape? Occasionally. Why do you ask?
-It seems a perfectly natural question.
-Do you know this man?
Uh, no, sir. I met him on the shuttle.
I'd better get you a uniform.
Come this way.
PRESIDENT: There's no doubt about it.
These are the same people.
No doubt. But that doesn't mean
we should hand them over to anyone.
(BEEPING)
(SIGHING) I'm surprised,
especially about the girl.
All these crimes!
Just the sort of people
the Draconians would employ.
Nevertheless, the dominion government
of Sirius 4 does have a claim to them.
And so do we.
They have vital information.
They must be very important to them.
I think I'd better see
their representative.
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
Send in the Commissioner
from Sirius 4, please.
Surely you're not going to
hand them over?
Well, we'll have to see, won't we?
Relationships with the colony
of planets are always difficult.
And if there is a war, we'll need
all the allies we can get, won't we?
(DOOR OPENING)
The Commissioner, madam.
Madam President,
this is indeed a great honour.
(SIGHING) Check and mate.
DALE: Yes, there's an excellent library.
There are books, videofilms,
handicrafts and discussion groups,
all sorts of ways of passing the time.
Including planning to escape?
That's not one of the things we discuss.
Oh, why? Doesn't anybody ever try?
Occasionally.
There was an attempt last month.
Yes, what did happen?
What always happens, they are dead.
No one escapes from here.
No. No, quite so.
But there's got to be a first time
for everything, hasn't there?
Come on, Professor, come and tell me
all you know about the layout here.
Truly, Madam President, I...
I sympathise with your position.
But my government has sought
these criminals throughout the galaxy.
They are now prisoners
of the government of Earth.
That's good enough.
With the greatest respect,
General Williams, I must disagree.
They are citizens of Sirius 4.
Part of Earth's empire.
Yes, but it has been granted
dominion status.
He has a point, General Williams.
Once a colony has been raised
to dominion status,
it enjoys certain autonomous rights,
including the right to try
and punish its own citizens.
Exactly. But I feel sure that
once these two have come to trial,
my government will be only too happy
to send them back to you
for further interrogation.
But, meanwhile, my orders are clear.
I must take them back
with me to Sirius 4.
I will not hand over vital prisoners
to some tin-pot colony!
As the commissioner has
pointed out, General Williams,
Sirius 4 is no longer a colony.
It is a dominion.
Your request is granted.
Madam President, I am most grateful.
Heaven help you if you let them escape!
You may rest assured, General Williams,
they will be perfectly safe with me.
Right, keep it moving!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Is this all we get?
It contains all the elements
to support life.
Mmm, and absolutely nothing
to make it enjoyable, eh?
You get used to it after a month or two.
Anyway, it's all we ever get.
-Keep moving!
-You heard him, move!
Not exactly friendly, are they?
One gets used to it.
What time do we get to bed?
Anytime. There's no day or night here.
No. Uh, tell me, Professor, when...
When do you plan to escape?
No one escapes from here.
But you're going to try?
For all I know,
you could be a spy for the Governor.
If I were, I'd hardly be
drawing attention to myself
quite so quickly, now would I?
No, a valid point of logic.
I wonder if I can trust you?
You've little
or no alternative, Professor.
We're all in this sector together.
Whatever you do, I shall know about it.
Yes, but we don't know you.
Why did they send you here?
Oh, I was sent here at the express wish
of a certain General Williams.
We have no proof of that.
We have no reason to tell you anything.
I'll tell you something.
There is a conspiracy to start a war
between Earth and Draconia.
There are warmongers on both sides.
We are aware of that.
But there's also
a third party, Professor,
who's plotting to set the two empires
at each other's throats.
No, I'll see her alone.
Penny for them, Miss Grant?
You! What are you doing here?
To coin a phrase,
I've come to take you
away from all this.
-What are you talking about?
-Well, surely you don't want to spend
the rest of your life in here, do you?
Well, I'm not going anywhere with you,
that's for sure.
Oh, but you are, you know.
Believe it or not,
I am a fully accredited commissioner
from the planet Sirius 4
and you and the Doctor
are two dangerous criminals
being handed over into my custody.
So it was you!
You ordered those Ogrons
to attack the ships
and pretend they were Draconians!
But, of course!
Those lumbering idiots
could never have thought up
such a brilliant scheme by themselves.
Why did you want to start a war?
Now, come on, Miss Grant, be reasonable.
You want to see
the Doctor again, don't you?
-Where is he?
-He's in another prison, on the Moon.
We're going to collect him.
How do I know you're telling the truth?
You don't.
And the only way you'll find out
is by coming with me.
Well?
(SIGHING)
How did you know
we were here in the first place?
Well, after they'd attacked
the cargo ships,
the Ogrons returned to their planet,
taking their loot with them.
Now imagine my surprise, and my delight,
when I found that
they brought me the Doctor's TARDIS.
And why are you taking us with you?
Oh, need you ask?
How could I leave two dear friends
in such dire straits?
Oh, you don't seriously think that
I'm going to believe that
you want to help us...
Believe what you like, Miss Grant,
I have my reasons.
Now, are you coming,
or do you really wish to vegetate in
this hole for the rest of your natural?
Very well. I'll come.
Excellent!
The prisoner and I
are ready to leave now, guard.
Anywhere is better than here.
DOCTOR: Well, there you are.
There you have it.
That's how I came to be here.
It's fantastic!
I mean, our people seeing Draconians,
Draconians seeing Earthmen.
I can't believe it.
Well, I can.
Good grief.
Do you know, sir, you're
the first person who's believed me?
It would explain a great deal.
After the stupidity of
the Draconian war,
the bitterness eventually died down
and we had many years of peace.
There were trade treaties,
cultural exchanges and then,
for no reason at all,
these sudden acts of hostility.
(DOOR OPENING)
Dale! Over here!
-Yes, what is it?
-Spot check. You ought to know.
If you'll excuse me,
one of our little prison rituals.
This is it. There's a VIP landing
on this spaceship
in 10 minutes' time, Bay 7.
You can pinch it.
I've set up two spacesuits for you.
I can't believe it.
Well, I keep my promises,
now you keep yours.
When you get back to Earth,
don't forget who your friends are.
When the Peace Party takes over,
you will be given a free pardon,
you have my word.
Right, you're clean. Report to
Air lock 3 for maintenance work.
You and one other.
You can choose him yourselves, okay.
-DOCTOR: What is it? What's up?
-Oh,just a search.
All part of the routine.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Come on, Professor. Come on!
You were giving off conspiracy
in waves over there.
You can trust me, you know.
The escape plan, it's now.
We have to walk from the air lock,
across the Moon's surface.
We're going to steal a spaceship.
They've left two spacesuits for us.
Who are you taking with you?
Well, I had planned
to take another member
of the Peace Party committee
but I'm afraid he'll have to
give up his place.
Doctor, I want you to come with me.
Well, that's very generous
of you, but...
We must get you back to Earth
so that you can tell your story.
Well, it was telling my story on Earth
that got me sent here
in the first place.
We have contacts everywhere,
journalists, broadcasters,
even friends in the government.
We'll make them believe you.
Thank you, Professor.
You don't know what it means to me
to have found allies at last.
Well, we'd better be going, Doctor.
This spaceship
will be landing any moment.
Good! He's left it open.
Excellent! Excellent!
Come on, Doctor, we haven't got long.
Take this one?
We can't use the main entrance
to the spaceport.
It's too well guarded.
All we have to do is to walk
across the Moon's surface,
about 10 minutes and we're there.
Tell me, Professor,
why is Cross helping you?
A kind of bribery, I'm afraid.
I promised to get him a free pardon
once we get into power.
That's extraordinary. I would have
thought he would have wanted something
far more positive than promises.
DALE: Oh, he's not a bad fellow
when you get to know him.
I appealed to his better self.
Now do hurry, Doctor.
(ZIPPER FASTENING)
(AIR HISSING)
What's that?
I thought I heard something.
Yes. Now, Doctor,
clip my cylinder on the back of my suit
and then I'll fix up yours.
DOCTOR: All right.
-Well, this one's empty.
-It can't be.
Well, it certainly is.
Take a look for yourself.
There, look at the gauge.
Yes, and so is this one.
They're both empty, Professor.
(AIR HISSING)
The door, it's locked!
-Listen.
-They're depressurising.
Don't you understand, man,
they're pumping out the air!