(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(AIR HISSING)
The door, it's locked!
-They're depressurising.
-Listen.
Don't you understand, man!
They're pumping out the air!
-We're, we're going to suffocate!
-Of course we're not.
That's no good.
They...they'll never hear us.
Well, they certainly won't
if we don't try.
DALE: Help! Help! Help!
Professor, don't shout!
You'll just waste oxygen.
Come on, Professor, come on.
Come on, up you get.
(AIR HISSING)
Listen! Listen, it worked!
I do hope that you're all right, Doctor.
(SIGHING) You...
Yes, I might have guessed.
I'd hate you to come
to any harm, you know?
It was a deliberate attempt
at cold-blooded murder, Governor.
And I demand an enquiry.
You were trying to escape.
You've only yourselves to blame
for the consequences.
I also believe there was a conspiracy
to destroy this man
because he's politically dangerous
to you.
How dare you!
Cross said he would help us to escape
and he left spacesuits for us
in the airlock.
With no oxygen in the cylinders.
Is there any truth in this?
No, sir. They stole the suits.
Must have messed it up
and taken ones with empty cylinders.
And I take it that we also locked
ourselves in the air lock
from the outside,
and switched off the air supply, mmm?
He does have a point there, you know,
Governor. Had it not been...
Maybe another prisoner did it.
You know, one who had it in for 'em?
You are both guilty
of attempting to escape.
You will both be placed in solitary
confinement for the next year.
Uh,just a moment, Governor.
Do what you will with the old man,
but that one comes with me.
Out of the question, I'm afraid.
He has committed an internal offence
and is subject to prison discipline.
Take them away.
Sorry about this, sir.
I'll see it doesn't happen again.
Yes, it had better not.
All right, you can go.
Sir.
You know, I do wish
that you'd reconsider, Governor.
Obtaining custody of that prisoner
is very important to me.
And I do have a warrant.
It's out of the question, I'm afraid.
You see, he is under punishment.
When he's completed his solitary
confinement, I'll reconsider.
I see.
You know, I have a theory
about this incident.
It's no concern of yours.
I think that those two prisoners
were telling the truth.
I think that your trusty Cross
was helping them.
Why should he do that?
On your instructions.
-That is an outrageous suggestion...
-Oh, come, Governor!
You rid yourself
of a politically dangerous prisoner
and foster the legend
that escape is impossible in one go.
I must congratulate you.
You're being very impertinent!
Suppose I were to support the Doctor's
demand for an official enquiry?
Some very awkward questions
could be asked.
-I have nothing to fear.
-Haven't you?
Oh, come, Governor.
Hand the Doctor over to me
and I promise you
he'll be no further trouble to you.
Well, I've no wish to be uncooperative.
What would you do with him?
Oh, take him back to Sirius 4
and see that he stands trial.
(EXCLAIMING) You wouldn't believe
the list of crimes he's committed.
I'm releasing you into the custody
of this commissioner.
He will fly you back to Sirius 4
to stand trial.
And may I ask
what I'm supposed to have done there?
(MASTER CLEARING THROAT)
"Defrauding the Sirius 4 Dominion Bank,
evasion of planetary income tax,
"assault and battery committed upon the
person of a Sirius 4 police official,
"taking a spaceship without authority
and piloting the said spaceship
"without payment of tax and insurance.
Landing said spaceship
"on an unauthorised area of Sirius 3."
Need I go on?
(SCOFFING) I seem to be
quite the master criminal, don't I?
You don't mean to say
that you really believe
all this nonsense, do you, Governor?
Whatever credentials
that he's shown you are forged.
Oh, come, Doctor, you know the game's
up. Why not admit defeat?
You know, this man always works
with an accomplice, a girl.
(CHUCKLING) I've got her
under lock and key in my ship.
Well, Doctor, are you coming quietly?
-Hello, Jo.
-Doctor!
-How are you? All right?
-Well...
Right, they'll be plenty of time
for the exchange of social pleasantries.
Put him inside.
Thank you, gentlemen.
You can leave them to me now.
Well, Doctor,
this is an interesting reversal.
I remember your once visiting me
when I was in prison.
You know, I'd very much
like to know why...
Why you've been locked up?
No, why I'm still alive.
Oh, come, your health is very precious
to me, for the moment.
You see, my employers
are most interested in you.
-The Ogrons?
-Miss Grant, please! I employ them.
Yes, well, whatever it is you're up to,
you needn't expect any help from me.
I don't need any help.
Your simple presence
will be quite enough.
Oh, by the way, I need hardly warn you
there is no point in trying to escape.
This is an interplanetary
police spaceship,
specially built for carrying prisoners,
as you can see.
Stolen, of course?
(SCOFFING) Of course.
Oh, and another thing...
There's a closed-circuit television
camera trained on you from up there,
so you will be
under continuous observation.
I think that's all.
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some rather complicated
astro-navigational calculations
to work out.
May I ask where we're going?
Certainly. To the home of our friends,
the Ogrons.
A barren and uninteresting planet
on the remote fringes of the galaxy.
Why are you taking us there?
That, Miss Grant,
you will discover when you arrive.
Right, now listen to me.
We haven't got much time
before he gets back to the flight deck.
Now, the first thing
we've got to do is to escape.
Now, they took my sonic screwdriver
from me in the prison
but they didn't get a hold of this.
-A steel file.
-Right, let's go.
No, not yet. Let's wait
till he gets back to the flight deck,
then he'll set the controls.
Now, this is an automatic spaceship.
Once we're underway,
the computers take over, right?
-Okay, so what's the plan?
-Now this is what we're gonna do.
(SIGHING)
(BEEPING)
Right, you'd better hold on in there,
you two. We're about to lift off.
(MASTER SIGHING)
So I told the High Council
of the Time Lords,
I said they had absolutely no right
to put me on trial in the first place.
Well, if I chose to go wandering around
the universe in my own time,
that was my business.
What about stealing the TARDIS?
I didn't steal it. I just borrowed it.
I fully intended to return it,
I assure you.
Anyway, she wasn't exactly
the latest model, poor old thing.
JO: (LAUGHING) You can say that again.
I tell you, I made a complete fool
of that prosecuting council, though.
I ridiculed his every argument.
Yes, and I told him
that I had the complete answer
to every one his charges against me.
JO: And then what happened?
DOCTOR: Then what happened, well,
they found me guilty,
changed my appearance
and exiled me to Earth.
JO: And that's where you met me!
That's right. That's where I met you.
And that alone
made the exile worthwhile, Miss Grant.
JO: Thank you!
Not that there's anything wrong
with Earth.
Well, it's quite a nice, little planet
in its own way, but...
After all, I am a Time Lord,Jo,
and I think I've deserve my freedom.
-JO: Right!
-In reminiscent mood, are you, Doctor?
Poor Miss Grant,
you have my deepest sympathy.
(CHUCKLING)
As I soon realised,
the trouble with Lethbridge-Stewart
is that he's got a military mind.
Well, he is a brigadier, after all.
I mean, what do you expect?
No, that's just the trouble though.
He's hidebound, you see.
He always does everything by the rules.
I keep telling him.
I said, "There are times, you know,
"when you've simply got to cut
right through the red tape."
And you've managed to do that, have you?
DOCTOR: Yes, I've managed to cut
right through it.
And I'm not going to let authority
stand between me and my freedom.
(SIGHING) Lethbridge-Stewart, I...
Hey! As far as he's concerned I've been
absent without leave all this time.
I'm always telling people
that you've no idea
where you're going
in that TARDIS of yours.
I mean, you're supposed to be getting me
back to Earth, right?
And we keep landing up in one
terrible situation after the other.
I mean, when I get back,
I'll probably be court-martialled
and then I'll be put in a cell again.
That's if we do get back,
and the way things are going,
it doesn't look like it.
But if we do get back, I'm telling you
one thing, right here and now...
I'm never going up in that TARDIS
with you again.
But if we do get back,
I really think you ought to be
a bit more reasonable with the Master.
I mean, he keeps offering you a share
in the galaxy, or whatever's going on,
and you keep refusing him
and playing dirty tricks on him.
But, you see,
the trouble is with you is,
well, you're so stiff-necked.
I mean,
you've got to realise that, this time,
the Master has won.
You might as well make the best
out of a terrible situation.
I mean, look at it now. Here we are...
(LOWERING VOLUME)
Goodness knows where he's taking us to.
I mean,just a few of those Ogrons
is bad enough.
Can you imagine, I mean imagine,
a whole planet of them?
Still, I suppose it's all my own
fault really.
I mean, if I hadn't asked my uncle to
pull those strings and get me that job,
I'd never have landed up in this mess
in the first place.
You know, some people think that it's
very romantic working in intelligence.
Oh, but, my goodness,
I could tell you it's not.
I mean, they think that I run
around all day
with a terrific-looking James Bond star
going to suave dinner parties.
Oh, but I don't, you know.
I mean, I dine with the Brigadier
and I'm doing the filing at HQ,
which is very, very difficult,
or else I'm running around making tea
and being general dogsbody.
I mean, the time's come,
really, when I'm...
(JO TALKING OVER INTERCOM)
(BEEPING)
You'd better hold on again,
you two in there.
Doctor, Miss Grant, I'm going to make
a rather sharp course correction.
It'll only last a moment.
Is everything all right, Miss Grant?
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
MASTER: You appear a little distressed?
No, I'm... I'm just a bit shaken,
that's all.
Yes, I can quite understand.
And how about you, Doctor?
No ill effects, I hope?
Doctor, are you all right?
JO: Please don't wake him.
He's...he's fast asleep.
Is he? How very relaxed of him.
(SIGHING) You really ought to be
more careful, Doctor.
I mean, I know there's a
lot of...a lot of evil in the universe,
but you can't help to put it
all right by yourself.
I mean, one of these days
your luck will run out
and you'll get yourself killed!
MASTER: Thank you, Miss Grant,
we'll let you know!
Where's the Doctor?
MASTER ON MONITOR: I say,
he has been busy, hasn't he?
Where is he, Miss Grant?
JO ON INTERCOM: He's gone.
MASTER: I see. He found a spacesuit and
he's gone into the air lock, is that it?
Why? What's his plan?
(SNIFFLING) He wanted to get
to the flight deck.
He was outside the ship
when you made your course correction!
Was he now?
(LAUGHING) How very unfortunate.
By now he's probably
thousands of miles away,
swimming around in space by himself.
(JO SOBBING)
But just in case he isn't,
you come with me, Miss Grant.
Come on!
Right, in you go, Miss Grant.
Can you hear me, Doctor?
Are you on the flight deck?
If so, listen to this.
Miss Grant is in the air lock.
Unless you surrender yourself
to me immediately,
I shall open the outer door
and hurl her into space.
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
What an ingenious fellow
you are, Doctor!
DOCTOR: Oh, no, you don't!
(GRUNTING)
JO: Please let me out!
Doctor! Please let me out, somebody!
(MASTER EXCLAIMING)
Now hold it, Doctor, hold it!
Get that blaster over to me
or I press this button,
and that will be the end of Miss Grant!
Thank you, Doctor.
(THUDDING)
Well, we appear to have company.
Would these be your Ogron friends?
Why, no, no.
Well, I should try and be
a bit more hospitable, old chap.
Come on, put that gun away.
They've probably got us outnumbered.
Welcome on board my ship.
To what do I owe the honour?
Why have you violated
the Draconian frontier?
Uh, yes, I'm most apologetic about that,
but it was really beyond my control.
You see, my prisoners
were trying to escape and my...
-My ship was thrown off course.
-Prisoners?
Yes, I am the commissioner
of Earth's Interplanetary Police.
I'm taking these two people back
to planet Sirius 4 for...for trial.
Uh, here is my warrant of authority.
Now, don't believe this man, he's lying.
I'm not concerned in disputes
between Earthmen.
Owing to the many insults and outrages
committed against the empire
of Draconia,
a state of emergency exists
and all diplomatic relations
have been severed.
You have violated Draconian space.
The penalty is death.
I insist on speaking
to higher authority!
You are in Draconian space.
I am the authority here.
Captain, you cannot condemn us
without a trial.
Now, I have vital information
for your Emperor.
At least give me the chance
to speak to him?
We shall take them to Draconia.
Put them in the cage.
But you can't do that!
I'm a commissioner
of Interplanetary Police!
This is my spaceship!
I tell you, you can't do that!
Well, personally I'm quite happy
to be going to Draconia, Jo.
Perhaps we can convince the Emperor
what our friend here
has been trying to do.
You really think he'd believe you?
Well, this won't be my first visit
to Draconia, you know?
Many years ago,
I spent quite some time there.
I was able to help them through a period
of very great difficulty.
(SCOFFING) Displaying your usual
sickening lovability, I suppose?
So there's a good chance
that they'll believe you, huh?
Well, it was a long time ago.
Things may have changed.
But I do understand
the Draconian mentality, Jo.
It all depends how you approach them.
So, if they do believe the Doctor,
you've had it!
Perhaps, Miss Grant, perhaps.
But one never knows
when help may be at hand.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I think that this is going to be
rather a long journey,
so, uh, good night.
We'll wake you with a cup of tea
in the morning.
Thank you.
(CLICKING)