Move on!
The Dalek!
What about it?
Can't you see it's armed?
Keep moving!
This area is restricted.
On whose authority?
Silence!
Repeat. This area is restricted.
Obey or you shall be exterminated.
I thought they obeyed us?
What do we do now, Doctor?
This way.
They will be exterminated.
We've won. The revolution's over. I'll pass the word to Valmar, Kebble and the rest.
Wait. The revolution is not quite over yet.
What more can we do? Hensell's dead, you're the new Governor. The battle's over.
Not quite. You mentioned Kebble, Valmar and that rabble. Well now they must be dealt with.
But those are our own men.
Huh, huh. Of course.
I don't understand.
Do you think I can ever be secure in that chair while that rabble are still loose? They rebelled against Hensell yesterday. Tomorrow it'll be my turn. Well, let them rebel. Tell them the guards have taken control. Let them attack, and then we can crush them, utterly!
You say "we".
Yes. We've come a long way together you and I. You going to back down now?
Couldn't you just arrest them?
Everyone must be killed.
Now!
What have you brought me in here for?
Quiet!
Whose side are you on anyway?
I thought I was going to be on the winning side.
What changed your mind?
Bragen. The colony's become too small for him. He wants us out of the way now.
Yeah, well it often happens that way, mate, when you follow blokes like him.
Look, I'm going to try and get your friends here, if I can. So wait here.
People of Vulcan. This is your new Governor talking to you. I have to announce that Governor Hensell has been murdered by the rebels. I have taken control temporarily, until order is restored. People living on the perimeter and in the interior can stay calm. We know who the murderers are.
I shall keep you informed of events as soon as I am able, so listen for the signal to watch your communication sets. That is all.
Ah! There you are.
- Ben!
- I knew you'd be all right!
Polly - you okay?
Oh, yes.
Did Valmar find you, then?
Valmar? No.
What's this about Valmar?
Well it seems Bragen's gone power-mad. He wants the rebels to revolt, then he can finish them off.
The Daleks won't care who they fight. They'll exterminate every human being on this planet.
Doctor, please let's go back to the TARDIS.
Quinn. Keep them both here.
Well, wait a minute, Doctor!
All right. All right.
Orders received. Daleks commence extermination.
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
Down everyone!
Don't come any nearer.
What do you mean?
I overheard your conversation with Bragen. But you can't stand up to the Daleks, so your plan will come to nothing.
Not my plan - Bragen's.
But that's the same thing.
Not any more.
You expect me to believe that?
I came here to do exactly what you've done. Let Bragen see what the Daleks are like. He doesn't know how strong they are.
He's got to be stopped.
You will lead us to the middle of your party of human beings.
Yes.
We will fight for you.
Believe me, Val, it's the only way to save all our lives.
Did you know that the Daleks are duplicating?
Yes.
But we are your friends.
We will serve you.
Take us to the centre of your group.
Can we trust them?
We must! The guards have orders to wipe us out. We must use the Daleks. Come on.
Doctor!
The window. Does it open?
I dunno.
It had better, or we're done for! Out you go.
Ah!... Ah!... What's happening?
The Daleks. They're teeming all over the corridors. We've got to get back to Lesterson's lab.
This is Governor Bragen speaking. A group of rebels is attempting to take over the colony. It is the duty of all loyal citizens to help the guards resist. Stay in your homes. Order will be restored. Listen to my bulletins.
The rebels are using the Daleks against our people!
Well, get back and fight! Why do you come running to me? What do you think your guns are for?
Well, the guns don't work against them!
Get back and fight them!
There, and there!
Over there!
No! No! Over there! They're our people!
Cut the Dalek gun off!
No! Ah!...
I told you to cut the gun off!
I did!
You've killed our own people!
We have to dismantle the gun, that's all.
Oh, look at it.
Your usefulness is over.
Come on!
Quick, Val. Come on!
Doctor, it's stupid to hide in here!
Well, do you fancy your chances outside in the corridor? No thanks.
The answer must be here somewhere.
Ssssh!
Ah!...
You must be absolutely quiet. They know everything that's going on. Everything! They even know what you're thinking.
Where do they get their power from, Lesterson?
Ah, I tried to turn the power off. But they were miles ahead of me. Marvellous creatures. You have to admire them.
But we've got to stop them!
Oh, it's too late for that. They're the new species, you see. Taking over from homo sapiens. Man's had his day. Finished now.
The static circuit is nearly complete.
Soon we can abandon the power we are using.
The humans are being exterminated.
Did you hear that? They're going to use their own power!
- No!
- Come on!
- Don't be a fool
- come on!
Take it easy, Polly.
Can't we do anything?! They're murdering everybody, one by one!
You've done all this. Why did you give them power in the first place?
Well, I could control it, you see. And then Janley got one of her men - Valmar, I think it was, yes - and he rigged up a secret cable. It's carrying power directly from the colony's supply.
Where? Where is it, Lesterson?
Valmar's the only one who can answer that. Or the Daleks of course. They know everything. Yes, you should ask the Daleks.
Then we must find Valmar.
No! You stay here and look after Polly.
I'll go.
You'll have to leave her now, Valmar.
Section One? Where's your report? Are you there Section One? Section Two? Section Two? Why don't they answer? Can you hear me Section Two? Section Three? Oh, why don't they answer? I'm their Governor. Why don't they answer?
This is Bragen speaking. I'm speaking to the Daleks. Daleks, listen to me. I am the Governor. You must work for me. Do not trust the rebels. I will give you whatever you want. But immobilise your guns. This is the Governor speaking.
He's nuts, trying to talk to the Daleks.
Lesterson, what's in that cupboard?
Nothing. I think It's quite empty.
Well, come on, Polly, we'll be safe in there, love.
Do you hear me, Daleks?! You will obey my orders!
No use, Bragen. The Daleks have stopped obeying your orders.
Ah! Guards!
Dead! The Daleks have killed them. You still have your guard units in the interior. How long will it take them to get here?
That depends.
Well, get them!
Well, they will be intercepted by the Daleks.
Exactly! It will draw them away from here and give the Doctor a chance to deal with them.
I refuse to allow my guards to be sacrificed.
In that case the Daleks will destroy everything on this colony.
Guards. This is Bragen speaking. All units will report immediately to the capital. Be prepared to face the rebel Daleks.
Ben! Polly!
Doctor, did you hear what Bragen said?
Yes, I did.
Well I only hope the Daleks do go for the guards.
A lot of the Daleks went out just now.
Good, because we're going inside. Come on Valmar. _.
Ben, give us that spare cable over there. Polly, keep watch at the door.
Well, you know what you're doing?
Of course I do!
Well, why can't you just take all the plugs out and cut the power off?
Because I prefer to do it my way!
Look out!
Static power is being stored. We can dismantle the human electric system.
The law of the Daleks is in force.
Extermination of humans.
Our cables have been moved.
And I could tell you who did it!
What were you doing in there?
I want to help you.
Why?
I am your servant.
We do not need humans now.
Ah, then, but you wouldn't kill me. I gave you life.
Yes, you gave us life.
Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!...
Out of control..
What happened to it?
I don't know.
It seems that your friend, the Examiner, was successful after all.
Now I shall restore law and order on this planet.
Not your law, Bragen. That's finished for good.
You'll obey me, or...
Your day is over, Bragen. No one will obey you now.
I'm still the Governor, and you will...
Valmar.
He was a murderer.
Enough of guns.
There's a lot of clearing up to be done. We will rebuild together. What is the extent of the damage?
Oh, I don't know if its repairable. The whole electrical system.
Are you all right?
Oh, he's OK. The clot knocked himself out.
It's a miracle. How did you do it?
Eh? What happened?
You destroyed the Daleks, that's what you did!
Did I do that?
You know you did!
You used the power from the colony's electric supply - overfed it - and blew up their temporary static circuit. Well didn't you?
Did I do all that?
You may have stopped the Daleks, but have you any idea of the damage you've done to the colony?
Oh. There was a blow back, was there?
A blow back? Our power supply has been destroyed! It'll be months before we can get things back to normal.
Valmar!
That is unfortunate.
But did it have to be this way?
I did a lot of damage, did I?
Come on.
I think we'd better get out of here before they send us the bill.
Oh, you needn't worry about them anymore, Doctor. Just a heap of old iron now.