Sincro: wyxchari
His face, his hair - look at it!
He's breathing...
...and the TARDIS seems to be normal.
Ben, what are we going to do? We can't just leave the Doctor there.
What, him? The Doctor?
Ben, do you remember what he said in the tracking room? Something about "This old body of mine is wearing a bit thin. "
So he gets himself a new one?
But it's impossible!
Not so long ago we'd have been saying that about a lot of things.
It's over.
What are we going to do?
It is the Doctor. I know it is... I think.
It's not only his face that's changed - he doesn't even act like him.
Come on, it's time we sorted this out.
Now look here!
Hold that.
And tilt it.
Have you done with this?
Put it down, put it down.
Now, what's the game?
Ah!
The crusades, from Saladin.
The Doctor was a great collector, wasn't he!
But you're the Doctor!
Oh, I don't look like him.
Who are we?
Don't you know?
Extermination!
Now look, the Doctor always wore this. So if you're him, it should fit now, shouldn't it?
There - that settles it.
I'd like to see a butterfly fit into a chrysalis case after it's spread its wings.
Then you did change!
Life depends on change... and renewal.
The Doctor kept a diary, didn't he?
Yes.
I thought so. Now, I wonder where?
I wonder where?
He's a very different Doctor, Ben.
Yeah, maybe. Just where do we stand, though?
Doctor? Doctor, what's going to happen to us?
I think... I think we must have landed for sometime. I think it's time we went for a stroll.
But you don't know where we've landed!
No, you haven't checked the oxygen or the temperature or anything!
Oxygen density one-seven-two, radiation nil, temperature... eighty-six - strong suggestion of mercury deposits. Satisfied, Ben? Now, are you two coming or are you not?
He does know us! He said "Ben", didn't you hear him?
Yeah, I heard.
Are you coming, you two?
Hello?
Hello? Is there anyone there? Hello?
Hello? Why don't they come?
Ah, so you've come at last. I'm from Earth. I'm the Examin...
"Earth Examiner. Accord every access. Vulcan. "
Whoa, they're hot!
Hmm, do you think the air's like this everywhere?
Nah - might be just round here. Don't want too many lung full of it, I know that. Here, when I was a kid, we used to live opposite a brewery. You could take a walk and get tipsy all in one go!
It's beautiful!
No, don't touch it, Polly!
I wasn't going to.
No, it's quicksilver - it gets through the pores.
Where is the Doctor, or whatever he is, got to?
So the murdered man was the real Examiner?
Well, didn't you see who did it?
The Doctor got this button though.
Well, I think it's pretty dull around here. I don't know why we don't just go back to the TARDIS.
Doctor, are you going to let them think you're the real Examiner?
Well, won't that be dangerous?
Look, why don't you stop blowing that thing and talk to us properly?
Ben!
Now don't you start - it's bad enough with him!
Well, he hasn't done anything.
No, that's just the trouble! He knows what happened back at the TARDIS, yet will he tell us? Will he come out and say? Will he admit to being the Doctor?
Come in!
I am Hensell - the Governor.
If Earth had seen fit to warn us you were coming...
If Earth didn't warn you we were coming, Governor, they must have had a very good reason. I wonder what it was?
Now look here - I run this Colony. I'm entitled to know why you've come to Vulcan. What is your brief?
I am the Examiner.
Why are you here?
To examine. And I intend to start my examination at once!
Someone's leaked reports about these rebel groups - that's it, isn't it?
There is Lesterson's capsule.
Internal affairs are my business, Bragen. Please don't interfere!
Please go on.
The capsule. It was found in a mercury swamp. It must have been here for centuries before...
...the Earth colony arrived. I felt it might be dangerous, it might contain bacteria.
I shall examine the capsule.
Where did you get this?
It dropped from the capsule.
Dropped?
Yes, when it was being hauled into the laboratory. But, you can see! This metal could revolutionise space travel. That's why I'm insisting that we open it. Well, who knows what other marvels there may be inside?
But Lesterson, I didn't think you could open it?
Well, I have a theory. I'm convinced that the opening mechanism on the other side is either here, or here.
Extermination...
Now, my theory is that I can insert a laser ray in this ridge here.
The ray spreads, fuses the opening device and gets us in.
Examiner, I shall have to make it your responsibility.
A laser? Why not? It shouldn't be too difficult.
Well, we'll try the other side.
Hmm, it's a bit... disappointing.
Not really. This is just an entry bay, isn't it?
Yes, I... I suppose so.
Well, this doesn't get us very far does it?
Ah, getting into the rest of the capsule will take time, Governor.
Well, can't you use that torch thing again? That must be an opening door.
Well, I should have to measure it up and find out where the lock mechanism is.
And I think we'll leave if for tonight.
Leave it?
Leave it for tonight? But what did we come here for?
That is my decision, Governor.
But, good heavens above, man!
Two hundred years, you say, this has been buried?
Oh, at least. Now, there must be something in the inner compartment.
We shall be able to find out where it came from originally.
It didn't come from this planet - Vulcan.
Oh no, no, no. The metal is quite alien.
Alien, yes. Very alien. Goodnight.
What's he up to now?
Ben, we're not going to let him out of our sight.
Well, Lesterson, you got your way. Was it worth sending for this Examiner? This idiotic Examiner?
I didn't send for him. I thought you did.
Why don't you let me talk to the Examiner, Hensell? I can find out what's he's here for.
No, no, no, no, you keep away from him. We'll leave him to work with Lesterson here. We've all got enough to do without having to worry about some amateur critic from Earth interfering.
But with five minutes, I _...
You heard what I said, Quinn. You won't mind keeping the Examiner busy, Lesterson? I don't mind what you do with him so long as you keep his nose... out of our business.
Yes. All right.
All right. Well, we shall talk about it tomorrow.
Ben!
What?
Shh! He's in the corridor.
Who is?
The Doctor, you clod! Come on - quick!
He's going towards Lesterson's lab.
Of course - to the space capsule!
Come on.
Polly, Ben, come in and meet the Daleks.
What?
The Daleks.
You could have opened this before.
These two pieces of metal are identical.
I knew I should find them here.
Ah, they look harmless, not very lively.
Two hundred years in a swamp and you wouldn't look very lively either. Nothing could live through that, could it?
Live?
Nothing human, no.
Doctor, look!
What's the matter?
Well, there were three Daleks in here! What's happened to the other one?
Doctor, look!