Sincro: wyxchari
With the Control Rig gone we can draw only one conclusion.
The weed is trying to take over all the rigs and form one vast colony.
With what objective?
The saturation of the British Isles and perhaps in time the entire planet.
Is such a thing possible?
Well, yes. Unless we can find the nerve centre and destroy it.
But how can we possibly do that?
It could be anywhere out there in the North Sea.
Yes, that is the difficulty.
- Doctor!   - What is it?
- Doctor! The pipeline, quick!   - Quickly! Quickly!
- What's happened?  - Here!
Come up!
What is heaven's name is that?
The advanced guard.
I don't understand.
What's happening?
The first part of the invasion.
Doctor, don't go near!
It's begun. The battle of the giants!
Feed HQ calling Rig F. Feed HQ calling Rig F.
Can you hear me? Come in please.
Oh Mr Harris. I can't raise any of the rigs. Not one!
- This is unbelievable!  - I'll try again, sir.
Feed HQ calling Rig B. Feed HQ calling Rig B, can you hear me?
- Well keep trying man!   - You're wasting your time, Miss Jones.
By now all those rigs will have been taken over by the weed colony.
I don't care about the rigs. What's happened to the crews?
The worst, I'm afraid.
- Then we've got to destroy the rigs.   - No!
- No, we daren't do that.   - Why not?
Well that would spread this menace over a wide area
and make it impossible to attack it.
Well what are we going to do?
No, what is the weed going to do?
What can it do?
Well, let's think. Now I imagine that in the first place...
the weed was drawn up by one of the drilling rigs.
No, no, anything that comes up through the bores...
would be cleared by the engineers at the source,
otherwise it would block the pumps.
Precisely. And the engineers who cleared it much have touched it, yes?
Yes, so they must have been amongst the first to be controlled.
You see then, this attack, and it is an attack, follows a set pattern.
- How do you mean? - Top priority people have been attacked first.
If your theory is correct, the weed now controls two people...
who know the entire layout and structure of this whole compound.
Yes, I'm very much afraid that is true.
Robson was here not long ago. We must find him...
... and prevent them using him, for his own sake as well as ours.
- Yes I agree. Price.   - Sir.
Get security to search the entire Compound.
I want Mr Robson found and put under armed guard in his cabin.
Very good, sir.
Doctor! There's one thing that doesn't fit in with your theory.
Oh, and what's that?
When Victoria was locked in the Oxygen Room.
Now she's nothing to do with the personnel here.
Yes, that's something that's being puzzling me too.
But she disturbed somebody who was interfering with the oxygen supplies.
Someone wearing a gas mask.
Now supposing that person was under the control of the weed.
He was wearing a gas mask for one reason only.
Because to him pure oxygen would be toxic.
Exactly, Mr Harris.
Well then we can use the oxygen as a weapon against the weed!
Well it's... it's only a theory at the moment.
Well as Mr Harris said before, you've been right so far.
There's no reason why you shouldn't be now.
Oh, how nice to be trusted. But I only hope I am right.
Good, see that he stays there.
- Mr Harris.   - Yes?
- They've found Mr Robson.   - Good. Where?
- In his cabin, lying on his bunk apparently.  - Oh well, that's a relief.
- There's a guard at the door, sir.   - Good.
Mr Harris. I want to see Mr Robson.
Robson? But he's ill, he won't be able to ...
- I want to see him.  - But you've seen him already.
Surely you could see that he was in no fit state to help us in anyway.
I fully realise that, Mr Harris, but we're old friends, he might talk to me.
There's just a possibility that he may know something that could help us.
I see. All right, but I'm coming with you.
Robson's in an unpredictable state at the moment, he could be violent.
- All right, you come too Perkins.  - Yes, Miss Jones.
Oh, if anything happens, Price, anything at all,
- I'll be with Miss Jones in Mr Robson's cabin.   - Very good, sir.
- Chief.   - I'm right with you, sir.
Look, why don't you get the Minister to call up the National Defences?
What exactly do you suppose the armed forces could do?
Well attack this weed, or whatever it is.
How? If we attack the rig, what about the men out there?
But we don't know that they are there.
Equally, we don't know that they aren't.
They could be prisoners, anything.
Anyway, even if we blow the rigs out of the sea,
there's no guarantee it will end this nightmare.
It might well spread the menace, as the Doctor suggested.
- This way please, Miss Jones.   - Right!
And come along, Perkins.
Don't look so worried, man, you might as well go home.
If you please, Harris.
Miss Jones, I'd rather you let me or Perkins come in with you.
No! Now don't fuss, Harris, I'll be perfectly all right.
Robson. Robson!
John. John.
It's all right John, it's me, Megan, Megan Jones.
Megan.
I want to try to help you.
Can't help. No one can help.
John, can you tell us what happened?
No.
John, listen to me. We can't help you unless you help us.
Can't help, no one... can help.
Yes we can, John, if you let us.
Now whatever it is that's affecting you, you've got to fight it!
- Can't fight.  -  You've got to fight it, John!
- Can't fight it. -  Now come on, Robson! Robson!
Now listen to me. I'm director of the board.
I put you in charge of this area
and I can just as easily send you back to the rigs.
Do you understand me, Robson?
Now pull yourself together, man!
- Megan.   - Pull yourself together!
Megan... Megan... help me.. help...
Help me, Megan!
- John.   - Help!
- It's all right, John.   - Miss Jones!
John, can you hear me? Can you hear me?
It's as if he was in a trance, hypnotised.
- I thought for a minute he was rational.   - I think we'd better let him rest.
Harris, is there nothing we can do to help him?
No, the Doctor couldn't help my... my wife...
so I'm sure there is nothing he can...
No. No, of course not.
As far as I can see the only thing to do is to destroy this weed.
Come on.
He does look worried this time. It's beginning to give me the willies.
Yes. I wish we could go back to the TARDIS.
- Leave all this trouble behind.  - We couldn't do that.
You know the Doctor would never leave these people.
- Not while there's...  - Oh I know, I know!
Oh, Victoria, you're not going to start again, are you?
Look, the Doctor's got enough trouble as it is.
So let him just sit and work it out.
Anyway, he says there's an obvious answer to this seaweed stuff.
Is there? What do you mean?
A way of fighting it.
If it's that obvious he would have thought of it by now.
Aye.
Well Doctor, have you thought of a way in which we can attack this weed?
Doctor!
Oh, Miss Jones. No, I'm afraid I haven't.
Well have you any idea what it might do next?
Well I think it has little alternative,
- but to attack us here.   - Here?!
- But why?   - 'Cause this is the gas distribution centre.
It will want to gain control of it!
We must find a way of attacking its nerve centre before it does.
But where is the nerve centre?
That's the trouble, we don't know.
And we're not sure yet quite how to destroy it, are we?
No, but there... there is something at the back of my mind.
- Well what about the oxygen?   - Yes, that is a possibility.
Then we must put the oxygen supply room under guard.
Right!
Yes. Yes.
The whole of the oxygen store?
Yes, sir, and there are no reserves left at all.
They seem to be one step ahead of us all the time
Yes, I was right.
Someone amongst us here is under the control of the weed.
You mean apart from Robson and Van Lutyens.
Yes, I'm afraid so.
How will we find out who they are?
Don't know, that's the difficulty.
Well, we must have a personnel check.
- Now there's a fingerprint file in security.  - Yes.
- Doctor, I shall need your help.   - Yes.
Hey you two, just a moment! Stop!
Hey, come back. You wont get away from me!
Careful!
Didn't know what hit him, did he?
Yes Jamie, I'm... I'm sure you're right.
There's a wee bit of power left in the old McCrimmon punch yet.
I'm sorry to disillusion you, Jamie, but...
I don't think it was the punch that did it.
- Mr Harris!   - What is it?
I think you better come, sir. Quickly!
- What's the trouble?  - The pipeline room.
- But it's incredible   - Why can't we do something?
We have to trust this strange Doctor.
He's the only one who seems to be able to anticipate events.
Don't you think that in itself is suspect?
He's our only hope. Come on.
What's happened to it, Doctor?
It's beginning to expand, like it did in the TARDIS.
Is there no way of stopping it?
No. I should have thought of this.
But you mean this horrible stuff's growing all the time?
I'm very much afraid so!
Mr Harris, sir. Mr Harris. Mr Robson's broken out of his cabin.
He's attacked the guard!
Doctor, look at that!
Right, Jamie, back. Back, everyone back. Come along.
Miss Jones, I think it's time you went. Come along.
FIXME RED EMERGENCY ALERT! RED EMERGENCY ALERT!
- Where's Victoria?   - She was here.
FIXME But, where is she?
FIXME RED EMERGENCY ALERT! RED EMERGENCY ALERT!
FIXME I don't know! She was standing right beside you.
- I thought she was with you!   - No!
Hey!
The doors!
Open these doors! Open these doors!
Let's try here, Jamie!
They've closed too.
They're not, come along!
FIXME Jamie, I... the doors, they're heavy.
I can't hold them! Jamie, hurry!
Jamie! Jamie, come on!
- Where?  - This way, in here.
Hurry up, I can't hold them!
Now what do we do?
We must look for Victoria. You go that way, I'll go this.
All right.
Seal off the pipeline room, completely!
Close the pipeline - in and out!
Well come on, man, don't just stand there!
Guards! You must find Mr Robson.
Search everywhere.
- Mr Harris!   - What is it?
Mr Robson has just taken off.
- Hey, have you seen Victoria?   - No I haven't.
- Look, haven't you found her yet?   - No, I was hoping you had.
- But she was standing right beside us...   - No, no, no...
Doctor, it's Robson. He's trying to get away in one of the company helicopters.
What?
I'm afraid he's got your young girl with him.
Oh no. Oh no.
- Can I speak to him from here?   - Yes. Price, switch to RT.
- This one, please.  - Robson. Robson.
Robson, listen to me. Can you hear me?
Robson. Come back, man, come back.
Robson, don't you realise what they're trying to do to you?
They're trying to control you!
- Now listen to me.   - Robson.
Listen! Listen!
I have the girl. She is my prisoner. She is my hostage.
Do you understand?
If you want her to live, come over to us.
- Come over to us.  - Robson. Robson!
He's switched off, sir.
What did he mean come over to us?
- Well he meant exactly what he said!   - You mean they want you?
Yes, they must think I'm a serious menace.
- But you won't go, surely? - But of course.
But we need you here, you're our only hope.
Doctor, we can't let him take Victoria!
Now we've got to do something to stop him!
You can't go with that man, you can see he's not responsible.
Jamie's right, we've got to go after him.
Yes, you can use the company helicopter.
Harris! If we let this man go now, what hope have we got?
Miss Jones, I have a feeling that ...
Mr Robson is going to lead us to the nerve centre of the colony.
Price, tell the helicopter crew to stand by.
Doctor, come with me. I'll get you some transport.
Good! Thank you, Price. Tell them not to lose touch.
Oh, and Price, the Doctor and the boy, are they airborne yet?
No, sir, they're just approaching the air field.
Mr Harris, sir. Mr Harris, the Doctor's airborne.
Doctor, can you see Robson?
No, can't see anything here.
All right, listen carefully. We managed to track him on the Radar scope.
He just landed on the control rig complex.
The control rig complex.
What? Say again.
We are proceeding there now.
What chance have they got?
Your guess is as good as mine.
- What do we do now?   - We sit and wait.
- But we can't...  - If the Doctor hasn't done something within an hour...
I'm evacuating the compound.
- No...   - And that's final, Miss Jones!
Jamie, there's the control rig complex.
Hey Doctor, one of those towers is all covered in white.
Yes, it's foam. That's the nerve centre.
- Robson's helicopter.   - Yes.
- We can't land there.   - Oh yes we can, Jamie.
Come on in, the water's lovely.
Go on, Jamie.
Goodbye.
So far so good, Jamie.
But the driver, will he wait for us?
Oh yes, he said he'd hang around.
Where do we go from here?
I think we'll go down that way.
Like walking into the lion's den.
Jamie, we're already in the lion's den.
What we've got to concentrate on is keeping our heads out of his mouth.
It's very quiet. Do you think Victoria really is down here?
There's nowhere else she can be.
Aye, I suppose you're right.
Jamie! Jamie! Now there's no element of surprise!
Jamie! Doctor!
See I was right.
- Now, Jamie!   - What's the matter?
If you were hunting, what would you do?
Well I'd set a... oh I see, you think it might be a trap.
Might be. We'll lets be cautious just in case, hey?
Here we go.
It's Robson!
Come in, Doctor. I've been waiting for you.