Sincro: wyxchari
There Victoria, up you get.
Trust you to bring us right down in the middle of the sea.
The TARDIS is perfectly capable of floating you know.
Where are we exactly?
Oh England undoubtedly.
Aye, you can tell by the weather.
And by the cliffs.
We always seem to land on this planet.
Aye, it's always England.
You'd think for all the hammering the TARDIS has got, you've gone an' spiked it
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, what's all this stuff Doctor?
Foam, you silly. You often see the stuff along the sea shore.
But not big lumps like this, aye Doctor?
No, not usually. Jamie.
Hey Jamie, feel that.
Hey, look at that. Maybe that's where the foam's coming from.
Oh I hardly think so, Jamie. Let's go and see.
What is it?
Just what it says, Jamie. Euro Sea Gas.
Gas from the sea? Oh, who are you trying to kid?
And it has nothing to do with the foam then.
No. No, I shouldn't think so.
Would it not budge?
No, can't budge it, I'm afraid Jamie.
Ah well, have to use this.
-What's that? - A Sonic Screwdriver.
Never fails.
There we are. Neat isn't it?
All done by sound waves. Now what have we got here?
Oh yes.
What is it? What's that noise?
I don't know Jamie.
- I can hear it too.  - Yes.
Probably throbbing from a pump, you know.
Doctor please hurry up.
I don't like this place. It's so quiet.
I feel as if we're being watched.
Alright Victoria.
Now then, Jamie.
Doctor!
Doctor?
Victoria?
Jamie you there?
I can't move... my legs.
What happened? What do you want?
Would someone kindly tell us where we are, please?
Why don't you answer?
Come on, where are we?
What have they done? Can't move...
I think we've... we've been tranquilised Victoria. Tranquilised.
Eh? Who do they think they are?
We should be the ones asking the questions.
I expect quite a lot of answers.
What is this place?
You mean you don't know?
If only I could just get up...
I wouldn't try if I were you.
You know, in this condition it's just a little difficult to communicate.
Shall we give them some U4 sir?
Yes. Do that Mr. Harris.
- Oh no.   - I think it's alright Victoria.
- Take it away from me, please.  - I think it's an antidote.
There's nothing we can do about it you know...
Oh yes. That's better... Thank you.
Thank you very much, yes!
You were on the beach, by the pipe line, in a restricted area. Now why?
We were lost that's all.
You were tampering with the emergency release valve remote control.
You're a saboteur.
He's not. He's a doctor.
I can assure you. I was only being curious.
I don't really think how they could have anything...
When I want your opinion Harris, I'll ask for it.
In the mean time, lock them up in one of the cabins.
I'll interrogate them later.
And you lot get back to work.
Is he always as charming as that?
We're in something of an emergency at the moment.
You see, we've lost contact with one of our rigs at sea.
Communications have broken down?
No, that's what's so curious about it.
As far as we can tell our video link is functioning normally.
The crew just aren't answering.
You can't blame us for that surely.
There's also been a drop in pressure in the feed line from the rigs.
You were seen tampering with the release valve on the pipeline.
I told you I was merely being curious.
Were you?
Are you calling us liars?
No. But you must admit your sudden appearance here
inside our restricted area is suspicious.
That's no reason to shoot us down like animals.
Maybe not, but we were under security alert
and Mr Robson... well, is under considerable pressure himself.
I'm sorry, but I shall have to do what he says...
- and lock you up.  - Oh dear.
Would you... er... follow me?
- Come along, this way.   - Why do we always...
May I see your pass please madam?
Pass?
I have instructions that no one is to leave or enter the compound
without a written pass from Chief Robson.
Not until after the emergency.
But you know who I am.
My husband is second in command to Chief Robson.
- Yes Mrs Harris, I...  - Then let me pass.
Please.
Sorry madam. I think you should return to the residential block.
I'm sorry but there is nothing I can do to help you
until you tell me what you were doing with that release valve on the pipe line.
It wasn't the valve I was interested in.
Oh?
I heard a movement coming from inside the pipe.
A movement?
Oh it's alright, you can go.
Yes. Movement. Don't ask me what it was.
I'm not sure what you're trying to suggest,
but I can assure you, marine life couldn't possibly get inside the pipeline tube.
It would never get pass the drill pumps.
Aye, that's as maybe, but there was something inside that tube
- because I heard it too.  - And so did I.
Well if the pressure is down in the pipes, perhaps that's the reason why...
Perhaps marine life has got into the pipe.
But that's impossible.
We've spent years of time, money and research into perfecting our emergency system.
Well, perhaps there's a fracture in the pipes - a break,
- and something has got in that way?   - Oh I doubt it.
Mr Harris. I don't wish to appear interfering,
but don't you think it'd be a good idea to turn off the gas -
at least until you've had a chance to check.
- Chief Robson would never agree to that.   - Why not?
Well he doesn't believe in working to the book.
He prides himself that the flow has never been shut off ever since he took charge.
Well he sounds like a very silly man.
Hmmm. But he appears to be right about one thing.
You seem to know quite a lot about our business.
Ah, Chief. We've gained contact with Rig D.
Come in Rig D. Come in please.
Rig D. Can you hear me please?
Yes. Rig D to HQ. I can hear you.
CARNEY? What the dickens is going on out there?
- Everything is quite alright, Mr...  - What?
... have the situation under control.
Would you speak up man. I can't hear a word you're saying.
- Don't worry...  - are we losing volume?
No, sir. I don't understand.
Could you speak up a little louder Mr Carney?
Everything is ...
Carney? What happened to the emergency crew we sent you?
- Have they arrived yet?  - Yes!
Yes... But they must stay here for the time ...
They what?
They had a slight accident. Two men out of action.
Now listen Carney. You get that rig fixed A1 and quick.
But it will take some time.
What? What did you say? What's wrong with this thing.
I don't know, sir. It must be their end. He seems to be whispering.
Everything is under control.
Carney, speak up man.
Carney...
I think we've lost contact again sir.
Fix it man.
Price is getting too old for his job.
Mr. Robson, I think we should turn off the gas flow
coming from the rig. Make a check.
You think what Mr Harris?
That Doctor chap. The stranger. He said he heard a movement
coming from inside the pipe line on the beach.
Oh did he now. Did he say what he thought it was? Mice?
Chief?
She's down at propeller 3. Pressure's on just 157.
- 157? Are you sure?   - Yes. Sir.
- That means the gas flow pressure is down 3% every.. .- Twenty minutes.
Doesn't that prove that something must be blocking the pipe line?
It proves nothing of the sort.
It's probably a faulty gauge that's all. Check it.
Look, at least give it the benefit of the doubt.
When you want to find out about pipe lines and rigs Mr Harris,
the thing to do is to go out and see and work on them.
Look I'm merely saying that if something had got into the tube...
You let me worry about that.
But Mr Robson, please listen.
This ties up with what I've been trying to tell you.
For three weeks now, there's been a regular and increasing build up of falls in pressure...
Look I think you should at least look at my calculations.
The time ratio of the increases and falls
corresponds to form a definite progressive pattern.
- So?  -  I'll get them.
What are you trying to prove Harris? That I don't know my job?
No, sir. Just that I do know mine.
It's your decision whether you take notice of my work
but I must put it on record that I have offered the information.
Don't threaten me boy. I've eaten up sods like you for breakfast.
You think you can baffle me with your little bits of paper don't you?
Alright, you go ahead and get them.
I'll show you where you've gone wrong.
Did you make a thorough check?
- Yes I checked it. Seems to be working properly.   - It's gone.
Doesn't seem to be anything wrong with her.
It's gone. The file's gone.
Well well well. Has it now?
I'm sure I put it in here this morning...
Err, I must have left the file on my desk at home.
- I'll go home and get...  - You won't. You'll stay here.
I'm not doing your job as well as my own.
What's the matter sir? Are you scared that I might prove you wrong?
No. You go ahead. But you'd better have something more than a high blown theory,
because if you haven't, I'm going to take up and chop you up into little pieces
and throw you back to your crummy little university. Alright?
I've got it.
Put that down Victoria.
Can you see anyone?
All clear.
You think you can make it?
Of course I can make it. Hold on.
Don't bother, Jamie. You can do it with this.
Pick a lock with that hairpin? Don't be daft.
Clumsy.
Maggie. Where have you been? I've been trying to contact you.
I was on my way to the village, but Robson's clamped down on security.
I was just coming to find you for a pass.
Yes. There's been a bit of a flap on.
- Well can I have a pass?  - No. Not at the moment.
- Look. Could you do something for me?  - Yes what is it?
There's a file - it's probably in the middle draw of my desk in the study.
Could you get it and bring it to me at the control room?
Alright darling. But what's the panic?
I'll explain later. Go along.
Alright darling.
- Oh he's stuck.  - No he's not.
Are you ready Jamie. Right.
Told you not to bother.
Sorry, about that Jamie.
Ow... Seaweed?
Mr. Robson. Mr. Robson.
Could I speak with you please?
Van Lutyens. I thought you were at the Control Rig.
I just got back on the supply boat.
Something wrong?
I'm not quite sure. The men out there seem very restless.
Restless? What are you talking about?
You lost contact with Rig D didn't you?
Yes it was only a temporary fault. We regained contact within the hour.
Then why didn't you tell us that?
Unusual incidents like that only cause tension on the rigs.
Don't tell me what happened out on the rigs.
I spent four years on one of those things without a break.
Then you should know better than anyone
how important it is to keep up the morale of the crew.
What do you want me to do? Wipe their noses for them?
Mind your own business van Lutyens.
Mr Robson. I think you're forgetting
we also have an interest in Euro Sea Gas.
We?
I'm here for the Dutch Government, not for myself.
You're here to offer me your expert advice,
not spread alarm amongst my crews.
How dare you say that to me?
I didn't ask you to come here -
it was Megan Jones and those fools on the board.
I said it wouldn't work and it never has.
Only because you're too proud to accept advice.
Let's get one thing straight, my friend
When I need your advice I'll ask for it.
Control. Chief Baxter at Control Rig. Is Robson there?
Yes sir.
Mr. Robson sir. Chief Baxter from Control Rig sir.
Right.
Yes Baxter, what is it?
- Van Lutyens arrive there yet sir?   - Yes. Why?
Did he tell you how the men feel sir?
Now listen Baxter. I'm in charge of this outfit - not van Lutyens.
- You take orders from me not him.  - Yes sir.
- But there's something else.   - What else?
Something seems to have got inside the pipe lines.
- Inside the pipe lines?   - We've all heard it sir.
- Heard what?  - This sound.
At first I thought it was something to do with the pumps, but it isn't.
Most peculiar sound.
A sort of regular thumping, pulsating... like a heartbeat.
That's the noise I heard on the beach.
What is it Doctor?
I don't know, but we're going to find out. Come on, Jamie.
Oh... ah Victoria. No. Not you.
- Why not?  - I think it'd be better if you...
Err... stayed back in the bunk room... hmmm?... please.
Alright.
Control.
Mrs Harris here. Married Block 420.
Could I speak to my husband please?
Have you recalibrated it?
I've just done Phase two.
Start on Phase three.
Mr Robson.
Yes Harris. Where are your figures?
Oh I haven't got them, sir.
I sent my wife for them, but she's not well.
- I wondered if I could go and...  - I would not.
Tell her to call a doctor, not pester you.
But Dr. Patterson is still out at Rig D sir.
Tell her to get one in from the outside.
But you've still go the compound on full emergency alert. Remember?
Alright. But make it quick.
What's that thing supposed to do?
It's an impeller Jamie.
It pumps gas from the main pipeline out to sea. Come on.
- This is the pipeline, then.  - Yes. Yes. They all are.
It's a continuation of the pipe we found on the beach.
Aye? But we can see inside the pipe.
Yes. It's transparent for checking condensation and...
er... anything else that might get inside.
Hello? Is anybody there?
Oh come on...
There it is again Jamie. Can you hear it?
Aye. What is it?
Your guess is as good as mine. There's something inside.
DOCTOR!
Victoria! Come on.
- Jamie!  - Victoria!
Jamie... help!
Victoria. Where are you?
Doctor... Jamie...
- Victoria. We're coming.  - Jamie!