Sincro: wyxchari
Very little time. You know what you must do.
Yes.
You will obey.
Rig D. Rig D. Control calling. Rig D, come in please.
Rig D. Rig D. Control calling, come in please.
I'm sorry sir, I can't reach them.
Try Rig A again.
Rig A. Control calling Rig A...
It's no good sir. That's three rigs not answering now sir.
The men on the remaining rigs won't last under this suspense much longer.
Try the guard post again and see if there's any sign of Mr. Harris...
Three rigs now. What could have happened to them?
Well, can't you send someone else to investigate?
No... I don't have the authority here. I'm just their technical adviser.
Mr. HARRIS is in charge. When he comes back...
he might properly authorise the company helicopter for at least to take a look.
- We can do nothing?  - Nothing.
Wait. Wait.
Nothing.
It's started again.
Jamie... Jamie...
Jamie... You asleep?
No. I'm just resting my eyes.
I don't know how you can with all this trouble going on.
Oh don't worry.
The Doctor will work something out. He always does.
Yes. What then?
Oh what do you mean "what then?"
What do we do next?
Oh Victoria, you know better than to ask a question like that.
We never know where we're going to land one place to the next.
- It's half the fun isn't it?  - Is it?
Victoria, what's the matter?
You've been acting very oddly ever since we got here.
Oh it's nothing. It doesn't matter.
- Look if you're worried, the Doctor...  - Jamie, I said it was nothing.
- Just go back to sleep.  - Aye.
Oh I wouldn't worry about that old bit of seaweed.
The Doctor will work something out.
Will he?
There's so many questions.
The weed grows. Feeds off natural gas.
How fast does it grow?
What happens to those who... who touch it.
Oh Jamie. Jamie I'm frightened.
Oh I'm sorry Victoria. Did I startle you?
Where's Jamie?
Up there. He's asleep.
- Nothing can wake him except a bomb dropping.   - Oh good.
Doctor what's happening?
Well I'm not sure, Victoria. I'm not sure.
It's so peaceful out there, isn't it?
- Heard that noise again?  - Yes.
Well what are they doing about it?
Well we'll have to wait.
Wait? But what for?
For one of those awful creatures to come and attack us all?
- Now Victoria, it's not as bad as all that you know.  - Isn't it?
Even you don't know really how bad it is, do you?
Well no. Not exactly.
Every time we go anywhere, something awful happens.
- Daleks. Cybermen.   - Yeti.
Yes, the Yeti. Why can't we go anywhere pleasant?
Where there's no fighting - just peace and happiness.
Mr. Robson. Mr. Robson.
What are you doing down here?
Have you seen my wife at all?
- Your wife?   - I've been searching for her.
You'll find her Mr. Harris. Very soon.
Then you haven't seen her.
ROBSON!
If you don't mind me saying so, Mr. Van Lutyens,
I think this is a very bad idea of yours.
You don't know what you're up against.
Aye, you wouldn't catch me down there.
Why don't we wait till Mr. Harris comes back sir?
The only way to find out whether this weed stuff of yours...
is blocking the base of the impeller is to go down and have a look.
Mr. Van Lutyens, I have no authority to send my men down there...
I realize that. That's why I'm going down.
- By yourself?   - Oh yes.
I wouldn't go down...
- Well I hope you know what you're doing, sir.   - I think so.
I... I wish you wouldn't do this Mr. Van Lutyens.
I can't sit about waiting any longer. I have no position of authority here.
But I do have the run of the company installations.
And if I can do nothing else, I...
I can at least inspect the base of the impeller shaft.
- Tot straks.   - Good luck. You'll need it.
All right, lower him down.
Help me! Let me out!
Get him up!
- What is it? What's happened?   - Van Lutyens is down there.
- What's happened to him?   - Oh we don't know, Victoria...
What happened? What did you see?
He's not in the shaft. He may still be down there.
Let's find Mr. Harris.
We can't just leave him down there.
- Oh what are we going to do?   - We've got to go after him.
- Oh Doctor no.   - Oh no we're not.
Jamie, you wouldn't want me to go down there all on my own now, would you?
Well you...err, oh, no!
Oh Doctor, you can't, you don't know what's down there.
Ms Megan Jones... just... just leaving reception now... Right. Thank you.
Oh Mr. Harris.
Mr. Harris, we've been looking for you everywhere.
What is it Price?
Are you all right sir?
Yes... Just tired.
Do you have any news of my wife?
No. I'm afraid not sir. You didn't find her?
- Oh Mr. Harris...   - Yes?
The director, Megan Jones is leaving reception on her way here now sir.
I see. Thank you Price.
- Where's Van Lutyens?   - In the Impeller Area I think sir.
All right.
This is terrible. You mean to say that they both went down that shaft?
I couldn't stop them.
- They went looking for Mr. Lutyens...  - What?
What has happened to him?
Mr. Harris. Thank goodness you're back.
Mr. Van Lutyens went down inside the impeller shaft
to find... to find what is blocking the pipe line.
- Yes?  - He didn't come back.
Now the Doctor and the boy has gone down there...
They've done what?
Get them up at once.
Stop the lift.
I'm sorry sir. it's too late.
Creepy sort of place isn't it?
Jamie, that hole goes straight down to the gasometer down below.
Hey, isn't that Van Lutyens' torch?
- Well it must be.   - But where is he?
Shine it down here...
What's happened... Oh, give it to me.
Come on Doctor. Let's get out of here.
I feel as if something evil is lurking down here.
It all seems quiet enough Ms Jones.
Of course it is. Robson's an efficient man.
Why do you think I gave him control of the compound?
He knows the job backwards.
- Then why the sudden panic?  - I don't know.
Harris was rather vague.
Vague? Harris said he was taking over from Robson. I wouldn't call that vague.
- You've not met Robson have you Perkins?   - No. But...
When you do, you'll realize that he's not the sort of man one pushes around.
- Then what's it all about?   - Just an internal squabble I'd say.
Harris is a bright man. I sent him thinking he might gain from Robson's technical experience.
Obviously the two haven't taken off together.
- So we're pouring oil? Politics? - Let's go and see shall we?
JAMIE... DOCTOR.
Oh I do wish they'd hurry.
Is there any way we can get them up, Chief?
Well we can't use the lift in case they want to get back in a hurry.
There's the ladder inside the pipeline...
- Mr Harris?  - Yes. What is it Price?
- Megan Jones has a rrived sir.   - Oh I see. Thank you.
Chief, you'd better come with me.
I'm going to need some support when I talk to Megan Jones.
- All right.  - But what about Jamie and the Doctor?
There isn't a great deal we can do at the moment, I'm afraid.
Oak, as soon as they signal, bring them up.
If there's any sign of trouble, come and get me.
- You can rely on us.   - Come on Chief.
Will they be all right. I mean is it safe?
Oh yes Miss. Don't you worry about a thing.
We'll take care of everything, won't we, Mr Quill?
Creatures? Seaweed Creatures?
- What do you say to that Perkins?   - It's true.
You can't be serious Mr Harris.
These creatures have been seen in the refinery itself...
By some half witted Doctor and a couple of teenagers.
And by me.
You've seen them?
Yes, Ms Jones. I have seen them.
Harris, I understand your wife has some sort of accident.
I know it must have been a considerable shock to you
- and I fully understand... - You think I'm lying. That I've been seeing things.
Believe me. There are things you don't know.
I know throughout the southern regions the sea rig stations are reverting to emergency supplies.
What are we going to do about it?
At present there is nothing we can do about it.
One by one we're losing contact with the rigs out at sea.
Then I suggest you send someone out to see what's going on.
All right. Have I your permission to call out air defence.
Certainly not. This is not a national emergency.
Use the company helicopters.
- But you don't understand. what's going ..  - Will you please do as I say?
- Price.   - Yes Sir.
- Get me the helicopter hangar please.   - Very good sir.
Now, Mr. Harris. I think I would like to talk with Chief Robson.
Oh I'm sorry. I think...
Well he's not very well.
- Not well? In what way?  - Something's happened to him. I...
That's all I can tell you.
- Like what? What happened?  - I... I don't know.
I just don't know.
Can you see anything?
No, it's too dark Jamie.
Not a sign of Van Lutyens.
Well no point hanging about here.
Wait a minute.
Come on Jamie. Let's get out of here. Press the button up there!
HQ calling Rig D. This is Feed HQ calling Rig D. Come in, please.
- Can you hear me?  - It's no use, there won't be a reply.
Don't be a fool, man. We must keep trying.
If there are men out on those rigs there must be a reply.
If? But we don't know.
We've already lost contact with three of our drilling rigs.
And you say there is definitely something down there in the impeller shaft blocking the flow?
- You've checked the impeller?   - Chief?
It's not the impeller. I've checked every last nut and bolt.
Whatever it is, it's down there in that shaft.
Get us out of here. Take the lift up!
Up here. Look behind you.
You all right?
Yes. I think so.
- What a climb.  - It's the weed.
It must fill the entire shaft
- It's moving too quick.  - Let's get out here in case, then.
- Where's Victoria?  - I don't know.
No wonder they didn't see the lift shaft signal. There's no one here.
- Victoria wouldn't desert us.  - No.
Unless she had been persuaded to.
Jamie, I think we'd better go and look for her. Come on.
- You go that way. I'll go this way.   - All right.
Foam and weed on all of the rigs?
According to the helicopter pilot - and no sign of life at all.
It's so fantastic. What on earth are we going to do?
Save the lives of all the men on all the other rigs.
- How?   - Give me permission to evacuate them.
- What?   - Then we blow every one of the rigs to pieces,
right out of the sea.
You must be out of your mind.
Miss Jones, you can't really agree to such a thing.
Just a minute. We have to.
The men's life is more important than any of those rigs.
- The minister would never agree.  - That will do Perkins.
You ask me to throw years of hard work, skill and government money like that?
I'm asking you to destroy this evil that's in the sea.
Before it's too late. Bomb the rigs. I implore you.
No... no. Never. You leave those rigs alone.
They're mine. They're mine I tell you. Mine.
Robson. What's the matter with you?
Don't you see? They're getting at me.
The rigs. They're mine.
I built them from my own flesh and blood. They're mine. They're mine.
They want to destroy everything.
They think in that way they can destroy me.
- We won't allow.  - We?
Who Robson? Who?
What? My... I... Don't know...
Chief.
Are you all right Robson?
Yes. I'm all right. I don't know... I don't know...
- Robson...  - Let him go.
The strain must have affected his mind.
- Oh it's not that I can assure you.   - Doctor!
And who are you?
- Well...  - Doctor, I've almost forgotten.
What about Van Lutyens? did you...
I... I'm afraid not.
Have you any idea what happened?
Yes. Jamie and I nearly joined him.
The whole of the bottom of the impeller shaft is covered in weed and foam.
What happened to Mr. Van Lutyens? And Mr. Robson?
I'm afraid that Mr. Robson is being controlled by some force that emanates from this weed.
That's incredible.
That's what we said so far about everything the Doctor's told us.
Each time he's been proved right.
I think it's about time we started to believe him.
All right. The least we can do is listen.
VICTORIA... VICTORIA... It's me. Jamie. Where are you?.
VICTORIA.
You think this seaweed, or what ever it is,
- is a living organism capable of exercising telepathic control?   - Yes.
But seaweed's vegetable matter. Everyone knows that.
This is a struggle for power, Ms Jones. Matter over mind.
I'm convinced all these people - Mrs Harris, Chief Robson, Mr. Van Lutyens,
have all been overcome in this struggle,
and goodness knows how many more people.
Where does it get the intelligence from Doctor?
- The human brain. It's parasitic.  - You mean...
The creature has taken over human beings.
I don't know, but they've certainly become part of the colony.
- Mr. Harris. Control rig...  - Hurry. Hurry. Emergency.
- Yes, Baxter, what is it?  - Mr. Harris, for pity's sake they're all around us.
- All right. What's happening.  - These things. They're everywhere...
They're all over every thing, in every place.
Baxter. Baxter. Can you hear...?
Argh! Get us out of here. Somebody get us out of here...
Feed HQ calling Control rig. Come in please. Come in please.
VICTORIA... VICTORIA...
VICTORIA.
Back to square one. She must be somewhere.
Victoria. Say something.
No. No, you can't be dead.
Victoria! If anything happened to you, I'd never forgive myself.
Oh Jamie. I didn't know you cared.
Victoria Waterfield. You tricked me. That's not fair.
I'm not. I was unconscious.
Yeah. What happened?
Those two engineers... they must have...
What engineers?
You know the... and the little one...
You mean the two that were... with the...
Yes. That's right.
I don't remember. I must have passed out.
If I ever get my hands on them.
You know the Doctor and me, we were nearly...
Oh never mind about that.
Oh Jamie, why are we always getting into trouble like this?
It's been every where we go.
How do you mean?
I don't know. I'm just fed up.
I'm tired of one crisis on top of another.
I just want some piece and quiet.
Oh Victoria. Are you not happy with the Doctor and myself?
Oh yes. Yes I am. But I just...
What's the matter...
- What's the matter?   - Listen Jamie.
- What is it?  - Can't you hear it?
That noise again.
Yes but where's it coming from?
Victoria look!
With the Control rig gone, we can draw only once conclusion.
The weed is trying to take over all the rigs and form one vast colony.
With what objective?
The saturation of the British Isles, and perhaps in time the entire planet.
- Is such a thing possible?  - Oh yes.
Unless we can find the nerve centre and destroy it.
But how can we possibly do that?
It could be anywhere out there in the North Sea.
Yes. That is the difficulty.
- Doctor.   - What is it?
The pipeline. Quick. Come on.
Hurry.
- What's happening? - It's here.
What in heaven's name is that?
The advance guard.
I don't understand...
What's happening?
The first part of the invasion...
Doctor, don't go near.
It's begun... The battle of the giants.