What's the matter? What is it?
Are you ill?
They're in there - making themselves! Duplicating!
What? What are you talking about?
I started this, opening the capsule!
Lesterson!
Don't try to stop me!
What happened?
They forget that I control them! I gave them life back again, and now I've taken it away! Finished! Stopped it!
The Daleks...
Evil! Horrible! I know what I'm going to do! Laser torches! Melt them down! I'm going to melt the Daleks down to pools of metal!
You won't Lesterson!
Ah, do you think I care what you can do?! Go on, tell everybody I was responsible for Resno's death! I don't care! I'm going to wipe out the Daleks!
Yes, tell everybody all about me! I'm still going to... I'm going to... wipe out the Daleks!
Get me the Examiner. But I've got to talk to him! I've got to, don't you understand?!
How did you get there?! I cut off the power!
We can store power. We will soon have our own.
Own power?!
Why was the capsule door closed?
Own power?! Ahh!
Seal off the capsule's secret entrance.
I obey.
Wait!
No more than three Daleks to be seen together at any one time.
I obey.
We are not ready yet to teach these human beings the law of the Daleks.
Well, Bragen - these trips are becoming more and more demanding.
I didn't expect you, Governor.
Ah, I had as much as I could stand. Well? What's been happening here?
One moment.
I asked you a question, man.
I heard you.
Look, your work can wait. You can hand over to me tomorrow. I want to hear about the Examiner.
He's an impostor, Governor. Possibly a murderer as well. We have just discovered the body of the real Examiner in the mercury swamp.
I hope you're sure of your facts, Bragen.
Quite sure.
This could have far-reaching consequences.
As far as I am concerned, there's nothing more to be said. So if there's nothing further...
Nothing further! Who the devil do you think you're talking to? Stand up when you're speaking to me man!
I prefer to remain seated.
Do you now?! We'll soon see about that. Guards!
Take this man out of my office.
Did you hear what I said? That's an order!
You forget, my dear Hensell. They're not your guards - they're mine.
I am the Governor!
No. Not now. I am.
Oh, I see. Your guards, eh? Yes, Quinn warned me about your guards, but we all took them too lightly, didn't we?
When the people hear that I am being kept a prisoner in my own capital...
The people will do exactly as they are told, Hensell.
It will, of course, be easier for them if you co-operate with us.
You're the last man I expected to see here.
Well your imprisonment hasn't been entirely wasted. It's brought your enemy out into...
Bragen? I've known that all along.
Yes. But, ah, did you know that he was the leader of the rebels?
Hmm. Work's by sound, does it?
Wait there. Guards, dismissed.
So Bragen, you want my co-operation, do you?
It would save bloodshed. I might even let you keep the title of Governor.
Might you now?! I'll tell you what you will do. You'll order your guards to disarm and place yourself under arrest immediately!
So you reject my offer? I thought it a generous one in the circumstances.
What circumstances?
Look at this.
What is it?
The reason that the colony is now mine.
Is it a weapon of some kind?
I'll arrange a demonstration for you. Do you still refuse my offer?
I will not be intimidated.
Of course not. In character to the last, Hensell. Kill him!
Why do human beings kill human beings?
Get on with your work!
Yes, master. I obey.
Yes, obey me! From now on, I will have complete obedience from everyone!
I'll have to check the cable circuit now. Otherwise, it's just as you asked for.
Very well.
Why can't you carry on with the power you're drawing from the colony? Why go to all this trouble?
Until now, we have had to recharge from the colony supply. With static power, the Daleks will be twice as useful.
Valmar, quick!
What's the matter?
The Governor's back.
What about the girl?
Leave her.
I will follow you.
What for?
I am your servant.
Come on.
An electrical circuit of their own supplying static electricity! I wonder how much longer we've got?
I didn't realise they'd have a circuit of their own.
Doctor, look out!
Are you all right?
Well done! Who was the man who went outside just now?
Valmar. He's been working for the Daleks.
On their static power supply.
Doctor, they've got Ben.
Yes, I know. He ran away so that I could... Oh well, it's a long story, but don't worry. That boy can take care of himself!
Did you hear that? That won't help.
Get out! All of you!
What about you?!
But Doctor! Oh...
Go!
Have they escaped?
Yes, return to capsule and report.
I obey.
We are to wait here until the human beings fight among themselves.
Then we will strike.
And exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! ...
But why? Why was he killed?
I can answer that.
He wanted to destroy the Daleks, so one of them killed him. Now, I'm declaring martial law.
Martial law! What good do you think that will do against the Daleks?
The Daleks will do as I tell them.
We shall see, shan't we.
Take them away.
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
Orders received. Exterminate all humans!
Exterminate all humans!
Exterminate! Annihilate! Destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy!
Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! ...