How is Spain?
No holiday. That's for sure.
The house was definitely haunted
A 300 year old ghost.
The trouble was George, my client.
I don't think I completely convinced him
the ghost was friendly.
- Bloody foreigners.
- You say that? But you sent me.
Just because I got promoted, doesnt say I care about your less
Yes, Patsy. Let's try and keep our personal relationships
simple from a professional way, shall we?
Oh, you looked at the wrong side of the plain(??)
Well anyway, the Preternatural Research Bureau is in safe hands
In fact I have something for you
on the back seat
An army experiment? really?
I know its not your favorite, but...
You need a second opinion.
Yes, I guess I do
Enough of that (??)
what were you saying about personal relationships
Shit
Williams
Goona take this.
I'll call you
All right
My name is corporal 7891-alpha
a.ka. Paul Reynish
and this is my story
I've been in the army all my adult life
and that's a very long time
a very long time
So,
what's so special about me?
Nothing. really
Except for one thing
Time
all the time in the world on my hands
I'm the covert MOD experiment
the one off test into longevity
I was in Bosnia, too
a never-aging military asset
Lower your weapon.
That is when I met Josie
But Josie didn't last
She had other fish to fry
Its funny, but after all these years, I'm still
learning to take the rough with the smooth(??)
I suppose I should consider myself lucky
Well, I know I'm costing the MOD millions
That's how much it takes to process these little babies
They're made from a martian meteorite
So they tell me
I don't understand how they work. but...
They do.
Come on
You got a big day tomorrow
Come to bed
All right, Bossy boost(??)
You'll be there tomorrow, won't you?
Fuck!
Everything ok?
I'm fine.
Morning, Dr. Shaw.
Hey, you're back. How was that? (??)
I don't know, somebody out there.
Wow, where did you find it?
In the storage hold.
On the Dr. Smith's shelf.
John Smith, Dr. John Smith.
It's Box, and never worked
Yeah, well, I'm gonna fix it.
Good luck, Gilles.
Whats that?
Priority job
And another one?
Liz, we got a case load as long as your arm.
I know, but this is important.
Giles
All right.
- Where do we start?  - Here.
When I'm not in battle, this, is where I live.
MOD covert operations HQ.
Let me know if it gets too tight and I don't think that...
Bennett is the latest professor to keep an eye on me.
We really erased(?)
- Do I look relaxed?
- For you (??), yes you do.
He does his best to make me feel at home
You see, Bennett's different to the others.
The key thing is the end...
Less distant. I liked him from the start.
He makes me laugh.
...doesnt' underdeveloped one...
It is one of Bennett's jobs to regulate my medication
to keep me fit forever
and, I suppose to keep me alive
I wonder how it would be if I stop taking these
I suppose I might be about to find out
I've had a look at your file, and...
Bennett told me there's a big debate going on about the costs
can they justify the expense?
Who said that?
Just relax yourself
The whole thing has left me thinking
What's it all for?
I have no more relatives
No emotional tides.
These conflicts and war zones are my only destiny
Perhaps its for the best
happy chap  his knee (??)
more security with PROBE
oh  I get it
Haggard knows you've got a soft spot for the outsider,
and you'll cause no fuss
Shut up, Giles
Good afternoon, everybody!
As you know, the prime minister and I
made a joint statement in the house
about the current defense cuts
and today I'm going to outline exactly
where those cuts will fall
I want to focus on challenges... strategic landscape...
and new budget constraints
and the choices we have in responding to these challenges
And, the opportunities that exist
to fundamentally reshape the defence....
Gentlemen, this has not been an easy decision
It should never have come to this
But it has. In times of austerity
when must all tighten our belts (??)
Will he go quietly?
He is a soldier. He is an honourable man.
I'm sure, given time, he'll GUN?? intent to do it.
This must be quick, and it must be clean.
This little experiment has cost enough already.
Yeah, all right, Major.
I appreciate you never approved of any of this.
Let's show some respect, shall we?
He is human
Barely
The procedure is all in place
and will be handled by Dr. Shaw at the PROBE.
Sorry
PROBE?
Don't worry, Sir. Shel'l be discreet.
Yeah, these things are killing
- Hi, you usual man boy(?)
- Thank you
Well?
But I look so surprised
There are things you don't know, Liz.
Is there anything in the pro box of tricks that night (?)
Do the job?
Patsy! Do the job?
You make the corporal sound like some machine.
Sorry.
You can take the girl out of the ministry (??)
But you can't take the ministry out of the girl.
Well
Your relentless
William's breathing down your neck again
Don't worry
I'm sure we'llfind something in the PROBE store.
So you are looking for a time loop converter?
Yeah
I'm gonna freak we're going to find one of those
with enough capacity to contain the courtfor(??)
There was such a device in the storage told
It wasn't me
It was me
- Box!
- Yes. Hello, Dr. Shaw.
It's you. In a box
My God, it works!
You fixed it!
Second island on the left.
Good thinking, Box
Thank you
Liz?
In here
Oh box does more than just talking.
Oh yes. Box is more than just a box.
Remember this?
How could I forget? 1995, wasn't it?
Bringing that witch back to life?
You sure this will work?
I mean, the corporal is about containment
- Positive.
- I wasn't talking to you.
You have any second thoughts?
This is a government organised execution
and I feel very uncomfortable about it
Hello, is that Charlie, Charlie Reynish?
- Hello
- Speaking
I'm Professtor Bennett, from the MOD.
And I'm a friend of your brother Paul.
- Paul? Paul's dead
- No, no, he's not dead.
I don't have time to explain.
You must get here now.
Paul, you're here ready.
Well, wouldn't want to be late for my own funeral, would I?
I fear, got somebody to meet you, Paul.
- Corporal 7891-Alpha
- I know.
Charlie's your brother, Paul.
Not much of a coffin (??)
Major Johnson might pursue (??)
Dr. Shaw.
Wait here
I'll send somebody to fetch you when we're ready.
Bennett, Dr. Shaw is here.
- Who are you?
- I'm Charlie.
- What are you doing here?
- I'll come to take him home
What, what would you mean?
You cant take him home.
Dr. Shaw. In here!
What the hell happened in here?
Wish I knew.
Bennett, what the hell have you done?
Something I should have done a long time ago.
Liz.
- They will be tracking us
- I'm not stupid
You seem to have lost control with the situation, Major.
- What are you going to do about it?
- Find him
I don't often give people second chances,
but I think I can trust you, Major.
Don't let me down
Understood. Leave it with me
- Yes, Pasty? - Liz, there's something more.
Drink?
No thanks
Remember this place?
They're going to find us, you know
Theres no need for PROBE anymore.
You can return to base.
No, Patsy. I'm staying here.
We can't forge your emotional state
to come into play here, Liz
I understand your backs up against the wall on this one
But you need me
You're right
But the major is in charge
I heard about the corporal, but of a shambles(??), don't you think?
So, let me get this straight. You led his brother in.
Charlie deserves to know that his brother is still alive.
But under the circumstances, this is now a right fuck up
- They're both on the run!
- I didn't know he'd be armed.
More importantly, Major,
why was the corporal told that Charlie was dead?
That had nothing to do with me.
It was one of my predecessors, Dr. Shaw
A big mistake, I can see that now.
Okey, enough talk
Now if you excuse me, I have to find the corporal
I trust you won't stand in my way
You can trust me, Major.
If you do the right thing
They have a gun, for Christ's sake
Bennett, you left me no choice.
I'm placing you under arrest
- I found the car.
- Excellent!
I'm on my way.
This doesn't change much.
They told me you had cancer.
Yeah, that much is true.
I'm sorry.
So, how did you find me?
- The professor.
- Bennett?
You're lying...Ah!
I need my meds.
Ready?
See what happens when I don't take my pills?
You're much the same if I don't have a drink
What did you hope to achieve,
storming in old guns blazing?
I didn't have much time to be rational.
What do you want from me?
Not this.
I lost you once before.
I would never forgive myself.
If I didn't, at least try.
I thought...
by bringing you to this place
we'd at least have five minutes peace before...
I'm sorry.
You're all I have.
No
Its me you should be sorry
I'll go in.
I've got clear view, sir.
On my command
Dr. Shaw, what are you doing?
It's a bit extreme, isn't it, Major?
I have no choice.
- He's on the move, sir - Fire
I'll talk to Bennett.
that should buy some time and then...
maybe you can put it in a safe house
Charlie!
What do you mean, you missed?
What about the corporal?
- He's on the move, Sir. - Shit!
Roman let it go. We're moving in.
We make sure we give him a decent burial.
Yes
The least we can do.
Sir, over here.
A tunnel, Sir.
It looks like it goes all the way to the village, Sir
Right, you lot, over here.GG
Hagood wrote like this
I thought you had this under control
Escaping once is bad enough, but twice?
What kind of operation is running here
but looks very mickey mouse? (??)
-I understand your first...
no, I don't think you do understand patsy
I'm about to brief the prime minister
I'm going to have to skirt around the fact that
we've screwed up such a simple task
Don't know about you,
but I'm rather keen to keep my job
Now get the grip?? GG
crack the whip
Let's get this little mess wrapped up minister
You looked surprised
Not really
I expected to find you here.
They're not to hate you?? Paul.
You know what? I'd noticed
Its worse than that
My husband wants you dead
Doesn't change anything
but I owe it to you.
I need my meds.
You're hurting me
Have you found him?
Not exactly
Why are you here?
I'm lost.
So how did you find Charlie?
All the family details 're on the records
I thought if they could just meet.
So this is it
Just 3 days left
This is a famous martian compound.
Without this, the corporal is dead
I don't mind telling you.
I'm really worried about this helplessness
Theres no time for anxiety,
we have to get him back to the lab
Don't worry about me, prof.
Paul.
You lied to me!
It's all right
I'm Dr. Shaw, Liz.
You told me he was dead
We had to protect you,
it was done in your best interest.
You murdered him!
Are you all right?
Give them to me
- They're not here.
- Give me the pills!
What's happening to me? It burns.
You are in very volatile state
You need us. This is only phase 1.
What is vital, Paul? It's vatal we get you back
to the lab where we can get you stablized.
- I don't trust youGG
- When the body is giving up, its over.
Shut up
Shut up, shut up
- So you ARE one of them?
- No! I'm only trying to help
I had no idea you go so mad, I'm sorry
Don't worried, Dr. Shaw.
my team will find him and deal with him
No, no guns
too risky
so
we have no idea of what were dealing with
exactly
the corporal has left some skin
so at least I can run some tests
I'm home.
He is still on the run
But he shot two of our men
so we have this under control
dear god
one piece of skin can do that
yes
and is a ticking time bomb
- Where are you going?
- I have to recalibrate the chair.
- What about the corporal?
- He'll find us
- So, we wait?
- Not for long.
Liz!
Shit
Most of cocktail (??)
I thought this was gonna be simple
How long can you be?
Stop
Don't put that away
Sir
Well?
nothing yet
Why the bloody hell haven't you found him?
Look at it
I'll come to the point
He show your chunks of proper up to this
You do realize what were dealing with
I am well aware, sir, of whats at stake
and I can't think of anyone more qualified than Dr. Shaw.
I hope you're right.
troll last 6 (??)
Oh,  no, shit
Not to implode (??) function to the elemental array
Good idea.
- Any news?
- We've some tests ??
And?
It's bad
Very bad
You think I made a mistake, don't you?
You've turned him into a monster
The calm before the storm
Now we're ready
Where are you?
Tiger located.
Dr. Shaw you're right
A ticking time bomb
has gone public
- Get the van ready - Sir
(Major Johnson)
Major.
You found it? where?
Shepherds Bush?
Quicky  ok  we will meet you there
We're going shopping
You're not going anywhere
If all this goes tits up  You're in charge
Where are you, I wonder?
Shit
I meant intercepting of transmission.
Major Johnson has just informed Haggard
that the corporal has a female hostage.
Just when we thought it couldn't get any worse
We just need to make sure that we've got a thorough briefing
- I presume we found him then
- As expected, sir, he found us
and there's something else
So?
Haggard, its not like you to beat around the Bush
It's Josie, Sir
Positions, gentlemen
Nice and discreet.
We don't want to disturb the natives,
and the corporal must not see us
Out
Now
- What the luck are you doing?
- Finishing the job.
Sit
You're hurt
More than you can imagine
Hold your positions
Where'd he taken her?
Security office
You were right
He has a plan
You can see everything that we do
Well
What's that.
That's the chair
Its the answer to all our prayers,
if we can get him to sit in it
Sir
Mrs Williams' number
Reasoning of what she said?
Good luck
Answer it
Hello? Mrs Williams, are you all right?
- Oh, I'm fine
- Is corporal there now, I need to talk to him
He has a gun
Its Major Johnson. He wants to talk to you
- Major
- Corporal
Is there anything you need from us?
No, there's nothing I need.
- Are you sure?
- I said nothing.
Where are you going to take Mrs Williams
Mrs Williams will be watching the fireworks first hand
Corporal, you've made your point
There are thousands of people at risk.
You've got to stop this now, soldier.
- But I'm no longer a soldier, Major
They in the secretary discharged me, Remember?
- Now listening...
- No, major, I'm giving you the orders now.
Do nothing
Sit back
and watch
unless you want Josie's blood on your hands
- He won't hurt her.
- You heard what I said
- The men are ready, sir.
- Keep them where they are.
Though we know  attack (??) for now
Hold on your positions
Yes, I know!
We're running out of time.
Sorry
You could get out of my depth on this one
We all are, major.
We all are.
Liz
What's that?
it's box.
A gift from an old friend
Something looking present
Does it serve any purpose?
It keeps me on my toes
Anything, box?
Liz, I need to talk to you
Excuse me, major
- Where are you going?
- Take care of the chair.
Go left
Up there
- What's happening to you?
- Didn't your husband tell you
the MOD's most lethal weapon
is being decommissioned in the most spectacular style
She's pregnant
A boy
Do you have any children?
I know what you're thinking, Patricia
when the shit hits the fan...
Sir
Oh you...need help
I understand, Sir
that you are in an impossible position
I made up my mind
If you're sure, Sir
I am sure, major.
And, get the job done.
Understood, Sir. We'll do our best.
All the member going in.
Paul, you have to let me go.
You're not going... anywhere.
Sheer to stop. Remember?
and only if you can get a clear shot
Come on, major
Men, listen
We've run out of time
You move on my order
Remember,
Its vital to keep the corporal alive
Go
Shit!
Maybe you're not so valuable after all.
It's the PM
I'll call him back
Wait!
Give me the gun
It's over
She's pregnant
No
It's true
4 months.
It's boy.
Go
And Dr. Shaw...
I'm running out of time.
You go.
That's a order, soldier
What's so...funny?
Our fate
and hand it deals us ??
What are you talking about?
We're both a little crazy, aren't we?
You and me.
Oh, come on.
You know what I'm talking about?
What's it all for?
I hear myself shout
You brother Charlie knew, didn't he, Paul?
Of course he did. Bennett told him.
It was more than that
He kept going despite the fact
that he knew he was dying
Come on, Paul
You're better than that.
Do it
Come in now.
Box?
Doctor Shaw
Yes, major?
I...I meant to say...
Thank you
What's this, a takeover bid?
Liz!
No.
There is only one boss of PROBE.
Thank God its all over.
What's the matter?
What?
Sit down
What is it?
I'm thinking...
of jack Quinn ??
What
I'm thinking it maybe Spain
Spain? You mad?
What about me?
I'd want you to come with me
hello everyone  nice and discreet
we don't want to disturb the natives
the couple must not know where here
its one of Bennetts jobs to keep me alive
No  no  its not
do less eyebrow
allowed to register my thighs
and feed it in any size
positions  gentlemen  the decisions
didnt even
this
in here
yeah
box is more than just
worst
my husband  to get
I guess
I presumably founded
but I'm just going by the door opening
don't go
I'm recording
its
oh  you should just
the fuck are you doing?
finishing the job
sit
a fucking  you do that shit
that you're going to eat something  and I don't don't tell me what hes going to do
Tell me  what are you cant do that