Doctor!
Litefoot's got visitors.
(CHINESE LANGUAGE)
你好吗
What happened?
- Chinese! Dozens of them!
- What?
Oh, the devils!
Well, they got what they came for.
- What?
- The time cabinet.
- Damn scoundrels!
- Get him a drink.
In a glass.
- Professor, how did they get in?
- I've no idea.
I locked and bolted all the doors
as soon as you left! Thank you.
- Were they all Chinese?
- Tongwallahs - criminals!
The gutter scrapings of Shanghai!
- And one midget.
- Yes! How on earth did you deduce
- that one was a midget?
- Elementary, my dear Litefoot.
He came in the laundry basket
and let the others in.
The same creature that attacked me!
- The Peking Homunculus!
- Who?
Liberation, Mr Sin! Freedom!
I can become whole again! Whole and alive!
Oh, I have dreamt of this moment -
to be free of this putrefying carcass,
to fashion myself anew
in some distant time and place!
And I can do it now, now at last
that I have the time cabinet!
I promise you, Mr Sin,
we shall not remain long among
these filthy barbarians! Where is the bag?
Answer me, you fools! Where is the bag?
It was... We did not...
- The bag, you cowering oaf!
- It was left behind, great lord.
What?!
(SCREAMS) What?!
Lee! Lee!
I told you to take it
out to the carriage! I ordered you!
You know the penalty for failing me!
Take the sting of the scorpion!
(WENG-CHIANG AND MR SIN LAUGH)
Thank you!
Kindly tell your employer
that Mr Jago wishes to see him!
- What?
- Your employer, Professor Litefoot!
- May I ask, sir, who you are?
- Confound your insolence! Announce me!
Consider yourself announced! I'M Litefoot!
Why, dash me optics! I should have realised!
That brow, those hands,
England's peerless premier
professor of pathology!
Henry Gordon Jago, sir, at your service!
Mr Jago, just tell me what all this is about!
- The Doctor.
- What?
This bag!
Shall we go inside?
Found this in my cellar.
Thought the Doctor might be interested.
- It may concern those Chineses.
- The Chinese?
I considered going to Scotland Yard,
where he's held in the highest esteem.
- The Doctor is?
- Of course. He solves half their cases
while they take the credit, don't you agree?
- I have no idea.
- It stands to reason.
I mean, they're policemen!
We all know they're solid, sterling fellows,
but their buttons
are the brightest thing about them!
Now, the Doctor's a real detective.
Yes, he's certainly very active.
How did you learn of my connection with him?
I enquired at the local station
and they told me that you'd been seen together.
The most formidable combination
in the annals of criminology!
It's a great honour to be working
with you on this devilish affair!
Thank you! I'm sure the Doctor will be
very interested in these things.
Unfortunately, he isn't here at present.
The sleuth that never rests, eh?
Well, he did remark that sleep is for tortoises.
I can't for the life of me discern
what purposes these articles might serve.
It's a queer lot of paraphernalia.
I thought so meself.
And they were left by Weng-Chiang,
this murderous lunatic?
They're nothing to do with the theatre.
The bag was amongst our old junk.
In that case, Mr Jago, is it not possible
that someone plans to return for it?
Yes, yes - good point.
We must tell the Doctor.
Or take a hand ourselves.
Well, the Doctor isn't here.
If you and I keep a discreet watch
on the theatre,
we might get a chance to nab this fellow!
You're suggesting a pernoctation, Professor.
Unfortunately, the nocturnal vapours
are very bad for my chest.
You can wrap up!
I'll lend you some extra clothing!
- Very kind, I'm sure.
- Now, you write a note to the Doctor,
and I'll look you out a cape!
We might be lucky, Mr Jago,
and if we are, I've a few lumps to repay!
This is their hideaway, no doubt about it.
It's unfortunate there were too many
for us to tackle, eh, Professor?
- I was itching for a scrap!
- The question is, what now?
We could adjourn for liquid refreshment.
I know a spot nearby.
One of us should stay
while the other fetches the Doctor.
- Good idea. I'll be as quick as I can!
- Too late, old man.
(JAGO ) Oh, corks!
Backs to the wall.
Keep off, you lot!
I'm a tiger when my dander's up!
(WENG-CHIANG) So...you choose
to pry on the House of the Dragon?
Unwise! Very unwise! You will suffer for it!
You'll be the sufferer when the police get here!
(LAUGHING) The police (?)
Mr Sin, they take me for a simpleton!
They'll be here, don't you worry!
You told them where you were coming?
Of course. We're not
completely without sense!
Lies! You didn't know where this was!
You followed my men from the theatre!
- If that's what you believe...
- Why were you at the theatre?
Answer me!
- Why were we at the theatre?
- I refuse to answer!
- You can do with us as you wish!
- I say, steady on!
Very well, I will tell you why.
- You were waiting to see...
- You don't know your own strength!
- ..who came to collect the bag!
- You're choking me!
Where is the bag?
What have you done with it?
- Let him go!
- The bag! Tell me!
It's at my house.
Now, for pity's sake, release him!
You will die later - slowly!
It will give pleasure to my wolves.
You filthy bounder!
In the meantime,
put them with the other prisoners.
(DOCTOR) Litefoot! Litefoot!
''My dear Doctor, contained in this bag,
which I discovered in the cellar,
''is a collection of sundry items
of baffling meaning.
''The Professor and I are keeping
observation on the theatre.
''Your fellow detective H.G.J.''
(JAGO ) Are they dead?
Drugged, I think.
You know why they're here.
Poor creatures!
Ah! Eureka! Do you know what that is?
You ask me so that you can tell me!
That's right. It's a trionic lattice,
an integral part of a time cabinet.
It can't be opened without it.
- It's a key?
- Yes. He's not only a scientific fool,
- he's an absent-minded one!
- Perhaps he has another ''Eureka''.
No, ''Eureka'' is Greek for ''this bath is too hot''.
There can never be another of this combination.
Dammit, Jago, I don't see any way out of this.
- I think we're done for!
- You're forgetting the Doctor!
- How can he find this place?
- A fleck of mud, a speck of paint,
clues that speak volumes
to an investigator like him!
I'll wager he's on our tracks this very minute!
- Look at this!
- What of it?
- Don't you see? It's a dumb waiter!
- Frankly, I'm not very peckish.
How can you think of food?
I'm not thinking of food!
I'm thinking that if we take that shelf out
and squeeze ourselves in,
we can make a surreptitious exit
via the dining room!
By jiminy, you're right!
We'll teach those blighters a lesson yet!
They picked the wrong man
when they decided to cross swords with me!
After you, Mr Jago.
Those ropes don't look too sound, do they?
''He that is down need fear no fall!''
- Hmm?
- A quotation - Bunyan.
(JAGO ) Very comforting!
- Mind your elbow, Professor!
- Sorry!
(BOTH SHOUT) Heave!
- This isn't the dining room!
- This isn't the way out either.
We must trap them in the crossfire, Doctor,
in the open where they cannot find cover.
What sort of crossfire?
Hazelnuts? Bread pellets?
A house this size must have protection.
The professor will have weapons
in fixed positions to guard the approaches.
I brought you to the wrong time,
my girl. You'd have loved Agincourt!