That's the most fantastic story I've ever heard.
I can only repeat, sir, what I have already told you.
You will get visitors from that other planet.
Nonsense.
It's imperative that I talk to you, General.
Get away, old man. Can't you see...
You, will you pay attention? Will you?!
Get this man back into the observations room. Sergeant, that was an order!
Take that man back to the obs...
Back to your places.
Oh no...
Come back Polly, they'll blow your head off!
Ah!
Now look, I don't know who you are or what you are
你看，我不知道你们是谁，是什么东西
but we've got two men in space, if we don't act now we won't get them back alive.
They will not return.
Why not?
It is unimportant now.
But... We must get them back! When...
There is really no point. They could never reach Earth now.
But don't you care?
Care? No, why should I care?
Because they're people and they're going to die!
I do not understand you. There are people dying all over your world yet you do not care about them.
Yes, but we could avoid their deaths...
You will be wondering what has happened.
Your astronomers will have just discovered a new planet. Is that not so?
Yes, that's right.
That is where we come from. It is called Mondas.
Mondas?
Mondas? But isn't that one of the ancient names of Earth?
Yes. Aeons ago our planets were twins then we drifted away from you...
...on a journey to the edge of space. Now we have returned.
You were right, Doctor.
But who or what are you?
We are called Cybermen.
Cybermen?
Yes, Cybermen. We were exactly like you once
but our cybernetic scientists realised that our race was getting weak.
Weak, how?
Our life span was getting shorter so our scientists and doctors devised spare parts for our bodies
...until we could be almost completely replaced.
But... that means you're not like us. You're robots!
Our brains are just like yours except that certain weaknesses have been removed.
Weaknesses? What weaknesses?
You call them emotions, do you not?
But... that's terrible! You... you mean you wouldn't care about someone in pain?
There would be no need. We do not feel pain.
But we do.
General!
Ha, that'll fix ya! Europe will know there's an emergency here now.
That was really most unfortunate. You should not have done that.
Switch off the radio and tell Europe that nothing further has happened and that all is well here.
I'll do no such thing.
That is an order.
Go take a jump!
Trigger pack.
Stay where you are.
You've killed him!
I have not killed him. He will recover.
Now, someone must answer your commander in Europe. He is waiting.
I refuse.
You.
Yes?
Which are the communication controls?
O... over here.
Dyson!
Stand aside
What are you going to do?
You will see.
If you destroy those we shall be unable to keep contact with the capsule.
Your commander is still waiting for your report.
For God's sake Barclay, do as he asks. Do you want the place destroyed?
All right.
Come in Geneva.
Snowcap. What's going on? We received an emergency from you on the radio link.
I-i-i-it was a fault. We're, we are looking at it now. I'm sorry about the false alarm.
Where is the static coming from? We can hardly hear you, even on these bands.
It it it, well, I-I-I, er think it must have been the reactor.
We had the moderator on, er, for a time this afternoon and er, well, well that's probably it.
I see. Contact us if you have any further reports on this new planet.
Yes sir.
Well done, Barclay. Now the space capsule will have another chance.
Now you must let us try and get in touch with our astronauts.
I told you it is impossible for them to get back now.
The force on them is too strong.
But you must let us try, please.
It is a foregone conclusion. You are wasting time.
However, if you wish to contact them I have no objection.
He and his colleagues may use their equipment.
Any attempt at deceit however, kill them at once.
Remove the soldier. I will carry on detail.
Snowcap to Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4, come in please.
We have you, over.
Prepare to check orbital density.
Ready.
Right Doctor, while they take him out we'll make a break for it.
Eh?
Then we can get back to the TARDIS!
Well how can we do that, boy?
Well, we can make a break for it. Down that corridor, the trapdoor and then bolt it from behind.
Nonsense, nonsense, they'll burn it down in a flash!
We can do with that for a start!
No, Ben!
If they see you... Ben, for goodness sake!
Stop! Come here.
You do not seem to take us seriously.
Blimey!
Heavens!
Take him out and look after him.
It is quite useless to resist us. We are stronger
and more efficient than your Earth people. We must be obeyed.
Uh! Locked... uh! No
What happened?
I'm afraid the spaceship exploded, my dear.
You mean they're dead?
Now perhaps you can see that your planet is in great and imminent danger.
In order to save you we shall require information to be transmitted to Mondas.
Save us?
What about those poor men?
Perhaps you will co-operate. Mondas drew the ship away. It was unavoidable.
Why? What is happening?
I will require your name.
Tell us!
The energy of Mondas is nearly exhausted
and now we turn to it's twin and will gather energy from Earth.
Gather energy?!
Age, name and occupation.
But for how long?
My name is John Dyson, supervising engineer.
Until it is all gone. Age.
But that means that the Earth will... will die!
Yes. Everything on Earth will stop. Age please.
But you can't calmly stand there and tell us we're all going to die!
You are not going to die.
And how are you going to stop this energy drain from Mondas?
Name and occupation please. We cannot. It is beyond our powers.
How are we going to survive?!
Speak please. By coming with us. Age.
With you?
Yes. We are going to take you all back to Mondas. Your age please.
- His age is unimportant here!
- That's the most ridiculous thing I've ever heard in my life!
You cannot for one moment...
Hey, wait a minute! If I was to turn this on the door...
...it might blind him! Yeah.
Hah! I saw that film 20 years ago.
Oy, come in here mate, you're wanted! Oy, come in here!
Blemmy ehny ah fu! Uh!
Now then, Fred!
Ahh!
Do not resist. Give me that weapon.
No, I'm sorry mate, I'm giving the orders here. Now look, get back.
Look, I'm telling you, get back!
You didn't give me no alternative!
There's no scientific certainty that this is a dying planet!
Perhaps we would prefer to take our chances here.
You must come and live with us.
But we cannot live with you, you're... you're different, you've got no feelings.
Feelings? I do not understand that word.
Emotions. Love, pride, hate, fear. Have you no emotions, sir?
Come to Mondas and you will have no need of emotions.
You will become like us.
Like you?
We have freedom from disease, protection against heat and cold, true mastery.
Do you prefer to die in misery?
But look, surely I... it's possible for us not to lose Earth's energy?
It is inevitable.
Then you don't mind if we all die.
Why should we mind?
Why? Why?!
Because millions and millions of people are going to suffer and die horribly!
We shall not be affected.
Don't you think of anything except yourselves?!
We are equipped to survive. We are only interested in survival.
Anything else is of no importance. Your deaths will not affect us.
But I can't make you understand, you're condemning us all to die, have you no heart?
No, that is one of the weaknesses that we have removed.
All right, get me Geneva, quick!
Come on, let's have some action. Get rid of these... things!
I don't think you should have done that, General. We may have learned a very great deal.
Yeah, we may have lost a very great deal, our lives!
Missile control? Program all Cobra anti-missiles for launch imminent. Stand in readiness and await instructions.
What a ghastly man.
Yeah, I wouldn't want him on the bridge.
We'll soon have this place sealed up like a bottle.
I think you rather underestimate the Cybermen, General.
Oh, that's what you reckon is it, old man?
Well, you're entitled to your opinions so long as you keep them to yourself!
General Cutler, sir!
Yes, what is it?
Strong signal on the early warning, unidentified.
Yes sir, it's er, er... There are hundreds of them, sir!
Hundreds of what, man?
Spaceships sir. In formation!