Dyson, get through to Zeus 5!
What's happened to you, Doctor?
I'm not sure, my dear. Comes from an outside influence. Unless this old body of mine is wearing a bit thin.
What do you mean "wearing a bit thin"?
Oh, don't worry child, don't worry, don't worry...
Silence. Anyone who moves will be killed instantly.
Your planet is finished. It will disintegrate. We know why you came here. So why not stay and live with us in peace, hmm?
We cannot talk while that missile is aimed at Mondas. It must be disarmed first.
A moment, please.
Are you able to disarm this rocket?
Well, yes - but...
It will give us the time we need!
The time for Mondas to burn itself out, you mean?
Yes, now quiet! We accept your terms. The warhead will be removed from the rocket.
It must be removed to below ground level.
Well, there's the Radiation Room. It's the deepest in the base.
That will do. And to make sure you do this, we will take two hostages.
That girl will go to the spacecraft.
Surely you're not going to return to Mondas now?
We will not discuss our plans with you.
What is your second objective? It's quite obvious, isn't it? The destruction of the Earth!
Listen to me. This close proximity of our two planets means that one has to be eliminated for the safety of the other. The one to be destroyed will be Earth. We cannot allow Mondas to burn up.
Take the old man out to the spacecraft.
You will regret this.
Doctor... Doctor?
Hmm... What is it, child?
Engines! They're not going to take off, are they?
No, no. Wait! The vibrations. Perhaps it's coming from Mondas!
What do you mean, Mondas?
This spacecraft receives its energy from Mondas. Perhaps it's absorbing too much.
Don't mean it's going to blow up, do you?
No, I don't know, child. It is an unknown power...
Doctor, I'm scared!
Just look at Mondas! I can't believe it!
Fantastic! It looks as if it's melting!
It's falling to bits!
The end of Mondas.
Hey, look!
What's happened to them?
They've disintegrated!
They must have been entirely dependent on power from Mondas!
Doctor!
Ben! Oh please, Ben, help me... get me out of this thing!
All right, don't panic, I'll have you out soon!
Ow! My hands were stuck and I couldn't get out!... Ben, I've been so scared!
Take it easy love, take it easy.
And that Cyberman thing, it just fizzled into nothing, Ben, it was awful...
Now what's the matter with the Doctor?
I don't know. When the lights went out, he just seemed to faint.
Hey, come on Doctor, wakey wakey! It's all over now.
What did you say, my boy?
"It's all over. " That's what you said.
No... but it isn't all over. It's far from being all over.
Wait for us!
Open the door!
Hey, let us in!
You can't leave us here, of all places! Open up!
Doctor!
Doctor! Quick, help him!
No, leave him!