Man, it's blowing like crazy out there. All I can see is snow, snow and more snow.
Quite an arctic storm blowing out there. Hmm! Come along Polly, my child, with my cloak.
Hey Doctor, you've got the most fantastic wardrobe!
Yes, well I'm glad you approve my child.
These are gorgeous. Where do you shop, Carnaby street?! Ha ha!
Who do you think you are, Nanook of the North or something?!
Oh now, now, now. Tcha, tcha, tcha. Stop being so flippant.
We don't know what we are in for outside there. Now come along, come along, come along.
Here you are, Doctor.
Are you sure you're going to be warm enough?
Oh, like toast my dear. Now, did you find everything you want?
Yes thanks!
All right, well let's go outside and investigate. Go along.
The Doctor was right about this being the coldest place on earth. I'm freezing already.
Yeah.
Hey, what's this?
Well watch it Polly!
It's some kind of an aerial. There must be something buried underneath there.
Hey, look over there, there's something moving.
Hey Tito, will you come over here?
Oh, what is it?
Come over here quick! I can see people!
Sure, sure, lots of people!
- And there's a woman!   - A woman...
A WOMAN! Hey!
Hey, hey! Mama Mia bellissima!
Looks... looks like some kind of a hut.
Quick, take those small arms, get upstairs and get... bring them down. Get moving!
I think we'd better go with 'em.
Move it, come on, hurry it up, come on, let's go, let's go, come on pops,
Will you move it, will you move it pops, let's go, come on!
Please stop that. Please, please stop that.
Just a moment pops. Now who are you, and what are you doing here?
Oh, we just landed outside.
- What in?  - Well it's a sort of spaceship actually.
- Ha ha! Some spaceship, box!   - You can knock off the jokes.
She's not joking.
Look buddy, I want the truth, and quick.
Can you tell us precisely where we are please?
You're at the South Pole base of international space command, and frankly pops...
Doctor.
...Doctor, your story's gonna have to be awful good.
So you mean we are on Earth?
Well you heard, the South Pole.
Oh boy. Tito, get the CO.
He's a-not going to like it.
Get him!
Why don't you speak up, I'm deaf!
Who's the CO?
The Commanding Officer, the boss.
Hallo... Sir? Er, Private Tito, duty guard here.
Could you give a message to the General please?
- General?  - General Cutler, the CO.
Sir? I know, but this is an emergency! What's that? The General's not there?
Well canna you tell me where he is then?
Right here, Private.
What is it Sergeant?
Ah, well sir...
Who are these people?
Well sir, they just appeared outside.
What?
Yes sir, as I said they just appeared, from a hut.
A hut?!
Yes sir. Never been there before.
That's a right General. That's just the way it happened.
Well? Who are you?
Able seaman Ben Jackson sir, Royal Navy.
Then why aren't you with your ship?
That's a bit difficult to explain sir.
Yeah, I'll bet my sweet life it is.
We don't intend you any harm General, I can assure you of that.
You can assure me of what you like, but whether I'll believe you or not is another question.
Huh, huh!
I haven't got time to deal with these now, but when I do you'd better have a good explanation.
I don't like your tone, sir.
And I don't like your face, nor your hair!
Hmm!
Sergeant, bring him into Tracking and put him under guard in the observation room.
I'll deal with them as soon as I have time.
Yes sir!
OK, come on, move...
Hey, this is smashing. It looks just like that rocket place in America.
Yeah, but I wonder why there are so few people.
I mean it's not like what you see on the telly, is it?
I don't know what you see on your TV, son,
but this is General Cutler's outfit. Come on, you'd better take a seat.
He don't like a lot of personnel, cuts down to the bare minimum and works them right into the ground.
We only spend a couple of months on this station anyway. We can't stand more than that.
Ha ha ha!
I see. Hey, perhaps we can catch a lift back to England.
Oh, I can't see the squire there giving us a free lift to anywhere.
Well I don't want to depress you both but I'm afraid we're not quite where you think we are.
- What do you mean?  - What?
Well, just take a peek at that. Huh huh! Hmm!
1986! Oh no, and I thought we'd be able to get home.
Yeah, we're still at sea. Here, but that'll explain the few people.
The computers must do all the work now. Here, I wonder if they got to the moon yet.
Sure, don't you listen to the news?
You mean you have sent people to the moon?
Yeah, an expedition just returned.
Well what's this flight then?
Oh, this is just a normal atmosphere testing probe.
Yes, I see, a rocket testing site. Hum hum!
Hey, what's that?
An error? Where?
Looks bad. We're now over south isle of New Zealand and reading a height of 1100 miles.
1100? But that's impossible! Dyson, check what it should be, will you?
It should be 980.
No, it can't be, let me try.
Let me do it.
No, you're right. 980 miles... they're out of position by more than a hundred miles!
Mmm, looks like it.
Snowcap to Zeus 4. Can you read me?
Zeus 4 to Snowcap. Strength 8, over.
Take visual checks on Mars to establish position. Report back.
Here we are. Well now, excuse me my dear...
...er, take this to your General please.
Me? Are you crazy?
Very well then, take me to the General. I think perhaps I can help him.
Oh I... I don't know.
Now look here Sergeant, this is urgent, I insist.
General, sir.
Yes, what is it?
The old boy would like to have a word with you. Claims it's urgent.
OK, bring him over. But make it fast.
I think I know what you are going to see.
How can you possibly? Oh, get him back over there.
I've written down here what he will see.
Take your hands off me please!
Barclay! It's not very clear but it's a planet all right.
How could it be? Planets don't just appear.
It must be on a weak orbit.
It's approaching quite fast. Barclay, couldn't it be...
I know what you're thinking. Zeus 4 is out of orbit and a new planet has appeared.
Therefore the new planet is influencing Zeus 4. Right?
That's about it.
We must get them down!
An emergency splash zone?
Yes. Snowcap calling Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4 come in please. Do you read me?
Yes, we read you loud and clear.
You are strength 2 only. Come in please, speak up.
Fuel cells are showing a power loss.
Power loss?
Its gravity is affecting the capsule.
What shall we do about it?
Well first of all we must give Zeus 4 a new correction path. Will you do that?
Right away.
You try and get a better fix on that so-called planet and see what it is.
Right sir.
It's better now.
You say you know what this planet is. Well what is it?
Well I'm not quite sure sir. Let me have another look into this instrument.
Feed the retina scope into the observations room's monitor.
Look Dr Barclay, let's just get those boys down.
General, General, yes, it's just as I thought.
Come and have a look at these land masses.
Land masses? I don't see... I see what you mean.
Now, doesn't that remind you of anything, hmm?
Remind? No, I don't think so.
Yeah, it looks familiar somehow.
Yeah. Hey Ben, look, that bit looks just like... Malaysia!
Oh, give over. No, hang on, isn't that... well it looks like South America but it can't be though!
Yes, there is a similarity.
Nonsense, how could there be?
This is unbelievable. That's surely Africa?
Yes, certainly and that is Malaysia!
Ridiculous. There must be some reflection of Earth.
No it can't be, there's nothing to reflect on!
And now my dear Dr Barclay I suggest you look at that piece of paper I gave you.
Paper? Oh yes...
You knew!
Certainly.
Knew what?
He has correctly written down what we have just seen and he did it before we saw it.
Oh, it's a... simple confidence trick, that's all.
No, I know when he gave me the paper.
Now, you clearly know something more about the situation. Can you be more explicit?
Yes sir, I'm sorry, I'm afraid I can.
You see, millions of years ago there was a twin planet to Earth and...
Oh, for heaven's sake!
Roger, Zeus 4...
Get me Geneva on the radio link.
We'll see what Wigner has to say about this.
You're looking terribly worried Doctor.
Am I my dear? Yes, I'm afraid I am rather worried.
What is it Doctor? What's up?
Well you see Ben, I know what this planet is and what it means to Earth.
And what does it mean to Earth?
Well, that pretty soon we shall be having visitors.
Now, suppose you tell me how you really came here.
Yes, well I'm afraid all that's going to be rather difficult.
Now just a minute. You turn up out of nowhere, a routine space shot goes wrong...
a new planet appears and you tell us you know all about it. That puts you slap bang in the hot seat, right
Hot seat?
But we've got nothing to do with it.
That you're going to have to prove.
Well, I think if you allowed us to return where we came from, huh, huh! I...
You're not going anywhere.
- Sergeant?  - Yes sir?
- Have you searched that hut yet?  - No, sir
Well why not?! Look, I don't want any excuses, get out there and do it immediately.
Now, perhaps we'll get to the bottom of this.
Come on Tito, we have to go break into a hut.
What, that thing out there?
Yeah, that's right. Come on, hurry up and get dressed up.
Oh, mama.
It's no good Tito, we'll need a welding torch to get inside this thing.
Get back inside and bring me out one. You'll need some help, OK?
Hurry up will ya, before I freeze to death!
What the heck? Huh, Tito! Is that you Tito?
What's going on here? Who is that?
Who the heck are you?!
OK Joe, that should do it. OK, let's go.
Hey, this is where it is guys.