The Tenth Planet
(Whopix fan edit)
(Based on subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
(Updated for whopix fan edit edition, by Bamanzi)
http://whoflix.wordpress.com/2014/04/21/the-tenth-planet-2/
Man, it's blowing like crazy out there. All I can see is snow, snow and more snow.
Quite an arctic storm blowing out there. Hmm! Come along Polly, my child, with my cloak.
Hey Doctor, you've got the most fantastic wardrobe!
Yes, well I'm glad you approve my child.
These are gorgeous. Where do you shop, Carnaby street?! Ha ha!
Who do you think you are, Nanook of the North or something?!
Oh now, now, now. Tcha, tcha, tcha. Stop being so flippant.
We don't know what we are in for outside there. Now come along, come along, come along.
Here you are, Doctor.
Are you sure you're going to be warm enough?
Oh, like toast my dear. Now, did you find everything you want?
Yes thanks!
All right, well let's go outside and investigate. Go along.
The Doctor was right about this being the coldest place on earth. I'm freezing already.
Yeah.
Hey, what's this?
Well watch it Polly!
It's some kind of an aerial. There must be something buried underneath there.
Hey, look over there, there's something moving.
Hey Tito, will you come over here?
Oh, what is it?
Come over here quick! I can see people!
Sure, sure, lots of people!
- And there's a woman!   - A woman...
A WOMAN! Hey!
Hey, hey! Mama Mia bellissima!
Looks... looks like some kind of a hut.
Quick, take those small arms, get upstairs and get... bring them down. Get moving!
I think we'd better go with 'em.
Move it, come on, hurry it up, come on, let's go, let's go, come on pops,
Will you move it, will you move it pops, let's go, come on!
Please stop that. Please, please stop that.
Just a moment pops. Now who are you, and what are you doing here?
Oh, we just landed outside.
- What in?  - Well it's a sort of spaceship actually.
- Ha ha! Some spaceship, box!   - You can knock off the jokes.
She's not joking.
Look buddy, I want the truth, and quick.
Can you tell us precisely where we are please?
You're at the South Pole base of international space command, and frankly pops...
Doctor.
...Doctor, your story's gonna have to be awful good.
So you mean we are on Earth?
Well you heard, the South Pole.
Oh boy. Tito, get the CO.
He's a-not going to like it.
Get him!
Why don't you speak up, I'm deaf!
Who's the CO?
The Commanding Officer, the boss.
Hallo... Sir? Er, Private Tito, duty guard here.
Could you give a message to the General please?
- General?  - General Cutler, the CO.
Sir? I know, but this is an emergency! What's that? The General's not there?
Well canna you tell me where he is then?
Right here, Private.
What is it Sergeant?
Ah, well sir...
Who are these people?
Well sir, they just appeared outside.
What?
Yes sir, as I said they just appeared, from a hut.
A hut?!
Yes sir. Never been there before.
That's a right General. That's just the way it happened.
Well? Who are you?
Able seaman Ben Jackson sir, Royal Navy.
Then why aren't you with your ship?
That's a bit difficult to explain sir.
Yeah, I'll bet my sweet life it is.
We don't intend you any harm General, I can assure you of that.
You can assure me of what you like, but whether I'll believe you or not is another question.
Huh, huh!
I haven't got time to deal with these now, but when I do you'd better have a good explanation.
I don't like your tone, sir.
And I don't like your face, nor your hair!
Hmm!
Sergeant, bring him into Tracking and put him under guard in the observation room.
I'll deal with them as soon as I have time.
Yes sir!
OK, come on, move...
Hey, this is smashing. It looks just like that rocket place in America.
Yeah, but I wonder why there are so few people.
I mean it's not like what you see on the telly, is it?
I don't know what you see on your TV, son,
but this is General Cutler's outfit. Come on, you'd better take a seat.
He don't like a lot of personnel, cuts down to the bare minimum and works them right into the ground.
We only spend a couple of months on this station anyway. We can't stand more than that.
Ha ha ha!
I see. Hey, perhaps we can catch a lift back to England.
Oh, I can't see the squire there giving us a free lift to anywhere.
Well I don't want to depress you both but I'm afraid we're not quite where you think we are.
- What do you mean?  - What?
Well, just take a peek at that. Huh huh! Hmm!
1986! Oh no, and I thought we'd be able to get home.
Yeah, we're still at sea. Here, but that'll explain the few people.
The computers must do all the work now. Here, I wonder if they got to the moon yet.
Sure, don't you listen to the news?
You mean you have sent people to the moon?
Yeah, an expedition just returned.
Well what's this flight then?
Oh, this is just a normal atmosphere testing probe.
Yes, I see, a rocket testing site. Hum hum!
Hey, what's that?
An error? Where?
Looks bad. We're now over south isle of New Zealand and reading a height of 1100 miles.
1100? But that's impossible! Dyson, check what it should be, will you?
It should be 980.
No, it can't be, let me try.
Let me do it.
No, you're right. 980 miles... they're out of position by more than a hundred miles!
Mmm, looks like it.
Snowcap to Zeus 4. Can you read me?
Zeus 4 to Snowcap. Strength 8, over.
Take visual checks on Mars to establish position. Report back.
Here we are. Well now, excuse me my dear...
...er, take this to your General please.
Me? Are you crazy?
Very well then, take me to the General. I think perhaps I can help him.
Oh I... I don't know.
Now look here Sergeant, this is urgent, I insist.
General, sir.
Yes, what is it?
The old boy would like to have a word with you. Claims it's urgent.
OK, bring him over. But make it fast.
I think I know what you are going to see.
How can you possibly? Oh, get him back over there.
I've written down here what he will see.
Take your hands off me please!
Barclay! It's not very clear but it's a planet all right.
How could it be? Planets don't just appear.
It must be on a weak orbit.
It's approaching quite fast. Barclay, couldn't it be...
I know what you're thinking. Zeus 4 is out of orbit and a new planet has appeared.
Therefore the new planet is influencing Zeus 4. Right?
That's about it.
We must get them down!
An emergency splash zone?
Yes. Snowcap calling Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4 come in please. Do you read me?
Yes, we read you loud and clear.
You are strength 2 only. Come in please, speak up.
Fuel cells are showing a power loss.
Power loss?
Its gravity is affecting the capsule.
What shall we do about it?
Well first of all we must give Zeus 4 a new correction path. Will you do that?
Right away.
You try and get a better fix on that so-called planet and see what it is.
Right sir.
It's better now.
You say you know what this planet is. Well what is it?
Well I'm not quite sure sir. Let me have another look into this instrument.
Feed the retina scope into the observations room's monitor.
Look Dr Barclay, let's just get those boys down.
General, General, yes, it's just as I thought.
Come and have a look at these land masses.
Land masses? I don't see... I see what you mean.
Now, doesn't that remind you of anything, hmm?
Remind? No, I don't think so.
Yeah, it looks familiar somehow.
Yeah. Hey Ben, look, that bit looks just like... Malaysia!
Oh, give over. No, hang on, isn't that... well it looks like South America but it can't be though!
Yes, there is a similarity.
Nonsense, how could there be?
This is unbelievable. That's surely Africa?
Yes, certainly and that is Malaysia!
Ridiculous. There must be some reflection of Earth.
No it can't be, there's nothing to reflect on!
And now my dear Dr Barclay I suggest you look at that piece of paper I gave you.
Paper? Oh yes...
You knew!
Certainly.
Knew what?
He has correctly written down what we have just seen and he did it before we saw it.
Oh, it's a... simple confidence trick, that's all.
No, I know when he gave me the paper.
Now, you clearly know something more about the situation. Can you be more explicit?
Yes sir, I'm sorry, I'm afraid I can.
You see, millions of years ago there was a twin planet to Earth and...
Oh, for heaven's sake!
Roger, Zeus 4...
Get me Geneva on the radio link.
We'll see what Wigner has to say about this.
You're looking terribly worried Doctor.
Am I my dear? Yes, I'm afraid I am rather worried.
What is it Doctor? What's up?
Well you see Ben, I know what this planet is and what it means to Earth.
And what does it mean to Earth?
Well, that pretty soon we shall be having visitors.
Now, suppose you tell me how you really came here.
Yes, well I'm afraid all that's going to be rather difficult.
Now just a minute. You turn up out of nowhere, a routine space shot goes wrong...
a new planet appears and you tell us you know all about it. That puts you slap bang in the hot seat, right
Hot seat?
But we've got nothing to do with it.
That you're going to have to prove.
Well, I think if you allowed us to return where we came from, huh, huh! I...
You're not going anywhere.
- Sergeant?  - Yes sir?
- Have you searched that hut yet?  - No, sir
Well why not?! Look, I don't want any excuses, get out there and do it immediately.
Now, perhaps we'll get to the bottom of this.
Come on Tito, we have to go break into a hut.
What, that thing out there?
Yeah, that's right. Come on, hurry up and get dressed up.
Oh, mama.
It's no good Tito, we'll need a welding torch to get inside this thing.
Get back inside and bring me out one. You'll need some help, OK?
Hurry up will ya, before I freeze to death!
What the heck? Huh, Tito! Is that you Tito?
What's going on here? Who is that?
Who the heck are you?!
OK Joe, that should do it. OK, let's go.
Hey, this is where it is guys.
That's the most fantastic story I've ever heard.
I can only repeat, sir, what I have already told you.
You will get visitors from that other planet.
Nonsense.
It's imperative that I talk to you, General.
Get away, old man. Can't you see...
You, will you pay attention? Will you?!
Get this man back into the observations room. Sergeant, that was an order!
Take that man back to the obs...
Back to your places.
Oh no...
Come back Polly, they'll blow your head off!
Ah!
Now look, I don't know who you are or what you are...
...but we've got two men in space, if we don't act now we won't get them back alive.
They will not return.
Why not?
It is unimportant now.
But... We must get them back! When...
There is really no point. They could never reach Earth now.
But don't you care?
Care? No, why should I care?
Because they're people and they're going to die!
I do not understand you. There are people dying all over your world yet you do not care about them.
Yes, but we could avoid their deaths...
You will be wondering what has happened.
Your astronomers will have just discovered a new planet. Is that not so?
Yes, that's right.
That is where we come from. It is called Mondas.
Mondas?
Mondas? But isn't that one of the ancient names of Earth?
Yes. Aeons ago our planets were twins then we drifted away from you...
...on a journey to the edge of space. Now we have returned.
You were right, Doctor.
But who or what are you?
We are called Cybermen.
Cybermen?
Yes, Cybermen. We were exactly like you once
but our cybernetic scientists realised that our race was getting weak.
Weak, how?
Our life span was getting shorter so our scientists and doctors devised spare parts for our bodies
...until we could be almost completely replaced.
But... that means you're not like us. You're robots!
Our brains are just like yours except that certain weaknesses have been removed.
Weaknesses? What weaknesses?
You call them emotions, do you not?
But... that's terrible! You... you mean you wouldn't care about someone in pain?
There would be no need. We do not feel pain.
But we do.
General!
Ha, that'll fix ya! Europe will know there's an emergency here now.
That was really most unfortunate. You should not have done that.
Switch off the radio and tell Europe that nothing further has happened and that all is well here.
I'll do no such thing.
That is an order.
Go take a jump!
Trigger pack.
Stay where you are.
You've killed him!
I have not killed him. He will recover.
Now, someone must answer your commander in Europe. He is waiting.
I refuse.
You.
Yes?
Which are the communication controls?
O... over here.
Dyson!
Stand aside
What are you going to do?
You will see.
If you destroy those we shall be unable to keep contact with the capsule.
Your commander is still waiting for your report.
For God's sake Barclay, do as he asks. Do you want the place destroyed?
All right.
Come in Geneva.
Snowcap. What's going on? We received an emergency from you on the radio link.
I-i-i-it was a fault. We're, we are looking at it now. I'm sorry about the false alarm.
Where is the static coming from? We can hardly hear you, even on these bands.
It it it, well, I-I-I, er think it must have been the reactor.
We had the moderator on, er, for a time this afternoon and er, well, well that's probably it.
I see. Contact us if you have any further reports on this new planet.
Yes sir.
Well done, Barclay. Now the space capsule will have another chance.
Now you must let us try and get in touch with our astronauts.
I told you it is impossible for them to get back now.
The force on them is too strong.
But you must let us try, please.
It is a foregone conclusion. You are wasting time.
However, if you wish to contact them I have no objection.
He and his colleagues may use their equipment.
Any attempt at deceit however, kill them at once.
Remove the soldier. I will carry on detail.
Snowcap to Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4, come in please.
We have you, over.
Prepare to check orbital density.
Ready.
Right Doctor, while they take him out we'll make a break for it.
Eh?
Then we can get back to the TARDIS!
Well how can we do that, boy?
Well, we can make a break for it. Down that corridor, the trapdoor and then bolt it from behind.
Nonsense, nonsense, they'll burn it down in a flash!
We can do with that for a start!
No, Ben!
If they see you... Ben, for goodness sake!
Stop! Come here.
You do not seem to take us seriously.
Blimey!
Heavens!
Take him out and look after him.
It is quite useless to resist us. We are stronger
and more efficient than your Earth people. We must be obeyed.
Uh! Locked... uh! No
What happened?
I'm afraid the spaceship exploded, my dear.
You mean they're dead?
Now perhaps you can see that your planet is in great and imminent danger.
In order to save you we shall require information to be transmitted to Mondas.
Save us?
What about those poor men?
Perhaps you will co-operate. Mondas drew the ship away. It was unavoidable.
Why? What is happening?
I will require your name.
Tell us!
The energy of Mondas is nearly exhausted
and now we turn to it's twin and will gather energy from Earth.
Gather energy?!
Age, name and occupation.
But for how long?
My name is John Dyson, supervising engineer.
Until it is all gone. Age.
But that means that the Earth will... will die!
Yes. Everything on Earth will stop. Age please.
But you can't calmly stand there and tell us we're all going to die!
You are not going to die.
And how are you going to stop this energy drain from Mondas?
Name and occupation please. We cannot. It is beyond our powers.
How are we going to survive?!
Speak please. By coming with us. Age.
With you?
Yes. We are going to take you all back to Mondas. Your age please.
- His age is unimportant here!
- That's the most ridiculous thing I've ever heard in my life!
You cannot for one moment...
Hey, wait a minute! If I was to turn this on the door...
...it might blind him! Yeah.
Hah! I saw that film 20 years ago.
Oy, come in here mate, you're wanted! Oy, come in here!
Blemmy ehny ah fu! Uh!
Now then, Fred!
Ahh!
Do not resist. Give me that weapon.
No, I'm sorry mate, I'm giving the orders here. Now look, get back.
Look, I'm telling you, get back!
You didn't give me no alternative!
There's no scientific certainty that this is a dying planet!
Perhaps we would prefer to take our chances here.
You must come and live with us.
But we cannot live with you, you're... you're different, you've got no feelings.
Feelings? I do not understand that word.
Emotions. Love, pride, hate, fear. Have you no emotions, sir?
Come to Mondas and you will have no need of emotions.
You will become like us.
Like you?
We have freedom from disease, protection against heat and cold, true mastery.
Do you prefer to die in misery?
But look, surely I... it's possible for us not to lose Earth's energy?
It is inevitable.
Then you don't mind if we all die.
Why should we mind?
Why? Why?!
Because millions and millions of people are going to suffer and die horribly!
We shall not be affected.
Don't you think of anything except yourselves?!
We are equipped to survive. We are only interested in survival.
Anything else is of no importance. Your deaths will not affect us.
But I can't make you understand, you're condemning us all to die, have you no heart?
No, that is one of the weaknesses that we have removed.
All right, get me Geneva, quick!
Come on, let's have some action. Get rid of these... things!
I don't think you should have done that, General. We may have learned a very great deal.
Yeah, we may have lost a very great deal, our lives!
Missile control? Program all Cobra anti-missiles for launch imminent. Stand in readiness and await instructions.
What a ghastly man.
Yeah, I wouldn't want him on the bridge.
We'll soon have this place sealed up like a bottle.
I think you rather underestimate the Cybermen, General.
Oh, that's what you reckon is it, old man?
Well, you're entitled to your opinions so long as you keep them to yourself!
General Cutler, sir!
Yes, what is it?
Strong signal on the early warning, unidentified.
Yes sir, it's er, er... There are hundreds of them, sir!
Hundreds of what, man?
Spaceships sir. In formation!
Spaceships. That means only one thing, more Cybermen.
Dyson, see if you can get hold of Zeus 5, I want to speak to my son.
Trying now, sir.
What's the matter, Doctor?
Dyson, get through to Zeus 5!
What's happened to you, Doctor?
I'm not sure, my dear. Comes from an outside influence. Unless this old body of mine is wearing a bit thin.
What do you mean "wearing a bit thin"?
Oh, don't worry child, don't worry, don't worry...
Silence. Anyone who moves will be killed instantly.
Your planet is finished. It will disintegrate. We know why you came here. So why not stay and live with us in peace, hmm?
We cannot talk while that missile is aimed at Mondas. It must be disarmed first.
A moment, please.
Are you able to disarm this rocket?
Well, yes - but...
It will give us the time we need!
The time for Mondas to burn itself out, you mean?
Yes, now quiet! We accept your terms. The warhead will be removed from the rocket.
It must be removed to below ground level.
Well, there's the Radiation Room. It's the deepest in the base.
That will do. And to make sure you do this, we will take two hostages.
That girl will go to the spacecraft.
Surely you're not going to return to Mondas now?
We will not discuss our plans with you.
What is your second objective? It's quite obvious, isn't it? The destruction of the Earth!
Listen to me. This close proximity of our two planets means that one has to be eliminated for the safety of the other. The one to be destroyed will be Earth. We cannot allow Mondas to burn up.
Take the old man out to the spacecraft.
You will regret this.
Doctor... Doctor?
Hmm... What is it, child?
Engines! They're not going to take off, are they?
No, no. Wait! The vibrations. Perhaps it's coming from Mondas!
What do you mean, Mondas?
This spacecraft receives its energy from Mondas. Perhaps it's absorbing too much.
Don't mean it's going to blow up, do you?
No, I don't know, child. It is an unknown power...
Doctor, I'm scared!
Just look at Mondas! I can't believe it!
Fantastic! It looks as if it's melting!
It's falling to bits!
The end of Mondas.
Hey, look!
What's happened to them?
They've disintegrated!
They must have been entirely dependent on power from Mondas!
Doctor!
Ben! Oh please, Ben, help me... get me out of this thing!
All right, don't panic, I'll have you out soon!
Ow! My hands were stuck and I couldn't get out!... Ben, I've been so scared!
Take it easy love, take it easy.
And that Cyberman thing, it just fizzled into nothing, Ben, it was awful...
Now what's the matter with the Doctor?
I don't know. When the lights went out, he just seemed to faint.
Hey, come on Doctor, wakey wakey! It's all over now.
What did you say, my boy?
"It's all over. " That's what you said.
No... but it isn't all over. It's far from being all over.
Wait for us!
Open the door!
Hey, let us in!
You can't leave us here, of all places! Open up!
Doctor!
Doctor! Quick, help him!
No, leave him!