(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Planet Of Giants
(Doctor Who 1963 S02E01 Whopix fan edit)
(based on subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
(time axis: bamanzi)
synced with whopix fan edit: http://wp.me/p1mHFo-11b
We're approaching a planet.
Which one?
We shall soon see.
Ow.
What's the matter my dear?
I burnt myself on the console.
Oh, something overheating here. Just as well we're
landing? Er, Susan, check the fault locator please.
Yes Grandfather.
We're not going to blow
up or anything are we?
Oh no no no, of course not.
It's just, well, there we were in the late eighteenth century
and I tried another frequency to sidestep the ship back
into the middle of the twentieth century.
GRANDFATHER, THE DOORS, THEY'RE OPENING!
What's happening... Unbelievable!
Chesterton close the doors please! We
haven't materialised properly! Quickly!
- What do you mean close the doors?
- Don't argue dear boy
it's an emergency,
close the doors! Quick! Use force!
Is everything alright?
We're just landing.
Are you alright Doctor?
.....what?
Are you alright?
Oh please, don't bother me!
What happened just then?
Susan, go back to the fault locator,
and I want you to check everything,
child you understand, EVERYTHING!
Well at least we seem to be alright.
Mm? Oh don't be childish, they opened!
The doors opened before we
had properly materialised!
But what does it mean?
Hah-ah!
Doctor, you needn't
keep it a secret from us!
What?
Doctor, don't keep us in suspense.
Oh don't go on with these futile questions!
Please, can't you understand, can't you see?!
No we can't
- that's just it!
Oh we were just about to materialise when the
doors opened and we hadn't properly adjusted!
You mean something went out of the ship?
No that's impossible!
Came inside then?
Oh please, don't keep talking on the
twentieth-century level! I'm talking about time-travel!
Neither of you can understand what
I'm talking about I can s-see that!
How could we, you've
never explained it to us!
My dear boy...
Grandfather everything's alright! There isn't
a fault anywhere, not even on yellow standby!
But there must be something wrong, Susan!
I shall have to check that fault locator myself
to make sure, excuse me...
Oh I do wish he
wouldn't talk in riddles!
So do I. Susan perhaps you can help us?
I just know that the most dangerous
moment is at the point of materialisation.
Nothing's ever happened to us before.
Well the doors have never
opened like that before.
Well, happily no harm's been done. It's most puzzling.
Oh my dear Barbara was I rude to you just now? If so, I'm so sorry.
I-I always forget the
niceties under pressure. Please forgive me.
There's nothing to forgive.
Thank you. Hm.. Hah!
Well I suppose everything's alright. And yet, er...
See the temperature there is perfectly...
it's quite safe to go outside.
Oh Susan, just turn on the scanner a
minute, let's try and see where we are.
Doctor!
Perhaps you need a new tube Doctor?
Did you notice the way it blew out?
It was like an internal explosion.
Yes, like, like ehh...something
too big for it's frame!
Yes.
And yet, I don't know...
That can't be right!
What do we do now Doctor? Take
the scanner out and strip it down?
Oh no no no, dear boy. No, it's most puzzling of course,
but now don't know what's behind those doors.
Well we must go outside and look.
You said it was quite safe...
Yes...I wonder why the..?
Well, we must see.
- Shall I open the doors Grandfather?
- Er, yes please Susan.
But all of you, cautiously please!
Doctor, what made the doors open before?
The space pressure was far too
great whilst we were materialising.
The strange thing is that we all came out of it unscathed!
Hah, it's, it's most puzzling,
it's a big mystery my boy, come along...
It's like a mountain pass or something.
Now why wouldn't the
scanner show us all this mm?
Perhaps that was the only damage to the ship, Doctor.
Overloading on the scanner circuits.
Yes, I suppose so it could be...
What a strange rock formation!
Yes, it is, isn't it?
There are two different
types of rock. Doctor?
Mm?
Look... This is ordinary stone up here,
but this down here seems to be quite different.
Chesterton, here. Come here,
look here. Is that cement? Heh.
Might be.
Rather a rough kind isn't it?
Mn, very rough. They look like
pebbles of sand don't they?
Yes, yes as a matter of fact it's in a way
to hold the stone in place.
You know to fix it firmly beneath!
I would have thought the stone was
heavy enough to keep itself in place.
Yes, it's all most odd
isn't it? Most odd...
Now Barbara, I suggest that you and I take that path,
and Susan and you sir, er, go that way, mm?
Yes alright, but stay within calling distance,
and you see anything sing out. We'll do the same.
Yes, yes, yes... Mmm.
Mm...
Now take this rock here,
it's most extraordinary...
Doctor! Doctor, it's a huge snake!
What, eh?
Let's call the others.
Oh, er, wait wait wait...
Yes, I-I I think it's dead.
Ian! Look at this.
That's odd. I suppose it couldn't
be an egg, hah. Not that size.
There are more of them over there, look.
Yeah. Ostrich?
It would have been rounder than this.
There are dozens of them over
here! There's a whole pile of them!
Oh! Ian, Ian!
It is dead isn't it?
Yes. It's dead alright
- stiff as a poker. What a fantastic size!
Yes.
It's a giant ant.
It is like it isn't he? It looks as
if it was trying to carry these eggs.
Yes, well that's natural behaviour for an ant,
when it's attacked, take the eggs to safety.
The worker ant would give his life
rather than abandon the eggs you know...
Well he couldn't have had
much of a chance could he?
I mean he must have died quickly.
Yeah... All these eggs scattered about.
Other ants must have been frightened away.
I wonder what sort of a world
could produce an insect that size?
Well here we are then, this is the tail end of it,
- And I know what it is. It's a huge earthworm.
- What?!
Yes, there are no earthworms
this size on your planet.
You're right there aren't!
know except for it's size, I would
swear that it came from your world.
However, lets..er,
let's go on. Come along.
Now this is really baffling!
A huge picture of Night Scented Stock!
Yes it is, but why put up a picture of it? I don't get it.
Ah, some writing there... "Alf's Seed Company, Norwich!"
Norwich! That's England isn't it? Norfolk!
Yes, it is. Susan, this
means we're on Earth!
Something's very odd here,
first those ants, now this.
Hey, look at the end
of that, it's all charred!
Yes, you can see quite clearly
what this is. It's a matchstick.
Well it certainly looks like one.
No, it just doesn't look
like one, it is a matchstick.
What, that size?!
Don't you see, that huge earthworm and now this?
Can't you see what's happened Mm?
Look at this matchbox!
It must be an exhibition Susan, something like the world fair.
- Things this size...
- No Ian.
Well what else? look
at the scale of things!
You're wrong Ian, completely wrong!
I-I thought just now that something was
wrong when I saw that, but now I'm sure.
Alright, what's your theory then?
That these things haven't been made
bigger, we've been made smaller!
Smaller?!
We have been reduced roughly
to the size of an inch!
An inch?!
Mm. You, me all of us, and the ship!
We must get hold of the others
quickly and return to the TARDIS!
What's that?
Run Susan, run!
Look urgh!
Yeah.. Well it looks a
tremendous distance to me.
There's a house over there, and there's
a man sitting down reading something.
It's a notebook I think.
- Did he have the matchbox?
- How do I know?!
I don't know how you know,
but you surprise me sometimes.
Yes, I suppose so. Look, watch
what you're doing will you?!
Look, Doctor give us some hope, I
mean, Ian's inside that matchbox!
Gently, gently gently!
We've got to find Chesterton!
But Grandfather, supposing the
man walks off with the matchbox!
Have courage my dear! I know that all of this is a bit of a nightmare,
but we've just got to get Ian back and then we can go back to the ship.
And then can you get
us back to normal size?
But of course, yes I'll try! There's always a chance!
But first things first, we must find Chesterton
It's Mr Forester isn't it?
We spoke on the telephone...
Yes, I got here as quickly as I could.
I hope you haven't taken any action yet?
Not yet, but I have written my report.
You do realise what's at stake here Mr Farrow?
The early experiments were noted
by the ministry, welcomed in fact!
I've already geared factories, advertising
and all the rest of it to start pushing DN6.
I'm sorry about that, but I can't
give you the approval that you want.
I see.
You're aware of course that if it doesn't
go into production I shall be completely ruined?
That is very unfortunate, but really, you
should have waited till we gave you the go-ahead!
Well that's all very well,
but it doesn't help me does it?
Surely we can work something out?
There's a fortune to
be made out of this...
I don't think I want to go
on with this conversation.
Do you know why I am a success Mr Farrow?
Because I've never allowed the word "can't"
to exist, there's always a way, always!
Not this time.
This isn't business, this is science, the formulae is unacceptable
And I can't and I do mean can't Mr Forester,
allow DN6 to go into production!
Now I'll make that phone call.
Just a moment!/
I think It's dead.
But it could still sting!
Mm. Hah-ha! What an
awe-inspiring sight!
Now what chance would human-beings have I really
wonder, in a world of creatures like this bee, mm?
None at all!
Little closer look...
Well I haven't taken my eyes off it
Grandfather, it hasn't even trembled.
It seems you're right, it is dead.
The same distinctive aroma!
Yes, I've noticed it on
all the other dead things.
Well that must be
what's killing them then.
I wonder what would want to
kill off nature like this?
Well what worries me is all the
different things it's killing.
Things that fly in the air, things that move on the ground...
things that move under the ground. So indiscriminate.
- Doctor?
- Mm?
Whatever it is that's killing these
things... Could it kill us too?
Well, we must presume that it can.
So no eating or drinking until we've
done our very best to find Ian mm?
(A roaring boom momentarily
splits through the heady silence.)
He's been shot dead.
- Are you sure he is dead?
- Oh yes
Nothing but death all around us!
Yes, what's happening here?
You weren't with us Chesterton, but
every insect we came across was dead.
Yes, Susan and I saw a
great many huge dead ants.
Everything else was the same, Ian.
Yes, and we don't know
what it is that killed them.
But that man, he's been shot.
Murdered!
But who'd kill insects in
a perfectly ordinary garden?
I mean pests one can understand, but...
Surely it's wrong to kill bees
and worms and things isn't it?
Quite so. Both are vital
to the growth of things.
However, we must leave this little mystery and get back to the ship.
As I said my dear, it's fortunate for
all of us us that everything is dead...
Argh! Grandfather!/
Don't move, any of you.
And whatever you do,
don't look into the cat's eyes.
Close your own if you want to.
Doctor, I think the
cat's losing interest.
Don't relax! One swipe of it's
paw would smash us to pieces!
Well we can't get back to the ship just
yet, and you know how fast cats can move.
And another thing, we could be mistaken for mice
and I don't fancy being part of the cat's diet!
Oh it gets more horrifying every moment!
Look, couldn't we make contact
with the people here somehow?
No, I'm afraid not.
Well why not, they
might be able to help us.
It's out of the question my dear, how
could we possibly communicate with them?
Imagine a record played
at the wrong speed, Susan.
We'd sound like a little squeak to them,
and they'd sound like a low growl to us.
Anyway, even if we could communicate,
what would they do to us?
We're freaks. They'd put us in a glass
case and examine us through a microscope!
Oh that's a thought isn't it.
And I would add another
and more important factor.
The people that live in this house
are murderers, or one of them is.
Therefore, we can't expect sympathy and
understanding from an insane or a criminal mind!
Yes, what about that dead man?
Oughtn't we to do something about it?
Well what can we do my dear? I
mean, surely this is the question.
Normally I wouldn't hesitate, but the
destruction of the life-force is frightful,
but there it is! I mean, what can we do as we are?
Well, I can't see any sign of that cat,
however much safety that gives us.
Well, shall we proceed?
I can see a huge leg coming, run!
This...this way!
- No, Barbara
- Go on, Susan!
- I'd like to help you, Ian.
- Go on!
- Sorry!
- It's alright. This way, quickly!
Oh, Grandfather, they're overstepping on us!
Oh they're alright, they're alright. It's
a pity they didn't come this way though.
Well shall we go over to them?
No, no, it's dangerous! Let's
go over to that pipe there!
Come on Barbara, get out of
here before it moves again.
- Oh...that was worse than the big dipper.
- It was.
You know we were
lucky this case was full.
Course, it had to happen to us,
of all the places to pick, hah,
we had to choose one that was movable!
Have you any idea where we are?
That's a ceiling up there.
That means we're indoors and
the Doctor and Susan are outside.
Let's move the body.
Where can we put him?
In a store room.
They've gone
It's much better when they're
a long way away, isn't it?
Are you sure you saw one of
them pick up the briefcase
and go into that building behind us?
Well I definitely saw
him pick up the briefcase.
Well when he walked past us it was
just like a mountain just a blur, you know.
But he must have gone inside the house!
Careful Grandfather, well
don't fall down there will you?
Oh-hah-Ooh POO! FAWF! An awful
smell of chemical in there!
Oh yes.
Foof! Oh, hm.
It's not just an
ordinary drainpipe is it?
Now, I wonder if that pipe extends
into the room where that briefcase went.
Are you thinking of
climbing up the inside of it?
Yes, yes of course my
dear, there's no other way.
If you go in there you'll see it's all corroded
so there's plenty of hand and foot holds.
And that chemical smell
means that it's germ free.
Oh, but it's too far
for you grandfather!
Well If it is, then I shall have to give up,
and I'm not going to give up before I've tried.
And remember you must think of the other two,
They must be constantly reminding
themselves they're only one in five!
There's only the two of us to help them!
- Alright, but you let me go first.
- Yes-yes, yes go-on.../
Ian look at this!
Mm, yeah.
What do you suppose it is, corn, wheat?
Wheat.
Still haven't thought of a way
of getting out of this place...
Oh yes, you're right it is wheat.
Ooh, it's all covered in some
sticky stuff, like toffee.
Hey Barbara, look at this...
Give me your handkerchief will you?
Do you see what this is? A
book of litmus papers, hah!
How often have I held a piece of
litmus paper in my fingers..?
- Oh well, it's a handy seat.
- Yeah
You realise what this place is?
Ooh it's some sort of a laboratory.
Yes, I think it must explain
those dead insects and things.
They must be doing some experiments.
Course it makes it all
the more dangerous for us.
Why do you say that?
Well, whatever killed those
insects could easily kill us.
The Doctor said something
like that, I... I'd forgotten.
Well don't touch anything, eh?
But...but...Ian...
I mean, look at the way these seeds
are coated. They're obviously samples.
Yes, I think they must be
inventing a new insecticide
and they've sprayed these seeds with it.
Oh surely I... I mean, couldn't
it be just preserving oil?
I doubt it, anyway,
you keep away from it.
I-AN!
BAR-BARA!
There they are, can
you see them Barbara?
Doctor, Susan we're up here!
- Hello up there!
- What uncanny good luck!
Oh ha-ha Grandfather, we've found them!
Yes, I know my dear, I know!
Did they really climb up that sink pipe?
Yeah, they must have done. I
wonder if we can get down it?
Climb down the plug-chain, to us!
Yes alright we will!
Here, it's about thirty feet or
thereabouts, do you think you can make it?
Yes, I'll make it somehow, it'll
be worth it to see them two again.
Alright, let me go first.
You been over doing things.
Yes... Yes, I-I think I have.
I'll go and get you some
water it'll freshen you up, eh?
Thank you
What are you doing?
- I want your handkerchief. I was going...
- No!
What's the matter?
You can't have it, you mustn't touch it!
Barbara!
No-one must touch...
There, it's the same aroma! Insecticide.
You didn't eat or drink anything?
Well no, certainly not!
Shes got insecticide on
her hands, she touched it.
Well she never told me,
I never saw her do this! I...
She did borrow my handkerchief.
Where were you then?
By that pile of seeds.
Yes you sh, you see, she's got it on her hands!
And she rubbed it off on your handkerchief!
Oh... Why didn't she tell us?!
You can help her, can't you Doctor?
Grandfather we can
do something can't we?
What happened? D-did I..?
You fainted, that's all.
The insecticide... Is
that why I feel like this?
Yes. You got some of it on your hands
and you didn't us tell anything about it!
It was very wrong of you, wasn't it?
Am I... Am I?
No-no-no, no this little
attack...experience is only temporary.
Oh take it easy Barbara,
Look out.
Come on Barbara take it easy
Well what can we do for her?
Well it's urgent that we get her back to normal size,
but, ah, at the moment her protective cells are too small
to cope with the molecules of poison in her bloodstream.
But if we can, that dosage of insecticide
will be seventy times less dangerous,
- practically nothing at all!
- Are you sure?
Yes I'm quite sure. But we
must get her back to the ship.
What are we waiting for?
How are you feeling?
Ooh..a bit ropey. Ooh, could
do with a glass of water.
We're going to take
you back to the ship.
Alright, just give me a minute.
Come on Barbara, we've
got a long way to go.
You can get us back to normal size?
Oho, yes! of course I can
dear boy, yes, course I can...
I hope.
We've got to repeat exactly wha..the
things that happened to us when we landed.
Is there anything I can do?
Yes, that seed over there by the chair. Take it over to the table
so that we can all see it. And wrap that round it when you do it.
Doctor!
Er!
Doctor I...
Shh-sh. I think it's working.
Splendid, I think it's working, my boy!
Doctor, look at that seed!
Yes yes, we've done it! Yes,
ha-ha ha-ha, we've done it, yes!
Doctor, it's incredible, that
seed, it's completely vanished!
No no my dear boy, no. Hah-ha!
Look, can you see, it
hasn't vanished at all!/
Grandfather,  is that the
seed you brought in with you?
The same seed!
Then we are back to normal!
Completely my dear!
Now before I check up and see where we are,
I suggest you all go and have a good scrub mm?
Oh please!
Go-on, off you go!
Oh dear-dear-dear-dear-dear,
now isn't that irritating mm?!
I had to repair that wretched thing
and now look at it, I can't see a thing!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)