- What have you done?!
- They're no longer human, just fictional.
If you consent to take my place here,
they can be released.
- You really would do that?
- No, my dear sir. You would.
Once you take up your post, it can be
your first official task as the new controller.
- I see. How very ingenious.
- I take it, then, that you agree?
No! My answer is still no!
How very unfortunate.
I'm sorry to have to use violent methods,
but you must submit.
You have no alternative.
I have yet to see a robot...that can climb!
You cannot escape...
but we will play your game a little longer.
(CHUCKLES)
(CREAKING)
- Doctor!
- Zoe! Jamie!
- Am I glad to see you.
- The Master said you'd been...
- Where do we go?
- To the Tardis.
We can't. It fell apart.
- It's all over now.
- The Tardis broke up.
- Yes, you said that.
- I'm tired. I think I'll sit down.
- Is something wrong, Zoe?
- Where do we go?
- To the Tardis.
- We can't. It broke up.
But you keep saying the same things.
The Tardis broke up.
Then it's true. They're not real.
They've been turned into fiction.
What's this?
The master tape! I wonder...
Perhaps if I were to create a few immortal
words of fiction of my own...
Yes. It's worth trying.
Oh... What I need is the strength of Karkus!
- I am at your command.
- Oh, thank you, my dear sir.
Perhaps you could release this for me.
- Zis is what you want?
- No. I want to get down here somehow.
- Ah. Wait.
-Thank you.
Jamie...
Jamie, Zoe...you are being controlled.
Jamie, listen! Listen!
- Oh, it's no use.
- A rope.
- Oh, thank you.
- Ouch! Careful.
Oh. Yes, of course.
You are the Princess Rapunzel.
- Are you a prince?
- No, I'm afraid not.
Would you mind if I used your hair?
No, of course not. Everybody else uses it.
Thank you. Where can we attach the...?
Oh, yes, of course.
(MACHINES WHIRR)
(KEYS CLICK)
Yes, yes. Go on.
''The enemy had been
finally defeated by the Doctor...''
No, no. I can't say that. If I say that...
I nearly fell for it. Another second
and I should have turned myself into fiction.
Halt!
Now we shall play games no longer.
- I'm very obliged to you both.
- Always happy to be of assistance.
Jamie and Zoe. I left them here.
Where are they? Jamie! Zoe!
(CHUCKLING)
''Jamie and Zoe realised at last
''that the Doctor was, in fact,
the most monstrous and cunning villain.
''There was no punishment too severe
for the crimes that he had committed.''
(ROBOTS BEEPING)
Splendid. Splendid.
Come closer, my children.
You sent for us, Master?
Now you know what the Doctor
is really like, don't you?
He's a monstrous and cunning villain.
No punishment is too severe for his crimes.
Word perfect. That is why I sent
for you both at this moment of crisis.
- We need your help.
- What must we do?
Well...
♪ A-tishoo! A-tishoo!
♪ We all fall down! ♪
- You are in an unhappy situation.
- Is there anything we can do to help?
- I wish there was.
- Look!
- What's that?
- I never saw it before.
The Tardis!
Safe and sound! By all that's wonderful!
- Are you ready?
- The time has come to leave.
- How did you find the Tardis?
- We'll explain later.
Just as I was thinking that all was over.
- Oh, no.
- It's not over yet, Doctor.
Not yet.
Jamie! Zoe!
(LAUGHTER)
What's happening?
The children obeyed perfectly.
Their mission is completed.
Now perhaps we can get down to business.
As you refused to take over at the controls,
we were forced to incorporate you
into the computer.
- To what purpose?
- To bring planet Earth under our control.
- And its people?
- We have no wish to destroy them.
Merely adjust their minds
to suit our purpose.
Sausages! Man would become
like a string of sausages.
Man will simply vanish from the Earth
and reappear here.
Leaving Earth undamaged and uninhabited
for you to take over.
- Precisely.
- If I co-operate.
You have no alternative.
You are part of the master brain.
So the computer
feeds off my thoughts, does it?
Correct.
Then it will create what I think.
Oh, no. No... You're now under control
of the master brain.
Are you so sure? You couldn't control my
mind before and you can't control it now!
- Submit!
- No!
You've given me equal power.
It's a battle of wits between you and me.
Oh, no. No! No! Stop! Stop!
Jamie, Zoe... Can you hear me?
Think for yourselves. Don't be afraid.
You can open the book.
Go on, you can do it.
Oh. Oh, dear.
This is against everything we ever worked for.
- (HUMMING)
- Warning, warning.
Emergency action.
Emergency. Emergency.
Calling white robots.
Guards will enter the control centre.
The master brain must be protected.
Push, Zoe. Push hard.
We will get out.
- Soldiers! To the roof! Immediately!
- Harder. Harder!
Splendid!
Soldiers, forward!
Seize them! Destroy them!
- (CREAKING)
- Get back, Zoe.
(CREAKING)
Can't you help us?
We obey our creator. That is all
that can be expected of any character.
And now, Doctor, obey me!
No!
Suddenly the Karkus came to their rescue.
I am at your command.
(DOCTOR) He raised his anti-molecular
disintegrator gun and destroyed them.
No! But the Karkus realised his mistake
and turned back to face his real enemies,
Jamie and Zoe!
With Jamie and Zoe firmly in his sights,
the Karkus pressed the trigger of his gun.
But... But all the power had been used up
on the soldiers and it was useless.
- You'll have to do better than that.
- A swashbuckling figure appeared.
Poet and swordsman,
the famous Cyrano de Bergerac.
Remorselessly, Cyrano advanced on those
who had dared to poke fun at his nose.
But wait.
He found himself face to face
with the fearless musketeer
and fearless swordsman D'Artagnan!
Come on, Zoe.
- Princess, can we use your hair?
- Of course.
- Why are we going there?
- We've got to find the Doctor.
Stop them! Substitute cutlass for rapier.
Cancel Cyrano.
Blackbeard the Pirate!
(DOCTOR) Cancel D'Artagnan.
Substitute Sir Lancelot in full armour!
This way.
(MASTER IN FLAT VOICE)
The Doctor is expendable.
He will be destroyed.
(NORMAL VOICE) Oh, no, no.
He's the only person. There's nobody else.
I can't go on for ever.
Please give me another chance.
(FLAT VOICE) The master brain
must be protected against overloading.
Robot force will deal with him.
Change robot weapon to destructor beam.
(LOW BUZZ)
It is a pity that we have to destroy
such an intelligent mind as yours, Doctor,
but you leave us no alternative.
Disintegrate!
(HUMMING)
Stop them!
They will overload the master brain!
Destroy them. Destroy.
Oh!
Zoe, duck!
(GUNFIRE AND EXPLOSIONS)
- Shouldn't we go?
- Yes. Jamie, give me a hand.
- What do you want to bring him for?
- Don't argue, Jamie.
(EXPLOSIONS)
I don't see why we had to bring him.
He caused the trouble.
- Are you all right, sir?
- I'm not sure where I am.
Is this the office of the ''Ensign'' magazine?
You were kidnapped.
They've been using your mind.
- What happens to us now?
- That depends on the white robots.
The order was to destroy.
Let's hope they're destroying one another.
What about the Karkus and Gulliver
and our friends?
- You can't blow up a fictional character.
- But what about us?
We'll have to hope the destruction
of the computer returns us all to reality.
- Oh. Do you mean I'm going home?
- I hope so.
But it could just as well send us into oblivion.
- Vanish for ever?
- We shall soon know.
- (EXPLOSIONS)
- Hang on. Here it comes.