(RUMBLING ROAR)
Doctor, come on, will you? Look!
Oh, my word! Into the Tardis. Quickly.
Oh, no! If I can't pull this down,
we'll get stuck. That stupid, idiotic...
Doctor, the lava's up to the Tardis!
If I can unstick this stupid, idiotic...
There we are.
- Have you done it?
- It's stopped the fluid links from vaporising.
- We shan't suffocate.
- If we don't hurry, we'll be fried by the lava.
- Isn't there any way we can get away?
- Well, there IS an emergency unit, but...
- I can't possibly use that.
- But this IS an emergency!
But it moves the Tardis out of the
time-space dimension, out of reality!
Fine. Reality's getting too hot, anyway!
I can't possibly use this.
We don't know what will happen.
Stop your jabbering and get on with it. Look!
(PULSATING WHINE)
Who are you?
(HUMMING INTENSIFIES)
Where are you?
What do you want with me?
No...
No, I must fight.
I must fight!
I will fight!
The Mind Robber
(Whopix fan edit)