''One glance from her eyes
would turn them to stone...
''but all was not yet lost.
''Suddenly, the Doctor found a sword
at his feet, picked it up
''and with one stroke slew the monster.''
- A sword!
- You're meant to use it like Perseus.
- Maybe it's another trap.
- Doctor, please!
No. How can I kill something
that doesn't exist?
- I've got to open my eyes. I've got to see!
- Wait!
Perseus. Of course. A mirror.
There. Look at her reflection in the mirror. Look!
- Can you see her?
- Yes.
This is how Perseus escaped.
He looked at her reflection in his polished shield.
There's no danger in the reflection.
''Cancel. Cancel. Cancel.
''The Doctor test - report failure.''
Failure?
(BEEPING)
(ROBOTIC VOICE) Attention.
There is a stranger inside the building.
Call out the search party.
- The young traveller. I had wondered.
- Have you been sent to find me?
His companions were in a state of anxiety
about his whereabouts.
Zoe and the Doctor! Where are they?
- Safe.
- You've spoken to them?
The gentleman desired to know
where I came from and whither I was bound.
- (BUZZING)
- What's that?
- I heard nothing.
- Probably that search party.
By law, every chamber must be searched.
- If they find me, I'm done for.
- You should be put to death.
- What about you?
- I shall come to no harm.
If you give me away this time, I'm finished.
I was ready with the hazard of my life
to defend his person.
(BUZZING AND BEEPING)
Where have they gone? The white robots.
Young sir, I do assure you,
there were no such persons here.
Aye. Robots or not,
I'm getting out of this place.
You desire your liberty?
Yes. I got in all right, but how do I get out?
After some consideration,
I was of the opinion that...
Go on, go on.
..this was altogether impossible.
Oh, yes. That's the citadel, all right.
The question is, how do we get up there?
- It's a long way to climb.
- Zoe, duck!
- The Karkus!
- You are my prisoners!
- It's the Karkus.
- What?
Come out
and put ze hands above ze head.
- You know. He's fictional too.
- Obey or I fire.
- What sort of a gun is that?
- (ZOE) An anti-molecular ray disintegrator.
Rubbish! Such a weapon
is scientifically impossible. It doesn't exist.
Hargh!
- That takes care of that.
- I shall tear you limb from limb!
Doctor, be careful.
The Karkus has superhuman strength.
You will be mincemeat!
Doctor, say it!
You know he's a fictional character.
But I've never heard of him!
- Hargh!
- What are you doing?
Please, I'm sure we can talk this over.
- Zoe!
- Lesson 17!
- Be careful.
- Oh, dear!
(ZOE) Lesson 32!
Don't do anything rash!
- Mercy!
- You'd better submit.
- The neck can't take much pressure.
- Help!
- Do you submit?
- I submit!
That's better.
I am your slave. Command me.
- Do you know the way to the citadel?
- I know it.
Take us up there, there's a good chap.
- (CLICKS)
- I obey.
Well, thank you, Mr...
What did you say his name was?
- K-A-R-K-U-S.
- Oh, yes. Mr Karkus. Thank you.
We won't be needing you any longer. Run along.
I obey.
- Come along.
- You can't just ring the bell.
Why not? It's the usual way.
(JANGLING BELL)
Are you sure this is a good idea?
State your name and attribution.
I am the Karkus.
- And your attribution?
- What's that?
Shh! Year 2000 comic strip creation.
The ''Hourly Telepress''.
Authenticated. You may enter.
(CREAKING)
You heard them giving orders to look for me.
Why do you suppose that happened?
These were orders
given by some person in authority.
- The Master?
- It is possible.
Now I'm getting somewhere.
Listen. If there aren't any robots,
who do you think was carrying out those orders?
Who was I hiding from?
- Why, sir, the Yahoos.
- Who's the Yahoos?
Inferior creatures.
I never beheld so disagreeable an animal.
I haven't seen any Yahoos,
you haven't seen any robots!
- Jamie!
- Stay where you are!
There's an electrical gadget that sets off an alarm.
The gong went off
and they sent robots after me.
- Robots? The ones we saw before?
- Big white ones.
- Doctor, did you hear that?
- Yes. I thought they'd turn up.
It's a simple photo-electric cell.
I'd better lift you over it.
- Careful, because...
- Oh, my jacket.
What happened when you left the tunnel?
I was chased by one of those tin soldiers.
I climbed up the cliff. How do we get out?
I'm not leaving yet.
The Doctor's going to see the Master.
This resolution may appear bold and dangerous.
- You see?
- Why do you say that?
I think you should not be here.
The Master makes rules for his kingdom.
It is unwise to disobey.
So we shouldn't see the Master?
My advice is to swear a peace
with the Master.
Find a place to lodge, stay
with the expectation that things would mend.
Yes. Well, I'll see.
I'll think it over very carefully.
- Your servant.
Your servant.
- You're not going to do as he says?
- No.
I said I'd think it over.
I've thought it over. We're staying.
But we won't know where the next attack
will come from. Medusa was bad enough.
Ah, Medusa.
I read about that on this machine.
- Wee words keep coming out of it.
- Let's have a look.
There. Look.
''Cancel. Doctor test - report failure.''
- I'm beginning to understand.
- I wish I was.
When somebody writes about an incident
after it's happened, that is history.
- Hm?
- Yes.
But when the writing comes first,
that's fiction.
If we'd have fallen into the Master's trap,
we would have become fiction.
- That's horrible. Let's get out of here.
- Zoe, don't go...
No!
(BEEPING)
Attention.
There are still strangers at large.
Renew the search.
The strangers must be found.
- What are we going to do?
- Gulliver walked through.
- Gulliver is not real.
- They're coming! Where can we hide?
- No need to hide.
- If they find us...
- Let them find us.
- Just wait?
Yes. We'll ask for an interview
with the Master.
- They may not give us time to ask...
- Look!
- (BUZZING AND BEEPING)
- Are you looking for us?
We... We demand an interview
with the Master!
(MAN) Ho, ho!
How very fortunate. Do come in, Doctor.
I've been expecting you.
Oh, don't be alarmed.
Won't you walk into my parlour?
Said the spider to the fly.
Come along.
(LOW HUMMING)
- It's hard to see anything.
- Where are you?
Here! Patiently waiting.
Oh! Oh, Doctor. This is a great pleasure.
And your two young companions.
Let me see... Oh, yes.
Zoe and Jamie. I have your dossiers here.
- You're well organised.
- Yes. We have to be.
Running this place
requires enormous attention to detail.
- It's a responsible position, but rewarding.
- Responsible, eh?
- To someone else?
- Not to someone. Another power.
Higher than any you could begin to imagine.
Oh, I must congratulate you
on the great skill
in which you tackled your examination.
What is the purpose of all these tests?
When I was first brought here myself,
I was as bewildered as you are.
- How long have you been here?
- I left England in the summer of 1926.
It was a very hot day, I remember.
I think I must have dozed off over my desk,
and when I awoke...
But that's a long story.
Did you ever hear of the adventures
of Captain Jack Harkaway?
No, I can't say that I... Wait a minute.
- A serial in a boys' magazine?
- The ''Ensign''.
And for 25 years,
I delivered 5,000 words every week.
You're a writer.
25 years, 5,000 words a week?
- That's over half a million words.
- Yes. It was probably a record.
That's why I was selected to work here.
- You're in charge of all this?
- In one sense, yes.
Yes. Or is all this in charge of you?
My brain is the source of the creative power
which keeps this whole operation going.
I see. That means
that you are virtually a prisoner.
No, no.
(HUMMING)
You... You must excuse me
for one moment.
- Let's get out of here.
- It gives me the creeps.
- No. I need to find out more.
- Zoe and me will find a way out.
I think we should all stick together.
- (HUMMING STOPS)
- Sorry to have kept you. Where were we?
You were about to answer my question.
Are you a prisoner here?
No. No, I wouldn't say that.
In fact, I rather like being here.
I have everything I could possibly want.
This vast library
with all the known works of fiction.
All the masterpieces written by Earthmen.
- I don't think he noticed.
- No. Let's try down there.
I see, yes. And only an Earthman-type creature
has the power to create fiction.
- The power to imagine.
- Exactly.
This is one field in which
the intelligence I serve cannot compete.
They need a man of boundless imagination
as a...um...
a powerhouse, a lifeline.
What is this intelligence you serve
and why was I brought here?
Well, as you see, I'm no longer young,
whereas you, Doctor, are ageless.
You exist outside
the barriers of time and space.
And you want me...
To take over this unique situation.
To take my place.
- I refuse!
- (HUMMING)
(FLAT VOICE) Refusal is impossible.
You are here to serve us.
There is no alternative.
- We've got to find a way out.
- There must be a door somewhere.
Jamie!
Oh!
No. Back this way!
Resistance is useless.
Submit your will for the sake
of the greater good. It has been decided.
I refuse.
I shall make that decision for myself.
- (HUMMING STOPS)
- There is only one decision open to you.
(HUMMING)
Mission accomplished.
Procedure as arranged.
- What does that mean?
- The latest chapter of the serial story.
I'll read you the last sentence.
''Zoe and Jamie attempted to escape,
''but in making through the library,
''they were ambushed by a party of guards
and overpowered.''
Oh, no! Jamie! Zoe!
Are you prepared to co-operate now?
Your life in return for theirs?
Is that a bargain?
(CHUCKLES)
Look.
(BUZZING)
(THEY GROAN)
- Oh, Jamie, my eyes!
- I can't see. Where are you?
Quick, back. Get away.
Zoe, here, quick.
No. It's a book! Back out again.
- Oh! Oh, push!
- Open up! It's closing!
- No!
- Aagh!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(HISSING)
Don't look in her eyes! Don't look!
The Medusa does not exist.
You must believe that.
- I can feel her fingertips like ice!
- No. That's marble.
Think of her as a marble statue. A legend.
But she's real!
I've got to look at her! I've got to!
It's safe now. You can look now.
The statue has become a statue again.
We all follow his adventures
in the ''Hourly Telepress''.
Oh, a strip cartoon of the year 2000?
You've been in the year 2000?
Yes, but I had no time to follow cartoons.
You'd better start following this one.
He's halfway there.