- Hello, Jo. - Doctor!
- How are you? All right? - Well...
Right, they'll be plenty of time
for the exchange of social pleasantries.
Put him inside.
Thank you, gentlemen.
You can leave them to me now.
Well, Doctor,
this is an interesting reversal.
I remember your once visiting me
when I was in prison.
You know, I'd very much
like to know why...
Why you've been locked up?
No, why I'm still alive.
Oh, come, your health is very precious
to me, for the moment.
You see, my employers
are most interested in you.
-The Ogrons?
-Miss Grant, please! I employ them.
Yes, well, whatever it is you're up to,
you needn't expect any help from me.
I don't need any help.
Your simple presence
will be quite enough.
Oh, by the way, I need hardly warn you
there is no point in trying to escape.
This is an interplanetary
police spaceship,
specially built for carrying prisoners,
as you can see.
Stolen, of course?
(SCOFFING) Of course.
Oh, and another thing...
There's a closed-circuit television
camera trained on you from up there,
so you will be
under continuous observation.
I think that's all.
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some rather complicated
astro-navigational calculations
to work out.
May I ask where we're going?
Certainly. To the home of our friends,
the Ogrons.
A barren and uninteresting planet
on the remote fringes of the galaxy.
Why are you taking us there?
That, Miss Grant,
you will discover when you arrive.
Right, now listen to me.
We haven't got much time
before he gets back to the flight deck.
Now, the first thing
we've got to do is to escape.
Now, they took my sonic screwdriver
from me in the prison
but they didn't get a hold of this.
-A steel file.
-Right, let's go.
No, not yet. Let's wait
till he gets back to the flight deck,
then he'll set the controls.
Now, this is an automatic spaceship.
Once we're underway,
the computers take over, right?
-Okay, so what's the plan?
-Now this is what we're gonna do.
So I told the High Council
of the Time Lords,
I said they had absolutely no right
to put me on trial in the first place.
Well, if I chose to go wandering around
the universe in my own time,
that was my business.
What about stealing the TARDIS?
I didn't steal it. I just borrowed it.
I fully intended to return it,
I assure you.
Anyway, she wasn't exactly
the latest model, poor old thing.
JO: (LAUGHING) You can say that again.
I tell you, I made a complete fool
of that prosecuting council, though.
I ridiculed his every argument.
Yes, and I told him
that I had the complete answer
to every one his charges against me.
JO: And then what happened?
DOCTOR: Then what happened, well,
they found me guilty,
changed my appearance
and exiled me to Earth.
JO: And that's where you met me!
That's right. That's where I met you.
And that alone
made the exile worthwhile, Miss Grant.
JO: Thank you!
Not that there's anything wrong
with Earth.
Well, it's quite a nice, little planet
in its own way, but...
After all, I am a Time Lord,Jo,
and I think I've deserve my freedom.
-JO: Right!
-In reminiscent mood, are you, Doctor?
Poor Miss Grant,
you have my deepest sympathy.
(CHUCKLING)
As I soon realised,
the trouble with Lethbridge-Stewart
is that he's got a military mind.
Well, he is a brigadier, after all.
I mean, what do you expect?
No, that's just the trouble though.
He's hidebound, you see.
He always does everything by the rules.
I keep telling him.
I said, "There are times, you know,
"when you've simply got to cut
right through the red tape."
And you've managed to do that, have you?
DOCTOR: Yes, I've managed to cut
right through it.
And I'm not going to let authority
stand between me and my freedom.
(SIGHING) Lethbridge-Stewart, I...
Hey! As far as he's concerned I've been
absent without leave all this time.
I'm always telling people ...
Is everything all right, Miss Grant?
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
And how about you, Doctor?
No ill effects, I hope?
Doctor, are you all right?
JO: Please don't wake him.
He's...he's fast asleep.
Is he? How very relaxed of him.
you come with me, Miss Grant.
Come on!
Right, in you go, Miss Grant.
Can you hear me, Doctor?
Are you on the flight deck?
If so, listen to this.
Miss Grant is in the air lock.
Unless you surrender yourself
to me immediately,
I shall open the outer door
and hurl her into space.
What an ingenious fellow
you are, Doctor!
Oh, no, you don't!
Now hold it, Doctor, hold it!
Get that blaster over to me
or I press this button,
and that will be the end of Miss Grant!
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Thank you, Doctor.
(THUDDING)
Well, we appear to have company.
Would these be your Ogron friends?
Why, no, no.
Well, I should try and be
a bit more hospitable, old chap.
Come on, put that gun away.
They've probably got us outnumbered.
Welcome on board my ship.
To what do I owe the honour?
Why have you violated
the Draconian frontier?
Uh, yes, I'm most apologetic about that,
but it was really beyond my control.
You see, my prisoners
were trying to escape and my...
-My ship was thrown off course.
-Prisoners?
Yes, I am the commissioner
of Earth's Interplanetary Police.
I'm taking these two people back
to planet Sirius 4 for...for trial.
Uh, here is my warrant of authority.
Now, don't believe this man, he's lying.
I'm not concerned in disputes
between Earthmen.
We shall take them to Draconia.
Put them in the cage.
But you can't do that!
I'm a commissioner
of Interplanetary Police!
This is my spaceship!
I tell you, you can't do that!
Well, personally I'm quite happy
to be going to Draconia, Jo.
Perhaps we can convince the Emperor
what our friend here
has been trying to do.
You really think he'd believe you?
Well, this won't be my first visit
to Draconia, you know?
Many years ago,
I spent quite some time there.
I was able to help them through a period
of very great difficulty.
So there's a good chance
that they'll believe you, huh?
Well, it was a long time ago.
Things may have changed.
But I do understand
the Draconian mentality, Jo.
It all depends how you approach them.
So, if they do believe the Doctor,
you've had it!
Perhaps, Miss Grant, perhaps.
But one never knows
when help may be at hand.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I think that this is going to be
rather a long journey,
so, uh, good night.
We'll wake you with a cup of tea
in the morning.
Thank you.