But all these charges are false, Your Highness.
We are not attacking Draconian ships. We never have!
Our soldiers have seen the Earthmen attack us.
Our cargos have been stolen.
We are Draconians, we do not lie.
The honour of your race is well known, Your Highness.
That is why I cannot understand your actions.
Actions?
You attack our ships, you steal their cargoes,
you ignore our protests and just meet them with these counter-charges.
Our charges are true but yours are false.
We do not attack your ships.
Well, I'm never going in that thing again.
Oh, come on, Jo, be reasonable.
Only you could manage to have a traffic accident in space.
- Well, we didn't hit it, did we? - Didn't we? Where's this then?
Well, by a rather brilliant last-minute course correction,
I've managed to materialise the TARDIS inside the spaceship.
But to avoid hitting it,
I've had to make a random jump back into normal space.
Terrific, but what do we do now?
Well, if I'm to get us back to Earth, I'd better find out where we are.
I'll just go and check the instruments.
HARDY: You won't believe this.
- Now what? - Maybe it's a wreck.
Try and make contact. They may need help.
This is Earth cargo ship C982 in close proximity to you.
Do you read me? Do you read me?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
- Try again. - Do you read me?
Are you in need of assistance?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
It's a weird-looking crate.
(HIGH PITCHED BLEEPING)
Draconians!
- Doctor? - Well, I think I know where we are.
I've got a pretty good idea about when.
- Come and take a look at this. - A look at what?
That.
Well, it's just a spaceship, Jo.
Now, I reckon we must be somewhere in the 26th century.
Well, interstellar travel's pretty routine by now.
A moment ago, it seemed to change shape.
- Hmm? - It was when I heard that noise.
Didn't you hear it?
Well, I did hear something but very faintly.
Come on, Jo. Let's go and find the crew.
I want to find the exact date for my calculations.
- HARDY: They're going to attack us! - STEWART: Get the blasters.
HARDY: You can't take on a battle cruiser!
Get the blasters!
Emergency, emergency, red alert.
This is Earth cargo ship C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser, galaxy class,
equipped with neutronic missiles.
Emergency, emergency!
Oh, how do you do? I'm sorry about this intrusion.
HARDY: Who are you?
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
DOCTOR: I said how do you do?
HARDY: Dragons!
- Drop that gun. - Gun?
I haven't got a gun. This is simply my hand.
(GASPING) No!
-DOCTOR: Jo, what's the matter with you? - He's a Drashig!
DOCTOR: Nonsense, it's simply a man with a gun.
Now pull yourself together.
(注: Jo 所看见的怪物名叫 Drashig , 这是在上一个故事 Carnival of Monsters 首次出现的一种猎食怪物)
This is Earth cargo ship C982.
Situation, red alert.
Draconian battle cruiser about to lock on now.
All anti-boarding procedures carried out.
Awaiting instructions. Out.
This is the commander of the Draconian battle cruiser.
We are locked onto your vessel
and are about to board.
If you offer any resistance,
you will be destroyed.
Open the hatch of your airlock.
I found these two Dragons in the hold.
But that's impossible. They... They're only just locking on.
Doctor, what's happening? What's going on?
I'm not sure, Jo. Something rather intriguing.
If you resist, we can destroy you with our neutronic weapons.
If you destroy our ship, you won't get the cargo.
Oh, so that's what it's all about.
Open the hatch to your airlock
or we shall enter your ship by force.
- We refuse. - They can blow us to pieces!
I've sent a message to Earth asking for help.
This is a transcript of a distress call from one of our ships.
"From Earth's cargo ship number C982 on coordinate 8972/6483.
"We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser,
"galaxy class, equipped with neutronic missiles."
The treaty between our two empires established a frontier in space.
We have never violated that frontier.
You have invaded our part of the galaxy many times.
In pursuit of your ships when they have raided ours!
We've been very patient, perhaps too patient.
General Williams!
I take it a rescue attempt has been mounted?
We've established an automatic procedure,
because of the frequency of these attacks.
Then I suggest you go and supervise the matter.
There's no need.
Please do as I say.
As you wish, Madam President.
Your general is insolent.
We know the hatred he has always felt for our people.
Long ago he caused war.
Now he wishes to do so again.
He's a soldier, Your Highness, and he's angry.
The people of Earth are angry.
So are the nobles of my father's court!
I must ask you to take my personal appeal to your father, the Emperor.
He must put a stop to these attacks.
If Draconia has some grievances against Earth,
then this is not the way to deal with them.
Many of our noblemen felt it was a mistake
to make a treaty with the Earthmen.
Perhaps they were right.
You attack our ships and when we protest
you trick us with lies and evasions.
I give you a final warning.
The path you are treading leads only to war.
And in that war, Draconia will destroy you!
(HISSING)
They'll be through that door any minute!
Doctor, what are you doing?
I'm reversing the polarity of my ultrasonic screwdriver's power source,
thereby converting it into an extremely powerful electromagnet.
Oh. What good will that do?
You wait and see, Jo.
Is it working?
(LOCK GRATING)
Yes, I think so.
- I'm going to get the prisoners. - What for?
We're using them as hostages, remember?
You'd better be quick about it. We haven't got much time.
- How is it going? - Nearly there.
(LOCK GRATING)
There you are, that's it.
Oh, how very embarrassing.  Good afternoon.
- Out. - That's just where we were going.
We're going to meet your friends.
- Come on! Get up there! - Come on, they're almost through.
HARDY: Get in front! If your friends start shooting,
they'll get you first.
- But they're not our friends! - You are part of their boarding party.
They haven't boarded yet. They're still breaking through that door.
- Now, try and be logical, man. - They're coming through!
- Ogrons! - DOCTOR: Back to the TARDIS, Jo. Back!
Doctor! Doctor!
JO: (SOFTLY) Doctor?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor!
- Jo? - JO: Doctor, I'm over here.
All right, Jo, what are you doing in there?
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness, you're all right.
I thought they'd killed you.
Come on, come and sit down.
Must have been some kind of neuronic stun gun.
I wonder why they didn't kill me? What exactly happened, Jo?
Well, they took the cargo, threw me in here and...
- Doctor? - Hmm?
- They also took the TARDIS. - Oh...
Oh, we're stranded. What are we going to do?
Well, try and get the TARDIS back, of course.
(JO SIGHS)
Why should the Ogrons attack this ship?
- To steal the cargo. - No. No, there's more to it than that.
That... That sound that you heard,
it's all too sophisticated for the Ogrons.
- Well, they're gone now. - Yeah, the question is, where?
Hey, Doctor, last time we met the Ogrons
they were working for the Daleks, right?
- Well, you don't suppose that that... - No, no, not necessarily.
No, the Ogrons are mercenaries.
Other life forms use them to do their dirty work.
Come on, Jo, let's go and find the crew.
(博士与 Jo 上一次碰到 Ogrons 是在09x01 The Day of the Daleks 这集,
Take a look at that one.
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jo. We're being rescued.
- What happened? - Well, don't worry, old chap.
You'll be all right now. I think...
Draconians! They're boarding!
- Stewart? Who are you? - Passengers.
I see. Having a fancy dress party? What happened?
- Dragons attacked us. - Did they get the cargo?
- I don't know. - Yes, they took everything.
Including some rather valuable property of mine.
- Well, tough luck. - Oh, thank you very much.
- Dragons... They attacked us. - Yes, we know.
You say you're passengers.
Isn't that a little unusual on a cargo ship?
Well, we're here, aren't we?
Where did you pick these two up?
I don't know. I can't seem to remember...
Pull yourself together! How did they get on board?
Stowaways... That's it, they were stowaways.
- They were sending messages. - That's right.