Oh, how much further?
There's no sign of the toy soldiers now.
- We've got to get out of this place.
- Look.
There's a house.
Creag an tuire!
- (FIRES)
- Jamie!
- Doctor!
- It's all right, Zoe.
Well, come on. If you want to play games,
let's get on with it.
(ECHOING LAUGHTER)
What's that?
I have to make up his face again.
- You did this before!
- Yes.
That's how Jamie's face got changed.
- You got it all wrong!
- What? No, no.
Well, I was rushed.
Now, then... There we are.
All right, I know!
There we are.
One... Now, then... Yes, that's his nose.
You can't mistake his nose, can you?
And...
(LAUGHS)
There you are, you see!
Jamie! Thank goodness you're back.
- I haven't been anywhere.
- You've got your face back.
- I have?
- Yes. Look.
You're right, I have! That's much better.
- Ah! The house.
- Yes. Come along. Let's go inside.
(CREAKING DOOR)
(ECHOING GLUGGING, DRIPPING SOUNDS)
Well, there must be somebody here.
This... These candles are alight. Ugh!
- Hello there!
- (VOICE ECHOES)
One, two, three, four tunnels leading off.
- We could easily get lost in there.
- Just a moment.
What's he found?
A ball of twine.
Hmm... Oh, yes...
This must have been an invitation.
Why?
It's the classical way of getting through a maze.
Tie that to the door, will you?
It's locked.
- Then we ARE meant to go on.
- Yes, I think we are.
But that means that wherever we go,
at any time, they know. They're expecting us.
Yes... Don't break the thread. Come along.
- Which way, do you think?
- To the right.
(DOCTOR) They look equally unattractive
to me.
It must be to the right.
I've been working it out.
- Doctor...
- Shh! How?
It soon fell into a clear pattern.
One left, two right, three left, four right
and so on. A simple arithmetical progression.
- Doctor...
- Shh!
What it is to have an arithmetical brain!
What do you want?
The thread's run out. Should we not go back?
No. You stay here
and Zoe and I will explore a little further.
There must be another way out of this maze.
I need to find it.
They don't want us to find a way out,
only a way in!
(GLUGGING, DRIPPING)
I was right. This isn't the way out.
We're in the middle of the maze.
- Doctor, I don't like it. Let's go.
- Just a moment.
I was rather expecting a welcoming
committee, but perhaps I was wrong.
I hope you were!
Someone WAS here,
not so long ago either. Look!
(BOTH) Oh!
There's some tracks of an animal too.
- Let's go...
- (FEROCIOUS ROAR)
- It couldn't be!
- What?
I know it's silly, but do you remember
the story of the Minotaur?
Half-man, half-bull, yes.
And he lived in the heart of a labyrinth.
And there were human sacrifices!
Exactly, but I don't think
we need be too alarmed...
(FEROCIOUS ROAR)
As long as we're quite certain
that the Minotaur is only a...
Doctor, look!
(ECHOING, SNARLING ROAR)
Zoe, It's a legend.
- But it's there!
- No!
The Minotaur is a mythical beast. Say it!
The Minotaur is a mythical beast.
It doesn't exist!
(ROARING STOPS)
It's gone!
Yes.
I'm afraid we made it
too difficult for it to stay.
Come on. Let's go and find Jamie.
So that's how you can see, is it?
With that wee lighthouse of yours.
(MASTER) No! Brainless idiot.
Get yourself free. Don't let the boy escape!
- I think this is the place.
- Yes.
There's no sign of him.
I'm sure he wouldn't have gone off without...
- What's that?
- His jacket.
- Well, he must be around here somewhere.
- Jamie!
Who's that?
- My dear sir!
- Your servant, sir.
- You keep turning up unexpectedly.
- Have you seen Jamie?
I walked alone
but saw no sign of any inhabitants.
- (ZOE) Are you positive?
- I would not impose any falsities upon you.
- I adhere strictly to truth.
- Of course.
This person who controls this place...
- The Master?
- The Master? Yes?
Have you seen him?
Upon occasion he has been pleased
to grant me an audience.
Where might I find him?
The Master's palace is a citadel,
a walled town at the top of a hill or cliff,
the highest in the kingdom.
Now I think I understand.
May I ask, sir, where you come from?
Would it not be Nottingham?
My father had a small estate in Nottingham.
I was the third of five sons.
He sent me to Emmanuel College
in Cambridge at 14,
where I applied myself
to learning navigation and mathematics...
(BOTH) Useful for those who intend to travel,
as I always believed
it would be my fortune to do.
Now I know who you are, sir.
- Your name is Lemuel Gulliver!
- Your servant, sir.
- Gulliver?
- Yes.
Oh, no!
I'd need to be a human fly to get up that lot.
I can't go back, though.
What I really need is a...
Who says wishes don't come true?
Ouch!
- I suppose you know that hurts?
- You mean this is your hair?
Of course. I don't object to people climbing it -
I'm quite used to it, actually -
- but you would keep tugging so.
- I'm sorry.
- Are you a prince?
- No. Why?
You're supposed to be.
I'm a princess, but I suppose you knew that.
My name's Rapunzel. You're not
a woodcutter's son, by any chance?
- No. I'm the son of a piper.
- How very disappointing.
You'd better go. Goodbye.
- Wait!
- Well?
I can't go back there. It's a sheer drop.
I'll have to climb in through the window.
- I don't know if that would be allowed.
- I won't stay long.
Just passing through, you might say.
- Och, please.
- It's a great pity you're not a prince.
You'd have made rather a good one.
Well, I suppose you'd better come inside.
For goodness' sake, be quiet.
Rapunzel!
Your Highness, where have you gone?
Don't be silly. I'm not going...
Hey, this doesn't look like
the inside of a princess's castle to me.
but it would not be proper to trouble you
with the particulars of my adventures.
I wouldn't dream of detaining you.
Having been condemned by nature
to an active life,
I must take my leave of you. Farewell.
Farewell.
Why does he talk
in such an extraordinary way?
He can only speak the words
that Dean Swift gave him to say.
That's ridiculous. There never was a Gulliver.
- He's a fictional character.
- Of course he is.
This world that we've tumbled into
is a world of fiction -
''The Doctor and Zoe,
''unable to find their companion
in the labyrinth,
''decided to return to the cave
in search of him,
''where a new terror awaited them.''
That wasn't there before, was it?
- A statue.
(HISSING)
(DOCTOR) Medusa!
''The Doctor and Zoe...
were face to face with Medusa.
''One glance from her eyes would...
''would turn them to stone.''
- Now we know what we have to do, Zoe.
- Yes.
(HISSING)
She's moving. She's going to look at us!
- We have to say Medusa does not exist.
- But she does!
Zoe, Medusa is a myth.
If you believe in her,
she can turn us both to stone.