Anyone would think we got rats up here.
Who's that?!
WHO IS THAT?!
Doctor, do something!
I'm trying to!
Everything back under control again.
Here, we're landing! Look!
Coming at a fair rate!
Oh, thank the lord for that. You know, Doctor, I'll never ask you to do that again.
There must be a reason for that.
Hey, wait a mo! This doesn't look like Mars to me.
How do you know? You never seen it.
No, Duchess, but I have seen pictures of the moon surface and that's what this looks like.
That's the moon?
Doctor, is it the moon?
Oh well, you weren't too far out, were you? Only two hundred million miles!
All right, let's move on - while we can.
- What!
- Now wait a minute! You don't expect to land us on the moon and let us fly off just like that, do you?
Yeah, at least let us have a look around!
That picture canna be the moon? The moon's way up in the sky.
Where do you think you're going?
You're not going to tell us there is no shore leave.
Oh please Doctor. The TARDIS isn't out of control or anything is it?
Oh no, no, no. Just a bumpy landing. That's all
Yeah?
Well, if you must go ashore... only half an hour.
- Right.
- Superb
You can't go ashore like that! You need space suits, there's no atmosphere out there. Come on, there's some in the chest.
Maybe we'll meet the old man in the moon.
You won't meet anybody mate if you don't get some gear on.
What? Oh aye.
Come on now, lets go over here.
Hey, look at this.
Its deserted.
Yeah, I don't think I like it.
Hey, what do we need this great clogs for?
Try a little jump.
All right.
Careful! One tear in that space suit and you'll suffocate.
Come on, it's easy.
Look out, here I come.
Where's he gone?
Over there.
What on Earth? Look!
Blimey! What is it?
Doctor, what is it?
I don't know.
Hey, I can see Jamie, there he is.
Hey, there's somebody coming out.
Come on, let's go.
And... Jules, you take over.
There must be some source to this infection.
Look, then get the lads in here and tell them what's happening. Get them on the blower would you, Nils.
Hello. Where did you lot spring from? Don't tell me the shuttle rocket arrived already?
No, it hasn't.
There was another one with them, sir. Bob taken him along to the Medical unit. He's all right. He's just knocked himself out or something.
Oh no, if we haven't got enough troubles already.
We don't want to cause you any trouble. Just let us collect our young friend and we'll be off.
Hey, not so fast.
Please let me go and see Jamie.
I will take you there Mademoiselle. If you come with me.
All right, young lady. You can carry on.
This way.
Well, you know what this place is?
Well, it looks like some sort of weather control centre.
Ah, yes. And that's the thing with which you control the weather. That's the culprit then.
Hey?
Hmmm. That's what gave us a bumpy landing.
- Hm-Hmm.
- I see
The gravitron controls the tides, the tides controls the weather.
And from this console we can plot it all on that map.
Simple, eh?
Yeah, very simple.
It's Jim. Quick Francois, take over.
International Space Control Earth calling Weather Control Moon - come in please.
Moonport - standing by.
It's never done that before, Doctor.
Hobson here.
What's happening up there? The hurricane you were guiding is now 45 degrees off course. It's threatening Hawaii.
One of my men were taken ill. We're operational again now.
The controller would like to know the cause of the illness.
Yes, so would we. We now have three men down with this mysterious virus in the past few hours - including the Doctor.
One moment please. Stand by for further instructions.
Just hang on for another couple of minutes lads. We better hear what the great Mr. Rinberg has to say.
We're being monitored again.
Monitored?
Someone, not too far away from the base, is listening to every word we say.
"Moonbase, Moonbase, come in Moonbase. "
Still standing by.
If you radio information about this virus, we can do our best to identify it and suggest treatment.
I demand to speak to Rinberg.
The controller is busy - I'm sorry. Over and out.
That whole conversion was monitored by someone or something.
Oh, never mind about that now. That Rinberg fellow won't talk to you. How can we trace down this mystery illness with the Doctor himself down with it.
We better get out of these things and see how Jamie is. Perhaps I can be of help in the sick bay now.
Anything you can do... Bob!
Yes, Mr Hobson?
Show them to the Medical unit will you?
Yes, of course. Now, if you will come this way, please?
Yes. Thank you.
Well, you all heard the position. We don't know what this inflection is and how it got into the base but I want you all to take extra precautions while this emergency is on. We may be short-handed for quite a while.
Is this how its goes, Doctor?
Yes, that's right. Then, this unit automatically controls the pulse, the temperature and the breathing.
A sort of electronic Doctor.
Yes.
And it even give you medicines too.
Yes. It will do very nearly everything.
How do you think he is, Doctor?
Oh, he's not too bad. He's a bit concussed and feverish but he'll be all right with rest.
The Piper! The McCrimmon Piper! Don't let him get me!
Piper?
Some legend of his clan. As far, as I can make out - this piper appears to a McCrimmon just before he dies.
Has this phantom piper appeared to Jamie yet?
You don't believe it, do you?
No, but he does. It's important to him.
He keeps asking us to keep the piper away from him.
Good. We can see if we can do just that.
Well, carry on Nurse.
Well, at least I try to help. There's a ward full of sick men and no doctor. Somebody got to do something.
I wonder who this is?
Don't get too near. Have a look on his chart.
That's a good idea.
It's Dr. Evans.
Oh, yes. The station doctor. He was the first one to get it.
He looks one of the worst.
There's something about this epidemic that I... I just don't understand. It's not like a real disease at all! It's almost like...
Not real! What more do you want?
I don't know. But there are certain signs and symptoms which don't add up.
Ben, I want you to go to the control room and keep an eye on things.
But how?
Give a hand, do anything but keep your eyes and ears open.
Right.
There's something very wrong here. Something very wrong indeed.
Still up, Nobby. Why not take a rest. Go and get some sleep.
Oh, How can I rest with that thing up the spout. You know the score as well as I do.
Five units off centre and we lift half London into space! Five more and the Atlantic water level goes up three feet!
Rinberg don't understand the pressure we're under.
Hey you! What do you thinking you are doing?! Skulking here?
Just wondering if I can help, sir.
Well, how can you help?
We can do with an extra pair of hands - he can help me.
Well, keep him away from me, that's all. All right, I'll go and lie down. Call me if anything happens.
Yes, of course.
Oh, by the way, there were two more of those momentary drops in air pressure while I was on. I have put them in the log.
Right.
What is that?
Shhhh, it's all right Polly. It's only me. We don't want to wake everybody up do we?
You look if you can do with some sleep yourself.
I'm all right.
What have you got there?
Oh, I been doing a little investigation.
A piece of silver paper. What is it?
I don't know.
What's happened?!
Oh, it's nothing. It probably just a changeover in the time cycle.
What do you mean?
Oh, you see - it's rather interesting really - you see on the moon, they have a fortnight of days and a fortnight of nights.
Well?
Well, it's oblivious isn't it? They have to make their own day and night artificially up there - or it would upset their own biological time clock.
Their what?
They won't know if they were coming or going. Get it?
Yes.
Clever girl. QED. That's why it's dark up here.
Oh, I see what you mean. Yes, of course. How stupid of me.
Of course along the control centre it's probably broad daylight.
Polly, you wouldn't be making fun of me would you?
No.
Dr. Evans.
The hand. No, don't touch me. No. The silver hand.
Doctor, is he...
Yes, I'm afraid he is.
What are we gone to do?
What does he means by the silver hand. I better report this to Mr. Hobson.
What's the matter?
Something just went out of that door!
Nils! John!
What was it?
Nothing. Nothing there.
Your nerves are getting the better of you. Where's Evan's body?
Over there.
All right, let's get it over with.
Is this somebody's idea of a particularly bad joke?
This is no joke, believe me!
Mr. Hobson, Mr. Hobson, you are wanted! Another man's collapsed at the controls and the Gravitron has been thrown off alignment again.
Come on!
And you better find that Doctor's body or out you all go - quarantine or no quarantine.
I don't understand what could have happened. I must have dozed off or something but one thing I am sure of - something went out of that door just as you came in.
That body can't just have vanished. Polly, I am going to leave you alone...
...just for a minute.
All right.
Water. Water.
I'll go and get you some.
Water!
It's you! The phantom piper!