Stand back, stand back from that door.
You're right! It is them!
Quick! Get out of it!
No!
Remain still.
You devils! You killed him! An unarmed man!
Get up.
You are known to us.
And you to me.
Who is in command?
I am.
You will be needed.
What have you done with my men?
They will return.
They're not dead?!
No. They are not dead. They are altered.
Altered? What have you done to them?
They are now controlled.
If you do anything to my...
You will do nothing.
You will now take us to the control centre.
I'll be damned...
Through here.
You will remain here. If you leave you will be converted like the others.
Survey party, come in, we are not receiving you, over.
Can we see the control antenna from here?
No, Roger. It's just around that first block just outside the main port.
So, we have to send somebody outside so get ready...
We have to...
Get back! Get back! These things are lethal!
None will move.
If you move you will be killed.
What are they?! How did they get in!?
Silence! We are Cybermen!
But you were all killed!
We are going to take over the Gravitron and use it to destroy the surface of the Earth by changing the weather.
But that will kill everybody on the Earth.
Yes.
You're supposed to be so advanced. Here you are, taking your revenge like children.
Revenge? What is that?
A feeling people have...
Feelings? Yes, we know of this weakness of yours. We are fortunate. We do not posses feelings.
Then why are you here?
To eliminate all dangers.
But you kill every single thing on the Earth!
Yes. All dangers will be eliminated.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
You seem to be better.
Aye, I feel myself again.
Lie back there!
But I'm better!
Oh, my head.
Well, take it easy, mate.
At least, you know it is not your McCrimmon piper.
It had me worried though, I admit that.
Yeah, those Cybermen have got us all worried mate. We see them in action before.
They must have some weakness.
Well, in my day, they used to sprinkle witches with holy water.
Fat lot of use that would be on them.
Sprinkle... Holy Water... Ben!
What are the Cybermen covered in?
As far as I know, their suit is a metal of some sort.
What about that thing on their chests? You know the part that replaced their heart and lungs.
Some kind of plastic I think.
I thought so. You see, it's simple. Nail vanish remover dissolves nail vanish. Nail vanish is a plastic so we do what Jamie says, we sprinkle them, see?!
No, clear as mud if you ask me.
Anyway, I am going to try an experiment.
Yes, Professor.
Dr. Evans! I thought he was dead. I thought that they were all dead!
Better if they were by the look of it.
Tell the operators in the power unit to come out.
Now.
All right, you can all see what is happening. Come on out, leave the machine and don't try anything.
They will now take over the Gravitron power unit.
Yes.
But you can't send them in their without protected helmets.
Why?
The machine produces very intense sonic fields. Without the helmets, those men will be insane in a few hours!
How many hours?
Twelve possibly.
Then there is no problem.
Why?
Our purpose will be achieved before that.
But what about the men?
They will be disposed of.
Now, keep your fingers crossed.
It's works!
But I still don't know what you are on about.
If we can sprinkle some of that on their chest units, it might help to soften them.
I get it! You mwan it will clobber their controls or something.
Yes, that's it.
Main power into the vortex generators now.
What is happening?
There is loss of control.
Now look, we only have one chance at this. When I open the door, drop down as low as you can, aim this things... at their chests and squirt like mad. Right?
Right.
Get ready.
Someone is there.
Quick, get their chest things!
Quick, get these things off their heads!
Come on! Quick, there isn't a moment to lose. We got to get the Gravitron down to safe level.
What about those poor men?
Shift them off to the medical unit, as quick as you can.
We are not receiving you. We are not receiving you.
They must have failed.
Yes. We must invade now. Prepare the weapons.
Yes.
Now listen everybody. I don't know how many more of these Cybermen there are, but our point of view we are under siege. I'll reckon they will be back in a bit...
Now communications. Charlie, keep trying to get through to Earth. Right?
Right, will do.
The rest of you, lower the armoured doors at all exits. Make up as much of that gubbins that you got, we may need it.
Mr Hobson, how far can the probe be lowered down?
About thirty degrees.
That's no good.
What do you mean?
Can any other part be lowered?
Well, the main coil lenses can be shifted about without too much trouble but too much trouble...
There's something outside there!
What is it?
It's a long way off.
I'll come.