It's time for a new adventure for Doctor Who.
The Doctor, together with his friends Ben, Polly and Jamie,
defeated the insane professor Zaroff to blow up the world.
Leaving Atlantis behind, the Doctor set course for Mars
But then the TARDIS goes wildly out of control.
Anyone would think we got rats up here.
Who's that?!
WHO IS THAT?!
The Moonbase
Whopix fan edit edition
(time axis: bamanzi)
(based on english subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
Doctor, do something!
I'm trying to!
Everything back under control again.
Here, we're landing! Look!
Coming at a fair rate!
Oh, thank the lord for that. You know, Doctor, I'll never ask you to do that again.
There must be a reason for that.
Hey, wait a mo! This doesn't look like Mars to me.
How do you know? You never seen it.
No, Duchess, but I have seen pictures of the moon surface and that's what this looks like.
That's the moon?
Doctor, is it the moon?
Oh well, you weren't too far out, were you? Only two hundred million miles!
All right, let's move on - while we can.
- What!
- Now wait a minute! You don't expect to land us on the moon and let us fly off just like that, do you?
Yeah, at least let us have a look around!
That picture canna be the moon? The moon's way up in the sky.
Where do you think you're going?
You're not going to tell us there is no shore leave.
Oh please Doctor. The TARDIS isn't out of control or anything is it?
Oh no, no, no. Just a bumpy landing. That's all
Yeah?
Well, if you must go ashore... only half an hour.
- Right.
- Superb
You can't go ashore like that! You need space suits, there's no atmosphere out there. Come on, there's some in the chest.
Maybe we'll meet the old man in the moon.
You won't meet anybody mate if you don't get some gear on.
What? Oh aye.
Come on now, lets go over here.
Hey, look at this.
Its deserted.
Yeah, I don't think I like it.
Hey, what do we need this great clogs for?
Try a little jump.
All right.
Careful! One tear in that space suit and you'll suffocate.
Come on, it's easy.
Look out, here I come.
Where's he gone?
Over there.
What on Earth? Look!
Blimey! What is it?
Doctor, what is it?
I don't know.
Hey, I can see Jamie, there he is.
Hey, there's somebody coming out.
Come on, let's go.
And... Jules, you take over.
There must be some source to this infection.
Look, then get the lads in here and tell them what's happening. Get them on the blower would you, Nils.
Hello. Where did you lot spring from? Don't tell me the shuttle rocket arrived already?
No, it hasn't.
There was another one with them, sir. Bob taken him along to the Medical unit. He's all right. He's just knocked himself out or something.
Oh no, if we haven't got enough troubles already.
We don't want to cause you any trouble. Just let us collect our young friend and we'll be off.
Hey, not so fast.
Please let me go and see Jamie.
I will take you there Mademoiselle. If you come with me.
All right, young lady. You can carry on.
This way.
Well, you know what this place is?
Well, it looks like some sort of weather control centre.
Ah, yes. And that's the thing with which you control the weather. That's the culprit then.
Hey?
Hmmm. That's what gave us a bumpy landing.
- Hm-Hmm.
- I see
The gravitron controls the tides, the tides controls the weather.
And from this console we can plot it all on that map.
Simple, eh?
Yeah, very simple.
It's Jim. Quick Francois, take over.
International Space Control Earth calling Weather Control Moon - come in please.
Moonport - standing by.
It's never done that before, Doctor.
Hobson here.
What's happening up there? The hurricane you were guiding is now 45 degrees off course. It's threatening Hawaii.
One of my men were taken ill. We're operational again now.
The controller would like to know the cause of the illness.
Yes, so would we. We now have three men down with this mysterious virus in the past few hours - including the Doctor.
One moment please. Stand by for further instructions.
Just hang on for another couple of minutes lads. We better hear what the great Mr. Rinberg has to say.
We're being monitored again.
Monitored?
Someone, not too far away from the base, is listening to every word we say.
"Moonbase, Moonbase, come in Moonbase. "
Still standing by.
If you radio information about this virus, we can do our best to identify it and suggest treatment.
I demand to speak to Rinberg.
The controller is busy - I'm sorry. Over and out.
That whole conversion was monitored by someone or something.
Oh, never mind about that now. That Rinberg fellow won't talk to you. How can we trace down this mystery illness with the Doctor himself down with it.
We better get out of these things and see how Jamie is. Perhaps I can be of help in the sick bay now.
Anything you can do... Bob!
Yes, Mr Hobson?
Show them to the Medical unit will you?
Yes, of course. Now, if you will come this way, please?
Yes. Thank you.
Well, you all heard the position. We don't know what this inflection is and how it got into the base but I want you all to take extra precautions while this emergency is on. We may be short-handed for quite a while.
Is this how its goes, Doctor?
Yes, that's right. Then, this unit automatically controls the pulse, the temperature and the breathing.
A sort of electronic Doctor.
Yes.
And it even give you medicines too.
Yes. It will do very nearly everything.
How do you think he is, Doctor?
Oh, he's not too bad. He's a bit concussed and feverish but he'll be all right with rest.
The Piper! The McCrimmon Piper! Don't let him get me!
Piper?
Some legend of his clan. As far, as I can make out - this piper appears to a McCrimmon just before he dies.
Has this phantom piper appeared to Jamie yet?
You don't believe it, do you?
No, but he does. It's important to him.
He keeps asking us to keep the piper away from him.
Good. We can see if we can do just that.
Well, carry on Nurse.
Well, at least I try to help. There's a ward full of sick men and no doctor. Somebody got to do something.
I wonder who this is?
Don't get too near. Have a look on his chart.
That's a good idea.
It's Dr. Evans.
Oh, yes. The station doctor. He was the first one to get it.
He looks one of the worst.
There's something about this epidemic that I... I just don't understand. It's not like a real disease at all! It's almost like...
Not real! What more do you want?
I don't know. But there are certain signs and symptoms which don't add up.
Ben, I want you to go to the control room and keep an eye on things.
But how?
Give a hand, do anything but keep your eyes and ears open.
Right.
There's something very wrong here. Something very wrong indeed.
Still up, Nobby. Why not take a rest. Go and get some sleep.
Oh, How can I rest with that thing up the spout. You know the score as well as I do.
Five units off centre and we lift half London into space! Five more and the Atlantic water level goes up three feet!
Rinberg don't understand the pressure we're under.
Hey you! What do you thinking you are doing?! Skulking here?
Just wondering if I can help, sir.
Well, how can you help?
We can do with an extra pair of hands - he can help me.
Well, keep him away from me, that's all. All right, I'll go and lie down. Call me if anything happens.
Yes, of course.
Oh, by the way, there were two more of those momentary drops in air pressure while I was on. I have put them in the log.
Right.
What is that?
Shhhh, it's all right Polly. It's only me. We don't want to wake everybody up do we?
You look if you can do with some sleep yourself.
I'm all right.
What have you got there?
Oh, I been doing a little investigation.
A piece of silver paper. What is it?
I don't know.
What's happened?!
Oh, it's nothing. It probably just a changeover in the time cycle.
What do you mean?
Oh, you see - it's rather interesting really - you see on the moon, they have a fortnight of days and a fortnight of nights.
Well?
Well, it's oblivious isn't it? They have to make their own day and night artificially up there - or it would upset their own biological time clock.
Their what?
They won't know if they were coming or going. Get it?
Yes.
Clever girl. QED. That's why it's dark up here.
Oh, I see what you mean. Yes, of course. How stupid of me.
Of course along the control centre it's probably broad daylight.
Polly, you wouldn't be making fun of me would you?
No.
Dr. Evans.
The hand. No, don't touch me. No. The silver hand.
Doctor, is he...
Yes, I'm afraid he is.
What are we gone to do?
What does he means by the silver hand. I better report this to Mr. Hobson.
What's the matter?
Something just went out of that door!
Nils! John!
What was it?
Nothing. Nothing there.
Your nerves are getting the better of you. Where's Evan's body?
Over there.
All right, let's get it over with.
Is this somebody's idea of a particularly bad joke?
This is no joke, believe me!
Mr. Hobson, Mr. Hobson, you are wanted! Another man's collapsed at the controls and the Gravitron has been thrown off alignment again.
Come on!
And you better find that Doctor's body or out you all go - quarantine or no quarantine.
I don't understand what could have happened. I must have dozed off or something but one thing I am sure of - something went out of that door just as you came in.
That body can't just have vanished. Polly, I am going to leave you alone...
...just for a minute.
All right.
Water. Water.
I'll go and get you some.
Water!
It's you! The phantom piper!
It's you.
The phantom piper!
No!
No! I'll not go with you!
Do you hear me, piper? No! Leave me!
Leave me. I'll not go with you, do you hear me?
Leave me! No, I'll not go with you!
I'll fight you every inch of the way.
I'll not go with you.
Leave me, piper.
No. Leave me. I'll not go.
Agh!
- Molly, what's happened?
- Oh, Doctor, it was horrible!
- A giant creature like a Cyberman!
- It's all right. Don't be frightened.
- Whatever it was, it's gone now.
- It's the... Doctor, the Cyberman was carrying a patient.
- Cyberman? What are you talking about?
- I'm sure it was.
- I'll not go with you.
- It's OK. It's safe now. Take it easy.
She's right.
There's another one gone.
Sam, Jules, you've got to find these men.
They can't just disappear in a place this size.
Search every square inch, come back until you find them. Now move.
Now, supposing you tell me your story?
What did you see?
I went out to get Jamie some water,
and when I came back,
I saw this giant man or creature or something,
just going out of the door,
carrying one of the patients... like a doll.
- I think it was a Cyberman.
- Forget that part. Then what?
Then nothing.
The door shut, and then you came in.
- What do you know about all this?
- Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
We'll see about that in a minute.
- This thing you saw. What was it like?
- It was enormous, and silver.
- It had holes in its head for eyes, like a robot.
- A robot?
But the Cybermen were all killed
when Mondas blew up.
Stop this Cyberman nonsense! There were Cybermen, every child knows that, but they were destroyed ages ago!
- So we all thought.
- That's enough.
Let's have a little calm thinking.
For the past two weeks,
a complete unknown disease has appeared in the base.
People drop in their tracks
and develop a black pattern on their skin.
Then some of the patients disappear, right?
They can't leave the base without wearing spacesuits,
and there are no spacesuits missing. So where are they?
- I must say, It does sound a little odd.
- More than a little.
I do know one thing - a new disease starts, people disappear, and then you turn up.
- And you think we did it!
- Oh, come on, we haven't done a thing!
Perhaps maybe, I don't know who you are,
what you are, or where you came from,
but you can get off the moon now!
- Well, that suits me fine, the sooner the better!
- No, Ben, we can't go yet.
- Why not? They don't want us here.
- Because there is something evil here. We must stay.
- Evil? Don't be daft!
- Evil is what I meant.
There are some corners of the universe
which have bred the most terrible things.
Things which act against everything
that we believe in. They must be fought.
This disease, for instance. It isn't really
a disease at all, but I can help you with it.
You'll see. I'll find the cause for you.
- Will you, indeed?
- Yes, certainly. I just need to examine a few things. That's all.
- It should be simple.
- Well, I'm not sure.
I'll give you just one Earth-day cycle
to find the cause.
- Earth what?
- 24 hours.
- But that's no time at all.
- It's all you're going to get.
Then you get off the moon,
with this bloke here.
- You can't move him! He's very ill.
- We accept.
Now tell me, you have pathological
equipment here, yes?
Yes. Evans was working on
an extensive research project. It's all in here.
It's quite a small unit. We're not equipped
to deal with a full-scale epidemic.
- Do you think you can manage?
- Yes.
Right. I'll leave you to it.
Don't forget - 24 hours.
- What are you going to do, Doctor?
- We'll start with this one.
- Are you really a medical doctor?
- Yes, I think I was once, Polly.
I think I took a degree once, in Glasgow.
1888, I think. Lister. Hold that for me, will you?
- Oh!
- All right. He's quite unconscious.
It's all right, Jamie. It's all right.
You're going to get better but you must lie still.
What is this place?
Is it the home of the piper?
No, we're on the moon.
You know, the moon up in the sky.
No, I can't be alive.
I've just seen the piper.
The piper! I knew!
Polly! What's happened?
Polly.
Are you all right?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
- Isn't there any clue at all?
- No. It's a complete blank.
All the tests are negative. As far as I can see,
this whole ridiculous place is sterile.
- We'll have to tell Mr Hobson, I suppose.
- I simply don't understand it.
Doctor, it couldn't possibly have
anything to do with Lister, could it?
- Lister?
- Well, I mean, you did say
that you took your degree in Glasgow in 1888.
That's an awfully long time from now, 2070, whatever it is.
Are you suggesting that I'm not confident to carry out these tests?
No, No, I'm just wondering if there was anything
that Joseph Lister didn't know in 1888
- that might help you now.
- Ssh! Somebody's coming!
It's Mr Hobson. Out for blood - ours. Look busy! Quick!
That's the third person
to disappear in the past few hours.
- It's completely illogical.
- Do you mind?
Would you mind standing away from the door
and allowing it to close? The slides. The dust!
It must be you people.
We've got some straight talking to do, you and I.
- Polly. Another boot.
- Do you hear me?
- This is extraordinary. Look here.
- Excuse me, please.
Excuse me. We ARE trying to help you.
- Help? Is that what you call it? You can all get off the moon now.
- No, wait a minute. You said...
- I don't care what I said!
- Ah!
- Have you found something?
- I think perhaps I have.
Yes, I may be onto something,
but I must have some room.
How can I work under these conditions?
Now, please, come along. Outside. I'm trying to work in here!
- Ben, see that they stay outside.
- Did you mean that?
- What?
- You've found something?
Oh, Polly, I only wish I had.
- Coffee? Sugar?
- Hello, Doctor. Thank you.
- It's very hot. Doctor, what about you?
- Thank you, Polly.
Doctor, as I was saying, you've had
your chance. You come up with absolutely  nothing.
Don't touch him!
Let me look.
Charlie and you, Ben,
give us a hand to get him into the medical unit.
Try not to touch his skin.
Don't drink that! It's the sugar!
That's why the disease doesn't affect everyone.
It's the sugar. Not everyone takes it.
Don't touch it.
- What are you doing?
- Just be patient.
Just as I thought.
A large neurotropic virus.
- Like the space plague?
- No.
It's a large infective agent
that only attacks the nerves.
That's why these patients got these lines appear on faces and hands.
It follows the course of the nerves under the skin.
That's _ it well. But how did it get in here?
It is the Cybermen. I believe
they have deliberately infected the base.
My men have searched every square of the base. There's no space to hide a cat, let alone a Cyberman.
Anyhow, how did they get in?
- One moment.
- What is it?
- You say you searched all the base?
- Yes. What of it?
- No chance of anyone hiding anywhere?
- None whatever.
Did your men search in here? Did they?
- There was'nt people in here, so...
- Did they search in here?
- No.
- There's nowhere in here they could hide.
Oh, no!
Back!
Back.
Stand back, stand back from that door.
You're right! It is them!
Quick! Get out of it!
No!
Remain still.
You devils! You killed him! An unarmed man!
Get up.
You are known to us.
And you to me.
Who is in command?
I am.
You will be needed.
What have you done with my men?
They will return.
They're not dead?!
No. They are not dead. They are altered.
Altered? What have you done to them?
They are now controlled.
If you do anything to my...
You will do nothing.
You will now take us to the control centre.
I'll be damned...
Through here.
You will remain here. If you leave you will be converted like the others.
Survey party, come in, we are not receiving you, over.
Can we see the control antenna from here?
No, Roger. It's just around that first block just outside the main port.
So, we have to send somebody outside so get ready...
We have to...
Get back! Get back! These things are lethal!
None will move.
If you move you will be killed.
What are they?! How did they get in!?
Silence! We are Cybermen!
But you were all killed!
We are going to take over the Gravitron and use it to destroy the surface of the Earth by changing the weather.
But that will kill everybody on the Earth.
Yes.
You're supposed to be so advanced. Here you are, taking your revenge like children.
Revenge? What is that?
A feeling people have...
Feelings? Yes, we know of this weakness of yours. We are fortunate. We do not posses feelings.
Then why are you here?
To eliminate all dangers.
But you kill every single thing on the Earth!
Yes. All dangers will be eliminated.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
You seem to be better.
Aye, I feel myself again.
Lie back there!
But I'm better!
Oh, my head.
Well, take it easy, mate.
At least, you know it is not your McCrimmon piper.
It had me worried though, I admit that.
Yeah, those Cybermen have got us all worried mate. We see them in action before.
They must have some weakness.
Well, in my day, they used to sprinkle witches with holy water.
Fat lot of use that would be on them.
Sprinkle... Holy Water... Ben!
What are the Cybermen covered in?
As far as I know, their suit is a metal of some sort.
What about that thing on their chests? You know the part that replaced their heart and lungs.
Some kind of plastic I think.
I thought so. You see, it's simple. Nail vanish remover dissolves nail vanish. Nail vanish is a plastic so we do what Jamie says, we sprinkle them, see?!
No, clear as mud if you ask me.
Anyway, I am going to try an experiment.
Yes, Professor.
Dr. Evans! I thought he was dead. I thought that they were all dead!
Better if they were by the look of it.
Tell the operators in the power unit to come out.
Now.
All right, you can all see what is happening. Come on out, leave the machine and don't try anything.
They will now take over the Gravitron power unit.
Yes.
But you can't send them in their without protected helmets.
Why?
The machine produces very intense sonic fields. Without the helmets, those men will be insane in a few hours!
How many hours?
Twelve possibly.
Then there is no problem.
Why?
Our purpose will be achieved before that.
But what about the men?
They will be disposed of.
Now, keep your fingers crossed.
It's works!
But I still don't know what you are on about.
If we can sprinkle some of that on their chest units, it might help to soften them.
I get it! You mwan it will clobber their controls or something.
Yes, that's it.
Main power into the vortex generators now.
What is happening?
There is loss of control.
Now look, we only have one chance at this. When I open the door, drop down as low as you can, aim this things... at their chests and squirt like mad. Right?
Right.
Get ready.
Someone is there.
Quick, get their chest things!
Quick, get these things off their heads!
Come on! Quick, there isn't a moment to lose. We got to get the Gravitron down to safe level.
What about those poor men?
Shift them off to the medical unit, as quick as you can.
We are not receiving you. We are not receiving you.
They must have failed.
Yes. We must invade now. Prepare the weapons.
Yes.
Now listen everybody. I don't know how many more of these Cybermen there are, but our point of view we are under siege. I'll reckon they will be back in a bit...
Now communications. Charlie, keep trying to get through to Earth. Right?
Right, will do.
The rest of you, lower the armoured doors at all exits. Make up as much of that gubbins that you got, we may need it.
Mr Hobson, how far can the probe be lowered down?
About thirty degrees.
That's no good.
What do you mean?
Can any other part be lowered?
Well, the main coil lenses can be shifted about without too much trouble but too much trouble...
There's something outside there!
What is it?
It's a long way off.
I'll come.
- They can't just march in here, can they?
- Not now we've discovered how they got in.
Yes. They tunnelled into the storeroom.
- Doctor, Mr. Hobson, come quickly!
- What is it?
MoonbaseI MoonbaseI
- They've got our wavelength. We hear you.
- You are surrounded.
All resistance is useless.
You must open the entry port.
Let me. You're wasting your time. We've
discovered your passageway and blocked it.
- You cannot enter now.
- Resistance is useless.
- Can they get in?
- I don't know, but I'm not stopping to find out.
- Get me Earth as quick as you can.
- Right.
Weather Control Moon calling Earth.
Come in.
Emergency! Emergency!
There is a spaceship
approaching from Earth.
It will arrive on the lunar surface
in 15 minutes.
Immediate offensive action must be taken.
They have blocked up our way into the base.
Other methods to gain entry will be tried.
The machine from Earth
must first be destroyed.
There are 14 minutes left.
Understood.
Transmit control signal.
You will listen to me
and follow my instructions.
Here we are. I've brought some coffee to keep us awake.
- Without sugar this time, I hope?
- Of course. Don't remind me.
- Take some to the Doctor. He's in the Dome.
- Right.
You will now change
field co-ordinates as instructed.
Doctor, they've spotted it
on the scanner - the relief ship.
- Ben, where?
- Over here.
- Let's see.
- Well?
- No doubt about it. I told you they would be on their way!
It's not far off.
Far off? It's coming in now off parking orbit. It will be down in six minutes.
- Don't think you ought to warn them?
- Yes, the Cybermen will be waiting for them.
Don't worry. They've got their own warning system and weapons.
They'll blast the Cybermen and their spaceship
to kingdom come four minutes from now.
Come on!
It seems to move so slowly.
- What are they doing?
- Looks like they've changed direction.
They've changed into an escape orbit.
Follow it.
- It's going too fast. I can't keep up with it.
- Keep trying.
- I can't hold it. It's accelerating too fast.
- Look out man. You're on the sun.
- That's where it's heading.
- The acceleration's gigantic!
- Get R/T contact with the ship.
- It's no good, sir...the
doppler effect...It's going too fast.
They've had it, I'm afraid.
- The sun...
- Yes.
Will somebody please tell us
what it all means?
The rocket has been deflected
towards the sun. Nothing can save them now.
- Save them? What do you mean?
- From plunging into the sun.
But the sun's millions of miles away.
Once they get into the sun's gravity belt,
they can't change course.
It may take a week but they'll end up there.
What on earth could have caused it?
The rocket was deflected off course,
but why, and how?
Deflected?
- Yes, of course. The Gravitron!
- Have the Cybermen got a gravity weapon, do you think?
- No, they haven't, but we have.
- You're not suggesting...?
The only one way that rocket could be deflected into the sun
was from this very room.
I see what you mean.
Of course - the Gravitron.
- Benson! He must...
- I said he'd been on duty too long.
If it IS Benson...
It's Evans!
- He was in the medical room.
- The Cybermen have control of them again.
- And the other men in there?
- They may not be affected yet.
- Get down to the medical room. Barricade the door with everything
you can find. Keep them in there at all costs!
- Right.
What is he doing in there?
Look at the field reactors. We must get back control soon.
He could flood half of Europe
if he keeps the Gravitron
aligned with spring tides.
That settles it. We'll have to rush him.
Get those weapons out.
Resistance is useless.
All further ships from Earth will be deflected.
Open the air lock to us.
If you do not, we shall destroy the base,
and you will be eliminated.
Can you hear me?
Everything you have said
in the past half-hour has been overheard.
You can hear this, too, then. We're not done
yet, and we'll fight you to the last man.
- You'll never get inside this base!
- We are in it already.
They've punctured the dome!
The oxygen masks.
Everyone take a mask over there!
I hope that we don't lose too much oxygen.
- Can we patch it, do you think?
- We can try.
Give me a hand off with this.
Doctor, I can't breathe.
Thank heavens! I can breathe again.
Oh, no!
- What can we patch it with?
- Nothing.
Wait...
Over there.
Slide it to me but don't let go of it.
We have to do it in one action. No second chance. Are you ready?
Now!
Stopped them for the moment.
- I wonder for how long.
- Let's have a look.
Polly! Are you all right?
Yes.
- Where's that air coming from?
- Reserve tanks of oxygen.
- Why couldn't we have had those before?
- And lose all our oxygen?
I see.
- It's so quiet!
- Yes, it is, isn't it?
The Gravitron's stopped!
Quick. Before he comes to. Ben! Jamie!
Joe!
We've barricaded the sick bay with half the chairs and tables in the base, but it won’t
hold them for ever.
Well done.
Here's another one for you.
- What do we do with him, Doctor?
- That's your problem.
Just make sure he doesn’t come
back here for a while.
I’ll be after a job as a copper when I get
back to 1966!
Mr Hobson, I've got an idea.
- Doctor, what do you make of this?
- Made by a laser beam, I think.
- Is there anything the Cybermen haven't got?
- They haven’t got a Gravitron. Or they wouldn't be after yours.
We'll have to stand guard here
with their cyberguns.
Not much use. They're getting
reinforcements. Looks like another spaceship.
Just there.
Another one!
We have brought
reinforcements with other weapons.
You have one chance.
You must open the entry port.
You cannot stop us now.
You will all be completely destroyed.
- What does he mean, other weapons?
- We'll soon find out. You stay here. I must report this to Mr. Hobson.
I shall count to ten.
If you still stupidly remain silent,
we shall fire.
One...
- Hurry! They've got another weapon. They're going to ...
- Yes, I know. There it is.
Everybody take cover.
Get down, all of you! Doctor!
- Is the Gravitron still switched on?
- Yes.
Then I shall certainly stay here.
.. nine, ten... FireI
Again. Fire.
- What happened?
- It just deflected over the dome.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- The Gravitron deflected it. The force field.
- Yes. And that gives me an idea.
What are they doing now?
They're packing it away.
What will they cook up next?
How far down can this be aimed? Can it be
brought to bear on the surface of the moon?
- I see!
- Well...
- Has it ever been tried?
- No, but we shall try.
- With Evans gone, the Gravitron is all yours.
- Je m'en occupe!
Any further down,
and the field may affect the base.
- What does that matter now?
- Ah, I suppose you're right.
- Get someone to stand by that window
and relay instructions direct to Benoit.
- Right!
- He's ready.
- Start moving the probe down.
- That's as far as it will go.
- What?
But it's way over their heads.
There's one chance.
We'll try bringing it down by hand.
- Is this still switched off?
- No, No.. Yes, of course.
- It won't go.
- All your weight. Once more.
- It's no use. It won't shift.
- Ah, stupid of me! Of course it won't!
- Why?
- The angular cut-out. It's obvious!
There's got to be a safety cut-out
on the angle of the probe.
Otherwise, it might affect the whole base.
That's done it. Stand back. Benoit can do it now.
Switch on!
Well, that's taken care of the Cybermen!
We've got to get this Gravitron
in operation as fast as we can!
- I'm so sorry we damaged it.
- What? Oh, yes...
Nils, rig up a temporary aerial.
Call up Space Control.
Tell Rinberg we'll be operational
in about two hours. It's the best we can do.
We've only two hours to get
the world's weather under control again.
Benoit, take charge of your side.
And, Doctor... What the...
It's just as well.
We've enough madmen here already!
I want to see
your first weather plot in two minutes!
Come on, boys.
Doctor, look.
Could that be them?
Possibly.
And I hope it's the last we see of them.
- Let's have a look at the Time Scanner.
- The what?
The Time Scanner. Instead of showing where
we are, it gives you a glimpse of the future.
The second sight? Very dangerous.
Nonsense! I haven't used it very much.
It's not very reliable, as you can see.
Doctor...
Look!
Next: The Macra Terror