Nothing can be done for this chap.
That's strange.
There's centuries between these two weapons.
What's that on his jacket?
Radiation detector and a gas mask.
The two things don't go together, do they?
It's like finding remains of a stone age man
with a transistor radio.
Playing rock music.
A 1 ,000 year war?
-Civilisation on the point of collapse.
-What?
Nothing. Just theorising, that's all.
-Come along.
-Where are we going?
Er...
forward.
Even the dead have a part to play.
Propped up to make
the trenches appear fully manned.
-Different sort of uniform from that other chap's.
-Yes. We may have crossed the lines.
-Same mixture of ancient and modern, though.
-Yes.
That's why I think this war
has being going on for a very long time.
They probably started out with the most modern
equipment but no longer have the resources.
-Have to make do.
-War of attrition, eh? Only backwards.
At this rate, they're going to finish up with
bows and arrows.
Well, it would explain the mixture of equipment.
Psst.
-Be careful, Sarah.
-It's all right.
-It's locked.
-It's pretty solid, isn't it?
Some kind of service tunnel, I suppose.
It might even lead into the dome.
Let's see where the trench leads.
(PROJECTILE WHISTLING)
-It's a gas shell.
-Gas!
-Poison gas.
-Respirators, quick.
Get back!
This one's alive. Get him inside.
There's another one here.
Get him inside. Quickly.
(part1 ends)
Sit down.
Thank you.
You're not with the military, I assume?
-I'm with the science division.
-Oh, good, good.
Then perhaps we can talk without interruption
from rifle butts.
That depends.
If you don't answer my questions,
I shall hand you back to the military.
They take a pride in loosening tongues.
Now, where did you get these things?
Oh, here and there.
If I didn't know better, I should have to assume
that these were made
by some intelligence on another planet.
If you didn't know better.
It is an established scientific fact
that in the seven galaxies
only Skaro is capable of supporting intelligent life.
It is also an established scientific fact
that there are more than seven galaxies.
-Indeed.
-Yes.
When you passed through our security scan
our instruments ran a complete check
on your blood and chemical make-up,
encephalographic patterns and so on.
Physiological compositions,
and so if you are from another planet...
-You were saying...
-There's nothing.
Nothing conforms to any known life on this planet.
Apart from external appearances.
You can't always judge from external appearances.
Who are you?
-Where are you from?
-It's a long story.
Then tell me.
Do you have any inkling of the theory
of space dimension correlated to relative time?
(ALARM RINGING)
(OVER INTERCOM) Davros wishes
all members of the Elite scientific corps
to assemble in the main laboratory immediately.
Our session will have to wait.
-Davros is coming.
-Your chief scientist?
He's our supreme commander.
When he calls a full meeting like this,
he obviously has something
of the greatest importance to tell us.
-Well, I shall be delighted to meet him.
-Stand up and keep quiet.
If I may have your attention.
For some time
I have been experimenting
with the Mark III project.
Details of modifications
will be distributed later, however...
I am anxious that you should see immediately
the remarkable results that I have achieved.
And to that end
I have arranged this demonstration.
-A Dalek.
-What?
A Dalek, very primitive but undeniably a Dalek.
You're mistaken. It's a Mark III travel machine.
-If you say so.
-DAVROS: Halt.
Turn left, move forward.
That's magnificent. He's perfected voice control.
Turn right.
Move forward and circle left.
You will agree, I think,
that voice control represents
an enormous step forward, however,
the best is yet to come. Nyder.
Our machine is now equipped
with a weapon for self-defence.
Now, I am going to turn the machine over
to total self-control.
It will be entirely independent
of all outside influences.
A living, thinking, self-supporting creature.
DAVROS: Brilliant.
Brilliant! It has detected the non-conformity.
DALEK: Aliens. I must exterminate.
-Exterminate.
-No.
You dare to interfere!
You have the audacity to interrupt
one of my experiments.
-But it would have destroyed him.
-So you think the saving of a worthless life
more important than the progress we have made?
My creature showed a natural desire,
an instinct to destroy and you interceded.
You will be punished for this!
Davros, I'm sorry.
But I believe these prisoners,
they could be extremely valuable.
By all means, when I finish my questions,
let the machine do what it likes with them but...
I do need to interrogate them further.
You will be punished for insubordination.
In the meantime, you may question the prisoners
until first light.
After that, they will be used to resume
the experiment.
This meeting is ended.
-Thank you, I am obliged to you.
-I was merely doing my duty.
I believe that you have knowledge
which could be of the greatest assistance to us.
But if you don't cooperate,
then it is certain that Davros will use you
as an experiment
with his machine in a few hours' time.
The prisoners are to be taken to the cells,
you can continue questioning them there.
Davros orders it.
-You all right?
-Looks like I might be.
What happened?
They took down reams of notes.
Every bit of scientific gobbledegook
I could think of.
Technical jargon that even I didn't understand.
-That'll keep their experts tied up for weeks.
-Yes.
And I learnt a great deal more from them
than they did from me.
-About this bunker?
-Yes.
-It is underground, isn't it?
-Yes, bomb-proof.
Impregnable from attack from the outside and
about three or four miles from the Kaled dome.
What are they doing down here?
Years ago, the Kaled government
decided to form an elite group.
The best scientific brains in every field.
-A sort of think tank.
-Yes.
But over the years the Elite has become
more and more powerful
and now they can demand whatever they like.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
-Open up.
-Perhaps this is the tea.
There's no need to wait, I am armed.
I'm sorry if they hurt you.
I lack the courage to interfere.
But you did save me from becoming
the very first victim of a Dalek. Thank you.
Yes, now you used that word earlier.
It had never been heard before.
And yet only an hour ago,
Davros announced that henceforth
his Mark III travel machine would be
referred to as a Dalek.
Now how could you have known that?
Well, I have an advantage in terms of time.
You see, we've come here at this time
because of future concern
about the development of the Dalek.
I think you're concerned, too, aren't you?
(WHISPERING) I think he's going to bite.
Yes, I am concerned and there are a few others
who think the same as I.
-But we're powerless.
-Then let us help you.
You see, we believe that
Davros has changed the direction of our research
into something which is...
immoral, evil.
You see, the Elite was formed
to produce weapons that would end this war.
We soon saw that this was futile
and changed the direction of our research into...
into the survival of our race.
But our chemical weapons had already
started to produce genetic mutations.
And the mutations were banished
out into the wastelands.
-Yes.
-The mutos.
Now Davros, he believed that there was
no way to reverse this trend
and so he started experiments
to establish our final mutational form.
He took living cells,
treated them with chemicals and produced
the ultimate creature.
Come with me.
Now this is what the Kaleds will become.
(GROWLING)
That is our future.
Go on, Ronson.
Well, knowing our ultimate form,
Davros had to devise a travel machine.
-The Dalek.
-Now he's trying to change that into a weapon.
And he's succeeding.
He's created a monster,
utterly devoid of conscience.
-And you want to stop him?
-Well, I must.
There are a few in the Kaled government
who still have the power to act.
If they knew the truth,
they would end Davros' power,
close down this bunker, finish the only...
Then go to them, Ronson, go to them.
But I'm not allowed in the city.
Security here is absolute.
Then help us to escape. Give us the names
of the men who have the power.
Could you get us out of here?
There is a way.
Through one of the secondary ducts
in the ventilation system
that leads to a cave at the edge of the wasteland.
-Well?
-The entrance is barred.
And there's something else.
Davros' early experiments were with animals.
Some of the things that he created were horrific.
And they're still alive.
And I have an uneasy feeling
you're going to tell me they're in that cave.
These are the people you should try to contact.
Righto.
Look, if anything at all should happen...
-Don't worry, we won't let it fall into wrong hands.
-Quick.
(part2 ends)
I've just had word
from one of our supporters in the dome.
Councillor Mogran has called a secret meeting.
The only councillors invited are known opponents
of the work we are doing here in the bunker.
I want a full report
on everything that was discussed.
I don't care how you get the information, get it.
I think we need not be too concerned.
Many times in the last 50 years, factions
of the government have tried to interfere
with my research here, they have failed.
They will fail again.
There's something else. The two prisoners in
Ronson's charge, they've been seen at the dome.
-They are at the meeting.
-Impossible!
-There is no escape from here.
-I've checked their cells. They are missing.
Find out how they escaped
and report to me immediately.
-What action shall I take concerning Ronson?
-For the moment, none.
I will deal with him in my own way.
-That was a very impressive speech, Doctor.
-Yes, it was meant to be.
Let's hope it's convinced them.
Yes, let's hope so, Harry.
Sometimes words aren't enough.
Well, they seem to have reached a decision.
I'm afraid, Doctor, the councillors could not agree
to halt all experimentation at the bunker.
-The councillors are fools.
-Let me finish, please.
It has been agreed that an independent tribunal
will investigate all work
that is being done at the bunker.
But that could take months.
Davros already has several
prototype Daleks ready for action.
It has also been agreed that,
pending the investigation,
Davros' experiments will be suspended.
It is less than I'd hoped for.
And I promise you, Doctor,
if your allegations are borne out,
-all work at the bunker will be closed down.
-Thank you.
And now I must go with my committee
and inform Davros of our decision.
I think it's high time
we looked for Sarah, don't you?
-The one you left behind in the wastelands?
-Yes, you have some news of her?
I can't be certain, you understand?
But our agents inside the Thal dome
report a newly arrived girl prisoner
who led an attempted break-out.
Gave the Thals quite a bit of trouble.
-That'll be her.
-In the Thal dome, you say?
The Thals are using prisoners
to load their last great rocket.
-Rocket?
-They think they'll win the war with it.
What they don't know is that
no matter how powerful their rocket,
it cannot penetrate our protective dome.
Only a matter of months ago,
Davros perfected a new substance
which has the strength
of 30-foot thick reinforced concrete.
Yes, well, never mind about that.
Could you help us to find Sarah?
One of my agents could lead you
into the service shaft underneath the Thal city.
-But after that, you're strictly on your own.
-Fair enough.
Right, I'll give you a map
showing how to reach the rocket silo area.
Thank you.
An investigation? But of course, Mogran.
I welcome any inquiry into our work here.
I think the idea is an excellent one.
There's one thing more.
Until the inquiry, all work is to be suspended.
If that is your wish, then naturally I will obey.
It will take some time
to close down certain pieces of equipment.
Shall we say 24 hours?
-Twelve.
-It will be difficult but it will be done.
The members of the tribunal
will arrive in that time.
We cannot allow this investigation!
They cannot fail to see the dangers
to themselves in the Dalek project.
Calm yourself, Nyder.
-There will be no investigation.
-But you can't stop it now.
I can and will!
The Council has signed the death warrant
of the whole of the Kaled people.
Only we, the Elite, we and the Daleks will go on.
The whole of the Kaled people?
You would go that far?
Did you ever doubt it?
No.
There is much to do.
I want the genetically conditioned creatures
installed in the machines immediately.
-20 of them.
-20?
-They are our troops in this battle for survival.
-But they are still very erratic, unstable.
They will not be allowed self-control.
I will prepare a computer program
that will limit their actions.
After that, we are going on a journey.
-You think they believed you?
-It is unimportant.
They are hungry for victory.
They will use the formula and fire their rocket
no matter what they believe my motives to be.
And when they do, Nyder, when they do...
I've given orders that a barrage
of shells containing the formula
should begin as soon as possible.
The rocket launch can begin immediately.
And now I'll arrange
your safe escort out of the city.
Doctor, somehow we've got to warn Mogran
and the other Kaled leaders.
Yes, and we haven't found Sarah yet. Come on.
Excuse me, can you help me? I'm a spy.
Their suits, Harry.
-Harry! Doc...
-You all right, Sarah?
Oh! I am now. Listen, we've got to get out of here.
-The Thals are going to launch this rocket...
-I know. Listen.
I want you and Harry to go back
to the Kaled dome. Harry knows the way.
Tell them all we know. There's a chance
if they launch an all-out offensive,
-I might be able to stop the rocket.
-What are you going to do?
-Try to sabotage it, or at least delay it. Off you go.
-Right.
-Good luck.
-Sevrin, you come with us.
(part3 ends)
I sent Harry and Sarah in there.
Switch it off.
We will avenge the annihilation of our people
with a retaliation so massive,
so merciless that it will live in history.
Let the vengeance begin
with the death of the arch traitor,
the Thal spy Ronson!
No! Davros!
Exterminate!
-Exterminate!
-No!
No!
Today the Kaled race is ended,
consumed in a fire of war,
but from its ashes will rise a new race,
the supreme creature,
the ultimate conqueror of the universe,
the Dalek!
-Did you have friends in the Kaled city?
-Yes.
Two people very dear to me.
I sent them into that holocaust.
What will you do now?
Start again.
Try and find a way
to complete what I set out to do
and stop the development of the Daleks.
-Daleks?
-Yes.
Machine creatures
that Davros is developing, monsters.
Davros? No, you're wrong.
It was he who told us
how to destroy the Kaled dome.
-His only interest is in achieving peace.
-Let me tell you something.
The Kaled government was on the point
of stopping Davros' experiments.
And rather than let that happen,
he helped you to destroy his own race.
You'll never convince my people of that.
Davros is a hero.
Yes, for how long I wonder.
I must go.
Under the general amnesty,
you're free to leave whenever you want.
Thank you.
-Well?
-The Daleks are in position.
They will act on your command.
I see no reason to delay any longer.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Exterminate!
(YELLING)
-What are they?
-Keep back.
Get out of sight.
We've got to get out of the Thal dome.
-Are those the Daleks?
-Out into the wastelands. Do you know a way?
Good. Yes, they are the Daleks.
Come on, lead the way.
DALEKS: (IN THE DISTANCE) Exterminate!
Exterminate!
Oh, there was no need to go that far.
When our leaders saw they were beaten,
they should've surrendered.
Perhaps they did.
But Daleks accept no terms,
they're programmed to wipe the Thals
from the face of this planet.
But there must be some who'll escape.
Some survivors.
A few perhaps.
But they need to be grouped together into
some kind of fighting force to strike the bunker.
-What?
-Destroy Davros and you destroy the Daleks.
-What chance do we have against them?
-It's your only chance.
Will you do it?
Yes.
Good girl. I'm going to try
and get back into the bunker.
-Alone?
-Good luck.
Exterminate!
SARAH: All right?
HARRY: Yes.
Doctor?
-Harry!
-Hello.
-Sarah! I can hardly believe it.
-What's the matter with you?
I thought you were in the Kaled dome
when it was hit.
-We didn't get there.
-No.
Halfway across the wastelands
we were attacked by a band of mutos.
And that's when the rocket was launched.
-And then when the Kaled dome exploded...
-The mutos just ran for their lives.
Of course, I knew you'd try and get back
into the bunker through the cave.
You were absolutely right, Harry.
It's vital we go back into the bunker.
-Why?
-Because they took the time ring.
The bracelet that the Time Lord gave me
is our lifeline.
Without it we can never escape from this planet.
Sevrin, would you do something for us,
something important?
Over in the Kaled trenches,
there's a Thal, a girl named Bettan.
She's trying to form a resistance group.
Join her with as many of your own people
as you can get.
Their idea is to knock out the bunker.
Do you think they'll get away with it?
It'll keep the Elite's troops occupied
while I try to find a weakness of the Daleks.
Good luck, Doctor.
Sevrin, thank you.
(GROWLING)
Who's that?
Just one of Davros' experiments.
We better stick close together.
HARRY: You're not scared, are you?
SARAH: Of course not.
I am.
Listen, I've been down tunnels before
and I've just had a rather nasty thought.
-Really?
-Yes.
Suppose something's waiting for us in there.
That is nasty.
Better not tell Harry, he's gone first.
Welcome back.
You were right, Sarah,
about there being something nasty waiting for us.
I have read the initial reports
of your interrogation.
The suggestion that you have travelled
through space and time
was utterly dismissed by the computer analysis.
I imagine it had never been programmed
for such a concept.
Precisely.
I, however, I am perhaps more flexible.
Though the power of such travel
is beyond my scientific comprehension,
it is not beyond my imagination.
Why did you come here?
-To stop the development of the Daleks.
-Why?
Because having lived
in what you would call the future,
I have seen the carnage
and destruction they have caused.
Then my Daleks do go on. They do survive.
Yes. As weapons of hate and machines of war.
-Fascinating.
-But there's still time to change all that.
Why not make them a force for good
throughout the universe?
-I could do it.
-Then do it.
Be remembered for that.
You have seen my Daleks in battle?
Many times. I've fought against them.
And do they win? Do they always win?
Not always. They have been defeated.
But never utterly defeated.
The Dalek menace always remains.
If, as you say, they become
the supreme creatures of war,
how can they lose? How can they fail?
Misfortune, lack of information,
sometimes overwhelming opposition.
Yes, but tell me, how do the Daleks fail?
No, Davros,
that is a question
that the future must keep secret.
What mistakes do they make?
-You will tell me!
-No.
-No, I will not!
Nyder.
You will tell me because you have a weakness
that I have totally eliminated
from the minds of the Daleks
so they will always be superior.
A weakness that will make you
give me the knowledge to change the future.
You are afflicted with a conscience.
Nyder.
Let me tell you what is going to happen.
You will answer my questions.
You will answer them carefully and precisely.
The instruments to which you are wired
are particularly sensitive.
They will detect instantly any attempt to lie.
-And if I do lie?
-If you lie, your friends will suffer.
I can create in their bodies
all the torments and agonies ever known.
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Don't tell him, Doctor.
Now, you will tell me the reason
for every Dalek defeat.
With that knowledge, I will program them.
With that knowledge, they will know their errors
and how to avoid them.
With that knowledge, there will be no defeats!
We will begin!
Davros...
if I tell you what you want to know,
I betray millions of people in the future.
-I can't do that.
-But you can!
You will tell me!
(part4 ends)
Doctor, please, don't tell... Doctor!
All right, all right!
Just leave them alone.
Dalek invasion of the Earth in the year 2000
was foiled because of an attempt by the Daleks
to mine the core of the planet.
-The magnetic properties of the Earth...
-Mars...
the Daleks were defeated
by a virus that attacked the insulation
on the cables in their electrical systems.
...in the space year 1 7,000,
was halted by the intervention
of a fleet of war rockets
from the planet Hyperon.
The rockets were made of a metal
that was completely resistant to Dalek firepower.
The Dalek Task Force was completely destroyed.
It seems an opportune moment
to end this session. Nyder.
Release the prisoners.
Take them to the detention area.
Interrogation will continue later.
And I must thank you, Doctor.
What you have told me will be invaluable.
All the information, this foreknowledge,
will be programmed into the Dalek memory banks.
Take them away.
Doctor, stay a moment.
Sit down.
Let us talk together now,
not as prisoner and captor,
but as men of science.
There is so much I wish to know.
-Nyder, take charge of the tape.
-Immediately, Davros.
It will be your responsibility
and remember, it is priceless.
Its value beyond computation.
-Thank you.
-Who are you?
-My name's Gharman.
-Gharman?
Until a few hours ago,
I was head of the Military Elite Scientific Corps.
And now you're a prisoner like us?
What happened?
Wait.
I was trying to organise
a movement against Davros.
He found out.
Now, what's happening out there?
Has there been any attempt
to take away control from Davros?
Not that we know of.
Halt! State your business.
I wish to question the prisoners.
Nobody is allowed
to communicate with the prisoners
unless they have a pass signed by Davros.
Stay where you are!
I...seem to have mislaid it.
I'll come back later.
Now future errors will be eradicated.
Defeats will become victories.
You have changed
the future of the universe, Doctor.
I have betrayed the future.
Davros, for the last time,
consider what you're doing.
Stop the development of the Daleks.
Impossible. It is beyond my control.
The workshops are already fully automated
to produce the Dalek machines.
It's not the machines.
It's the minds of the creatures inside them.
Minds that you created. They are totally evil.
Evil? No.
No, I will not accept that.
They are conditioned simply to survive.
They can survive only by becoming
the dominant species.
When all other life forms are suppressed,
when the Daleks are the supreme rulers
of the universe,
then you will have peace.
Wars will end.
They are the power not of evil, but of good!
Davros, if you had created
a virus in your laboratory,
something contagious and infectious
that killed on contact,
a virus that would destroy all other forms of life,
would you allow its use?
-It is an interesting conjecture.
-Would you do it?
The only living thing,
a microscopic organism,
reigning supreme.
-A fascinating idea.
-But would you do it?
Yes.
To hold in my hand
a capsule that contains such power,
to know that life and death
on such a scale was my choice.
To know that the tiny pressure on my thumb,
enough to break the glass, would end everything.
Yes.
I would do it.
That power would set me up above the gods.
And through the Daleks, I shall have that power!
-Release me.
-No, Davros.
-Don't touch that switch.
-Why not?
It controls my life support systems.
I could not survive 30 seconds without them.
Order the destruction of the incubator section.
Destroy the Daleks? Never.
(ALARM BEEPING)
I mean it, Davros.
Next time I press that switch, it stays pressed.
Now give the order!
Even if I do this, there will be no escape for you.
I'll take that chance. Now give the order.
Press the communicator switch.
This is Davros.
Elite unit 7 will go to the incubator room.
All survival maintenance systems
are to be closed down.
The Dalek creatures are to be destroyed.
Tell them the order cannot be countermanded.
This order cannot...
This is Davros. This is Davros.
My last order is cancelled. Repeat, cancelled.
No action is to be taken.
What do you want done with this?
For the moment, he must be kept alive.
He has knowledge that is vital to our future.
And I will drain
every last detail of it from his mind.
And then,
he will learn the true meaning of pain.
I will take him to the detention room.
The dissidents. What progress are they making?
Feeling against you is rising.
Many of the scientific corps
are openly speaking against you.
Even some of the military are joining them.
As I expected.
-They will take action soon?
-Almost certainly.
They outnumber those of us who are loyal.
Davros, why don't you let me take
a squad of Elite men I can trust?
In an hour, I could wipe out their leaders.
You think like a soldier, Nyder.
Rebellion is an idea in the mind.
Suppress it and it hides away and festers.
No. My way is best.
As you wish.
On your feet!
Open up.
Not exactly as planned, Sarah.
Doctor.
-He's a bit groggy but he'll be all right.
-Come on, Kavell, we've a lot to do.
What about the guards?
Suppose they won't come over to our side?
They'll be disarmed and held in custody
until we've presented our ultimatum to Davros.
No, wait, wait. Davros knows what you're planning.
I heard him talking to Nyder.
If he knows,
why hasn't he taken action against us?
Perhaps because he knows it's futile.
-There are too many of us.
-No, no, it's not that.
I don't know what he's got prepared for you
but believe me, he's ready.
Even so, there'll still be too many for him.
Just be careful. Be careful.
I think we can take care of things.
Thanks for the warning.
-No point in telling you to rest, I suppose.
-No, there isn't.
We've got to recover that time ring.
Because without it, we'll never get off this planet.
But where is it?
It's on the desk in the main laboratory.
And there's that tape recording that Nyder took.
We've got to get it back at all costs.
It would make the Daleks invincible. Come on.
Davros, they're taking over. We must act quickly.
In another hour, they could be totally in control.
Do you hear me, Davros?
I have a dozen crack men hiding in section 9.
Let me order them into action.
-Davros?
-I hear you.
Then what are we going to do?
I want you to find their leaders
and hand over your weapons to them.
Surrender?
Order all members of the Elite guards
still at liberty to do the same.
Do you know what you're saying?
I know precisely what I am saying.
Now, I will command and you will obey!
You will do as I order!
You will inform the rebel leaders
that I have given these orders to avoid bloodshed.
Tell them I submit
and will listen to their demands.
-That is all.
-Then we are admitting that we're beaten.
That is what they will believe.
You mean that...
You and they will find out exactly what I mean
all in good time.
Now carry out my orders.
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
(WHISPERING) Useful.
Ah.
This is something rather more useful.
-They're explosives, aren't they?
-Yes.
Explosives and detonators.
It seems almost providential.
Why? What are you going to use them for?
The Time Lord gave me three options.
There's only one still open.
-Genocide.
-Genocide?
Yes. I'm going to kill everything
in the incubation room.
I'm going to destroy the Daleks forever.
Where is Davros?
-You said that Davros had agreed to meet us here.
-He'll be here.
You have something to say to me?
Davros, we wish to make our views plain to you
concerning our work here.
With what authority do you speak?
With whose backing?
We speak for virtually all the Elite scientific corps
and many of the military.
We represent the majority.
Very well. Continue.
Nobody disputes that in the past,
under your guidance, we've made
incredible progress in many fields of science.
You did not come here to flatter me.
You came to offer an ultimatum.
Confine yourself to the terms of that ultimatum.
Very well.
The initial concept of the Dalek
was to build a life support system
and a travel machine
for the creature that we know
our race will ultimately evolve into.
You disapprove of that?
No, but we believe that concept
has been perverted.
You have tampered
with the genetic structuring of the creature
to create a ruthless power for evil.
We cannot permit this to continue.
Then what do you suggest?
All work on Dalek projects is to cease immediately.
The creatures that have been conditioned
and programmed are to be destroyed.
If these terms are met, we will then be proud
to work under your guidance
on the rebuilding of our society.
And if I refuse?
If you refuse, you will be placed under arrest.
The Daleks will be destroyed
and our work here will then continue
under a new, democratically elected leader.
Have you finished?
Well?
You might at least do me the courtesy
of giving me time to consider.
(SQUEAKING)
The Daleks are in there.
The flesh and blood part of them.
Indeed they are flesh and blood.
Some of them can move about.
Well, how do I see?
Press the button.
-Here we go.
-Harry.
You're not going in there, are you?
They're harmless enough, I think. Just unpleasant.
-You don't want me to come in, do you, Doctor?
-There's no need, Harry.
It just remains to put the charges
where they'll do the most damage.
It shouldn't take me more
than a couple of minutes.
I have made my decision.
I accept your ultimatum.
-On one condition.
-Go on.
That you allow me to speak to a full meeting
of the Elite, both scientific and military.
Anyone you elect may speak against me.
When this is done, a vote will be taken.
I will abide by the decision of the majority.
You already know the decision of the majority.
You will lose, Davros.
With such confidence,
you can hardly deny my request.
It was you who introduced the word ''democracy''.
Do we accept his proposition?
Very well, it's agreed.
The meeting will take place in one hour from now.
Arrange it.
You may go.
Ours is the victory, Nyder. We have won.
(part5 ends)
What's taking him so long?
It's a very difficult operation, Sarah.
Still, he should have finished by now.
Doctor?
Doctor, are you all right?
Sarah!
Get it off!
Got it.
Doctor!
What are you waiting for?
Just touch these two strands together
and the Daleks are finished.
Have I that right?
To destroy the Daleks? You can't doubt it.
Well, I do.
You see, some things could be better
with the Daleks.
Many future worlds will become allies
just because of their fear of the Daleks.
But it isn't like that.
But the final responsibility is mine,
and mine alone.
Listen, if someone who knew the future
pointed out a child to you
and told you that that child
would grow up totally evil,
to be a ruthless dictator
who would destroy millions of lives,
could you then kill that child?
We're talking about the Daleks.
The most evil creatures ever invented.
You must destroy them. You must complete
your mission for the Time Lords.
Do I have the right?
Simply touch one wire against the other
and that's it.
The Daleks cease to exist.
Hundreds of millions of people,
thousands of generations
can live without fear, in peace,
and never even know the word ''Dalek''.
Then why wait?
If it was a disease or some sort of bacteria
you were destroying, you wouldn't hesitate.
But if I kill, wipe out a whole intelligent life form,
then I become like them.
I'd be no better than the Daleks.
SARAH: Think of all the suffering
there'll be if you don't do it.
GHARMAN: Doctor!
Doctor, I've been looking everywhere for you.
Davros has agreed to our terms.
-He submitted?
-He did. But he asked only one thing.
That he might be allowed to address
a meeting of all the Elite, scientific and military.
He's going to put a case?
Yes, but a vote will be taken.
It's a foregone conclusion.
There will be a complete landslide
against any further development of the Daleks.
We've won.
I'm grateful to you, Gharman.
More grateful than I can tell you.
Everybody is here, Davros.
The issues are simple and clear cut.
I have given my life's work
to the survival of our race.
The travel machine I designed,
the Dalek, will give the creature
into which we will mutate
its only possibility of continued existence.
But you have deviated from that intention.
You have introduced genetic changes
that will alter the mutation
into a creature without morals and without ethics.
One race must survive all others.
And to do this, it must dominate.
Ruthlessly.
Now I intend that
when all the bickering and battling is over,
the supreme victor shall be our race,
the Daleks.
At this very moment,
the production lines stand ready,
totally automated, fully programmed.
The Daleks are no longer dependent on us.
The machinery is ready.
They are a power in their own right.
If any one of you would destroy
everything that we have ever achieved,
then here...
is a destruct button.
Press it and you will destroy this bunker
and everything in it.
Only this room will remain.
Press it and you will wipe out our entire race,
destroy the Daleks forever.
Which of you will do it?
You are men without courage.
You have lost your right to survive.
You have heard Davros' case.
What he has not made clear
is that there is another way.
There is no other way.
Production of the Dalek can continue.
We can destroy
the genetically conditioned creatures
and allow the mutation to follow its own course.
Our race will survive if it deserves to survive.
But let it have all the strengths
and weaknesses that we have,
compassion and hate.
Let it do good things and evil.
But we cannot let it become
an unfeeling, heartless machine.
That is our choice. Now...
we must decide.
-We've got to find that time ring.
-SARAH: Doctor.
Good girl, Sarah.
Now all we need is the tape recorder.
So keep an eye on Nyder.
You've heard our cases.
I will give you two minutes to decide.
Then you must answer not only to me,
but to the future.
You've had ample time to decide.
Those who would remain loyal to me
and to the future of our race,
move forward and stand at my side.
Now, I wonder where Nyder is going
at such a crucial moment.
-I think we ought to find out.
-So do I.
Let's go.
Right, bring out the explosives.
Now, lay the charges
on each of these main carriers.
One charge for each beam should be enough.
Now, where are you going in such a hurry?
Davros is lost. I am getting away while I can.
Oh.
Somehow that just doesn't ring true.
Why didn't you just join the other side?
Now, that's a good question.
Do you have a good answer?
Evidently not.
Well, then let's try something else.
That tape recorder you took. Where is it?
It's put away in a safe in Davros' office.
-Shall we go and see?
-Down here.
Are you quite sure
this is the only way into the bunker?
Well, the only other way was from the Kaled dome
and your war rocket caved that in.
It can never be cleared.
If we do the same here, we'll entomb
the Daleks and those who created them.
But Sarah and the Doctor are inside.
You'll give them a chance to get clear, won't you?
I must blow the roof
as soon as the charges are laid. I can't delay.
If the Daleks find out
what we are doing and attack,
I don't have enough men or arms
to stand them off.
-How long?
-Thirty minutes, perhaps less.
-Then I must get inside and try and warn them.
-That's up to you.
But you must understand,
if you're not back, I must go on.
-You'll die in there with them.
-I understand.
I'll give you what time I can.
Right.
Thank you.
Now, let's destroy it.
-How about this?
-How very apt.
A Dalek gun.
There.
He's not important.
We've got the time ring, we've destroyed the tape
and Davros' power is broken.
What about the Daleks
that are already operational?
Oh, I think we can leave Gharman to destroy them.
-Why is it going on so long?
-Who knows?
It's out of character for Davros
to submit quite so easily.
This is your last chance. Move to join me now.
Or suffer the consequences.
Why don't you just accept the fact
that you have lost? It's over for you, Davros.
Do you believe that I would let a lifetime's work
be ended by the will of spineless fools like you?
You have won nothing.
I allowed this charade to be played out
for one reason only.
To find those men who were truly loyal to me
and to discover those who would betray me!
We...
I will go on!
You are insane, Davros.
Exterminate!
Stop them, Davros. You must stop them.
-That's the last one in position.
-Right. Prepare to detonate.
The automated Dalek production line
has been started.
I gave no such order. Who did?
DALEK: I gave the command.
You will perform no function
unless ordered by me.
You will obey only my commands.
The production line is to be halted immediately.
You heard my order. Obey!
Obey!
I created you! I am the master, not you!
I. I. I!
-Nyder.
-Yes, Davros.
Production will continue.
DALEK: Our programming does not permit us
to acknowledge that any creature
is superior to the Daleks.
You cannot exist without me.
All inferior creatures
are to be considered the enemy of the Daleks
and destroyed.
No, wait!
Exterminate!
For the last time, I am your creator!
You must, you will obey me!
We obey no one.
We are the superior beings.
Exterminate!
(DAVROS SCREAMING)
Main exit blocked by explosion
for a length of at least 1,000 yards.
We are entombed, but we live on.
This is only the beginning.
We will prepare. We will grow stronger.
When the time is right, we will emerge
and take our rightful place
as the supreme power
of the universe!
Failed? No, not really.
DOCTOR: You see, I know
that although the Daleks will create
havoc and destruction for millions of years,
I know also that out of their evil
must come something good.
(part 6 ends here)
(SARAH GRUNTS)
Thank heaven for that. We've made it.
-Haven't we?
-Of course we've made it.
Did you think we wouldn't?
Well, in these past few weeks, yes.
-Quite frequently.
-There is really nothing
that could go wrong with the time ring,
except the molecular short circuit.
-Doctor.
-Yes?
The Tardis isn't here.
Well, it probably hasn't arrived yet.
We're a little early.
Hasn't arrived yet?
No, you see, the Tardis is drifting back
through time, Harry.
We'll just have to wait
for it to turn up.
(CHUCKLES)
I say, Doctor,
did you want this ring thing?
-What, that?
-Yes.
-No.
-Oh, well, I'd rather like to have it.
-Well, you take good care of it, Harry.
-Of course I will. Thank you.
(GASPS)
You knew that was gonna happen,
didn't you?
-He's dead. Been dead some time.
-How long?
A week or two, I'd say.
There's very little sign
of putrefaction though.
Sterile atmosphere.
Yes, exactly, and no sign of injury.
Nothing to indicate the cause of death.
Well, he was just sitting against
the door as though he'd collapsed.
He wouldn't have been there
for two weeks unless...
Unless what?
Unless there was something
seriously wrong here.
Come on.
(BEEPING)
(end.)