VARGA: See, it is working. Zondal is coming to life. Zondal. Zondal. Zondal.
JAMIE: Wish me luck, Doctor.
DOCTOR: You take care of yourself, Jamie, and keep an eye on Arden. I don't think he quite realises how dangerous this creature is.
JAMIE: After what's happened here? He must be blind.
DOCTOR: Well, he's a scientist and a bit inclined to have his head in the air. You know what they're like.
JAMIE: Aye, I certainly do.
ARDEN: Are you all ready, lad?
JAMIE: Aye, let's away.
DOCTOR: Good luck.
ARDEN: Now we don't know how many of them there are, so we'll have to tread carefully.
CLENT: You will not expose yourself to any unnecessary violence, Arden?
ARDEN: Now listen, Clent, we both know that I'm responsible for what has happened. If I hadn't brought that creature back here in the first place, none of this would have occurred. I also caused the death of Davis. I can't forget that, either.
CLENT: Well, you just remember your mission, that's all. And no wild sorties after the girl. It's vital that you get your information back to us immediately.
JAMIE: Look, we'll not leave Victoria to the warriors, if that's what you mean. If there's half a chance of us two
CLENT: You will take your orders from Scientist Arden! Act according to your priorities, Arden.
ARDEN: Come along, boy.
CLENT: Arden?
ARDEN: Yes?
CLENT: Don't be to too hard on yourself. Scientists must question, you know. I mean, if I'd been in your shoes I think I'd have done the same. I'd have, I'd have brought it back. So, anyway, good luck.
DOCTOR: Good luck, Jamie!
JAMIE: And you, Doctor.
CLENT: Well, Doctor, let's see you go into action. I'll just get Miss Garrett to take you over the set-up here.
DOCTOR: Miss Garrett? Oh, no, no. There's no need to go into formalities.
CLENT: Miss Garrett? I like things done properly. Where is she?
DOCTOR: Now Clent, just remember I am not a member of your staff. I'm just a working guest, as you might say.
CLENT: Yes, of course. But this is a formal establishment, and our regulations
DOCTOR: Your regulations do not apply to me. I work in my own way, freely.
CLENT: I see. Like Penley. Regulations seemed to bother him, too. Probably caused his eventual breakdown, in fact.
DOCTOR: Breakdown? I thought you said he defected?
CLENT: Did I? Well, one thing lead to another, naturally. He was under a great deal of pressure. Just too much for him, that's all.
DOCTOR: Oh, I see.
STORR: A creature growing out of the ice! Bah!
PENLEY: I assure you that what I saw was very real. And terrifying.
STORR: You've been out on the mountain too long. It takes some people that way. Especially the brainy ones.
PENLEY: Hmmm. Very well, don't believe me, but I still intend to find out.
STORR: Ah well, you can leave me out of your fun and games. I've got enough troubles of my own.
PENLEY: You're fit enough now. To do the cooking, at least. Thanks to science.
STORR: Science! Och, it wasn't science, it was just good plain doctoring. And if you smirk again like that, I'll crack your head open with this.
PENLEY: Yes, you're definitely back to your normal witty self. What's the matter?
STORR: Someone's outside.
PENLEY: They must have tracked me here from the base. Hide yourself. We don't want you carted off to Africa yet. You!
GARRETT: I followed you. It's all right, I'm alone.
PENLEY: What do you want?
GARRETT: Elric, we're in desperate trouble at the base. You're the only one who can help us.
PENLEY: Clent doesn't need me. All he wants is a mirror. Preferably rose-tinted.
GARRETT: He does need you to make the ioniser work again.
PENLEY: Is that all?
GARRETT: No. He's faced with having to report the full situation to World Control.
PENLEY: Oh well, now we're coming to it, aren't we? The great Clent would have to admit failure. That's it, isn't it? Poor old Clent. He never could face the music. Here, what about this creature at the glacier?
GARRETT: That's only part of our trouble. The real problem is the ioniser. Will you come?
PENLEY: It's typical of him to send you, instead of armed guards.
GARRETT: He doesn't know I'm here. I'm asking you.
PENLEY: I won't come.
GARRETT: But you can't just step aside. A man like you, living like a scavenger? It's utterly wrong. Civilisation needs you.
PENLEY: Jane, I chose this existence. I chose it because I refuse to be sucked into that computerised ant-heap you call a civilisation. I'm a man, not a machine. I will not return.
GARRETT: Not even to save the world?
PENLEY: Save the world? Well, that has a fine Clentian ring to it. No thanks, no. It'll take more than me to do that. But don't you worry, you don't get rid of my sort all that easily. Machines corrode and rust, but mankind goes on. You'll find Clent one of these days in a museum, like that ancient stove, with an inscription round him. Robotised human mark two, now extinct. But you'll find others like me still alive.
GARRETT: Surely, Elric, that's all the more reason to come back. To change things.
PENLEY: Don't you understand, Jane? Clent's just a talker. He's a glib political animal. Even if I did change things, the Clent's of this world would still come out on top. Running things according to their own whims and indulgences. And the pity of it is, they believe they're right.
GARRETT: Then you leave me no alternative. You will come, and now!
PENLEY: You must be desperate. But tranquillising me isn't going to make it any easier. You'd never be able to carry me all that way.
STORR: Oh no you don't!
GARRETT: Who's this?
PENLEY: Just a friend. Now what are you going to do?
GARRETT: Return to base and wait for the inevitable disaster.
STORR: Oh no, you don't. I'm not having you set the dogs on me. I'd as soon put an end to her game. Give me that.
PENLEY: Storr, no. She won't put us away.
GARRETT: No, I won't.
STORR: I don't trust any of them.
GARRETT: Please trust me enough to come with me to safety. Apart from the danger of the glacier, these creatures.
PENLEY: Oh yes, your ice warriors. Well, we shall just have to take our chance. No, I won't return. And now you must go. But if Sir Genius does have trouble with the ioniser, look up my notes on the Omega factor.
GARRETT: Thank you for that at least.
STORR: This ice warrior. It's real then.
PENLEY: Oh yes. And I'm going up there again.
STORR: But why, man?
PENLEY: Because I must know. Now, put this knife to more sensible use.
VARGA: If you value life, obey, and do not anger us.
VICTORIA: I want to go back to my friends.
VARGA: Perhaps later. For the moment, you are useful to us. Zondal.
ZONDAL: Commander.
VARGA: You will locate our buried spaceship without delay.
ZONDAL: That will not be difficult.
VARGA: You will excavate sufficient space to form a cave.
ZONDAL: A cave.
VARGA: To act as a trap.
VICTORIA: A trap? Who for?
VARGA: Do not interfere. Your friends may attack us.
VICTORIA: But they don't want to attack you. They could help you.
VARGA: We do not need help.
VICTORIA: You'd still be frozen and dead if it wasn't for us.
VARGA: You are a child.
VICTORIA: Oh, why won't you listen?
VARGA: Commence.
VICTORIA: What are you going to do with me?
VARGA: Bait. Bait for the trap.
ZONDAL: Activate direction sensors. Steady. Sonic stalls ready. Set to wide impact. Take aim. Continuous fire!
DOCTOR: If I was to reverse the sequence to give a density ratio. Where did I? Yes, here we are. If I reverse the sequence to give a density ratio. Excuse me. Excuse me! Yes.
CLENT: Genius at work, I see. Good morning Doctor.
DOCTOR: Mmm? Yes.
CLENT: Well, this is all very impressive, Doctor, but don't you think it'd be simpler to use a computer?
DOCTOR: Four. What computer?
CLENT: The base computer.
DOCTOR: Six. Yes, they're useful for digital analysis, but I very rarely use them, except when I have to. There is one thing you could do for me which would be very important.
CLENT: Yes, yes, anything. What is it?
DOCTOR: Lend me a pencil. Oh, that would be even better.
CLENT: Doctor, would you mind explaining just what it is that you are
DOCTOR: Now, this is wrong, this is wrong. It's not right. There's something missing.
CLENT: Would these figures help?
DOCTOR: Supposing I? What are they?
CLENT: Data readings from the other bases.
DOCTOR: Oh, computer checked, I hope?
CLENT: Of course.
DOCTOR: Oh, thank heavens for that.
GARRETT: Doctor, I've found something here that I think you might
CLENT: Where have you been, Miss Garrett? Your instructions were to help the Doctor, were they not?
GARRETT: Yes, Leader Clent. I have been looking up Scientist Penley's notes. These. Could these help?
DOCTOR: What are they? Omega. Well, what does he mean? Omega. What does he? Wait a minute. Wait a minute! Yes! Yes, of course. The Omega Factor! There and here and there. Yes! Ha ha! Your friend Penley is very clever.
CLENT: Is that it?
DOCTOR: Yes, that's it!
CLENT: That's fantastic.
DOCTOR: Oh, when you've been at it as long as I have it's nothing.
GARRETT: Do you think it could possibly work?
CLENT: It's very possible.
DOCTOR: Possible? It's perfect! Well, it's nearly perfect.
CLENT: We shall see.
DOCTOR: Oh, it'll work, all right.
CLENT: The computer will confirm that, I'm sure.
DOCTOR: Computer?
GARRETT: Well, everything's checked.
DOCTOR: I resent that!
CLENT: Just normal practice, Doctor.
DOCTOR: It should be the other way round.
CLENT: We have to be quite sure. It'll only take a matter of seconds. Copy all this down, Miss Garrett, and then we can feed it through the computer and do a simulator run. I'll just go and set it up.
DOCTOR: I shall demand an apology, you know.
GARRETT: We may not have time for that.
DOCTOR: Well, I'm glad you had time to look up Penley's notes.
GARRETT: I thought it might be useful.
DOCTOR: Pity that he turned traitor.
GARRETT: Oh, Clent might call him that, but he's still the most brilliant scientist we have.
DOCTOR: Oh? Oh, it's nice to see he still has some friends in the base.
ARDEN: Glacier task unit. Leader Clent, please. Leader Clent, please.
CLENT: Clent here. Report.
ARDEN: We've arrived at the glacier site. There's something strange.
CLENT: What is?
ARDEN: The ice face. It's been excavated into a cave.
DOCTOR: How?
ARDEN: By some kind of tool, I think.
CLENT: Is there any sign of a spacecraft?
ARDEN: Yes.
DOCTOR: There is? Where?
ARDEN: Well, at the back of the cave, there's what looks like a metal door in the ice.
ARDEN: The place is apparently deserted.
DOCTOR: Well make sure you don't go too near.
CLENT: Excuse me. Take the necessary readings, and leave quickly, Arden.
ARDEN: I'll take care.
JAMIE: What readings?
ARDEN: Radiation, magnetic field and ion density. Won't take long.
JAMIE: I don't fancy this place.
ARDEN: There's never been such a discovery as this. All my life
VICTORIA: No! Oh Jamie, no! What have you done to him? You killed them!
VARGA: It was necessary.
VICTORIA: Oh, you're monsters!
VARGA: Remove her inside.
VICTORIA: Oh, leave me alone! Oh, please. Haven't you done enough? Please, leave me alone! I want to go back! Please!
ZONDAL: There may be more of them.
VARGA: If more of them come, we will destroy them. If no more of them come, we will know there are not enough of them to resist us.
ZONDAL: Let us destroy the girl now.
VARGA: They came after her. She is obviously of some value to them.
ZONDAL: Then they will try again.
VARGA: We shall be ready for them. But first, Zondal, you have a task to complete. The propulsion unit. It must be made to function. Time is vital. You must succeed.
ZONDAL: Yes, Commander.
VARGA: Come.
CLENT: We've just finished programming the computer. We shall have the result very quickly.
DOCTOR: Isn't it about time that Arden and Jamie reported again?
CLENT: Yes, that's true. But you know what Arden is, with his scientific curiosity.
DOCTOR: Yes, very human. I'm worried about them too.
CLENT: Yes, I'll do it if you don't mind. Leader Clent calling Scientist Arden. Arden? Do you receive me?
DOCTOR: He's not answering. Perhaps something has happened to them.
CLENT: It looks as if he's. Arden. For heaven's sake man, come in!
DOCTOR: Jamie, answer me! Jamie, what's happened? Jamie! Jamie!
DOCTOR: I will never forgive myself if anything's happened to Jamie.
CLENT: What about this project with Arden missing?
DOCTOR: Oh, your ioniser will work all right.
CLENT: I hope so. I'm not sure that I trust your judgement yet, Doctor.
DOCTOR: What do you mean, I'm only human? Well as a matter of fact
GARRETT: It works!
DOCTOR: I told you it would.
GARRETT: The equation works!
CLENT: Good. Good. Jolly good. Success is at last possible. Inform all ioniser bases, Miss Garrett. Thank you, Doctor. It's a triumph.
DOCTOR: Very likely. But somewhere, out on that ice face, are two young people for whom I have considerable affection. That is no triumph!
CLENT: I appreciate your feelings. I, too, have lost a colleague.
DOCTOR: They're not colleagues, they're friends.
CLENT: We cannot be sentimental in this situation, Doctor. Our mission continues. We must all play our part.
DOCTOR: I've played mine. It's finished.
CLENT: What a triumph. Europe saved. Science the victor over nature, and it happened in my sector. Well, it's not the first time.
GARRETT: Now we can go ahead. It only needs programming.
DOCTOR: Aren't you forgetting something?
CLENT: I'm sorry, but some lives are bound to be lost.
DOCTOR: No, no, I don't mean that. Arden. He's not yet completed his mission.
GARRETT: Oh yes, of course. The spaceship reactor. We daren't proceed until we've heard from Arden.
CLENT: Where is he? Where is he? Where is he?
STORR: What did you have to bring him back here for? Another mouth to feed.
PENLEY: You may hate scientists, Storr, but there's no need to hate all human beings.
STORR: I don't trust anyone from Clent's base.
JAMIE: Who are you? Where's Arden? What happened?! Oh, my head.
PENLEY: Now you must rest. You're suffering from severe shock. Now just lie still.
JAMIE: Well, where am I?
STORR: Ah, never you mind. Somewhere safe.
JAMIE: Well, what happened to me and Arden?
PENLEY: Arden's dead. You were both shot down by the warriors.
JAMIE: Arden dead?
PENLEY: They used some sort of ray gun.
JAMIE: So we failed.
STORR: You came to rescue the girl? Is that it?
JAMIE: You've seen Victoria? Is she still alive?
PENLEY: Yes, she is alive.
JAMIE: Then we can still save her! You will help me, please!
PENLEY: Now you're not yet well enough. We'll discuss it later.
JAMIE: No, it'll be to late then. They might. Oh, my head. No, you must help me save Victoria. It'll be too late.
VICTORIA: Doctor, if only I could make this thing work. This is Victoria calling the Doctor or Leader Clent. This is Victoria. Please answer me.
ZONDAL: The girl, Commander. She will betray us.
VARGA: She has courage. But she is also very stupid to think that we would not watch her every move.
ZONDAL: She must be stopped.
DOCTOR: It's Victoria! Victoria, where are you?
VICTORIA: I...
VICTORIA: I don't know.
VICTORIA: Some sort of cave.
DOCTOR: Are you all right?
VICTORIA: Yes, but, oh Doctor, something terrible's happened!
DOCTOR: What?
VICTORIA: They, they've shot Jamie and Arden!
DOCTOR: What? Well, is he dead? Is, is he wounded? Is he badly wounded?
VICTORIA: I don't know.
DOCTOR: What do you mean?
VICTORIA: Well, he's gone.
VICTORIA: Arden's body's still here and he's dead, but the warriors are from Mars, and. Oh, Doctor, it's horrible!
CLENT: Keep calm, girl. We want facts. Tell us about the spacecraft first.
VICTORIA: No, please, please listen to me. Arden's dead, and Jamie's disappeared.
VICTORIA: Don't you understand? They're ruthless killers and they'll stop at nothing. Now please, listen to me. There's no time to lose.
ZONDAL: Ready to fire.