Sincro: wyxchari
Let me have it. Give it to me at once.
那是什么东西？ 把它给我, 马上把它给我
Zondal. Zondal fire!
Zondal! Zondal 开枪！
Fire now! Zondal fire!
Zondal fire! Fire now!
马上开枪！Zondal 开枪！Zondal 开枪！马上开枪！
Co-ordinates for area red one: oh-oh-eight-one-nine-three
vertical. Eight-five-eight-one-eight-oh lateral. _ controls are set.
红色一区坐标：纵轴 008193 侧轴 858180
The records wing - it's gone! It's demolished!
We're under attack!
我们被攻击了！
Report!
赶紧报告！
Leader Clent, surrender or die!
组长 Clent, 不投降就死
What in the blazes?
Surrender now or I will blast your base to fragments.
现在投降, 否则我就把你们的基地轰成齑粉
No, I refuse! You can't destroy us!
不, 我拒绝！你们不可能摧毁我们
You do not believe me? Very well. Must I fire again?
你不相信？ 好, 必须得我再开一炮？
We must play for time.
我们必须拖延时间
The building won't stand much more of this bombardment, Sir!
这栋建筑受不了几次这样的轰击, 先生！
Then we must talk. Who am I addressing?
那我们必须谈谈, 我在跟谁对话？
My name is Varga. Do you surrender?
我叫 Varga． 你们投降吗？
Now frankly, you gain nothing by destroying us, Varga. We both
have urgent needs. I will agree to talk... but nothing more.
坦白地说, 毁灭我们你们什么也得不到, Varga.
No treachery? If I come in peace
there must be trust between us.
Very well. There will be
no traps, or conditions.
See that you keep to
that, for if you lie...
What does he want?
Our guards won't stand a chance
against weapons like that, Sir.
Ah, you heard what he said
- no treachery, only trust.
But can we trust him?
I'm afraid we have to. He's got the best argument on his side
- that gun, or whatever it is.
We can bluff him though.
How?
He doesn't know the computer's command to wait. We can
threaten to destroy the glacier, and his ship with it.
Yes, yes. Yes possibly.
Well why can't we do it, Sir?
It's our only chance for survival!
Because you know the computers decision
- and its reasons.
I know all about that! But it doesn't
exactly give much thought to us, does it?
The computer thinks of everything,
considers all the facts.
And it's supposed to come up with all the answers, isn't it? Well a fat lot of good it's doing us now! Wait,
it says, wait! With glaciers on the one hand, and, and warriors on the other! Well what price your computer now!
Walters!
What we need, is, is someone like, like Penley, or that Doctor! Someone who can think! Not with a machine! And what
good's your precious computer done anyway? Nothing! Nothing but trouble! And it's time somebody put a stop to it!
That's Varga's voice.
We are going in now.
We must escape.
It's not just a question of escape, Victoria. We've got to take some action.
Right, this gun that's given Varga control of the base, without it he'd be helpless.
What can we do?
Well now, gentlemen, you, you said no traps. And we for
our part, have made utterly sure, that there are no traps...
I made no promises. I merely
warned you not to trick me.
How can we help you?
I will tell you what I want
and you will give it to me.
Oh, come now Varga, that's not the way to talk. We're, both of us, in a very difficult situation. Under
times like this it beholds us both to proceed with mutual respect and, because the whole world could be...
So much for your word.
That was, that was not planned.
I have one major requirement: the mercury isotopes
for my ships reactor. You will give them to me.
But we don't use mercury isotopes.
The Doctor stated
that you had them here.
Well he was wrong, we have none.
You are lying.
What good will it do me?
Tell me what will happen if we halted your reactor
in order to remove the fuel elements we need.
You can't do that!
Why?
That reactor gives us
light, heat and power.
And it powers the ioniser.
So that without it, you
would be completely helpless.
In Arctic conditions like
these... we'd soon perish.
Where as we would not.
You'd be wasting your time. This
reactor does not use mercury.
I do not believe you.
But you must.
There is only one way to find out. Where
are the reactor controls? Tell me now.
Did you hear that? Making
them shut down the reactor!
Yes. Now this is Varga's main weapon. There's
just a chance that I can turn it against him.
What?
If I can open these doors...
there we are! Come on.
Now careful. Just stay there.
How does this gun operate?
Oh, hurry Doctor, hurry.
You've got to believe me!
So you say.
Listen, Varga, the power source is locked in directly with the ioniser. Now if we cut the
power before it is safe, the feedback effect could blast this building into a state of ion flux.
What's its temperature range?
It can melt rock!
Don't interfere with
it! It's fully primed.
It can melt rock. What a weapon.
It is not a weapon. It is
a scientific instrument.
I see it differently.
It's still a highly dangerous machine.
Then run is carefully down to
safety level. But no tricks.
You do it now.
It will take some time.
Doesn't matter. You
dare not use it anyway.
What?
Your Doctor friend talked. I know your fear of my
spaceship. That it will explode if the heat is too great.
Would it?
Close it down. Or you die.
She's the only person qualified
to disconnect the ioniser safely.
What are you qualifications
for existence?
I'm the leader here!
You have less value to me than your
colleague, who has certain skills.
But she doesn't know everything. I
have the answers that you require.
I know all I need to know. If I killed
you, it would be no great loss to me.
No! Please!
Then you will do as I say. Run down the machine as
quickly as is safely possible. No more tricks. At once.
Ah, ah.
What is it you're trying to do?
Well it's a little difficult to explain,
Victoria. Oh. Oh dear. Hold this for me, will you?
Ah. This gun works on the basis that sound waves
produce reverberations in the objects in their path.
The objects vibrate in sympathy.
Well I know, my father told me once.
Yes, that's right. Well if you can produce
unsympathetic vibrations, damage results.
Damage? Oh, like a
singer breaking glass.
Yes. But I want to be able to get at the warriors without it affecting
the scientists too much. Now, if we change this to frequency seven...
What will that do?
Well primarily it affects fluids.
What good is that to us?
Well I believe that Varga and his warriors have a
far greater fluid content than human-beings. There.
If it works, what happens?
That's just it, I don't know.
Oh now look, Doctor.
But I do know that whatever effect it has on the
scientists, it'll have a far greater one on the warriors.
Well how's that?
Well apart from the fluid question, their
helmets will trap and intensify the sound waves.
You mean, it'll knock them out and leave
the scientists a bit dizzy? Well is that it?
Well that's what I'm hoping, but, there is just a vague
risk that it'll kill everybody. Clent and Penley included.
And Jamie?
It's done.
It is safe now?
Yes. Just ticking over. Not even
holding the ice in check at all.
Disconnect it completely, now.
Now we must move quickly, before the
glacial surge does too much damage.
You'll regret this, Varga.
At least I will live to regret it.
Now, the reactor. Shut it down, quickly.
Perfectly at home in ice age conditions.
Well, we'll soon change all that.
Shut it down at once.
Ooh.
The heat. What is happening? There is something wrong.
You are trying to trick me again. For that you will die!
No no! It's too dangerous!
It's a risk we must take, Victoria!
Oh!
Now, cross your fingers. Here we go.
Varga, this is the Doctor. Are you going to retreat, or shall I fire again? Trouble is I dare not use it again,
if it hasn't killed them all already, another firing most certainly will! Varga! Answer me or I fire again!
You will die for this.
What are you doing now?
Get well back, Victoria.
What?
Stand by for fireworks! Here we go.
Now quickly! Let's get out
of here before they come back!
The gun is useless.
Victoria, see if you can find Jamie.
Doctor, Jamie's in there. He's alive!
Well thanks heavens for that! Now you get
back to the TARDIS, and close the doors!
Sorry about that.
Oh.
Up you get. Come along. Ah.
What happened? Did you do that?
No time for questions. Come along.
So, you allowed them to trick you.
I await your punishment, Commander.
We have no time. Everything depends on being ready to
break free from the ice as soon as they evaporate it.
Up you get. Come along
Miss Garrett. There you are.
Clent. The Doctor did something, but
don't ask me what it was. Are you alright?
Oh, the ioniser! They
made me... disconnect it!
Then it must be switched
on again immediately!
I don't take orders from you!
Miss Garrett, if we are to obey Computer
Control, it must be reconnected. Do so please.
Yes, of course.
Clent! Their spacecraft is
powered by an ion reactor.
Well that means we dare not use the ioniser
at full force. That's our last chance gone.
Why, for heavens sake?
Because of the risk, man!
You know what would happen.
Of course there's a risk, but it's a
risk we must take! It's the only way!
Exactly!
The computer says no!
The computer...
Is our supreme advisor.
And what sort of advice
is that? Do nothing?
We must obey!
And be destroyed? Has the
computer considered that?
The computer considers everything.
But that's why in this case you
cannot rely on its judgement!
We trust the computer! It is
our strength and our guide.
Not this time!
Well why not?
Because Jamie, the computer is faced with an insoluble problem. Either
way it risks destroying itself and this it cannot do. It must play safe.
Aye, but if it does
nothing that's just as bad.
I'll explain to you another time, Jamie.
There's only one way out.
What?
We must override the computer.
You can't do that!
We must. This is a decision for a man to take, not a machine. The computer isn't
designed to take risks, but that is the essence of mans procrease. We must decide.
But if you do that soon ruin the world plan! All the ioniser bases must act together!
Through World Computer Control! If we act too soon it's as bad as being too late!
Yes I know that, but the other bases haven't got a glacier right on top of them, and apart
from that, what about these ice warriors? If they live, they threaten our entire civilisation.
A decision must be taken, and quickly!
I can't.
I daren't.
Penley, it's up to you.
Well Clent?
I reserve the right to
consult the computer.
Go ahead.
Problem: alien spacecraft is powered by an ion reactor.
Dare we use the ioniser? What are the alternatives? Answer.
It's as though it's gone mad!
Well Penley?
We will use the ioniser at full strength to turn back
the glacier. Miss, Miss Garrett, inform World Control.
Er, but the spaceship, if
you release it from the ice?
At full strength the
ioniser will melt rock!
Commander, the glacier is
breaking up. Soon we will be free.
What use is our freedom if we are
helpless? Our engines must still dead.
I have not given up yet.
Nor I. There must be some
life left in the elements.
Commander, power.
What? The ice is our
friend. We still have power.
Shall I increase it?
Carefully. We must time full
take-off boost perfectly.
And when we are free and in
flight, we will be invincible.
Instrument readings on the glacier face show a
steady rise in temperature. Now near to maximum.
Well how will we know?
The instruments on the ice face have the highest heat _ resistance known to
man. When they cease to function, everything about them will be destroyed.
You're wrong! You're
wrong! We'll all be killed!
It is a risk I willingly take!
It was not power in the engines, Zondal, it was heat, our
greatest enemy! The heat from the ioniser! The... heeeeeeeeeat...!
Only a minor explosion.
We're safe!
Oh. Goodness me!
Set all circuits to automatic, Miss Garrett. And tie in with the World loniser instrumentation.
Clent, will you, er, check these readings with me? And you've a report to prepare haven't you?
Yes, yes, yes I have. Penley. You are the most insufferably irritating
and infuriating person, I've ever been privileged to work with.
Thank you.
Can't write a report though, can you? Something I've got to do for
you. Well don't worry it's something that I've been trained to do.
Without the computer?
No Penley. I've always written my
own speeches, and my own reports.
Are you going to include...
Well where's the Doctor?