I'm going down. You go back.
Well be careful Thara!
Doctor!
Are you alright Zoe?
Yes, I think so.
Come on, this way.
No, we must find the Doctor!
Well where is he?
S-somewhere over there, I saw him fall.
I'll look for him. You stay under here.
Vana, what are you doing here? Why aren't you in the hills?
Because Thara and I stayed behind with Beta to make some acid./?
We were bringing it here for the Doctor
when we felt the earthquake.
The Doctor!
Has anyone seen him?
He's probably buried down there with the digging party.
I've found him Zoe!
Oh...
Are alright Doctor?
Yes, yes, I think so. I don't think there's any bones broken.
But if they don't get that vibration under control soon..!
We must hurry, there's gonna be a...
- Oh look out!
- Look out!
Oh!
Oh, Thara! Ah, don't worry, we'll get it off you. Zoe!
Oh Doctor.
CUT AUXILIARIES.
AUXILIARIES CUT.
OUTPUT ZERO.
FEED IN EMERGENCY POWER.
GRAVITATION FEED CHECK.
STATIC.
DYNOTROPE BALANCE NORMAL.
Could be a fracture.
Feels painful enough.
I'll strap it. Oh Doctor, give me the wood.
Yes w.. hurry up Zoe!
We've got to move out of here you know.
You think there'll be another earthquake?
Oh that was not an earthquake.
Oh no, it was coming from the machine.
- It's stopped.
- Yes.
That means the Krotons are free to deal with us.
Haven't you finished yet Zoe?
No I haven't. Hey, can I borrow your braces?
No!
Ooh!
Here, I'd much rather you use this.
Oh...
Yes Doctor, I'm afraid we have failed.
The machine is unharmed.
I'm not so sure - look at that.
What is happening to it?
I-I'd say it was no longer functioning under full power.
Vana, how is Beta getting on with the acid I asked him to make?
- Oh, he sent this Doctor.
- Oh good.
He only made a small amount to start with.
- Yeah... Uh-huh.
- Is it alright.
Pooh, sulphuric acid isn't it?
Yes, well basically... with a few things added.
Uh-uh, don't touch - it'll burn you.
Doctor what about Jamie?
Jamie! I'd forgotten all about him in the excitement!
Has anybody seen him?
But he followed you.
Followed us? What, in there?
Yes, I tried to...
Well how long ago?!
About an hour after you and the Doctor.
But Doctor, Jamie wouldn't be any use to them!
His mind is completely untrained.
Yes, and if the machine rejects him like the others... Come on!
Doctor!
A-argh... aah... ah Doctor!
- Jamie!
- Quick!
Jamie, watch out for the poison jets!
It's just on my back!
We've got to get you out of here!
- I know!
- Jamie!
It's just another inch I think.
I think you're getting free.
Oh quick!
What's been happening? I though that machine
was going to shake itself to pieces!
There's no time to explain Jamie. How are you feeling?
- Well I...
- Good.
- There's something I want you to do for me.
- Oh not again!
Now Beta is making some special sulphuric acid for us,
I want you to go and tell him to make it in bulk.
- Yes, but...
- As much as you can.
- Oh, b-b-but Doctor...
- There's no time to argue, now hurry.
We'll see you back at the learning hall.
Eh... ah.
BALANCE ZERO PLUS TWELVE.
WE HAVE RESERVE POWER FOR TWENTY-SEVEN MORE MINUTES.
THEN WE SHALL EXHAUST! OUR FUNCTION WILL END.
Oh, what do we do next?
Well if only we can get inside that machine again, Zoe.
You can Doctor.
Oh?
We'll help you into it.
Oh, that's very good of you...
What?! What's all this?
Oh... oh Doctor!
THE HIGH-BRAINS HAVE BEEN CAPTURED! BALANCE CHECK?
ZERO PLUS NINE.
EXHAUST TIME TWENTY-TWO MINUTES.
SHALL I OPEN THE DYNOTROPE?
ONLY THE TWO HIGH-BRAINS MUST ENTER.
Well take them up!
Oh really! We will not be bullied! Don't push!
Vana, Vana have you got that bottle, it's vital!
THE HIGH-BRAINS WILL ENTER IMMEDIATELY!
I think we'd better do as they say Doctor.
Yes... V-Vana... oh!
THE HIGH-BRAINS ARE ENTERING THE DYNOTROPE.
PREPARE FOR TAKE-OFF. PHASE ONE.
PHASE ONE READY. SHALL I DESTROY THE GONDS NOW?
THEY ARE OF NO VALUE.
NO, THE DISPERSION UNITS USE POWER.
WE HAVE NO POWER TO WASTE.
That bottle Selris?
It's alright, I have it here.
The Doctor needs it, he says it's vital!
Come back!
I believe you wish to speak with us.
- Doctor!
- Look out!
No!
SET THE INTERGALACTIC LINK.
TAKE OFF PHASE TWO.
PREPARE TO TRANSFER.
ALL SYSTEMS SET.
YOU WILL ASSIST US NOW.
Assist you? In what way?
THE DYNOTROPE WILL EXHAUST IN TWELVE MINUTES.
Well that's your problem.
Er, no Zoe. If this machine does run down
there will be the most colossal release of energy.
Enough to destroy us, the Krotons and most of the planet.
Er... If you want us to help you, you must explain
what it is you want us to do. What is this thing?
IT TRANSFERS THE DYNOTROPE BACK TO OUR OWN COSMOS.
IT OPERATES THROUGH MENTAL POWER.
You've discovered a way of using mental power?
And you Krotons haven't enough.
FOUR HIGH-BRAINS ARE NEEDED IN RELAY.
THERE ARE ONLY TWO OF US.
Then how did you get here?
NO MORE QUESTIONS!
If you want us... if you want us to cooperate
you must expect questions!
UNLESS YOU DO AS WE ORDER YOU WILL BE DISPERSED!
Very well, but that won't help you, will it?
WE'RE WASTING TIME! THE DYNOTROPE WAS PART OF A BATTLE FLEET,
TWO OF OUR CREW WERE EXHAUSTED BY ENEMY FIRE.
Do you mean that they were killed?
CEASED TO FUNCTION. WE CARRIED OUT THE EMERGENCY PROCEDURE
AND LANDED ON THE NEAREST PLANET.
TO CONSERVE POWER WE SET THE DYNOTROPE IN PERPETUAL STABILITY.
Ooh I see! And you set the-the machines systems
to educate the Gonds up to the standard you require.
YES. THEY WERE PRIMITIVES.
Well you didn't have to kill them to do that!
GOND SAMPLES WERE BROUGHT IN FOR TESTING AT INTERVALS.
THE DYNOTROPE ABSORBED THEIR MENTAL POWER INTO IT'S CIRCUITS
- THE WASTE MATTER WAS REJECTED.
AND DISPERSED. NINE MINUTES TO EXHAUST TIME, COMMANDER!
Look out!
Hey now, careful. Hey watch it!
Watch it, it's deadly.
Cue back davit.
Ad admonito.
Where do you think you're going? What's that?
It's something called acid.
The Doctor asked me to make it for him.
He won't be needing that now.
You've been wasting your time.
W-where is he then?
He's joined the Krotons.
You mean he's gone into the machine?
Well what about Zoe?
Zoe too. The Krotons wanted them,
and Eelek surrendered them.
You did what?
The Krotons need your friends
to enable them to leave our world.
And you just handed them over, did you?
If the Krotons will leave our world,
they're welcome to your friends.
Ya miserable...
Careful Jamie!
It's time we were leaving.
Leaving?
- Unless you want to die.
- What are you talking about Eelek?
Beta, for a scientist you're very stupid.
The learning hall and most of our city
is built around that Kroton's machine,
- and once that machine starts moving off...
- The whole place will come down.
Exactly, and you'll be buried alive.
Aye, well I'm staying. Somehow I'm gonna
get the Doctor and Zoe out of there. Beta?
Yes, I'll stay here and help you.
Vana?
I'll stay here and look after Thara.
I'm not sensible enough to run away and leave my friends.
No. Let them stay, and let them die.
He could be right you know.
Aye, maybe so. But I'm not going down without a fight.
Now where do we put this stuff?
PUT ON THE HEADSETS.
Now just a moment. If we're going to help you
transfer the Dynotrope back to your own planet,
- what's going to happen to us?
- YOU WILL SUFFER NO HARM.
Well how can we be sure of that?
We die without oxygen you see.
Er, just as you would die if anyone was to
upset the stuff you're drawing from that tank.
TAKE UP YOUR POSITIONS.
I was merely trying to say that
if anyone was to contaminate what was in that tank,
you'd know what it was like to breathe poisoned air!
SIX MINUTES.
YOU HAVE NO CHOICE. PUT ON THE HEADSET.
Oh well, I suppose we had better just take your word for it then.
SET THE TRANSFER LINK.
FINAL PHASE ON AUTOMATIC.
Oh. Now then ah, where do you want us to stand?
UNIMPORTANT.
Oh. Well I'll stand over here then.
Oh... Oh Doctor I wanted to stand over there.
Oh my dear, oh well you stand there and I'll stand here.
Better still, a much better idea.
I'll stand here and you stand...
PUT ON THE HEADSETS OR YOU WILL BE DISPERSED!
Alright, alright. How do, how do you wear these things?
Nothing seems to be happening.
Alright, give it time, give it time.
Oh, ha-ha! Butterfingers!
Oh Doctor you are clumsy!
ENOUGH OF THIS! PUT ON THE HEADSETS!
Well it's your fault, you're making me nervous!
Down Zoe!
Yeah. Look Doctor, it's dissolving.
Yeah... yeah. It's returning to it's basic form.
Oh Doctor! These fumes, they're choking!
Yes, we must get out of here. Zoe, look!
The machine, it's melting! Come on,
let's get out of here before we're trapped.
Doctor, Zoe!
What happened?
Did you get out alright?
Yes.
How are you?
Yeah.. yes, well I'm a little bit shaken;
but ah, not half so bad as the Krotons I can assure you.
What're you doing here?
Look at the machine!
It's working Thara! Look, it's working.
Well what made you think of pouring acid on it?
Well we reckoned that if the Doctor thought
it worthwhile experimenting with a few drops,
- we'd see what a few gallons would do.
- Oh Well done!
But how did you know that the machine would dissolve?
Mm? Oh, well the machine was eighty percent tellurium, Zoe.
And tellurium is soluble in sulphuric acid.
But the machine wasn't pure tellurium.
Well the acid wasn't pure sulphuric acid,
but it worked didn't it?
Come on, let's get away. I don't like goodbyes.
It's finished now, isn't it?
Yes it is finished - the end of the Krotons.
We're free at last!