So, these creatures have a life system based on tellurium, eh?
It's fascinating isn't it Zoe?
Then that tank must have been a polarised centrifuge.
- Which we activated.
- Oh don't blame yourself Zoe.
Oh, that machine must have lain around
for thousands of years for someone as clever as us to turn up.
Just like a giant mousetrap -
and those poor Gond students have been the mice.
Yes, that's horrible. Still, you must admit,
that it's a-a very good way of existing through time.
Are you sure you're strong enough?
Of course. I'm alright now.
I can carry you.
That won't be necessary, I'll walk Thara.
It's a long way to the hills...
Doctor you're back!
Yes, I'm sorry I've been so long.
But... we thought you were dead!
Dead?
Selris said that you'd gone into the machine.
Oh yes, well we did, but er... Well-well er,
what goes in must come out, mustn't it?
- You're better aren't you?
- Much.
Sit down, you mustn't...
Oh, I'm glad to see you're going on holiday.
Holiday? We aren't goi...
Well it looks as though...
Well the city's being evacuated.
Evacuated? What do you mean?
My father's going to lead an attack on the Krotons.
He hopes they'll strike back and come out into the open.
Didn't he learn last night?
Oh he's going to attack the machine from underneath.
Demolish the machine's supports.
Oh I don't think that's a very good idea!
Zoe, there's no time to be lost!
Will you take me to Beta please?
Yeah.
Thara, if you've come to try and persuade me
to leave you're wasting your time.
I haven't, the Doctor asked to see your laboratory.
Can you hold my bag please.
Er, there's a small job I want you to do.
Oh, what's that?
It's sulphur. I've written out some instructions here,
I don't know whether you can follow them, can you?
Yes, I think so. But the Krotons forbid us to study chemistry.
Yes... Beta, did it ever occur to you to wonder why?
Doctor, where's Jamie?
He's supposed to be looking after you.
Well where's he got to?
Well he followed you out to the Learning Hall.
Well I haven't seen him since this morning!
Oh you don't suppose he tried to get into the machine do you?
Come on, we must go!
Yes, let's!
Give me a sample of that as soon as you can will you?
Vana, I'm staying here to help.
Oh no you're not, you're going to the hills the pair of you.
Oh don't be ridiculous Beta we're not leaving you here.
Besides, I feel quite faint - I don't think I could walk a step.
THE GRAVITATION FEED IS DROPPING.
THE DYNOTROPE IS MOVING OUT OF BALANCE.
STATIC BEAM, SWITCH TO FULL VOLUME.
FULL VOLUME ON.
SYSTEM CHECK COMMENCE.
If that comes down we shall all be killed!
But the machine will come down first!
Look at the vibration!
Stop it! Stop it!
What do you think you're doing, you idiots?!
Just unhook the thing,
you're meddling with things you don't understand!
Oh Doctor, look out!