Oh Doctor don't move!
Aah, it's alright Zoe. I-I think it's quite safe now.
Oh I wouldn't be so sure!
Just watch this Jamie.
Pattern recognition!
Yes, and the pattern is my face!
Doctor, do you mean that thing was sent out
to attack you and only you?
Yes, so it seems. It's rather flattering isn't it?
Well then the Krotons know who you are,
Aye!
Or at least what you look like.
Yes... That means they must have a scanner
in the wall of the machine./?
Now if we can find that we might be able to get in touch with them.
Uh.. Doctor!
Oh no.
It's gone back.
Yes. That poor fellow must have confused it's attack mechanism.
Eh?
Well it was programmed to kill once - me!
It must think that it's succeeded, stupid machine!
There's your wonderful Krotons for you Father! MURDERERS!
No! Thara, don't provoke them!
Is that all you care about, not provoking them?!
What can we do against their weapons?
We can fight..!
THIS IS A WARNING. YOUR LEADER HAS BEEN DESTROYED. /08.2
ALL GONDS LEAVE THE LEARNING HALL AT ONCE - AT ONCE.
No, stay and fight!
LEAVE THE LEARNING HALL. ALL GONDS LEAVE THE LEARNING HALL.
Everyone leave the hall. Now!
Where did this come from?
I borrowed it from Beta.
But I thought they didn't know anything about electricity?
They don't - er, that works on stored solar energy. /52.6
Yes the Gonds are quite advanced in some ways. /55.1
The-their medicine is pretty good,
but they haven't got very much general chemistry./17.2
I wish they had an ECT machine though.
Yes. There are tremendous gaps in their knowledge./?
Well they only seem to know what the machines teach them.
Yes. And the machines are programmed by the Krotons,
so the gaps in their knowledge may be significant.
Ah, Selris...
How is she Doctor?
Well I think she's better, it's difficult to tell. /?
Um Selris, is it safe to enter the Learning-Hall yet?
Why?
Er, Zoe and I want to have a look round, don't we Zoe?
Oh, do we?
Yes, that's right. Ah Jamie, hold out your hand will you?
Well what for?
Ah, these pills I got from Beta.
Well there's nothing wrong with me!
No-no. Ah, they're for Vana.
I want you to stay and look after her.
Oh but why can't I go with you?
Because I particularly want you to give her those pills the moment she wakes up.
Ah well...
Well why are we going back to the Learning-Hall?
Oh, to learn Zoe, why else?
I am coming with you Doctor.
Oh my dear fellow, there is no need for that.
I must know what is happening.
Oh well.. ah, certainly. Come along Zoe.
Er Selris um, what's that?
Oh, ah, that leads to the under-hall.
Oh, what's down there?
Nothing, it's never used.
I wonder how far underneath..?
Ah, let's have a look shall we?
Oh, ah... Oh yes, it's-it's a bit dark and musty down here. /?
Zoe, stay up there will you? We shan't be long.
I told you there was nothing down there.
Ah, but there was Selris. Something rather curious.
Only the foundations of the machine.
It stands on those metal pillars.
Zoe!
Oh, you're soon back Doctor.
What do you think you are doing?!
I was just trying the machine.
You should know better than to do a thing like that!
Oh but Doctor, it was all so easy!
The Krotons were very pleased with me.
Very pleased?
- Well I felt they were.
- Zoe! Now just you listen to me!
Whatever else they are, these Krotons are certainly not friendly!
- Now we know that don't we?
- Yes of course!
And they use these machines to plant impressions in the mind.
That's how they've enslaved these people all these years.
Doctor!
What?
Look at the dial!
Oh what of it?
It's amazing! Even the best of our students
registered less than half of that score!
Yes well, Zoe is something of a genius.
Of course it can be very irritating at times!
... I went into the machine...
Did you see the Krotons?
The ball... Flashing! Coming down on me!
Now you're quite safe here Vana, now!
You'd better take these, here.
Drink up now - all down. That's it.
Flashing ball burning her mind?
What did she mean? Is it another of the Krotons weapons?
I don't know... Look, you stay here with her,
I'll go and get the Doctor.
It's crystalline.
Yes, it's hard but it-it's not brittle.
I've never seen anything quite like it.
What was it like down there?
Mm? Oh, what Selris calls the foundations.
Uh... Zoe, it was like a root structure.
A root structure!? But indicates that...
That this so-called "machine" is organic in structure.
Well is that possible?
Well why not? Some crystals do resemble simple virus forms.
I wish I could get a bit of it for analysis...
Well if you're right that means
that the whole of this machine is a sort of a living thing!
Well all life doesn't necessarily have feeling you know...
Great jumping gobstoppers! What's that?
The Krotons command. It means there is a message for me.
Oh, what does it say? Mm?
Class three-one-nine-seven, selected female Zo-Gond.
Zo-Gond? Zoe - they mean you!
They've chosen you as a companion.
And we all know what happens to them don't we?
Oh Doctor what shall I do?
Well she doesn't have to go does she?
Well does she or doesn't she?!
I'm afraid she must.
Complete obedience is the Krotons first command
- And if we fail to obey...
- They'll destroy you, I see...
Oh dear.
Now d'you see what you've done?!
Fooling around with this stupid machine!
Oh, but I'm not a Gond!
But that machine doesn't know that!
Oh, where are you going?
I'm going to take the test,
I can't let you go in there alone! Er... what do I do?
Oh sit down, and put this... This headset on.
And press the button.
Press the button!
Alright, no need to shout!
Now go away and don't fuss me!
No come back, what's this?
- .. What..
- ...It's alright, I know!
Alright, fire away. I'm ready.
Ah. Oh... oh.
Oh Doctor, you've got it all wrong!
Oh dear, I've been working in square roots.
Er, can I have that again please?
Well they don't give you a second shots!
Oh.
Well press the button again!
This is the most advanced machine.
Perhaps he can't answer the questions?
Of course he can. The Doctor's almost as clever as I am!
I see.
Uh... oh now what have I done?
Oh Doctor, you've divided instead of multiplying!
You must concentrate!
I am Zoe, I am!
Good.
Mm-mm. Yes er, I think that's rather better.
I think I've scored more than you have Zoe!
You answered more questions.
Besides, this isn't supposed to be a competition!
It's clever isn't it?
The way they make you feel that they're pleased with you...
Yes. Perhaps the Krotons aren't as bad as we think?
What..?
What? Of-of course they are!
Ah, what happens now?
The Krotons will be waiting for Zoe.
Well they can wait! We are going in there together.
Normally the names don't come through for some time.
Well mine did.
Yes, but perhaps they were impressed
with your performance, and that's why.
Sounds a bit like a dinner gong, doesn't it Zoe?
Class three-one-nine-eight, selected male - Doctor-Gond.
Doctor-Gond. Idiots!
Well it means you anyway.
Yes, er-er... Well, are you ready?
I suppose we have to...
Well we started this, we'd better go through with it./?
We've got to get to the bottom of this somehow Zoe.
Oh this is all my fault!
Oh cheer up, cheer up.
I expect it'll be quite interesting really.
I am sorry Doctor.
My people will always remember you.
Eh? Oh... oh that's very nice of them.
Stay close to me Zoe.
Doctor! No wait, come back!
What's happened?
Where've they gone?
Your people are gone. They are now companions of the Krotons.
Wha-?
It is a spaceship!
Yes, but there doesn't seem to be any crew.
Hello... anybody there? Is anybody at home, hello!
I think we've been asked to sit down.
Yes I think we have Zoe.
Uh, Zoe... Hold onto the end of this chain.
What for?
Look up there - it's a force generator.
This chain might help to equalise the power load.
Well what are they going to do?
Doctor I can't move!
No, it's a forcefield. Try and relax... relax.
But why did you let them go?
It is a command of the Krotons.
Ah, the Krotons! They just rap out an order
and everyone jumps don't they! /?
Aye, well I'm not just standing here to see my...
Where are you going?
To find a way into this box of tricks!
Ow!
Are you alright Zoe? Oh!
Yes... I think so...
Oh!
What happened?
Oh some tremendous power, oh!
They seem to have a way of transferring
mental power into pure energy.
Yes. And they used it -
or-or rather us to operate a thermal switch.
Doctor look!
Yes.
I thought there was a wall here.
Yes, there was. Zoe I think that I'm beginning to understand.
What's that?
That's curious... Zoe, I think we've gone and done it.
What?
Well... Just a minute I've got an idea.
Oh yes... This is a form of slurry. Crystals in suspension.
But what's its purpose?
Well, life is supposed to have begun on your planet in the sea, mm?/?
Primeval soup someone once called it. /?
Well there are lots of sorts of soups aren't there,
I-I wonder what this sort is?
And what do you suppose these are?
They look like astronauts' air lines.
Yes I think you're right Zoe. Zoe look!
I think it's time we... got out of here.
Come along! Uh..
Well what are we going to do if we do get out?
We haven't learned anything yet.
Yes we have, once we can analyse this.
Now uh, come on...
It should slide somewhere.
Yes, there must be a trip-mechanism.
Doctor look, there's a photo-electric cell here.
Aah!
It can't be working.
Well if it's not working...
Then the Krotons must have cut the circuit.
Yes.
Then we're trapped, they know we're here!
Just a moment I have an idea.
Er, that piece of mica that I picked up, here we are...
Now if I can use it to bridge the gap...
Well will mica work?
Well the whole machine's made of crystal.
Wait! The poison jet!
THEY HAVE ACTIVATED THE CIRCUIT.
THEN THE DISPERSION UNIT WILL KILL THEM.