How long ago did they go in?
BENTON: Some time ago, sir.
Tracy followed them as far as the official boundary
of the railway sidings.
They went in about an hour ago.
-Is Tracy still round there?
-Yes, sir.
-Right, stick around for a while.
-Just a minute, sir.
Yes, what is it, Benton?
The Doctor and the boy.
They're coming out, sir, with Vaughn.
They've all got into Vaughn's private car.
Oh, they're driving off, sir.
Is any force being used?
No. Not that I can see. Packer was there,
but it all seemed very friendly to me.
Shall we follow?
No, I'll have them tracked more discreetly.
-Over and out. Sergeant Walters.
-Yes, sir?
-Alert all area patrols in section three.
-Yes, sir.
-Did you hear all that, Jimmy?
-I did, sir.
Look, we'll get you aboard a chopper,
and you can rendezvous with the tracking agent.
All right, sir.
(ROTORS WHIRRING)
Yes, they've just gone into the IE area, sir.
Shall I follow?
No, circle the area. We can't really do anything
until we get a request from the Doctor.
-Standing by, sir.
-And, Jimmy, keep out of sight.
If Vaughn's private army see you,
they might well get the wind up,
and that might make things rather unhealthy
for the Doctor and the boy.
Hey!
-Doctor, it's...
-Confusing, isn't it?
It's exactly the same as your office in London.
In all basic essentials, yes, it is.
That's the secret of my success, you see.
Uniformity. Duplication.
My whole empire is based on that principle.
The very essence of business efficiency.
-Do sit down.
-DOCTOR: Oh, how kind.
I must say I'm rather glad
we have this opportunity to talk.
Really?
I should, of course, be angry with you.
You've thwarted
my elaborate security precautions twice.
-I'd like to know why.
-Oh, that's quite simple.
I hate computers
and refuse to be bullied by them.
Your young friend Zoe.
-Well, what about her?
-Well, she appears to have the same instincts.
She so confused one of my computers
she ruined its memory store.
So that's why your thugs dragged her
and Isobel away.
My dear young man, I wasn't angry with her.
On the contrary, I found the incident
quite amusing. She's a remarkable girl.
And you, Doctor, are obviously a man
of no mean scientific ability.
Why do you say that?
Well, my research department
found these quite fascinating.
There's a totally illogical factor
in their construction.
Are they of your own invention?
Ah, you're determined to guard your secret, I see.
I don't blame you,
and I promise not to pry any more.
-In fact, I'll do all I can to help you.
-Oh, how kind.
Now, you say you came here
looking for Professor Watkins
because you thought he might be able to help you.
Yes.
Well, then I'll try to persuade him
to put aside his work and, um,
concentrate his efforts on your behalf.
Make yourself at home.
Hey, look, you're not going to trust him, are you?
I mean, what about Zoe and Isobel?
I haven't forgotten them, Jamie.
They're in that box. I'm sure of it.
Jamie, we're not going to help Zoe
by annoying Mr Vaughn, are we?
I don't think you can annoy that man
even if you wanted to.
He's being as nice as pie.
He's too nice.
-Yeah, but why should he be?
-I don't know.
He's a little bit too interested in these circuits
for my liking.
Hey, do you think he knows
about the Tardis, then?
Well, I don't see how he could do.
No, well, perhaps this Professor Watkins
will be able to tell us what's going on around here.
-Yes, but that's what's worrying me.
-What?
Well, if Vaughn has anything to hide,
why is he letting us talk to Watkins?
I'd think about it if I were you, Professor.
After all, she is a pretty girl.
It'd be a shame to spoil all that.
What a vicious sadist you are, Packer.
I don't believe you, anyway.
I don't make idle threats, Professor,
as you well know.
If you want to see that girl again in one piece,
I suggest you do as Mr Vaughn asks.
How do I know that you already
haven't harmed her? If you had got her...
You can take my word for that, Professor.
(LAUGHING) Your word.
I know just how much value I can place on that.
Harsh words, Professor, harsh words.
Any progress?
-So you haven't yet completed the machine?
-No, and I don't intend to.
Oh, I think you will, Professor.
Much as I detest violence,
I find it difficult to restrain Packer's
indisputable talent for persuasion.
Your niece is in our custody,
and unless you do as I ask,
I shall hand her over to Packer.
The choice is yours.
If I do cooperate, will you let her go?
Oh, no, she's our guarantee,
but she'll come to no harm.
All right.
-But I must see Isobel first.
-Of course.
Oh, there is just one other thing.
Don't look at me so suspiciously,
my dear Professor.
It's merely that there are some friends of yours
here who wish to see you.
-Friends?
-Yes, they've gone to great pains to seek you out.
But I haven't been allowed visitors
since I came here.
Why are you suddenly considerate?
I might tell them everything.
Everything?
My dear Professor,
you know nothing that can harm me.
Besides, there's always Isobel to consider,
isn't there?
-Or would you rather leave her to me?
-Now, now, Packer.
The Professor's going to do exactly as we ask.
Aren't you?
Yes, of course, I remember Anne Travers
telling me about you.
She was a student of mine, you know,
some years ago.
-Brilliant girl. Brilliant.
-Yes.
Yes, they went to America, didn't they?
Oh, Travers was getting past it a bit, you know,
and Anne persuaded him
to go to America with her.
Oh, yes.
What are you doing here?
Well, it's a long story.
The strange Doctor
has been on another planet, Packer.
That's not possible!
It is a fact, Packer.
He has some sort of machine.
Now let's see if we can learn more about it,
shall we?
Switch on, Packer.
With sound.
So we went to see Mr Vaughn,
and he said that you were working
on something important.
I see. That's why you wanted
to leave them alone together.
Exactly, Packer.
(COMMUNICATOR HUMMING)
But the Doctor needed some help
on some electronic circuits that the Tardis had.
-Really?
-Aye, aye.
Jamie, Jamie. I don't think
the Professor wants to hear about that.
Oh, on the contrary, what Anne told me
about the Tardis was most intriguing.
I'd like to hear a lot more about it.
Professor, I think I should warn you
that Anne Travers allowed her imagination
to run a little wild.
You mean to say that there is no such machine?
-Of course there is...
-Jamie, I think
there are other more important things
to talk about at the moment.
Oh, I see, yes.
Professor, tell us about what you're doing here.
Oh, it's very simple, really.
I've been developing
a new kind of teaching machine.
-Oh, yes? A teaching machine?
-What's it called?
-I call it the Cerebraton Mentor.
-Oh, aye.
The main difference
from other teaching machines is that it's able
to induce emotional changes in the subject.
JAMIE: Oh.
Our friend the Doctor is a resourceful man.
No wonder our allies fear him.
-Our allies know him?
-Oh, yes, I was ordered to destroy him.
But first I must learn the secrets
of this extraordinary machine of his.
-If you're ordered to destroy him...
-I don't take orders, Packer. I give them!
Now, I think the time has come
to stop playing games with this Doctor!
But what can we do?
If, as you say, they have got Isobel
and your young friend,
then we're entirely at their mercy.
No, no, not entirely.
There's my friend the Brigadier, remember?
-Do you think he can help us?
-Possibly.
But quickly, tell me, what is Vaughn up to?
What's he doing here?
I know no more than you do.
He's a ruthless man, without morals or principles.
His object, I'm sure, is to get complete control
of the electronics industry of the world!
I wonder.
I've a nasty feeling he's aiming
somewhat higher than that.
Doctor, quick, somebody's coming.
Don't bother, Doctor.
Allow me.
Very ingenious. A simple magnet.
I congratulate you.
Oh, how kind.
However, you must surely realise
that it's forced me to consider
other methods to make you talk.
What are you going to do?
Your friend Zoe is due to arrive here shortly.
So you have got her!
Listen, if you've harmed her in any...
You may still be adolescent enough
to make idle threats, young man,
but I can assure you, I am not.
I want your travel machine, Doctor.
Otherwise, I shall hand your friend Zoe
over to Packer.
It's a simple choice and shouldn't take you
longer than an hour to consider.
Take them away, Packer.
-All right.
Leave them to me. I'll take them.
Now, Professor,
I suggest you continue with your work.
Oh, dear. You know, Jamie,
I've always been rather scared of lifts.
Why?
I never even like to start them.
You will have to push the button for me.
-Keep your mouth shut. Do as you're told.
-Yes, Jamie. Do as you're told.
-Oh, yes...
-PACKER: Be quiet!
Packer! Mr Packer,
I obviously can't let you hurt Zoe, and so
I'll have to tell you all you want to know, now.
You mean you're willing to talk?
Yes, I'm sure that Mr Vaughn would...
-Oh, there he is now...
-Quick, Doctor.
Your knife.
Your knife. Give me your knife.
-Why? What are you going to do?
-I'm going to try and break the circuit.
What would that do?
Well, it will either stop the lift
or send us out of control.
But we're six floors up.
We'll have to take that risk.
Hold tight, here we go.
(CLATTERING)
-Why are you so gullible, Packer?
-Just wait till I get hold of them. I'll...
You'll do nothing! I want them in one piece.
-There was a 50/50 chance, you know, Jamie.
-Yes, but what good has it done us?
I mean, we're stuck here in this lift now.
No. No, it's the lift that's stuck,
not us. Look!
Hey, where does that lead to?
Out into the lift shaft, I imagine.
Quickly, on me back.
You know something? You're a clever wee chappie!
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHING)
Thank you, Jamie.
Oh, my word!
Well, that's a long way up, isn't it?
Oh, well, we better get cracking
before they realise what's happened, eh?
-Perhaps I'd better shut this.
-Aye.
(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
Hey, Doctor, I've just been thinking.
What happens if they get the lift going
before we get to the top?
-Oh, that's simple.
-What?
-We get squashed.
-Oh. What! Well, come on!
Right!
They've switched over the circuits.
The lift's working!
How splendid. Bring it up here.
Bring it up to the sixth floor.
(CLANGING)
Hey, that's not what I think it is, is it?
I'm very much afraid it is. Come on!
-We'll never make it!
-Yes, we will! Come on!
(LIFT CLATTERS)
What's happened?
It's stopped! They must be checking.
Come on, they may guess where we are
and come after us.
The engineer's certain...
The shaft terminates in the roof,
doesn't it, Packer?
-Yes, sir.
-Why didn't you think of that?
-I'll get them!
-Call me when you do, Packer.
I'll be in my office. And please don't fail this time,
there's a good fellow.
They've started it again!
Hurry, Jamie! Hurry!
-Come on, Jamie.
-Wait a minute, Doctor.
No, come on. Let's see where we are.
-Now where?
-Down there.
JAMIE: Oh, no!
Well, we can't go down the lift again, can we?
Hello. There's a fire escape. Come on.
Oh, Packer, you do disappoint me.
They must have got down the fire escape, sir.
And, of course, you didn't think
to have a guard on that!
-Well, normally...
-You're a stupid incompetent!
I want that Doctor!
Put the whole compound on alert!
Have every available guard on the job!
Find him, Packer! Find him!
(ALARM BLARING)