(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
-The Cybermen.
-Shh.
-(WHISPERING) Where do they come from?
-I don't know, Jamie,
but they're here, aren't they?
Come on, let's go back to the canoe.
What did you find out?
-Some old friends of ours are here, Zoe.
-Who?
-The Cybermen.
-Yes, I'm afraid it's true, Zoe.
-That's what you suspected, wasn't it?
-What on Earth are Cybermen?
-They're from another world. Inhuman killers.
You...You're serious?
We've met Cybermen before
and seen what they can do.
Where exactly are they and how many?
-JAMIE: At Vaughn's headquarters in London...
-Hundreds of them, probably thousands.
ZOE: So Vaughn's helping them.
So that's what those UFOs were.
But there've been hundreds of those sightings.
Aye, they must have quite an army by now.
-The thing is, where are they hiding them all?
-I don't know, Jamie.
-Captain, where's the Brigadier?
-At the Ministry of Defence.
I'll get on to him immediately
and tell him what you discovered.
No, no, Captain.
The people who went into Vaughn's Headquarters
-were different when they came out, weren't they?
-Yes.
-Do you think they're been controlled, Doctor?
-Controlled?
Yes, the Cybermen have means
of controlling people's minds.
They appear to be almost normal,
but they're not, they're controlled.
-Who is the Brigadier immediately answerable to?
-Major-General Rutlidge.
No cause for alarm?
Billy, do you realise what's happened?
They tried to shoot down one of my helicopters.
You were trespassing over their top-security area.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
If you can't trust a UNIT force, who can you trust?
There's nothing we...
-What's the matter?
-Oh. Nothing. Nothing at all.
Look, Billy, Vaughn's a powerful chap, I know that.
But surely we can at least
request a thorough investigation.
This isn't our province.
-Well, then whose province is it?
-It's no good getting angry about this.
You must see this from my point of view.
All you've given me are vague reports,
-nothing conclusive, no proof.
-No proof!
I'm sure this is all a misunderstanding.
I'll talk to the C in C of internal security myself.
But, Billy, talk isn't going to help.
I want some sort of action, and I want it now.
At least get the civil authorities to investigate.
You'll have to leave this matter with me.
Will I?
If you're thinking of going to the C in C yourself,
I shouldn't bother, you'll be wasting your time.
So you're going to do nothing?
-What sort of hold has Vaughn got on you?
-Vaughn? I...
Brigadier, your UNIT force will take no precipitous
action without top-priority permission.
-That is an order.
-I see, sir.
Well, you can override my authority
but not that of UNIT Central Command.
I'm sending a full report to them in Geneva.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Have Gregory work
with Professor Watkins on the machine.
Yes, Mr Vaughn.
No, wait.
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
-VAUGHN: What is it, Rutlidge?
-The UNIT group.
-Well?
-There'll be trouble. I can't stop it.
-Why not? You have authority to.
-I have no authority outside this country.
A report is being made to UNIT Central Control.
They're bound to investigate and take action.
DOCTOR: You see,
a network of tunnels underneath London.
BRIGADIER: And that's where you think
they might be?
Yes.
And look. There's a main flood-relief sewer
running right underneath the warehouse.
Yes, but if there's water in the sewers,
wouldn't that affect them?
Oh, no, no. Besides, many of these tunnels are dry
and only flood during heavy rainfall.
What do we do? Pray for a cloudburst?
Miss Watkins, this could be very serious.
I'm sorry, but, well,
it's a pretty fantastic story to swallow.
Yes, but so was the attack from the Yeti,
but nevertheless it happened.
With all due respect, sir, she's right.
No one believed in the Yetis until they saw them.
If you go to Central Command with this story,
they'll think you're mad.
Yes. Yes, Jimmy, you're right.
'Course, what we really need is
some sort of evidence, some proof.
It might be better at the moment
to find out what form this attack's going to take.
-Jamie...
-What?
That transistor radio that Vaughn gave you.
Have you still got it?
Aye, here.
-Brigadier, have you any IE equipment here?
-Um, Jimmy, have we?
Yes, we have, sir. A computer
and various radio and radar components.
-May I see them, please?
-Certainly. Jimmy, would you...
-I'll show you, Doctor, it's this way.
-DOCTOR: Thank you.
-Ah, there you are, Packer. Everything going well?
-Yes, Mr Vaughn.
Good. Time for our little experiment.
-Mr Vaughn, I don't think you should...
-We must try the machine, Gregory.
But it's dangerous.
It would be even more dangerous
if we didn't try it.
We must be sure we have
an effective weapon against the Cybermen.
-You're going to try it on one of them?
-Why not?
Revive it.
Uh, just enough to bring it out of its cocoon.
MAN: Yes, sir.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Hold it there.
Now, Gregory, connect the Professor's machine.
-Mr Vaughn, please...
-Connect it!
-What emotion shall I induce?
-Fear!
Let's see how the Cybermen will react to fear.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Increase the power.
(DISTORTED HUMMING)
VAUGHN: More power!
GREGORY: That's all there is!
(GUN FIRING)
VAUGHN: Quick!
I told you, the machine isn't ready yet.
-It's following the others into the sewers.
-Let it go.
It's gone mad. It could've killed us all.
Possibly, but I think we proved
that the Professor's machine can be effective.
Get him to work on it, Gregory.
I want twice as much power
and I want directional control.
Yeah, but what about that one?
-You can't let it roam down there alone!
-Why not?
-Well, it'll kill anything that gets in its way.
-Good.
Anyone fool enough to be down
those sewers deserves to die.
This is rather like looking for
the proverbial needle in the proverbial...
-Just a minute...
-Found something?
I don't know. Wait a minute.
Yes. Yes, I'm almost sure
that this is the same sort of circuit
that was in Jamie's radio.
-But what does it do?
-I've no idea.
But it's certainly not part of that equipment.
Have a look.
But why put in a circuit if it doesn't do anything?
Oh, it does something, all right.
The question is, what?
COMMUNICATOR: One hour before invasion,
the Cyber-transmitter units will be
launched into orbit around Earth.
The effect will be immediate?
Yes, transmissions will penetrate all areas.
And if it doesn't work?
Humans cannot resist Cyber-control.
Our forces will penetrate all areas
and select suitable humans
for cybernetic conversion.
-Found anything?
-No. I'm afraid not.
What I really need is laboratory facilities.
I'm sure that this micromonolithic circuit
is something to do
with the Cybermen's invasion plan.
Perhaps we can find a lab for you to work in.
Oh, no, that's no problem. I can go up to London
and use Professor Watkins's laboratory
at Travers's house.