-GUARD: You two! Over here!
Get those two girls
over to the main administration building! Move!
-Zoe and Isobel.
-Wait. We'll follow in a few moments.
Take them inside. Central block, tenth floor.
(ROTORS WHIRRING)
Could be the Brigadier's lot. Call them up for help.
No, no, not yet. We've got to rescue the girls first.
Tenth floor, central block. Come on.
There's a lot of unusual activity, sir.
Guards everywhere.
It looks like some sort of emergency.
BRIGADIER: Any sign of the Doctor and the boy?
No, sir. None at all.
Right,Jimmy. Get out of the area and stand by.
Right, sir. Will do.
-All units, please, Sergeant.
-Yes, sir.
Go ahead, sir.
This is the Brigadier. All units, stand by.
Full penetration of red sector imminent.
Hey, Zoe.
Zoe, look!
-Doctor!
-Jamie!
Yes, Doctor, come in.
Brigadier, I think we shall require
a little assistance in a few moments.
Are you in trouble?
No, but we shall need help.
You have a helicopter in the area?
Yes.
I wonder, have they a rope ladder on board?
Yes, I'm pretty sure they have. Where are you?
We're just going up to the roof
of the main building.
That is the central block on the north side.
That should give your helicopter cover
should there be any ground fire.
-Have you got that?
-Yes, I've got that.
Over and out.
You were lucky, dead lucky.
He said it would be
a simple rescue operation. Simple.
But what about my uncle?
-They've still got him prisoner.
-Don't worry, Miss Watkins.
As soon as we return to base,
I'm going to raise hell and get some action.
You think they'll listen to you now?
No one, not even Tobias Vaughn, can go as far
as trying to shoot down one of my helicopters.
Oh, I wish I'd had my camera.
I could have got a fortune for those pictures.
Yes, it was a pity.
That would have clinched it
as far as the Ministry are concerned, sir.
Don't worry, Jimmy.
Billy Rutlidge will have to take some action now.
Why am I being taken back to London?
What about my niece? What's happened to Isobel?
I tell you, she's perfectly safe.
Well, I want to see her!
So you shall.
When you've finished working on your machine.
Do as I ask and you shall both go free.
You don't even expect me to believe you, do you?
Well, you've very little choice.
Now, we're going back to London.
There you will work on your machine
to my specifications.
You will have 24 hours to complete it.
Only if you haven't finished your work by that time
would you have cause to worry about your niece.
-BRIGADIER: Mean anything to you, Doctor?
-Possibly.
How long ago were these objects first sighted?
Reports have been drifting in
for well over a year now.
We sent up fighter planes to investigate,
but nothing ever came of it.
The odd thing about these sightings
is that they usually seem to disappear
somewhere over southeast England.
But isn't that where all those factories
and laboratories of Vaughn's are?
Exactly.
Well, obviously they bring these things,
whatever they are, up from the factory
in the country to the London premises.
That's where we're going to find the answer.
You mean go back to Vaughn's place?
I don't think that's wise, Doctor.
You've been lucky so far.
Aye, if you think I'm going back inside there...
Jamie, we have to find what is inside these crates.
Brigadier, have you got a map,
including the London premises?
-Yes, yes, I think so. Sergeant Walters!
-Sir?
-Jamie, I'm afraid I was right!
-Eh?