(DOOR BUZZING)
Packer.
Yes, sir.
-Have you discovered where the Professor is?
-Yes, Mr Vaughn.
Go and collect him.
I want work started on the production
of the machines immediately.
Go and recapture Watkins.
Don't let anything or anyone stop you.
-Oh, thanks!
-Thank goodness you made it.
-Any trouble?
-Hundreds of Cybermen about, sir.
The sooner we get out of here, the better.
Everybody ready?
ALL: Yes!
ISOBEL: Yes, we're ready, we're coming.
Listen!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
We'd better get out of here,
out of the back way as quickly as possible.
-Right!
-Come on, move, everybody. Quickly!
Out of the back door. Hurry it up.
Come on, Jamie. Professor, all right? Good.
(GUN FIRING)
-Yes, Jimmy, where are you?
-TURNER: In bother, sir. We need help.
-Can you give us a chopper?
-Yes.
-Can you make sector five?
-We can try, sir.
Right, I'll get the chopper there. Out.
How could they escape the Cyber-control?
It's that Doctor, something to do with him.
You should've got rid of him
when you had the chance.
Shut up, Packer!
I must go on with the invasion.
But what about the Professor?
Without him, we can't make any more machines.
Without machines, we can't control the Cybermen.
Let me worry about that.
For the moment,
I have the Cybermen exactly where I want them.
Yeah, but for how long?
Now, can you honestly say
that everything's going according to plan?
That nothing's been overlooked? Well, can you?
Just obey my orders!
Now, get in touch with the compound
and have the radio beam projected.
The invasion fleet must be brought in.
Now, Doctor, we must deal with
this invasion you say is coming.
Yes, at least we know where they'll land.
They'll home in on Vaughn's radio signal.
Would we be able to pick them off
with anti-missile missiles?
Yes, that's a good idea. We might have a try.
Right. There's a base near Henlow Downs.
Er, just a minute.
-Sergeant Walters?
-Oh, Zoe, sit down, dear. It's a bit bumpy.
-Now, how's Jamie's leg?
-Oh, it's just a slight flesh wound.
But he's furious, because the Army doctor
won't let him walk on it.
Well, he would be, wouldn't he?
How's the Professor?
Oh, he'll be all right. Isobel's with him.
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
-Anything I can do, Doctor?
-Well, I...
I suggest that you...you go with the Brigadier.
As much as I detest computers, I...
I think that remarkable brain of yours
will come in very handy.
Right. What are you going to do?
I think it's about time I had a serious talk
with our Mr Vaughn.
What, go back?
But he'd kill you as soon as look at you.
No, we need time
if we're going to stop this attack,
and I think I can get us that time.
No, this is madness.
I can't afford to let you take that risk.
You can't afford not to, Brigadier.
If you're going to attack
the Cybermen with missiles,
they're going to retaliate,
and we want to know how and with what.
But how can you find that out?
I'll leave my radio on and then you'll hear
every word that passes between me and Vaughn.
But you'll never get near the place.
The whole area will be crawling with Cybermen.
Oh, there's one place
where there'll be no Cybermen.
-Where's that?
-In the sewers.
UNIT Control. This is the Doctor.
-Is Brigadier there, please?
-WALTERS: Hold on a moment, sir, I'll get him.
(STATIC BUZZING)
BRIGADIER: Yes, Doctor, go ahead.
Er, Brigadier, I've just entered the sewers.
I'm going to make my way
to Vaughn's headquarters.
I'll give you a call when I get there.
Right. We'll have a chopper in the area
in case you get in trouble.
Thank you.
(WATER DRIPPING)
And all the main communication centres
are now manned by our forces?
Yes, but, um...
What? But what, Packer?
Well, we can't make a complete takeover
without a full invasion force.
They'll arrive, Packer, they'll arrive.
And when they do,
there won't be one city in the entire world
that we don't control.
Think of it, Packer, the entire world!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
It's the security alarm,
the UNIT forces must have...
Packer.
There you are.
I hope I haven't called
at an inconvenient moment, but I...
I would rather like a word with you.
Clever of you to avoid our Cyber-control beam.
Oh, it was nothing.
I'll...I'll come up, I know the way.
He must be out of his mind!
Far from it, Packer.
Have the guards search the building,
just in case he's brought any friends with him.
Tell the raiding party to stand by.
-Yes, sir.
-DOCTOR: (WHISPERING) Ah, Brigadier. Brigadier.
-Yes, Doctor, go ahead.
-I am just about to enter the lion's den.
I will leave the radio on as of now.
-Right. Good luck.
-Thank you.
Keep that channel open
and get the whole thing on tape.
-Yes, sir.
-If he yells for help while I'm away,
-send in everything we've got to get him out.
-Right.
VAUGHN: Ah, Doctor,
what an unexpected pleasure.
Do come in.
And you trust them?
Doctor, I've worked with the Cybermen
for five years, preparing this invasion.
I know them, the way they think,
the single-mindedness of their purpose.
Then you must know what ruthless
and inhuman killers they are.
Of course.
But then, they are my allies, not my enemies.
Do you really think they'll honour
any bargain that you make with them?
Oh, I've planned this whole operation
in great detail, allowing for every possible factor.
It was I who contacted them in deep space,
provided the means by which
they travelled to Earth.
And masterminded the whole operation
from A to Z.
(SCOFFS)
They have merely provided their advanced
scientific skills, their might and strength.
And what do they get out of all this?
What they want and what they're going to get
are two entirely different things.
Oh, you're a fool, Vaughn.
When they get here, they'll take over.
All Cybermen here are conditioned
to obey my orders.
They are directly under my command.
Oh, possibly.
But what about the others, out there in space?
Are they conditioned to obey your commands?
If they're not, I'll destroy them.
-With the Professor's machine?
-Yes.
With one machine?
I'll have more made.
But you'll have to have
the Professor's help to do that, won't you?
We've got the Professor.
They'll be under my command,
exactly like the others.
But you can't be sure of that, can you?
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Well, we can't get them all.
Let's take as many as we can.
-Lift off the activation check.
-Coordinate programme running, sir.
-Link programme to telemeter guidance.
-PETERS: Roger.
Major, I think we stand a good chance of getting
at least 90 percent of them.
-How? We haven't got enough missiles.
-Oh, please, Major.
Just knocking out half a dozen of them will do
very little good at all.
Let's try for them all.
Look, miss, I know my business and
I'm telling you we haven't got enough missiles.
Yes, you have.
These things are coming in in a formation pattern.
Now if you set your missiles carefully,
you can set up a chain reaction of explosions.
No, there isn't time to compute
all the relevant information.
-They'd be on top of us by then.
-Give me 30 seconds.
Give her what she asks, Major. 30 seconds.
-But, sir, this is ridiculous!
-Just 30 seconds.
-Hold for 30 seconds!
-Sir, that doesn't give us much time.
All right, Sergeant, I know.
Countdown to begin at T minus 45 seconds.
Here. Feed this into your computer.
Do as she says. Now. I'll take over.
Sir.
-You'd better be right.
-I am.
T minus 45 seconds from...now.
(WHIRRING)
Once the Cybermen take over,
they'll destroy the Earth as we know it!
You're just playing for time, aren't you?
I'm trying to stop you
from destroying the human race!
Your UNIT friends...
You presumably managed to protect them
from the Cyber-control as well?
What are they planning?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Packer?
Yes, sir.
-Is the radio beam in the compound aligned yet?
-Yes, sir, it's all ready.
Good. Then link the beam to the invasion fleet.
Right, Mr Vaughn.
Now whatever it is
your UNIT friends are trying to do...
it's too late.
COMMUNICATOR: The first transporter fleet
is being attacked and destroyed.
-You have betrayed us.
-No!
The failure of this mission is due to you.
We will now take over the invasion.
No! Wait! Give me time!
I can stop this opposition!
There is no more time.
We no longer need you.
The Cyber-Megatron bomb will be delivered.
We must destroy life on Earth completely.
Every living being.