Oh, yes, it could be 20th century.
What's the matter with the Tardis, Doctor?
It keeps going wrong all the time.
It merely needs an overhaul, Jamie,
just like any piece of machinery.
We might try and look up our old
friend Professor Travers in London.
-He might be able to help us, hmm?
-Yeah. Aye.
Always supposing he's not a baby or a schoolboy!
Now come along!
Let's just collect this circuit
There.
Yes. It's all right.
It's just a fault in the visual stabiliser circuit.
It's, uh... We'd better take that, too.
-Er... Can you give us a lift to London?
-Yes, I suppose so.
DOCTOR: In you get.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
DOCTOR: Here we are.
Right.
-Well, that's odd! It says ''Watkins''.
-JAMIE: Must have the wrong house.
Well, the telephone directory definitely said
number 1 8.
We'll ask.
(DOORBELL RINGING INCESSANTLY)
If you don't mind, I'm trying to work!
Oh. I'm sorry, miss, but we wondered
whether you could help us.
We wondered if...
Oh, look, now the stupid thing's
gone and jammed!
Oh, dear, perhaps I could help you.
Well, do you know anything about cameras?
Yes, a little. I see...
Now I had it on automatic shutter.
Taking photos of yourself?
Yes, then you interrupted me
and the stupid thing jammed!
Have you come to see my uncle? He's not here.
But who are you?
Friends of his? Fellow nuts?
Please let me answer one question at a time.
Hey, you be careful with that thing.
It cost me a fortune.
It's all right. It's a very simple mechanism.
-Who is your uncle?
-Professor Watkins.
Oh.
Then Professor Travers doesn't live here?
Well, he did. He left about a month ago.
Gone to America for a year with his daughter.
Oh, that's just great!
My uncle worked at the Cavendish lab.
He wanted to do some work so Professor Travers
said he could use his daughter's lab here.
And I moved in because I got kicked
out of my studio last week.
What field of science is your uncle in?
Oh, I don't know,
he's in applied physics or something.
Always messing around with computers
and things. Complete nut.
Well, that is fortunate.
Perhaps he might be able to help us.
-Is he at home?
-No.
-Well, where is he?
-Well, how do I know? I'm not his keeper.
-Hey, have you fixed it?
-Oh, yes, that's all right.
-That's really great, thanks!
-Miss...
Hey!
That's a jolly outfit.
Would you mind posing for me?
-What?
-Look. Just stand there.
-Miss!
-Isobel.
Yeah, okay. Now just stand here.
Now get... Head over the shoulder.
Have you any idea when your uncle
is going to be back?
No, he left about a week ago.
I haven't seen him since.
A week?
Yeah, he was prattling on about some
new invention, or something or other,
and having the chance to develop it.
Now... Not you.
-Oh.
-ISOBEL: Okay. Now.
Can't you get in touch with him?
No, I tried.
I wanted to borrow a couple of quid off
him in a hurry,
but, well, they said
he wasn't available for phone calls.
They! Now... Now who is ''they''?
Just get that, will you? I don't know.
International Electric, something or other.
International Electromatics?
Yes, probably.
You mean your uncle has gone to
work for these people?
-Mmm-hmm.
-Well, surely we can get in touch with him.
Well, you can try telephoning,
but I doubt if you'll get any joy.
Oh, phone's in the hall and
the number's scribbled on the wall.
Thank you.
Hey. Don't go.
I don't often get the chance of
photographing a real model.
Oh, all right.
Come on. Let's get you fixed up with some gear!
WOMAN: International Electromatic Company.
State your business.
I would like, please,
to speak with Professor Watkins.
One moment.
-Party not available.
-Oh, yes. You see, but this is very important.
Party not available.
-Yes, but I must speak with him.
-Party not available.
-But this is an automatic answering device!
Ah, shut up, you stupid machine!
-So, now what?
-There's only one thing for it!
We'll have to go there ourselves.
Okay, that's fabulous, just keep it like that.
Great. Any luck?
No, it was a stupid simple-minded
computer answering service.
Well, what do we do now?
Well, Jamie and I are going to this place.
Come on, Zoe.
Oh, no, thanks. I think I'll stay here.
It's great fun.
You look like a chicken with all those feathers on!
Well, come on, Jamie. Oh, the address?
-Oh, that's scribbled on the wall, too.
-DOCTOR: Oh, thank you.
Do you not write anything down on paper at all?
Well, I'd only lose it if I did.
Writing on a wall is much safer.
You can't lose a wall, can you?
No.
HQ are checking now. Where are they?
Gone round the back, down the side alley.
It's a dead end, isn't it?
So they've got to come out this way!
If they come out.
Come and sit down, gentlemen.
DOCTOR: Thank you.
-You can go, Packer.
-Yes, sir.
I must apologise for Packer's crude
devotion to duty.
But your method of entry into my building
was rather...unconventional, wasn't it?
-Aye, well, there was no need for all that...
-Jamie!
...gas and stuff.
I think perhaps it is we
who should be apologising to you, Mr...
Vaughn. Tobias Vaughn.
I'm the Managing Director
of International Electromatics.
Your business must be very pressing
to force you to such extremes.
Yes, it is.
-Concerning Professor Watkins?
-How did you know?
My computer. It reported directly to me.
Oh, I see.
You've gone to a lot of trouble for nothing,
you know.
The Professor's working on an experiment
and refuses to see anyone.
Ah, well. We only want to talk to him, you see.
Perhaps I can help.
No, I don't think so, thank you very much.
Oh, come on, Doctor,
it's only a couple of electronic circuits.
(GRUNTING)
Circuits? Electronic circuits?
My technicians are the best in the world.
I'm sure they'd be able to assist you.
-Show me the circuits.
-Well, I...
Please, I'd like to help.
As you say, rather complex.
-However, I'm sure we'll be able to help you.
-Yes. You see...
I'll have them sent to my workshops immediately.
-Oh, how very kind.
-Not at all.
Professor Watkins is a valued colleague.
Any friend of his is... Oh.
-Have you got one of these, young man?
-No, what is it?
Surely you've seen them about.
They're disposable transistor radios.
One of our latest products. Most popular.
We've sold 1 0 million in this country alone. Here.
Compensation for the treatment
you received from the worthy Packer.
Thank you. How does it work?
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Yes, that's how you turn it off, Jamie.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm afraid I have an urgent appointment.
Yes, of course. Come along, Jamie.
Packer will meet you
and show you the way out, Mr...
-Doctor. Goodbye.
-Goodbye, Doctor.
Goodbye, Mr Vaughn, and thank you for the radio.
Not at all.
-Packer?
-Yes, Mr Vaughn?
Show our visitors off the premises, will you?
Very good, sir.
PACKER: The next time,
read the notice on the door.
JAMIE: Oh, don't tell me you can read as well.
What else do you do?
Jamie!
That fellow's not what he seems.
That big idiot? Oh, don't worry. I'll soon sort...
No, no, no. I mean Vaughn.
Oh, and he's got a forked tail and wee horns.
Oh, I'm not joking, Jamie.
Underneath all that charm,
there was something odd.
Sinister. Almost inhuman.
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)