You can't do this! I won't let you!
You cannot stop us.
No one can.
Now you're beginning to understand
the Cybermen, Vaughn.
You can't make bargains with them!
I won't let them take over, I won't!
You think you're indestructible?
Well, I can destroy all of you!
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Packer! Packer! Where are you?
Vaughn, what have you done to us? What have you done?
(HUMMING)
(SCREAMING)
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Vaughn!
Where is the transmitter for the radio beam?
We can't fight them.
They're too powerful, too many of them.
Oh, don't be a fool, man. Where do we turn it off?
-At the compound, but they'll be there.
-Right. We must stop them.
Brigadier, Brigadier, this is the Doctor.
Can you still hear me?
Yes, Doctor, we heard everything. What do we do?
There are only two possibilities.
We must either cut off the transmitter
of the radio beam at the compound
or destroy the Cyberman spaceship.
How much time do we have?
Oh, I've no idea. It could be minutes or hours.
Depends how long it takes them
to prepare this bomb of theirs.
Well, destroying the spaceship
is going to take time.
Then there's only one chance. The radio beam.
Er, wait. Vaughn.
Now, Vaughn, will you help us?
We must try to get to the controls
of the radio beam.
We'll never do it in time unless you help us!
You still think you have a chance?
-Yes, if you'll help us!
-Help you? Why should I?
Well, to save us! To save yourself!
And if I survive, what future have I got?
What will the world do with me?
Oh, for heaven's sake,
stop thinking about yourself!
Think of the millions of people on Earth
who are about to die!
Appealing to my better nature.
No.
If I help you, it'll be because I hate them.
The Cybermen, my ''allies''.
You think I'm mad,
that all I want is power for its own sake.
No, I have to have power.
The world is weak, vulnerable,
a mess of uncoordinated and impossible ideals.
It needs a strong man, a single mind.
-A leader.
-Vaughn, will you listen?
Right.
I'll help you to destroy them because I hate them.
They... destroyed my dream.
What are you doing?
We must destroy them!
We want to get to
the radio transmitter control room!
The Cybermen don't know we're here yet.
Let's keep that element of surprise.
Come on, we'll try down here.
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
-Now they know we're here.
-Right.
Up there. We'll go over the roofs.
VAUGHN: That's it.
(PANTING) That's where we've got to get to.
Down there.
Look out!
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
(CLATTERING)
Look out!
Come on!
-Is this the only way down?
-Yes.
Come on, then.
Cybermen! Take cover!
They've got a main control switch
for the radio beam.
There doesn't seem to be
any Cybermen about at all. That's odd.
Well, let's not waste time, then.
Look behind you!
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
(SCREAMING)
Whoa!
(SHOUTING)
Doctor, get down! Right, bazooka!
-You all right, Doctor?
-What?
Yes, yes, it's there, in that building.
The radio transmitter control,
you've got to destroy it!
Leave it to us. Forward!
Just a second.
Oh, but I...
That's it, that's better. Sit still.
(GUN FIRING)
(SHOUTING)
BRIGADIER: Grenades!
Bazooka!
That was just a dozen of them.
I'd hate to have to meet a hundred.
Forward!
There we are, all done and ready to go.
(LAUGHING) Bye-bye.
-Bye-bye!
-Bye.
A police box?
I don't believe it!
(WHOOSHING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)