You're still worried about your two friends,
aren't you?
Packer.
Yes, Mr Vaughn?
Packer, those two uninvited guests
we had this morning,
- I assume they were photographed?
- Yes, sir.
Have some prints taken and sent up to me.
-Well, what do we do now, Doctor?
-Accept the situation, Jamie.
Nothing else we can do.
You're still worried about
your two friends, aren't you? Why?
Oh, I don't know.
I've just got this feeling
that something's happened to them.
Why on earth should it have?
No reason at all, really.
It's not a logical conclusion, just intuition.
Well, I'll tell you what we'll do, then.
We'll go right out after them, okay?
Oh, yes, please.
But we'd better leave a note for them,
just in case they come back when we're not here.
Would you mind telling us what all this is about?
You'll find out, sir.
Sir?
-All right, Benton, thank you.
-Sir.
-NAAFI break, sir?
-Very well.
How nice to see you again, Doctor.
It's Colonel Lethbridge-Stewart!
Ah, Brigadier now. I've gone up in the world.
Of course, the Yetis. We met you in the...
That's right, McCrimmon, in the Underground.
Must be four years ago now.
That long. It only seems like
a couple of weeks ago, doesn't it?
I've told you over and over again, Jamie.
Time is relative.
Are you still making a nonsense of it, Doctor,
in your... What was it called?
-Tardis?
-Yes, we're still travelling. Yes.
Yes, Mr Travers told me all about it.
It's, um... Well, it's...
To say the least, an unbelievable machine.
DOCTOR: Any more unbelievable
than the Yetis, hmm?
No, true. I'm not quite so much of a sceptic
as I was since that little escapade.
But what's all this, and why all the
cloak and dagger stuff to bring us here?
Yes, I'm sorry about that, but my chaps have to be
a bit melodramatic in their methods.
But I'll explain. Oh, do sit down.
-Thank you.
-How nice.
(WHIRRING)
Has the information been considered?
COMMUNICATOR: The images of the two humans
have been analysed and registered.
They are known and are hostile.
Hostile? How can that be?
Have you been on Earth before?
No, they have been recognised
They are dangerous and must be destroyed.
Yes, well, since the Yeti do, I've been in charge
of an independent intelligence group
that we call UNIT,
that's United Nations Intelligence Taskforce.
You mean you're like a... A world secret police?
Not quite. We don't actually arrest people,
we just investigate them.
What about us? I mean, you arrested us.
Not really.
You see, my men were keeping a watch on
the International Electromatic Headquarters
when you two showed up.
I've been keeping a check
on everyone going in that building.
Your photographs were transmitted to
this Headquarters and I recognised you.
Well, what's so odd about
people going into the building?
Oh, nothing odd about them going in.
The problem is some of them haven't come out.
BRIGADIER: This is Gordon Jones,
lecturer in physics, Churchill College, Cambridge.
Next one's a chap I knew at Sandhurst,
old Billy Rutlidge.
He's got himself a very cushy number
at the Ministry of Defence.
And all these people went into the building,
the IE building, and didn't come out.
No, no, most of them came out again,
but there was something
definitely odd about them when they did.
Odd?
Ah, yes, Miss Watkins.
You're concerned about your uncle, aren't you?
I'd like to know where he is, yes.
He's perfectly well, I assure you,
although a little, uh...
uncooperative at the moment.
Your visit here is most opportune.
I think that you can be very useful to me.
Me? But... But how?
Your uncle needs to be ''persuaded''
to continue his work for me.
But I can't do anything about that.
No.
But I can. Now...
Packer, I'd like you to take care
of these two young ladies, please.
Take them!
(GIRLS PROTESTING)
Um, Brigadier, tell me more about this
International Electromatics setup.
Well, there isn't much to tell.
The head of the group
is a man named Tobias Vaughn.
Oh, yes, we've met him. A nice man.
He gave me this.
Jamie.
-Oh, yes, that's just the small stuff.
-Put it away.
They control practically
all of the major computer lines.
They made their real breakthrough in
micromonolithic circuit designing.
Undercutting practically everyone else
on the market.
But what's your interest in this?
Well, I knew a little about Vaughn
before his sudden success.
I put out a routine check on him and
we came up with one or two things of interest.
Like the disappearance of Professor Watkins.
-Yes.
-Ah, see.
I... I don't suppose you have any authority
to search the building, have you?
No, Vaughn's too powerful,
he's got too many top people on his side.
You see, Doctor, I daren't make a move
against him unless I have good reason to do so.
Well, it looks to me,
if Jamie and I want to find the Professor,
we'll have to do it in our own way.
That's about the sum of it.
However, should you find yourself
in any difficulty...
Sergeant Walters!
-Yes, sir?
-Got a TM-45 handy?
Yes, sir. Right here.
-Is that a tank?
-Oh, no, no.
My units are on constant alert,
so should you find yourselves in any trouble,
you can just give us a call.
-Jolly good!
-Here you are, sir.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Now, this is a small transceiver,
range of about fifty miles on a set frequency.
-Just press this button and ask for me.
-Oh, yes, that's splendid! Yes.
This should come in very handy.
Call me anytime. I'm usually available.
No. They must have gone out.
Zoe?
Isobel?
Probably gone for a walk.
Look, Jamie, sandwiches. I'm hungry.
-Want one?
-Thank you.
You know, Doctor, that chap Mr Vaughn
doesn't seem such a bad man.
(TURNS RADIO ON)
Oh, Jamie!
How can I think when you've got that thing on?
Hey!
All right, all right.
-Don't break it.
-All right!
I just want to have a look at it, that's all.
Oh, yes.
-It's an interesting little piece...
-What?
Well, well, well.
What have we here?
What do you mean, ''What have we here?''
There's a micromonolithic circuit
in the back plate of this radio.
Well, what's that?
It's a very complex circuit in miniature.
What's so odd about that, then?
It has nothing to do with the radio,
as far as I can see.
-Oh, Doctor, just put it back together again!
-All right.
I don't suppose Zoe would have left a note,
do you?
No, I can't see anything.
Well, you might at least help me look for it.
I suggest we try the wall.
Eh?
Isobel never writes anything on paper.
-You can't lose a wall, remember?
-Oh.
Ah! ''Tired of waiting.
''Gone to IE offices to look for you.
Zoe and Isobel.''
Jamie! We better go after them.