(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
-You wish for my answer, Doctor?
-I do.
Then here it is.
SARAH: No!
The female, too.
It seems I am doubly fortunate.
-Get up. Get back to work!
-DOCTOR: Linx.
Can't you see that your prisoners
are physically exhausted?
They've had no sleep
and nothing to eat for days.
-They can still work!
-Not for much longer.
LINX: I owe these primitives nothing.
My only concern is to rejoin
our glorious struggle for freedom.
DOCTOR: That's such an old tune.
Don't you know there's no such thing
as the super race?
Your Time Lord philosophy
is egalitarian twaddle.
It is a weakness.
Every species
has its own weakness, Linx.
For instance, you can only be stunned
by a blow on the probic vent,
that small hole
at the back of your neck.
LINX: In our case, Doctor,
it is a strength,
because it means we must
always face our enemies.
Now, to return to the question
of your demise.
I think it would be better
if you witnessed first the destruction
of your female companion.
Well done, Rubeish.
-Doctor, are you all right?
-Yes.
Yes. The blast was too brief.
But I wouldn't have been
in a few moments.
-Thank you very much, Sarah.
-Oh, pleasure.
Hadn't I better be getting on
with the rest of your plan?
-Yes. All right, but be careful.
-You, too, Doctor.
Right. Well, if we can secure
our friend here,
we can get on with the job of restoring
his wretched victims.
Will this help?
Rubeish, you're invaluable,
my dear chap.
-Bloodaxe.
-Captain.
Fetch me Linx.
Fetch me that scabby-faced stoat
from his burrow.
At once, Captain.
Well, that should hold him for a while,
even on this planet.
Why this planet?
Well, in his own environment,
he weighs several tons.
Fortunately, his muscles
have been designed for load bearing
-rather than leverage.
-Fascinating.
I'd always assumed that creatures
from a high-density planet
would have developed
a pressure-balanced physiology.
For example, if you take
certain types of seaweed...
BLOODAXE: Linx! Linx!
-Linx?
-DOCTOR: Who speaks?
Captain Irongron commands your presence.
Tell him I'm busy.
Well, come soon
or we come and fetch you.
Who is Irongron? Is he a nice chap?
Well, I wouldn't recommend him
for the Royal Society.
All right, Rubeish, you know how
to bring these people round?
-Yes. A simple, repetitive optical...
-Yes, quite so.
-I'll leave you to get on with it.
-What do you propose to do?
I was going to preset
this osmic projector.
Send these people back
to their own time.
But now I have to find a way
of stalling Irongron.
The robot! Yes, of course.
That ought to give him
something to think about.
Thief!
You common scullion, stand aside!
How dare you obstruct me?
I shall have you flogged.
Oh, so, a lady, are you?
-A lady dressed as a serving wench?
-I'm hungry.
Please let me go. I've tasted neither
bread nor meat for nearly a month.
No, nor done no work for longer
by the look of you.
All right, my girl,
I'll give you bread and cheese,
but you'll have to earn it.
Who are you?
DOCTOR: I am a gift to Captain Irongron
from the one who made me,
my master, Commander Linx.
It is indeed the robot, Bloodaxe,
though somewhat different in shape.
And I remember, Linx promised
to make me a second iron man,
one that would obey my voice.
But why has Linx sent you?
Why has he not himself
obeyed my summons?
My master toils in his workshop
to make you more fighting robots.
-He sent me as proof of his goodwill.
-What?
-Now I must return.
-Hold.
I would see something
of the mettle of this gift.
-Can you fight, iron man?
-That is my purpose.
Then fight me.
I was programmed to fight for you,
not against you.
-Cease thy gabble and fight.
-You will damage my circuits.
Fight, iron man,
or you'll return to Linx in as
many pieces as did your brother.
Hold.
It's truly a marvel, Captain.
Never have I seen a finer swordsman.
Ah, 'tis great sport this, Bloodaxe.
Draw your sword and join me.
We'll try this creature's strength
to the utmost.
Get on!
(SWORDS CLASHING)
What's that?
Oh, fighting again in the great hall,
I'll warrant.
Men were ever like children,
fond of noise and brawling.
Get about your work, girl.
Hold!
Hold, I say!
We must slow this
iron man's speed a little.
Stick me some crossbow bolts
in the creature.
We'll see if it fights as well with
a crossbow bolt or two in its gizzard.
And if that fails,
we'll lop off its head
and try again then.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Isn't that a bit unsporting, old man?
I mean, sitting ducks and all that.
This iron man talks like
some Norman ninny.
-Lift up your visor.
-I cannot reveal my face, Irongron.
Why?
Because if I did,
it might give you a seizure.
-The wizard!
-Well, I did warn you, didn't I?
Seize him!
No.
The sword is too quick and clean
a death for you.
Well, since you are a wizard,
then by wizardry shall you die.
Not so much of that oatmeal, girl. It's
only pikemen we're feeding, not horses.
Hey, watch that pot.
If you burn Lord Irongron's stew,
he'll have your liver cut out.
-Is all this for Irongron?
-Him and his chamber guard.
-How many's that?
-Half a dozen.
-You're full of questions, girl.
-Don't the guards on the gate get stew?
What? Meat for those common creatures?
I should say not.
They'll have oatmeal,
the same as the rest of us,
and lusty enough they are on that.
So you watch yourself
if ever you take out that skillet.
I'm not afraid of men.
They don't own the world.
Why should women always
have to cook and carry for them?
-What else should we do?
-Stand up for ourselves.
Tell the men you're tired
of working for them like slaves.
-We are slaves.
-Then you should set yourselves free.
-Oh, and how should we do that?
-Don't you want to be free?
Women will never be free
while there are men in the world, girl.
-We have our place.
-What subservient poppycock.
-You're still living in the Middle Ages.
-Eh?
-Nothing.
-You're young and foolish, girl.
And I warn you,
keep those thoughts to yourself
or you'll not live long enough
to grow wiser.
I must tell them their food
will soon be ready.
Look at that great spider!
(SCREAMS)
♪ Oh, see me dance the polka
Oh, see me... ♪
(RUBEISH HUMMING)
Ah, that's it.
Come on. Stand up, my dear chap.
Come on.
Come on. That's it.
Now listen, all of you.
You've been kidnapped,
but you're about to be rescued, I hope.
There's a machine here
that'll send you home again.
Unfortunately,
I don't know how to work it,
and the chap who does has vanished.
But I expect he'll pop up again.
He usually does.
But the important thing is,
until then, you must carry on working
as if you were still hypnotised.
-Can I ask...
-Morrison, don't start asking
a lot of awkward questions.
I assure you, I don't know the answers
-any more than you do.
-IRONGRON: Linx!
Back to work, everyone.
Someone's coming.
Linx, you dog!
Where are you hiding?
Oh, there you are, you dragon-eyed toad.
-Who put these bonds on you?
-The Doctor.
I was struck from behind.
-Where is he?
-The Doctor is dying.
What method have you chosen
to destroy him?
Thank you, sir,
for your charm and old world courtesy.
May I ask the purpose
of this tomfoolery?
If you're going to have me shot,
why don't you get on with it?
I would not have your death
be in vain, good sorcerer.
I intend that it shall be
of some use to me.
Nothing that I do will be
of use to you, Irongron.
Oh, nay, Doctor, but you're wrong.
These knaves of mine lack practice
with their star weapons.
A living target will give them a chance
to better their aim
before tomorrow's battle.
You, shoot!
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
These knaves of mine aim so ill, Doctor,
that you are mayhap safer
to stand still.
You, shoot!
The aim improves, Doctor. Be patient.
We shall hit the target
all in good time.
I'm in no great hurry, I assure you.
Oh, beshrew me,
but I grow fond of this fellow.
Shoot when you please, lads, and a bag
of gold to the one that brings him down.
(GUNS FIRING)
That noise. I can hear shooting!
-More tomfoolery.
-What is it? What's happening?
They captured Sir Edward's sorcerer,
this fellow, the Doctor,
and now they're slaying him
in the great hall
with these devil's weapons of theirs.
For the life of me,
I can't see what's wrong
with a good, old-fashioned broadsword.
By the stars! This fellow
hops around like a flea on a griddle.
Give me a weapon. I will destroy him.
What? Would you spoil good sport,
old toad?
(GUNS FIRING)
Doctor!
Well done, Sarah.
Just like a daring young man
on the flying trapeze. Come on.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(IRONGRON SHOUTING)
Sarah, wait.
Come on.
(DOCTOR WHISTLING)
Do you know, I think
that was one of the most active days
that I've had in years.
Well, it's not as if
I was a lad any more,
once you're over 200.
So then, Doctor,
your plans have miscarried, I fear.
-What will you do now?
-Oh, wait a bit.
Give the potion time to work
and then go back.
-Doctor, you can't!
-Sarah, I must.
Rubeish and all those scientists
are there.
Linx's spaceship
is just about ready for takeoff,
and when that happens,
there'll be a tremendous explosion.
All that will be left of that castle
will be a pile of stones.
-But, Doctor, how can the castle go?
-Just believe me, sir.
When Linx goes, it goes.
Irongron's castle is to be destroyed
by sorcery? Then all is well.
There are innocent people
in that castle, my lady,
and I don't like the idea
of anybody going up in smoke.
Not even Irongron.
If you're going back,
then I'm coming with you.
I, too, will come with you
if my master permits.
Well, thank you. Thank you both.
I can do with all the help I can get.
Thank you, my friends.
Your work is finished.
You may rest now for a time
until the power build-up is complete.
Doctor, I think you'd better get
a move on.
I've a feeling
time's beginning to run out.
-Good evening.
-It's working, Doctor. Look.
Aye, the villains sleep
like innocent babes.
Good.
Well, we'll wait a bit to be on
the safe side then we'll go in.
At last, Doctor, there you are.
Something most
interesting happening here.
Yes, I see. Where's Linx?
I don't know. He started
his spaceship going then cleared off.
Where's the osmic projector?
It was over there on the table.
He put everything back inside the ship.
I'll just have to
take it out again, won't I?
Hal, scout around the castle.
See if Irongron and his men
are sleeping.
If they are, disarm them
and come back here.
What are you going to do, Doctor?
Get the osmic projector.
Fortunately, it's an independent unit.
-Can't you switch this thing off?
-Well, I can try.
Suppose you don't succeed?
Then we've got between five and ten
minutes to get out of here
before we're all blown to kingdom come.
(MAN SNORING)
-Couldn't you shut it down?
-No, the drive system is sealed.
Linx must have taken the activator key.
I managed to get a hold of this, though.
I was lucky to get it out
with the drive running.
I think that should do it.
I've got to send them back
one at a time.
Get the first one to stand over there,
will you, Rubeish?
Come on, Morrison.
All right, Rubeish, come over here.
I may want you to take over.
Now then, all you have to do is this,
-this and this. Get it?
-Yeah.
Right, here goes.
Right, that ought to surprise them
back at the research centre.
-Next gentleman, please.
-Come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
For the last time, Linx,
let there be no more talk of leaving.
And I tell you for the last time,
I am leaving now.
Our alliance is at an end.
It ends when I say it ends
and not before.
You would be well advised
to march from this castle now
and capture another.
Soon you will have need of it.
-He threatens us, Captain.
-He does not understand our ways.
Tomorrow, Linx, we smite the enemy,
hip and thigh!
But tonight, we feast.
By your dawn, I shall be
700 million miles from here.
Can I be concerned
with the fate of primitives?
(ALL LAUGHING)
What did he mean, Captain?
He is a toad.
Who knows what a toad thinks?
Aye, Captain, 'tis truly said.
This stew has made me heavy.
Eh?
That's Linx.
Send the rest of them back.
I'll try and keep him busy.
(SNORING)
Trickery! Sorcery!
What sorcery! Treachery.
That toad Linx bewitched us all!
-Now you, Professor.
-I really don't think
-I ought to go and leave you.
-Off you go now.
-Now then, this, this and this.
-Well, goodbye and good luck.
It really was
the most fascinating experience.
I hope you and the Doctor will be all
right. See you back at research centre.
SARAH: Doctor!
So...
destroy my castle by sorcery,
would you, toad face?
Well, Irongron's magic
is too strong for you!
Now listen, dog!
In minutes now, this castle
will be destroyed by the sorcery.
If you'd save your miserable skins,
then get you gone!
Flee, dogs!
Flee for your life!
Come on, waken, you dogs!
And flee! Flee for your lives, you dogs!
Waken! Waken up! Now flee!
Doctor, do get up.
We've got to get you out.
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Something's gone wrong.
He must have hit
the takeoff button too soon.
Come on, we've got about a minute
to get out of here. Quick! Run!
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING BUILDS)
(BUZZING INTENSIFIES)
Well, you can tell Sir Edward
that his problems are over, Hal.
Irongron, his castle,
his magic weapons and his sorcerer,
they're all destroyed.
Will you not tell him yourself, Doctor?
He will reward you well.
We owe you much.
I'm sorry. I'm afraid we must be off.
-Goodbye, Hal.
-Goodbye, Doctor.
-Goodbye.
You are truly a great magician, Doctor.
To tell you the truth, Hal,
I'm not a magician at all.
I'm not so sure about that.
(WHOOSHING)