WILLIAMS: Well, Doctor, shall we try again?
You can suit yourself.
But I warn you, you're wasting your time.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Are you a member of the Draconian Secret Service?
No.
No change in the rhythm, sir. He must be telling the truth.
How did you get on the cargo ship?
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
I came here in my own ship, the TARDIS.
- TARDIS? - Yes, my own spaceship.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Why did you help the Draconians attack the cargo ship?
DOCTOR: I didn't.
In any case, it wasn't the Draconians, it was the Ogrons.
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
Your machine can't be working properly. Or else he's controlling it.
We've checked all the circuits, sir. Those are his thoughts.
We know this man is a Draconian agent. He must be lying.
Perhaps he's already been brainwashed, sir.
But as far as he's concerned, what he's telling us is the truth.
Then we must break through his conditioning.
Unless you tell me the truth, the real truth,
I shall be forced to use increased power.
I wouldn't do that, old man.
I know these machines. They aren't awfully reliable, you know?
You'd do better to worry about the effects on your mind.
There's just no telling some people, is there, my dear?
Step up the power.
Increase to 12.
Now!
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Are you an agent of the Draconians?
- DOCTOR: No. - When do they plan to attack us?
They don't.
- How did you board the cargo ship? - Through the TARDIS.
- Who first recruited you to serve the Draconians? - No one.
WILLIAMS: Who are the other Draconian agents on Earth?
I don't know.
WILLIAMS: The truth, man. I want the truth.
- I'm telling you the truth. - WILLIAMS: I will get the truth.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(MIND PROBE SPARKING)
Doctor, are you sure you're all right?
Mmm-hmm, apart from a bit of a headache.
I like the new outfit. Who are you fighting tonight?
(JO CHUCKLING)
What happened to you, anyway?
Oh, they kept going on at me to confess.
Yeah, it's awkward, isn't it?
Well, they've made up their minds, you see.
They'll only believe us if we tell them what they want to hear.
It's a pity really that the Ogrons didn't succeed in kidnapping us.
Perhaps we should have been more helpful.
- Why?  - Well, if they had succeeded,
presumably they'd have taken us to where the TARDIS is.
(SIGHING) I'm sorry, Jo,
but I'm afraid another kidnapping attempt is our only ray of hope.
So, we just sit around here waiting for
those jolly old Ogrons to turn up again?
(CHUCKLING) That's about it, yes.
The President wants to see you. Get moving.
Not you. You.
This maybe your chance. Good luck.
- See you later. - Bye.
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm giving you a final chance to tell me the truth.
Madam President,
I've been telling you the truth for some considerable time
but you just won't believe me.
I can't think why you chose to work for the Draconians.
But whatever it is, I'll double any offer they've made to you.
That's very generous of you, madam,
but you'd only be buying information that doesn't exist.
You leave me no alternative.
Under the powers invested in me by the Special Security Act,
I'm sending you to the Lunar Penal Colony.
What, without a trial?
Without even a chance to state my case?
So, you're just tucking me quietly away, are you?
What about my companion?
She will remain here.
I have hopes that, away from your influence,
I might be able to make her see the error of her ways.
But you will see that she comes to no harm?
We are not barbarians.
If you want to help her,
why don't you tell me where she comes from?
I'd like to inform her family.
I'd like to, madam.
I really would, but there's nothing that I can say that you'd believe.
May I say goodbye to her?
No! You'll be leaving immediately for the penal colony.
We're putting you where your Draconian friends will be unable to reach you.
Penny for them, Miss Grant?
You! What are you doing here?
To coin a phrase, I've come to take you away from all this.
What are you talking about?
Well, surely you don't want to spend the rest of your life in here, do you?
Well, I'm not going anywhere with you, that's for sure.
Oh, but you are, you know.
Believe it or not,
I am a fully accredited commissioner from the planet Sirius 4
and you and the Doctor are two dangerous criminals
being handed over into my custody.
So it was you!
You ordered those Ogrons to attack the ships
and pretend they were Draconians!
But, of course!
Those lumbering idiots could never have thought up
such a brilliant scheme by themselves.
Why did you want to start a war?
Now, come on, Miss Grant, be reasonable.
You want to see the Doctor again, don't you?
- Where is he? - He's in another prison, on the Moon.
We're going to collect him.
How do I know you're telling the truth?
You don't.
And the only way you'll find out is by coming with me.
Well?
(SIGHING)
How did you know we were here in the first place?
Well, after they'd attacked the cargo ships,
the Ogrons returned to their planet, taking their loot with them.
Now imagine my surprise, and my delight,
when I found that they brought me the Doctor's TARDIS.
And why are you taking us with you?
Oh, need you ask?
How could I leave two dear friends in such dire straits?
Oh, you don't seriously think that
I'm going to believe that you want to help us...
Believe what you like, Miss Grant, I have my reasons.
Now, are you coming,
or do you really wish to vegetate in
this hole for the rest of your natural?
Very well. I'll come.
Excellent!
The prisoner and I are ready to leave now, guard.