(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 10x03 Frontier in Space
(whopix fan edit version)
(time axis: bamanzi)
(based on subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
But all these charges are false, Your Highness.
We are not attacking Draconian ships. We never have!
Our soldiers have seen the Earthmen attack us.
Our cargos have been stolen.
We are Draconians, we do not lie.
The honour of your race is well known, Your Highness.
That is why I cannot understand your actions.
Actions?
You attack our ships, you steal their cargoes,
you ignore our protests and just meet them with these counter-charges.
Our charges are true but yours are false.
We do not attack your ships.
Well, I'm never going in that thing again.
Oh, come on, Jo, be reasonable.
Only you could manage to have a traffic accident in space.
- Well, we didn't hit it, did we? - Didn't we? Where's this then?
Well, by a rather brilliant last-minute course correction,
I've managed to materialise the TARDIS inside the spaceship.
But to avoid hitting it,
I've had to make a random jump back into normal space.
Terrific, but what do we do now?
Well, if I'm to get us back to Earth, I'd better find out where we are.
I'll just go and check the instruments.
HARDY: You won't believe this.
- Now what? - Maybe it's a wreck.
Try and make contact. They may need help.
This is Earth cargo ship C982 in close proximity to you.
Do you read me? Do you read me?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
- Try again. - Do you read me?
Are you in need of assistance?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
It's a weird-looking crate.
(HIGH PITCHED BLEEPING)
Draconians!
- Doctor? - Well, I think I know where we are.
I've got a pretty good idea about when.
- Come and take a look at this. - A look at what?
That.
Well, it's just a spaceship, Jo.
Now, I reckon we must be somewhere in the 26th century.
Well, interstellar travel's pretty routine by now.
A moment ago, it seemed to change shape.
- Hmm? - It was when I heard that noise.
Didn't you hear it?
Well, I did hear something but very faintly.
Come on, Jo. Let's go and find the crew.
I want to find the exact date for my calculations.
- HARDY: They're going to attack us! - STEWART: Get the blasters.
HARDY: You can't take on a battle cruiser!
Get the blasters!
Emergency, emergency, red alert.
This is Earth cargo ship C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser, galaxy class,
equipped with neutronic missiles.
Emergency, emergency!
Oh, how do you do? I'm sorry about this intrusion.
HARDY: Who are you?
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
DOCTOR: I said how do you do?
HARDY: Dragons!
- Drop that gun. - Gun?
I haven't got a gun. This is simply my hand.
(GASPING) No!
-DOCTOR: Jo, what's the matter with you? - He's a Drashig!
DOCTOR: Nonsense, it's simply a man with a gun.
Now pull yourself together.
(注: Jo 所看见的怪物名叫 Drashig , 这是在上一个故事 Carnival of Monsters 首次出现的一种猎食怪物)
This is Earth cargo ship C982.
Situation, red alert.
Draconian battle cruiser about to lock on now.
All anti-boarding procedures carried out.
Awaiting instructions. Out.
This is the commander of the Draconian battle cruiser.
We are locked onto your vessel
and are about to board.
If you offer any resistance,
you will be destroyed.
Open the hatch of your airlock.
I found these two Dragons in the hold.
But that's impossible. They... They're only just locking on.
Doctor, what's happening? What's going on?
I'm not sure, Jo. Something rather intriguing.
If you resist, we can destroy you with our neutronic weapons.
If you destroy our ship, you won't get the cargo.
Oh, so that's what it's all about.
Open the hatch to your airlock
or we shall enter your ship by force.
- We refuse. - They can blow us to pieces!
I've sent a message to Earth asking for help.
This is a transcript of a distress call from one of our ships.
"From Earth's cargo ship number C982 on coordinate 8972/6483.
"We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser,
"galaxy class, equipped with neutronic missiles."
The treaty between our two empires established a frontier in space.
We have never violated that frontier.
You have invaded our part of the galaxy many times.
In pursuit of your ships when they have raided ours!
We've been very patient, perhaps too patient.
General Williams!
I take it a rescue attempt has been mounted?
We've established an automatic procedure,
because of the frequency of these attacks.
Then I suggest you go and supervise the matter.
There's no need.
Please do as I say.
As you wish, Madam President.
Your general is insolent.
We know the hatred he has always felt for our people.
Long ago he caused war.
Now he wishes to do so again.
He's a soldier, Your Highness, and he's angry.
The people of Earth are angry.
So are the nobles of my father's court!
I must ask you to take my personal appeal to your father, the Emperor.
He must put a stop to these attacks.
If Draconia has some grievances against Earth,
then this is not the way to deal with them.
Many of our noblemen felt it was a mistake
to make a treaty with the Earthmen.
Perhaps they were right.
You attack our ships and when we protest
you trick us with lies and evasions.
I give you a final warning.
The path you are treading leads only to war.
And in that war, Draconia will destroy you!
(HISSING)
They'll be through that door any minute!
Doctor, what are you doing?
I'm reversing the polarity of my ultrasonic screwdriver's power source,
thereby converting it into an extremely powerful electromagnet.
Oh. What good will that do?
You wait and see, Jo.
Is it working?
(LOCK GRATING)
Yes, I think so.
- I'm going to get the prisoners. - What for?
We're using them as hostages, remember?
You'd better be quick about it. We haven't got much time.
- How is it going? - Nearly there.
(LOCK GRATING)
There you are, that's it.
Oh, how very embarrassing.  Good afternoon.
- Out. - That's just where we were going.
We're going to meet your friends.
- Come on! Get up there! - Come on, they're almost through.
HARDY: Get in front! If your friends start shooting,
they'll get you first.
- But they're not our friends! - You are part of their boarding party.
They haven't boarded yet. They're still breaking through that door.
- Now, try and be logical, man. - They're coming through!
- Ogrons! - DOCTOR: Back to the TARDIS, Jo. Back!
Doctor! Doctor!
JO: (SOFTLY) Doctor?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor!
- Jo? - JO: Doctor, I'm over here.
All right, Jo, what are you doing in there?
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness, you're all right.
I thought they'd killed you.
Come on, come and sit down.
Must have been some kind of neuronic stun gun.
I wonder why they didn't kill me? What exactly happened, Jo?
Well, they took the cargo, threw me in here and...
- Doctor? - Hmm?
- They also took the TARDIS. - Oh...
Oh, we're stranded. What are we going to do?
Well, try and get the TARDIS back, of course.
(JO SIGHS)
Why should the Ogrons attack this ship?
- To steal the cargo. - No. No, there's more to it than that.
That... That sound that you heard,
it's all too sophisticated for the Ogrons.
- Well, they're gone now. - Yeah, the question is, where?
Hey, Doctor, last time we met the Ogrons
they were working for the Daleks, right?
- Well, you don't suppose that that... - No, no, not necessarily.
No, the Ogrons are mercenaries.
Other life forms use them to do their dirty work.
Come on, Jo, let's go and find the crew.
(博士与 Jo 上一次碰到 Ogrons 是在09x01 The Day of the Daleks 这集,
Take a look at that one.
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jo. We're being rescued.
- What happened? - Well, don't worry, old chap.
You'll be all right now. I think...
Draconians! They're boarding!
- Stewart? Who are you? - Passengers.
I see. Having a fancy dress party? What happened?
- Dragons attacked us. - Did they get the cargo?
- I don't know. - Yes, they took everything.
Including some rather valuable property of mine.
- Well, tough luck. - Oh, thank you very much.
- Dragons... They attacked us. - Yes, we know.
You say you're passengers.
Isn't that a little unusual on a cargo ship?
Well, we're here, aren't we?
Where did you pick these two up?
I don't know. I can't seem to remember...
Pull yourself together! How did they get on board?
Stowaways... That's it, they were stowaways.
- They were sending messages. - That's right.
But that's absolute nonsense.
Look, we didn't want to be on this ship. It was an accident.
You said you were passengers.
I was merely trying to avoid a lot of tiresome explanations, old chap.
Stewart, I'll leave Kemp on board to take your ship back to Earth.
What about these two?
Lock them in the hold, put a guard on them.
- But we haven't done anything. - They say you have. Take them away.
Now, if you'll only listen to me...
You can talk to Earth Security.
They'll listen, it's their business.
- Put them in the starboard cubicle. - All right, get moving.
In there.
Oops. No need to push.
Doctor, well, now the Ogrons have gone,
why don't the crewmen remember what really happened?
Because the true facts have been erased from their minds, that's why.
Well, yes, but why did they keep telling lies about us?
Oh, they don't know that they're lying, Jo.
They're desperately trying to fit us into their version of things.
Well, what are we going to do then?
Well, when we get back to Earth,
we've got to reach someone in authority
whose mind isn't already closed.
Closed to what?
Jo, look, these people believe
that the Draconians are attacking their spaceships, right?
- Right. - We know that they're wrong, don't we?
Well, yes, it was Ogrons.
Oh, we also know that the Ogrons couldn't possibly
have created that hallucinatory device
that makes the Earthmen think they're Draconians.
Oh. Oh, well, that's simple then.
I mean, what we've got to is find out what's going on,
who's behind the Ogrons, where they've taken the TARDIS,
go and get it back and then we can all go home.
- Right? - Right.
Oh. I don't know what I've been worrying about.
We are now in space port 10.
The ship will land in 15 minutes. The crew are safe.
Also aboard, two human stowaways, origins unknown.
I want a cordon around the landing area,
the minute that ship touches down.
Nobody on, nobody off till I get there.
Sir.
I'd better get down there.
I want handle the preliminary interrogations myself.
- Outside. - We want to see somebody in authority.
You're going to, but outside.
Now then, what's all this about?
- Draconian agents? Are you sure? - What else can they be?
Their story is obvious nonsense.
But why? We...
Why would the Draconians leave them on board the ship?
The Draconians are preparing for war.
You're still only suspecting that. There is no proof.
Then they need to plant human agents,
traitors, on this planet to sabotage our war effort.
But we are bound to suspect them. They must have realised.
The Draconians probably thought the crew was dead.
We could easily have accepted those two as passengers,
two unfortunate refugees from a Draconian attack,
- When did you last eat? - Quite some while ago.
Well, I'll see they send you some food.
I'd like to get a message through to your president.
Not a chance.
I'm going straight back to my ship.
Don't want to get mixed up with security.
It's not healthy.
- Look, I'll give you a piece of advice. - DOCTOR: Yes?
Sooner or later, you're going to tell them everything.
They'll use the mind probe. You talk to them now.
You'll save yourselves a lot of trouble.
PRESIDENT: And you are quite sure it was a Draconian battle cruiser.
Of course, Madam.
They locked on and boarded us.
We saw them. They were Draconians.
Thank you. That will be all.
I hope you will soon recover from your ordeal.
Well, Your Highness?
These men are your servants.
They are saying what they have been ordered to say.
On this occasion, we have more than our servants to confront you with.
We have captured two of your human agents.
We have no human agents.
Subversion and espionage are expressly forbidden
by the treaty of peace between our two empires.
A treaty which you have flagrantly broken.
I shall return to my embassy.
Just a moment please, Your Highness. Bring them in.
These people stowed away on the cargo ship.
They transmitted signals
which enabled your battle cruiser to home in on its prey.
I know nothing of this.
Perhaps you do not, but some servant of the Draconian empire employed them.
Madam, I can assure that I've never been employed by anybody.
Least of all by the Draconians.
Your servants should have been better rehearsed in their lies.
Or they're showing a misguided loyalty to their Draconian masters.
If we really were working for the Draconians,
why did they leave us in your ship?
To act as spies when you were brought back to Earth.
Allow me to congratulate you, sir.
You have the most totally closed mind that I've ever encountered.
Madam, I beg of you to listen to me.
Some third party is trying to provoke war between Earth and Draconia.
You are both being duped.
Take them away.
Just a minute, please.
Why should a third party wish to do this?
I've no idea, Madam,
but believe me, that is what is happening.
Take them away.
Now please listen to me! If you don't
you'll be involved in a war that could cause the death of millions.
Is this the evidence upon which you accuse me?
I must ask you to convey a formal protest to your Emperor.
I shall inform him of this latest insult
to the honour of the Draconian empire.
But why?
Why should they produce such an elaborate lie?
The ways of the Earthmen are devious. They're an inscrutable species.
Obviously, they are preparing the next stage of their plan.
First, the attacks on our ships and now this.
Is it possible, Your Highness,
that for once the Earthmen spoke the truth?
Some plan of the Emperor of which Your Highness has not been informed?
The Emperor would not possibly contemplate such a plan.
We do not break the treaty of peace.
Shall I prepare your Excellency's report
to the Emperor on this meeting?
I must have more information.
It would be useful to question the humans who were found on the ship.
They are supposed to be prisoners.
Prisoners have been known to escape, Your Highness.
Not without help.
And that would be a grave act of hostility.
I could not possibly countenance such a plan.
But, should two escaping prisoners seek sanctuary in this embassy,
it would be uncivilised to turn them away.
I must not detain you longer.
No doubt you have duties demanding your attention?
WILLIAMS: Well, Doctor, shall we try again?
You can suit yourself.
But I warn you, you're wasting your time.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Are you a member of the Draconian Secret Service?
No.
No change in the rhythm, sir. He must be telling the truth.
How did you get on the cargo ship?
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
I came here in my own ship, the TARDIS.
- TARDIS? - Yes, my own spaceship.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Why did you help the Draconians attack the cargo ship?
DOCTOR: I didn't.
In any case, it wasn't the Draconians, it was the Ogrons.
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
Your machine can't be working properly. Or else he's controlling it.
We've checked all the circuits, sir. Those are his thoughts.
We know this man is a Draconian agent. He must be lying.
Perhaps he's already been brainwashed, sir.
But as far as he's concerned, what he's telling us is the truth.
Then we must break through his conditioning.
Unless you tell me the truth, the real truth,
I shall be forced to use increased power.
I wouldn't do that, old man.
I know these machines. They aren't awfully reliable, you know?
You'd do better to worry about the effects on your mind.
There's just no telling some people, is there, my dear?
Step up the power.
Increase to 12.
Now!
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Are you an agent of the Draconians?
- DOCTOR: No. - When do they plan to attack us?
They don't.
- How did you board the cargo ship? - Through the TARDIS.
- Who first recruited you to serve the Draconians? - No one.
WILLIAMS: Who are the other Draconian agents on Earth?
I don't know.
WILLIAMS: The truth, man. I want the truth.
- I'm telling you the truth. - WILLIAMS: I will get the truth.
(MIND PROBE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(MIND PROBE SPARKING)
Doctor, are you sure you're all right?
Mmm-hmm, apart from a bit of a headache.
I like the new outfit. Who are you fighting tonight?
(JO CHUCKLING)
What happened to you, anyway?
Oh, they kept going on at me to confess.
Yeah, it's awkward, isn't it?
Well, they've made up their minds, you see.
They'll only believe us if we tell them what they want to hear.
It's a pity really that the Ogrons didn't succeed in kidnapping us.
Perhaps we should have been more helpful.
- Why?  - Well, if they had succeeded,
presumably they'd have taken us to where the TARDIS is.
(SIGHING) I'm sorry, Jo,
but I'm afraid another kidnapping attempt is our only ray of hope.
So, we just sit around here waiting for
those jolly old Ogrons to turn up again?
(CHUCKLING) That's about it, yes.
The President wants to see you. Get moving.
Not you. You.
This maybe your chance. Good luck.
- See you later. - Bye.
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm giving you a final chance to tell me the truth.
Madam President,
I've been telling you the truth for some considerable time
but you just won't believe me.
I can't think why you chose to work for the Draconians.
But whatever it is, I'll double any offer they've made to you.
That's very generous of you, madam,
but you'd only be buying information that doesn't exist.
You leave me no alternative.
Under the powers invested in me by the Special Security Act,
I'm sending you to the Lunar Penal Colony.
What, without a trial?
Without even a chance to state my case?
So, you're just tucking me quietly away, are you?
What about my companion?
She will remain here.
I have hopes that, away from your influence,
I might be able to make her see the error of her ways.
But you will see that she comes to no harm?
We are not barbarians.
If you want to help her,
why don't you tell me where she comes from?
I'd like to inform her family.
I'd like to, madam.
I really would, but there's nothing that I can say that you'd believe.
May I say goodbye to her?
No! You'll be leaving immediately for the penal colony.
We're putting you where your Draconian friends will be unable to reach you.
Penny for them, Miss Grant?
You! What are you doing here?
To coin a phrase, I've come to take you away from all this.
What are you talking about?
Well, surely you don't want to spend the rest of your life in here, do you?
Well, I'm not going anywhere with you, that's for sure.
Oh, but you are, you know.
Believe it or not,
I am a fully accredited commissioner from the planet Sirius 4
and you and the Doctor are two dangerous criminals
being handed over into my custody.
So it was you!
You ordered those Ogrons to attack the ships
and pretend they were Draconians!
But, of course!
Those lumbering idiots could never have thought up
such a brilliant scheme by themselves.
Why did you want to start a war?
Now, come on, Miss Grant, be reasonable.
You want to see the Doctor again, don't you?
- Where is he? - He's in another prison, on the Moon.
We're going to collect him.
How do I know you're telling the truth?
You don't.
And the only way you'll find out is by coming with me.
Well?
(SIGHING)
How did you know we were here in the first place?
Well, after they'd attacked the cargo ships,
the Ogrons returned to their planet, taking their loot with them.
Now imagine my surprise, and my delight,
when I found that they brought me the Doctor's TARDIS.
And why are you taking us with you?
Oh, need you ask?
How could I leave two dear friends in such dire straits?
Oh, you don't seriously think that
I'm going to believe that you want to help us...
Believe what you like, Miss Grant, I have my reasons.
Now, are you coming,
or do you really wish to vegetate in
this hole for the rest of your natural?
Very well. I'll come.
Excellent!
The prisoner and I are ready to leave now, guard.
- Hello, Jo. - Doctor!
- How are you? All right? - Well...
Right, they'll be plenty of time
for the exchange of social pleasantries.
Put him inside.
Thank you, gentlemen.
You can leave them to me now.
Well, Doctor,
this is an interesting reversal.
I remember your once visiting me
when I was in prison.
You know, I'd very much
like to know why...
Why you've been locked up?
No, why I'm still alive.
Oh, come, your health is very precious
to me, for the moment.
You see, my employers
are most interested in you.
-The Ogrons?
-Miss Grant, please! I employ them.
Yes, well, whatever it is you're up to,
you needn't expect any help from me.
I don't need any help.
Your simple presence
will be quite enough.
Oh, by the way, I need hardly warn you
there is no point in trying to escape.
This is an interplanetary
police spaceship,
specially built for carrying prisoners,
as you can see.
Stolen, of course?
(SCOFFING) Of course.
Oh, and another thing...
There's a closed-circuit television
camera trained on you from up there,
so you will be
under continuous observation.
I think that's all.
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some rather complicated
astro-navigational calculations
to work out.
May I ask where we're going?
Certainly. To the home of our friends,
the Ogrons.
A barren and uninteresting planet
on the remote fringes of the galaxy.
Why are you taking us there?
That, Miss Grant,
you will discover when you arrive.
Right, now listen to me.
We haven't got much time
before he gets back to the flight deck.
Now, the first thing
we've got to do is to escape.
Now, they took my sonic screwdriver
from me in the prison
but they didn't get a hold of this.
-A steel file.
-Right, let's go.
No, not yet. Let's wait
till he gets back to the flight deck,
then he'll set the controls.
Now, this is an automatic spaceship.
Once we're underway,
the computers take over, right?
-Okay, so what's the plan?
-Now this is what we're gonna do.
So I told the High Council
of the Time Lords,
I said they had absolutely no right
to put me on trial in the first place.
Well, if I chose to go wandering around
the universe in my own time,
that was my business.
What about stealing the TARDIS?
I didn't steal it. I just borrowed it.
I fully intended to return it,
I assure you.
Anyway, she wasn't exactly
the latest model, poor old thing.
JO: (LAUGHING) You can say that again.
I tell you, I made a complete fool
of that prosecuting council, though.
I ridiculed his every argument.
Yes, and I told him
that I had the complete answer
to every one his charges against me.
JO: And then what happened?
DOCTOR: Then what happened, well,
they found me guilty,
changed my appearance
and exiled me to Earth.
JO: And that's where you met me!
That's right. That's where I met you.
And that alone
made the exile worthwhile, Miss Grant.
JO: Thank you!
Not that there's anything wrong
with Earth.
Well, it's quite a nice, little planet
in its own way, but...
After all, I am a Time Lord,Jo,
and I think I've deserve my freedom.
-JO: Right!
-In reminiscent mood, are you, Doctor?
Poor Miss Grant,
you have my deepest sympathy.
(CHUCKLING)
As I soon realised,
the trouble with Lethbridge-Stewart
is that he's got a military mind.
Well, he is a brigadier, after all.
I mean, what do you expect?
No, that's just the trouble though.
He's hidebound, you see.
He always does everything by the rules.
I keep telling him.
I said, "There are times, you know,
"when you've simply got to cut
right through the red tape."
And you've managed to do that, have you?
DOCTOR: Yes, I've managed to cut
right through it.
And I'm not going to let authority
stand between me and my freedom.
(SIGHING) Lethbridge-Stewart, I...
Hey! As far as he's concerned I've been
absent without leave all this time.
I'm always telling people ...
Is everything all right, Miss Grant?
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
And how about you, Doctor?
No ill effects, I hope?
Doctor, are you all right?
JO: Please don't wake him.
He's...he's fast asleep.
Is he? How very relaxed of him.
you come with me, Miss Grant.
Come on!
Right, in you go, Miss Grant.
Can you hear me, Doctor?
Are you on the flight deck?
If so, listen to this.
Miss Grant is in the air lock.
Unless you surrender yourself
to me immediately,
I shall open the outer door
and hurl her into space.
What an ingenious fellow
you are, Doctor!
Oh, no, you don't!
Now hold it, Doctor, hold it!
Get that blaster over to me
or I press this button,
and that will be the end of Miss Grant!
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Thank you, Doctor.
(THUDDING)
Well, we appear to have company.
Would these be your Ogron friends?
Why, no, no.
Well, I should try and be
a bit more hospitable, old chap.
Come on, put that gun away.
They've probably got us outnumbered.
Welcome on board my ship.
To what do I owe the honour?
Why have you violated
the Draconian frontier?
Uh, yes, I'm most apologetic about that,
but it was really beyond my control.
You see, my prisoners
were trying to escape and my...
-My ship was thrown off course.
-Prisoners?
Yes, I am the commissioner
of Earth's Interplanetary Police.
I'm taking these two people back
to planet Sirius 4 for...for trial.
Uh, here is my warrant of authority.
Now, don't believe this man, he's lying.
I'm not concerned in disputes
between Earthmen.
We shall take them to Draconia.
Put them in the cage.
But you can't do that!
I'm a commissioner
of Interplanetary Police!
This is my spaceship!
I tell you, you can't do that!
Well, personally I'm quite happy
to be going to Draconia, Jo.
Perhaps we can convince the Emperor
what our friend here
has been trying to do.
You really think he'd believe you?
Well, this won't be my first visit
to Draconia, you know?
Many years ago,
I spent quite some time there.
I was able to help them through a period
of very great difficulty.
So there's a good chance
that they'll believe you, huh?
Well, it was a long time ago.
Things may have changed.
But I do understand
the Draconian mentality, Jo.
It all depends how you approach them.
So, if they do believe the Doctor,
you've had it!
Perhaps, Miss Grant, perhaps.
But one never knows
when help may be at hand.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I think that this is going to be
rather a long journey,
so, uh, good night.
We'll wake you with a cup of tea
in the morning.
Thank you.
So, Father, once more
Earthmen have invaded our space.
You will address the Emperor
in a proper manner.
Your pardon.
May I have permission
to address the Emperor?
My life at your command.
One day, my Son,
you will inherit this throne.
Then you will realise
the importance of due formality.
Now, what do you wish to say?
Surely, now you will declare war
upon the Earthmen?
Let me lead your battle fleets
to crush their...
They too, have battle fleets, my Son.
Such a war could
well bring down both empires.
Not if we strike first,
then we shall be the victors!
In such a war, there are no victors.
The nobles of the court
are demanding action.
They fear for the honour of Draconia.
I am the emperor!
The honour of Draconia is vested in me.
The throne depends upon
the great families for support.
Emperors have been deposed before now.
An emperor who does not rule
deposes himself!
Then what will you do, Father?
I shall question these Earthmen myself.
I have already sent for them.
Why waste time listening to their lies?
Majesty, I bring the prisoners.
May I have permission
to address the Emperor?
Wait!
This is an insult!
My life at your command, sire.
How dare you address the Emperor
in a manner reserved
for a noble of Draconia?
Ah, but I am a noble of Draconia.
The honour was conferred on me
by the 15th Emperor.
The 15th Emperor reigned 500 years ago.
(LAUGHING)
Your Majesty, do not be taken
in by this ridiculous story...
Be silent!
There is a legend
among our people of a man
who assisted the 15th Emperor
at a time of great trouble
when we were almost overwhelmed
by a great plague from outer space.
But you could not be that man.
No Earthman lives so long.
Your Majesty,
this man that you speak of,
was he not known as the Doctor?
And did he not come to this planet
in a spaceship called the TARDIS?
He did.
Well, I am that man, sire.
And I come from a race of people
that live far longer than any Earthman.
Even if I accept your claim,
you have broken our law.
Why did you violate Draconian space?
Your Majesty, this man was,
and still is, my prisoner.
It is true, Your Majesty.
I did come here as a prisoner,
but I came willingly,
in order to inform you that
this man is plotting a war
between Earth and Draconia!
All Earthmen are determined upon war.
Ah, but the Master is not an Earthman.
I'm sorry to have to admit it,
but he's a renegade of my own race
and he's using creatures called Ogrons
to attack your spaceships
and those of the Earthmen.
The Earthmen who attacked
our spaceships,
they have been seen many times.
I'm sorry,
but there you are in error, sir.
Your people have seen Ogrons,
but they appear to them as Earthmen
because of a hypnotic device.
It's true, Your Majesty.
When the Ogrons attacked
the Earth ships,
the Earthmen saw them as Draconians.
Silence! Females are not permitted
to speak in the presence of the Emperor.
Your Majesty, do not be deceived
by the pathetic ravings
of two criminals
trying to evade justice.
If what you say is true,
it would explain much.
We lived at peace with the Earthmen
for many years,
then suddenly they began
to raid our spaceships.
When we protested,
they said that we were attacking them.
In order to cover up their own attacks!
This is simply a plot of the Earthmen
to lull us into false security.
Speak!
Your Majesty, a spaceship from Earth
seeks permission to land
in the palace spaceport.
They say they're on a special mission
from the President of Earth.
This is a trick!
You must not allow them to land!
We are not yet at war with Earth.
I shall hear what
their president has to say.
I give my permission.
Your Majesty.
A wise decision, Your Majesty.
For only by Earth and Draconia
working together
can we hope to arrive at the truth.
I, too, welcome your wisdom,
Your Majesty.
Nobody could be more devoted
to the cause of peace than I.
As a commissioner of Earth's
Interplanetary Police,
I have devoted my life
to the cause of law and order.
And law and order can only exist
in a time of peace.
You feeling all right, old chap?
Only during a period
of social stability,
can society adequately
deal with criminals
such as this man
and this unfortunate girl.
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
Doctor, listen! That sound!
PRINCE: Silence, female!
Quiet!
It's the same noise
that I heard on the cargo ship.
Doctor, it's the Ogrons!
Your Majesty,
I beg of you to be cautious.
Something is seriously wrong here.
This ship that has just landed,
I beg you,
place it under guard immediately.
Your Majesty, please?
DRACONIAN: (SHOUTING) Earthmen!
MASTER: Seize them, fool!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Ah, you idiots!
Back to the ship, all of you!
Come on, back to the ship!
Now will you believe
in the treachery of the Earthmen?
Your Majesty, look down here
and tell me, what do you see?
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
I see one of your Earth soldiers
who attacked my palace
and killed my people.
Jo? Jo, can you still hear that sound?
(HYPNOTIC PULSE FADING)
Yes, it's fading. It's almost gone.
Your Majesty, I beg of you, please.
Look again.
Why do we delay? Destroy him!
Wait!
He has spoken the truth.
Great, lumbering idiots!
Now you tell me that you've left
one of your fellows in the palace!
Do you realise what this means?
As soon as the effect
of the hypno-sound wears off,
the Draconians will know
who it really was who attacked them.
You've ruined everything!
What shall we do now?
Do? There's only one thing we can do.
Make sure that the Doctor
and his evidence
is never allowed to reach Earth.
Why does the Master want war
between Earth and Draconia?
Did you attack our spaceships
and those of the Earthmen?
Oh, it's no good.
We're not getting anywhere.
Let me take him for questioning.
He will answer to me.
I shall use the mind probe.
You'd only be wasting your time.
The Ogrons have got the finest
defence mechanism of all, stupidity.
They haven't got a mind
for you to probe.
Then remove him.
We will deal with him later.
Why did that sound make us see
this creature as a soldier from Earth?
Because you're frightened of Earthmen.
Draconians fear nothing, female.
Well, of course you do.
You fear them and they fear you.
That's why when Earthmen
heard that sound, they saw Draconians.
That is true.
We do fear the Earthmen
and they fear us.
And fear breeds hatred, Your Majesty.
Fear is the greatest enemy of them all,
for fear leads us to war.
We shall tell the Earthmen
what has happened here.
They, too, must know the truth.
They will not believe us.
The Prince is right, Your Majesty.
We must mount an expedition at once
and we must take the Ogron as evidence.
The empires are on the verge of war.
A Draconian spaceship in Earth space
could be destroyed before it
reaches its destination.
We could use the ship
the Master brought us in.
It's an Earth police spaceship.
Females are not permitted to speak...
The female may speak.
-But...
-We must respect
the customs of our guests,
strange though they may be.
The suggestion had merit.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
You too, will go on this mission.
But it must be headed
by a Draconian of noble rank.
I shall send my son.
Doctor, where are we?
We're just about to cross
the frontier into Earth space.
Ooh, that's good.
Unless your Earth people destroy us.
Well, this is an Earth police spaceship,
you know, sir.
Even if it is stolen.
What is that?
DOCTOR: It looks like another spaceship.
It appears to be following us.
OGRON: Look!
MASTER: Well, that must be them.
DOCTOR: We should be picking them up
on the visual scanner now.
JO: It's an Ogron ship!
Fire!
DOCTOR: Hang on.
I think we're shaking them off.
(OGRON GRUNTING)
Doctor!
He's broken out! Get out, Jo!
MASTER: We must have hit them.
They're losing speed.
OGRON: Shall I fire again?
No, no, it might be possible
to take the Doctor alive after all.
Muster a boarding party.
Yes, Master.
(OGRON GRUNTING)
Right, there you are, my friend.
Are you all right?
JO: Oh, no, you don't!
No, no!
-No, let go of me!
-This way!
JO: Let me go!
We've been boarded!
We need the blasters, come on!
-The prisoner?
-Don't worry about him.
He's no use to us at the moment.
JO: Let me go! No! Doctor!
DOCTOR: Get down!
OGRON: The enemy!
OGRON: Fool, go!
JO: Help! Doctor!
OGRON: You come!
-You must come!
-No!
Look out! We must take the girl!
No!
In here!
MASTER: Right. Unlock!
CAPTAIN ON RADIO:
This is Earth battle cruiser X29.
Do you read me? Identify yourself.
Hello, this is Earth
police spaceship 2390,
on a special mission
to the President of Earth. Over.
CAPTAIN: Identify the ship
that has just unlocked from you.
They refuse to answer our signals.
Look, it's of vital importance
that you pursue and capture
that ship immediately. Over.
You are in possession
of a stolen police spaceship.
You are under arrest.
Stand by to be boarded.
DOCTOR ON RADIO:
Look, you don't understand.
The man who stole this ship
is escaping in that vessel.
CAPTAIN: You are under arrest.
You'll be given the opportunity
of making a full statement.
Do not offer any resistance.
Stand by to be boarded.
DOCTOR: Oh, very well.
We're standing by.
(LAUGHING)
Poor Doctor.
Enmeshed in the throes of bureaucracy.
(LAUGHING)
It'll take him a long time
to talk himself out of that one.
But he'll get to see the President,
eventually.
She won't believe him.
Oh, yes, she will,
when she sees the Ogron prisoner.
He's our evidence.
Your evidence is standing
right behind you.
The Draconian Prince knows
the truth and he's with the Doctor.
My dear, Miss Grant, in the climate
of opinion that I have created,
do you think that any Earthman
is going to believe the word
of a Draconian?
Your Highness,
we've heard the Doctor's theory before.
And, with respect,
there is still no concrete evidence.
I myself would like to believe you
but, as you can see,
I need proof to convince my people.
Then we must mount an expedition
to the planet of the Ogrons.
The proof we need is there, madam.
With Earth on the brink of war,
how can we divert our forces
into such a pointless expedition?
My dear chap,
I'm not asking for a battle fleet.
All I require is one small spaceship.
Well, Miss Grant,
welcome to my humble abode.
I think you were better off in prison.
Oh, temporary quarters, my dear.
I shall soon be changing them
for something better.
Oh, you'll soon be back in jail.
When the truth gets out,
Earth and Draconia will combine
their forces to attack you.
I don't think so.
There's too much distrust between them.
The Doctor will find you, eventually.
Ah, there I agree with you.
He must find me.
Not only to rescue you,
but also to be reunited
with his beloved TARDIS.
Your Royal Highness,
could you convince your people
they were not being attacked
by Earthmen?
(SIGHING) If only we had proof.
Then I could convince my people
and you could convince yours.
But there's not much time.
Madam President, everything is ready.
We shall use my personal scoutship.
We'd better leave at once.
Madam President.
-My life at your command.
-Madam President.
DOCTOR: Right, 34 seconds,
a course correction to galactic
coordinates 2349-6784.
You realise where that will take us?
A completely uninhabited sector
of the galaxy.
Well, not completely uninhabited,
General Williams.
That's where the Ogron's planet is.
No doubt your information
is better than mine.
-May I ask where you obtained it?
-Certainly. From the Master.
He fed the co-ordinates into his
ship's computer when I was his prisoner.
And after you'd captured the ship, sir,
I extracted the information
from the ship's memory banks.
We're simply wasting time...
Dragons!
Let me talk to them, I shall explain!
Somehow I don't think
they're in the mood
for explanations at this minute.
-Can you outrun them?
-This ship can outrun anything.
Hyper-drive. Max hyper-drive!
-Right, we're out of range now.
-Reduce speed, return to course.
MASTER: They should be here very soon now.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Judging by the size of the ship,
they can't be in any great force.
So conceal yourselves and ambush them
as soon as they arrive, right?
Hold on, wait a minute.
Something's happened.
They must have landed very nearby.
Right, send out patrols!
Get them and bring them
back here immediately.
And, remember, I want the Doctor alive.
OGRONS: Yes, Master.
One dominant life form,
a large and savage reptile.
Yes, well, let's hope
we don't encounter one.
Doctor, has it occurred to you
what we're going to do
when we discover
the source of this signal?
I've no idea, old chap.
We'll find out when we get there.
Come on, can't be far.
-Drop! Surrender!
-WILLIAMS: Take cover!
(GROWLING)
WILLIAMS: What is that?
I've no idea, but whatever it is,
it's on our side.
Yes, I await your arrival
with the greatest of pleasure.
And I shall be there to meet you
the moment that your ship touches down.
(OGRONS GRUNTING)
-So, where's the Doctor?
-The monster came.
The monster?
And I suppose you all ran like rabbits?
-We fear the monster!
-You stupid, cowardly idiots!
You will answer
to your masters for this.
-What? They are coming?
-Yes, they are coming!
Which means that I can dispense
with your doubtful assistance.
Out of my way!
Hello, Doctor!
So here you are at last, eh?
-Surrender or you'll be shot down!
-No, he's unarmed.
Unarmed maybe, but not unaccompanied.
I've brought some old friends along
to meet you.
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Quite a touching little reunion.
CHIEF DALEK: Doctor, you are in our
power and you will be exterminated.
-No, not yet.
-You will obey the Daleks!
You know as well as I do
that this man does not fear death.
I want him to suffer
a much worse punishment.
Look, my skill and cunning
has brought about this war
which will make you
the masters of the galaxy.
Leave the Doctor with me
and let him see the result of that war.
Let him see the galaxy in ruins.
Let him see the planet Earth,
that he loves so much, in ruins,
then exterminate him.
Very well. He will remain your prisoner
until the war is concluded.
Then you will bring him to us
and we shall exterminate him.
We shall now return to our base
and prepare the army of the Daleks.
Oh, I suppose I should thank you
for saving my life?
Not for long, Doctor.
It's going to be a very short war.
Right, take them away.
-Hello, Doctor.
-Hello, Jo.
Oh, so now they've got all of us.
All except the pilot.
He's repairing the ship.
Why do these Dalek creatures wish
to set your people and mine at war?
'Cause war will mean the extermination
of both empires, Your Royal Highness,
and the Daleks will emerge
as the supreme rulers.
Now somehow, we've got to get
out of here and stop them.
(WHISPERING) Doctor! Doctor,
would the Master's little fear-box help?
Well done, Jo!
You see, we could use it
to frighten the Ogrons away
and then we can all escape.
Well, that's hardly practical,
Miss Grant.
They'd just run off
and we'd still be locked in.
(SIGHING) Oh!
There is one thing we can do, though,
and it'll need a very slight adjustment.
There's nothing to worry about.
The Doctor will be perfectly safe
in my hands.
And I promise you,
when I deliver him to you,
he'll be a broken man.
CHIEF DALEK OVER RADIO:
Do not fail the Daleks.
The war is certain now.
And once the great empires
have destroyed each other,
I ask but one thing, let me rule
the planet Earth in your name.
General Williams,
if we do manage to get out of here,
and Jo and I manage
to create a diversion,
could you find your way back
to your spaceship?
-Certainly.
-Good.
Right, that should do it.
Now I want you to take off immediately.
Get the truth back
to your respective governments.
Yes.
Tell them that they must mount
a joint expedition
-and capture this base at once.
-I shall stay and help.
No, we'll need you to convince
the Emperor, Your Royal Highness.
What about you and Miss Grant,
how will you get away?
Jo, I presume that the TARDIS
is still here?
-Yes, I know where it is.
-Well, don't worry about us.
-Our spaceship is here.
-That's all very well, Doctor,
but we still happen to be locked in.
Yes, well, would you mind
blocking your ears
and covering your eyes
just for a moment?
I do not understand.
No, but I think you will in a moment.
Just do as I ask, would you?
-You, too, Jo.
-Oh, no, it's all right.
-I can resist it.
-Can you?
-Yes.
-Good.
DOCTOR: Uh, how much longer are you
gonna keep us locked in here?
Yes, I'm talking to you.
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
Open the gate. Open the gate.
Open the gate or I will exterminate you.
It worked.
DOCTOR: Right.
JO: Come on, then. Follow me.
CHIEF DALEK OVER RADIO:
Do not fail the Daleks.
(SCOFFING)
Right, we'll see who rules
the galaxy when this is over.
(MOCKINGLY IMPERSONATING THE DALEKS)
"Do not fail the Daleks", indeed!
You stupid, tin boxes!
(OGRON GASPING)
Why aren't you guarding the prisoners?
-The Daleks sent me away.
-There are no Daleks!
-The Daleks have all left the planet.
-The Dalek said to open the cell.
Did he now? Fetch the others!
I want them here immediately.
-Doctor, look at this.
-DOCTOR: Well, that's fascinating.
Is it some sort of idol?
I saw one of the Ogrons worshipping it.
Yes, I'm not surprised.
We've seen the real thing, haven't we?
They're probably more frightened of him
than they are of the Daleks.
Right, come on. This way.
Right, you can get out this way.
Good luck.
-And you, Miss Grant. Doctor.
-General Williams.
WILLIAMS: Farewell.
JO: Good luck.
DOCTOR: Your Royal Highness.
PRINCE: My life at your command.
The TARDIS is over there.
Going somewhere, Doctor?
You know, you really are incredibly
persistent, aren't you?
-That is my property, I believe.
-Oh, yes, a most ingenious device.
I congratulate you.
OGRONS: Oh! The monster!
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
-Oh, Doctor, I thought you were dead.
-Help me.
Come on, yes. Careful.
-Help me into the TARDIS, Jo.
-Okay.
-All right, Jo.
-Careful.
The first thing we've got to do
is get out of here.
(WHOOSHING)
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Doctor, what are you doing?
Telepathic circuits,
sending a message to the Time Lords.