But that's absolute nonsense.
Look, we didn't want to be on this ship. It was an accident.
You said you were passengers.
I was merely trying to avoid a lot of tiresome explanations, old chap.
Stewart, I'll leave Kemp on board to take your ship back to Earth.
What about these two?
Lock them in the hold, put a guard on them.
- But we haven't done anything. - They say you have. Take them away.
Now, if you'll only listen to me...
You can talk to Earth Security.
They'll listen, it's their business.
- Put them in the starboard cubicle. - All right, get moving.
In there.
Oops. No need to push.
Doctor, well, now the Ogrons have gone,
why don't the crewmen remember what really happened?
Because the true facts have been erased from their minds, that's why.
Well, yes, but why did they keep telling lies about us?
Oh, they don't know that they're lying, Jo.
They're desperately trying to fit us into their version of things.
Well, what are we going to do then?
Well, when we get back to Earth,
we've got to reach someone in authority
whose mind isn't already closed.
Closed to what?
Jo, look, these people believe
that the Draconians are attacking their spaceships, right?
- Right. - We know that they're wrong, don't we?
Well, yes, it was Ogrons.
Oh, we also know that the Ogrons couldn't possibly
have created that hallucinatory device
that makes the Earthmen think they're Draconians.
Oh. Oh, well, that's simple then.
I mean, what we've got to is find out what's going on,
who's behind the Ogrons, where they've taken the TARDIS,
go and get it back and then we can all go home.
- Right? - Right.
Oh. I don't know what I've been worrying about.
We are now in space port 10.
The ship will land in 15 minutes. The crew are safe.
Also aboard, two human stowaways, origins unknown.
I want a cordon around the landing area,
the minute that ship touches down.
Nobody on, nobody off till I get there.
Sir.
I'd better get down there.
I want handle the preliminary interrogations myself.
- Outside. - We want to see somebody in authority.
You're going to, but outside.
Now then, what's all this about?
- Draconian agents? Are you sure? - What else can they be?
Their story is obvious nonsense.
But why? We...
Why would the Draconians leave them on board the ship?
The Draconians are preparing for war.
You're still only suspecting that. There is no proof.
Then they need to plant human agents,
traitors, on this planet to sabotage our war effort.
But we are bound to suspect them. They must have realised.
The Draconians probably thought the crew was dead.
We could easily have accepted those two as passengers,
two unfortunate refugees from a Draconian attack,
- When did you last eat? - Quite some while ago.
Well, I'll see they send you some food.
I'd like to get a message through to your president.
Not a chance.
I'm going straight back to my ship.
Don't want to get mixed up with security.
It's not healthy.
- Look, I'll give you a piece of advice. - DOCTOR: Yes?
Sooner or later, you're going to tell them everything.
They'll use the mind probe. You talk to them now.
You'll save yourselves a lot of trouble.
PRESIDENT: And you are quite sure it was a Draconian battle cruiser.
Of course, Madam.
They locked on and boarded us.
We saw them. They were Draconians.
Thank you. That will be all.
I hope you will soon recover from your ordeal.
Well, Your Highness?
These men are your servants.
They are saying what they have been ordered to say.
On this occasion, we have more than our servants to confront you with.
We have captured two of your human agents.
We have no human agents.
Subversion and espionage are expressly forbidden
by the treaty of peace between our two empires.
A treaty which you have flagrantly broken.
I shall return to my embassy.
Just a moment please, Your Highness. Bring them in.
These people stowed away on the cargo ship.
They transmitted signals
which enabled your battle cruiser to home in on its prey.
I know nothing of this.
Perhaps you do not, but some servant of the Draconian empire employed them.
Madam, I can assure that I've never been employed by anybody.
Least of all by the Draconians.
Your servants should have been better rehearsed in their lies.
Or they're showing a misguided loyalty to their Draconian masters.
If we really were working for the Draconians,
why did they leave us in your ship?
To act as spies when you were brought back to Earth.
Allow me to congratulate you, sir.
You have the most totally closed mind that I've ever encountered.
Madam, I beg of you to listen to me.
Some third party is trying to provoke war between Earth and Draconia.
You are both being duped.
Take them away.
Just a minute, please.
Why should a third party wish to do this?
I've no idea, Madam,
but believe me, that is what is happening.
Take them away.
Now please listen to me! If you don't
you'll be involved in a war that could cause the death of millions.
Is this the evidence upon which you accuse me?
I must ask you to convey a formal protest to your Emperor.
I shall inform him of this latest insult
to the honour of the Draconian empire.
But why?
Why should they produce such an elaborate lie?
The ways of the Earthmen are devious. They're an inscrutable species.
Obviously, they are preparing the next stage of their plan.
First, the attacks on our ships and now this.
Is it possible, Your Highness,
that for once the Earthmen spoke the truth?
Some plan of the Emperor of which Your Highness has not been informed?
The Emperor would not possibly contemplate such a plan.
We do not break the treaty of peace.
Shall I prepare your Excellency's report
to the Emperor on this meeting?
I must have more information.
It would be useful to question the humans who were found on the ship.
They are supposed to be prisoners.
Prisoners have been known to escape, Your Highness.
Not without help.
And that would be a grave act of hostility.
I could not possibly countenance such a plan.
But, should two escaping prisoners seek sanctuary in this embassy,
it would be uncivilised to turn them away.
I must not detain you longer.
No doubt you have duties demanding your attention?