Sincro: wyxchari
We will get our power. We will get our power. We will get our power. We will get our power. We will get our power. We will get our power.
Turn back the power supply.
I will, I will. But I want you to remember that I control you.
We are your servants.
I know. Remember it. I gave you each a special charge to bring you back to life. Any further power you need must come from this generator. And I control it. Is that clear?
We obey.
Where are they going?
To await your orders, master.
Good. Have you completed the blueprints for the meteor storm computer?
It is ready.
Oh, it's marvellous! I'm glad we understand each other.
We understand the human mind.
Isn't that finished yet?
Nearly.
This is Valmar. Test call please.
Terrace. So I can hear you clearly all right, good. Now try and get in connection now with the interior, and then the perimeter stations.
Well, no troubles now.
About time. This work should have been completed long before this.
Well, I did the best I could!
Well, it isn't good enough!
Then get someone else, Bragen.
Be careful! I shall be watching you, Valmar, after this - now get out!
What does this intrusion mean?
I'm sorry, Bragen. I tried to stop them.
Intrusion? It's no intrusion. We're just returning the various calls that you made. This guard tried to tell us you were busy. You're not a bit, are you?
All right - I'll see them.
Oh, what a nice new uniform. Very smart, very smart. I would like a hat like that.
Well, what do you want?
Some joker has kidnapped Polly and sent us this note.
Yes.
Well, we want to know what you're doing to find her.
Now that the communications are restored we can start a search.
Yeah, I can just imagine what kind of job you'll make of that. Haven't you heard anything yet?
The planet is a large one.
So! They've given you the run of the colony, have they?
We obey. Do I bring liquid for your visitors?
No. They won't be staying much longer.
Look, Doctor, if he's not going to help us, we'll have to search for Polly ourselves.
Sound advice. Why don't you, Doctor?
Ah, ah, Examiner.
I wonder how much longer they'll be able to move around on these floors?
Eh?
Floors. They're not metal.
Doctor.
Ah, there you are Bragen. Thank heavens the communications are working again. It's bad enough being stuck out here on the perimeter. Well? Your report man. Hurry up. I've got a very full schedule.
There is nothing to report, Governor.
The Examiner?
I'm taking good care of him.
Good, you know my orders.
Yes, sir.
All right, well you can reach me here if you have to, that's all.
One moment, Governor. When will you be coming back?
Oh, not for a day or two at least. You can manage, can't you?
Yes. Yes of course, Governor.
What do you want?
Have you finished your liquid?
No. No I haven't.
You'd better check the agenda.
I'll do it now.
Static you see. They need a constant supply of static from the floor, some sort of electrical field.
Doctor. Why should he...?
It's madness!
What is?
Letting them run around like this.
Hey, wait a minute! Bragen had one acting as a servant, and we've just left him!
One Dalek in Bragen's office - three Daleks just gone down the corridors. That makes four!
Where did the fourth one come from?
Well, Lesterson can't have been making them. Perhaps there were more in the capsule than we thought?
We must go and see Lesterson. Yeah, and show him this note. Maybe he or Janley knows where Polly is.
We frightened him off. I wonder what the fascination of this notice board is?
It looks like a perfectly ordinary noticeboard to me.
Yeah, well come on, Doctor. We must find out who's got Polly. Doctor, come on!
Janley?
What is it?
The Daleks. They've given me another list of materials they need.
Let me see. We've got all those things?
Yes, but why these quantities, Janley? Why? How can they have used up all the materials I gave them? What is it? D... why, it's only a matter of a few hours ago.
They're building new things for us.
Yes, well I don't want them to do anything without consulting me. What is it they do inside there?
You're worrying too much.
Look Janley, say what you like, but I'm beginning to believe that the Examiner is right about the Daleks. Their original thinking terrifies me. If we can control them, fine. But if not...
Yes?
Then I shall have them destroyed. It's too dangerous. The Examiner knows something about them that we don't. I'm going to ask his advice.
I wouldn't bring the Examiner into it if I were you.
And why not?
You want him to find out about Resno?
Oh, a little accident. How is he? Is he better?
He's dead.
What are you talking about? You told me he was...
You're busy with the experiments on the Daleks.
But you should have told me. But... but the body - it'll have to be reported.
Don't worry, no one will find the body.
Oh Janley, you've done a terrible thing.
The experiments on the Daleks were more important.
More important than human life? No. No, I won't accept that.
You will. You must! Your carelessness was the cause of Resno's death. You murdered him. It's only your word against mine.
I won't be blackmailed by you!
All I want is for you to go on as you are. Scientific discovery can't stop dead, Lesterson.
I told the guard that no-one was to be allowed in.
"Accord every access" remember?
We're looking for Polly.
Well, she isn't here, and I haven't seen her.
Well, she's been kidnapped.
Oh, it sounds a little unlikely.
Oh it does, does it? Well, we've got this note which tells us so.
I'm very sorry, but I don't know anything about it.
Lesterson?
Yes?
You haven't been building Daleks, have you?
Building? No I wouldn't know how to begin.
And there were only three in the capsule?
Yes.
Well we've just seen four. One in the Governor's office and three in the corridor!
But that's not possible!
There's only one explanation. The Daleks are reproducing themselves!
These things are machines. How could they reproduce?
Machines! What makes you think they're just machines. The Daleks are brilliant engineers. Nothing is beyond them given the right materials.
What?
I said nothing is beyond them given the right materials.
Oh...
Lesterson, what's the matter?
Leave him alone. He's just been overworking, that's all.
Well, he looks bad.
Will you both go away. Guard! It's you - badgering him with questions. You've done nothing but hound him ever since you arrived on Vulcan.
Bragen's orders were that no one was to be admitted.
Yes, but I thought that the... the Examiner.
He attacked Lesterson. Get them out of here. Both of them.
He did not attack Lesterson.
Out, do you hear?!
All right, all right.
Janley here. Tell Valmar to come over to the lab right away. Good.
Now, it's all right. Come on. Rest here for a bit. There. You've been doing far too much.
Ssssh.
I've sedated him.
Well, what's the matter with him?
Overwork, I suppose. He just suddenly broke up. Anyway, it'll give you a chance to lay in the new power cable the Daleks have asked for.
You don't miss a trick, do you?
We're going to lay in the new cables you wanted.
Good.
You're sure this is okay, Janley?
Of course. We help them. They help us.
Yes. We are your servants.
Don't take too long about it, Valmar. Oh, you saw the notice, did you?
I saw it.
Well, we're still no nearer finding Polly. What are we hanging about here for?
Ben, I've found a message in code. It's an anagram, you just take the capital letters, see, work it out yourself.
Oh, I can't do crosswords.
Meeting tonight, 2000 hours. R O C K E T - Rocket. R O O M - Room. P. Rocket Room P!
It's the rebels way of calling a meeting. Only tonight we're going to be there - early.
Yeah, maybe we're nearer finding Polly than I thought.
Aw, I've got pins and needles now.
What's the time?
Time we went home!
Yes.
Now, we're going to demonstrate something. You section leaders can pass on what you've seen. So far, we've been concerned with testing the strength of the Governor with a few acts of sabotage. But now, we're ready to take over.
What is that thing? I've seen them moving about, but all we've been told is that it's a machine Lesterson discovered.
Valmar?
Well, Lesterson removed the armaments of the Daleks he discovered. I've rearmed this one, but with a controlling device. We can regulate the fire power and turn it off and on whenever we choose.
Shall we have the demonstration now?
That's the one we want. He must be the boss of this outfit.
Sssh!
This screen is two inch thick tungsten steel. Right, Valmar.
Fire at the screen.
Quiet! You must keep quiet. We're too vulnerable here.
But, you can't control a thing like that. It'll turn on us!
No it won't.
I wouldn't let any of my group go anywhere near it.
I can control it.
Prove it. Ah, you daren't! I'm not talking about that thing firing at the wall or bits of metal or anything. I mean people. Have you tested whether it... you can stop it from killing people? Our people?
Look, I can show you what I've done here.
Forget it. How do you know a Dalek can tell the difference between the Governor's people and our people?
But I can tell the difference, you fool! And I control it.
We want something better than words.
Test it on me. Will that satisfy you?
Well yes, but...
She's out of her mind!
Is it all right?
Now, when I tell you to fire...
I am your servant.
Get back to your places.
Are you all right?
Of course. I don't take needless risks
Oh well done, Janley.
You haven't disarmed the Dalek! Well go on take the gun away. We don't want any accidents. Now, what about the girl?
We've got her safely locked up. Never fear.
I think the best thing for us to do is...
Hear that? Maybe they'll say were she is.
Who's there?
You stay there, I'll distract them. Find out where Polly is.
No!
Help! Help!
The guards will have heard that! Come on we've got to get out of here! Take him and lock him up! Quick! Out!
You might as well come out. We know you're there.
Bragen!
Of course. Who else is fitted to be leader of the rebels?
No doubt you want to be leader of the Daleks too.
I am the leader of the Daleks.
Well see if you can stop this one from killing me.
Stop! You heard me, that's an order. Turn away. Fetch the guard.
I obey.
You hope to have it both ways, Bragen. But how will you look in front of the Governor, when I explain your dual role to him?
The Governor will hardly listen to an impostor.
An impostor? How do you propose to prove that?
My guards are now going to produce the body of the real Examiner from the mercury swamp.
The one you murdered.
The one you pretended to be.
Murder's a far worse crime than impersonation.
Yes, but you can't prove I'm a murderer, while I can prove that you're an impostor.
Take this man away. Detain him.
A dangerous man.
Now the only one left is the Governor.
Perhaps we should have dealt with the Examiner earlier.
I'll deal with him in time - and Quinn.
You're the last man I expected to see here.
Hmm. Work's by sound, does it?
I'm speaking to you, Examiner.
Oh, I'm sorry.
If you'd listened to me in the first place, you wouldn't be locked up here now.
Well your imprisonment hasn't been entirely wasted. It's brought your enemy out into...
Bragen? I've known that all along.
Yes. But, ah, did you know that he was the leader of the rebels?
Bragen? The leader?
Yes. It's quite a simple sort of lock, really.
Hensell's trouble is he thinks he can run this colony on his personality alone.
But even if he knew of the danger, could he do anything? The rebels are well organised.
The Governor's popular. He can count on the mine workers of the perimeter for support.
In that case we must get word to him.
If you'd done your job properly, Examiner, you wouldn't be here now, and I'd have been out too.
Ah yes. But then, I'm not the real Examiner. Ben, Polly and I - We're... we're just travellers, that's all. I found the Examiner, dead. Bragen murdered him.
Everything leads back friend Bragen. Just give me a chance get my hands on him.
We aren't going to have the chance, unless we can get out of here.
There's just a little matter of the cell doors.
Ah... Oh...
You sent for me?
Take up a position at the communications room. Watch and report.
I obey.
They're conspiring together! Oh, why didn't I realise? The Examiner was right. They are evil!
There are four. They can't be reproducing!
Dalek nine complete.
Check.
We are the new race of Daleks!
Dalek ten complete.
Check.
Dalek eleven complete.
Dalek twelve complete.
Check.
Dalek thirteen complete.
Dalek fourteen complete.
Check.
Dalek fifteen complete.
Dalek sixteen complete.
Check.
Dalek seventeen complete.
Dalek eighteen complete.