(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 11x01 The Time Warrior
(whopix fan edit version)
(time axis: bamanzi)
(based on subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
(SPACESHIP WHIRRING)
Stars are falling!
It has fallen in the forest!
Come on, get up. Get up! Get up!
It is an omen.
- An evil sign! - It is mine.
Irongron's star. I will have it!
- Hurry. Fetch the horses.
- Hurry? Hurry where?
To find the star before some knave robs me of it.
It landed close by.
But the forest is still in darkness.
Who knows what demons may set upon us?
Why, you chicken-hearted knaves, every man of you!
It's but an hour till dawn! Let's wait till then.
To wait and see what faces us. We'll follow you then, Captain.
Let all be made ready. I ride at dawn. - Alone if need be.
We're with you, Captain.
Then bring me some wine.
We'll drink a toast to Irongron's star.
A star. A fallen star.
Careful, Captain, looks like the devil's work to me.
A warrior? A warrior from the stars!
Have you come to challenge me?
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
Flee for your life, Captain!
- What creature is this?
- 'Tis a devil from hell.
Peace.
Fear not. I shall not harm you.
It speaks. Who are you? Where do you come from?
I am a Sontaran officer.
My name is Linx.
Help you? Why should I help you, star warrior?
Why should I not kill you and take your ship
and its treasure for myself?
LINX: The ship is in need of repair.
Even if it were not, you would destroy
yourself should you tamper with it.
Then why should I not just slay you for sport?
Can you overcome all of us with your magic?
LINX: You are a soldier, are you not? A warrior?
I took this castle by force of arms.
Those that were here before me, I slew.
All the countryside around here pays my tribute.
Yet no doubt you have enemies?
Other warriors who envy your good fortune?
Aye, but they cannot harm me.
The king has levied tribute.
All their troops are at the wars.
And when they return?
Then we shall fight.
I can give you weapons,
weapons that can make you masters,
so that none dare stand against you.
You shall take what castles you will.
Magic weapons? Like that, that smote the sword from my hand?
Other weapons fitter for your purpose.
Weapons that can strike a man dead from far away.
- You can be supreme warrior.
- I can be king.
But what do you ask in return, apart from your life?
Shelter.
A place to conceal my ship and help with its repair.
- You have men that can work in metal?
- An armourer to sharpen weapons,
a smith with a forge if these will serve your need.
I need more, much more.
There is damage to the drive mechanism of my ship.
I need alloy, skilled technicians, complex circuitry.
Oh, we have none of these things of which you speak.
Then I must take them from those who have.
In here, Brigadier?
Yes, I'm afraid so, Doctor. Not exactly the Ritz, I know,
but it's no joke providing emergency accommodation
for all these scientists.
All right, Brigadier,
you've had your little bit of mystification.
Now I know where I'm supposed to stay,
perhaps you wouldn't mind telling me why?
This place is one of the most top secret
security establishments in the whole country.
Most of their work is so secret,
they don't know what they're doing themselves.
And?
It's also one of the best-guarded places in the country.
Security details, alarm systems...
I rather gathered that when we arrived.
For a moment I thought they weren't going to let you in.
Yes, exactly. The place is almost too security conscious.
That's what makes it all the more puzzling.
Makes what all the more puzzling?
Come on, Brigadier, you can tell me.
- People vanishing.
- People?
Well, they've lost. Half a dozen leading scientists
and several million pounds' worth of ultra-secret equipment.
What are they working on here anyway?
Space hardware. New alloys, guidance systems,
methods of propulsion.
- And what action have you taken so far?
- Well, I had rather a bright idea.
It's pretty hard to keep an eye
on all these scientist chaps at home,
so I had these cubicles put up on several floors.
Confined the whole lot to barracks,
all my eggs in one basket so to speak.
That's fine, so long as no one steals the basket.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Linx! My Lord Linx!
Will you open the door?
LINX: None may enter here.
Such was my agreement with your captain.
Yay, it is my captain who sent me.
He would have words with you, Lord Linx.
Then tell him I'm occupied. Now leave me to my work.
(BANGS ON DOOR)
Insolent primitives. Did I not need their aid...
Where is the star warrior?
He would not come. He says he's occupied.
Oh, the insolent barbarian.
Did I not need his help, I'd...
See, Bloodaxe. The first of the new weapons.
Watch!
Oh! Claps the ears!
I'll soon master the aim.
Rubeish.
- I beg your pardon?
- Joseph Rubeish.
Oh, I see. I'm so sorry. Hello. How do you do?
It's disgraceful, of course. Utterly disgraceful.
Oh? What is?
Well, shutting us up. Like a lot of kids kept in after school.
And that brigadier chap, military idiot.
Yes, I know how you feel. Still, he means well, you know.
Haven't seen my wife and family for three days.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Ah, well, just shows there's always a silver lining.
- And your name?
- Uh, Smith, Dr John Smith.
- Seems to be a lot of them about today.
- I'm sorry?
I was talking to a young woman just now, also Smith.
- Well, there she is. Miss Smith?
- Yes, Professor?
Come and meet your namesake.
- Miss Lavinia Smith, Doctor, uh...
- Dr John Smith.
- How do you do, Miss Smith?
- Hello.
Doctor, I'm intrigued. What's that for?
That? Oh, that, that contains my equipment, Professor.
That's original.
- You're the virologist, Miss Smith?
- Yes.
Who told you?
I read your paper on the teleological response of the virus,
- a most impressive piece of work.
- Thank you.
Particularly when I realised,
you must have written it when you were five years old.
Ah, uh... Yes, that is rather difficult to explain, isn't it?
You're going to try, aren't you?
Well, um... My Aunt Lavinia is in America
on a lecture tour, you see.
- Mmm-hmm.
- She had an invitation to visit here.
- I took her place.
- Why?
I thought all this might give me a good story.
I'm a journalist. Sarah Jane Smith.
You realise this is a very dangerous place to be in?
Well, I can't help that. I'm stuck here now.
Anyway, we've got all these soldiers looking after us.
Are you going to give me away, Doctor?
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
Well, you can make yourself useful.
We need somebody around here to make the coffee.
If you think I'm going to spend my time
making cups of coffee for you...
Professor!
Would you kindly desist? This is not a blackboard, you know.
Oh, I do beg your pardon, Doctor. I was just trying to prove...
What are you going to do in there?
Make myself a cup of coffee. Good day to you.
We caught this little rabbit in the forest, sire.
Sir Edward's squire.
- Are you loyal to your lord, boy?
- I am.
We shall see.
He carried this. He tried to eat it when we caught him.
Are Sir Edward's men so ill-fed?
Bah! I make nothing of their Norman scribbles.
- What's it say?
- I cannot read, Captain.
What's the message say, boy?
So your Sir Edward is going to attack me, eh?
Well, speak.
I know nothing.
Take him below. We'll loosen his tongue presently.
- Edward.
- What is it? Is Eric back?
- You haven't eaten all day.
- Why does he not return?
I could have ridden to my Lord
of Salisbury's castle three times over.
- It's not good for you to worry so much.
- How can I not worry?
Think that tomorrow will be brighter.
Edward, I've heard that Irongron
walks his battlements every morning.
Oh, it pleases him to be high. He's like a cockerel.
But does he climb so high that an arrow cannot reach him?
LINX: Irongron.
(IRONGRON CHUCKLING)
That strange armour you wear suits you, Linx.
- It is Sontaran space armour.
- But why must we never see your face?
This helmet conceals the fact
that I am not of your kind, Irongron.
You might not find my true appearance pleasing.
(CHUCKLING) By my sword, Linx,
I'll wage you're the fairest beauty in the castle.
Why did you summon me? You know my work is pressing.
I have a prisoner in the dungeon,
a surly fellow who will not speak.
- And you wish him to?
- Yes.
Then give him to me. I will make him speak.
Tell Bloodaxe to bring up the prisoner.
Well, Linx, you cunning old devil,
what fresh tricks can you show Irongron, eh?
What is the nature of the information you seek?
He's a messenger of those who plot a war against me.
A war? That is excellent.
- Oh, so you like war, eh?
- Who does not?
My race has been at war for millennia.
There is not a galaxy in the universe
which our space fleets have not subjugated.
But you do not understand me.
I am stranded on this primitive planet
when I should be leading my squadron to glory.
- I am an expert at war, Irongron.
- I know.
What about those weapons you promised me?
Keep your side of the bargain, I shall keep mine.
You shall have your weapons.
(GROWLING)
We make good allies, Linx.
Each has much that the other wants.
- Miss Smith...
- No, no, I'm the Doctor.
You really must keep your glasses
on the end of your nose, Professor.
No, no. Listen, she's not Miss Smith.
- She isn't?
- No. Who is she?
I don't think I quite understand
what you're talking about, Professor.
Just now I was in the common room with Sir Maxwell Dingle.
I happened to mention I was on the same landing
with Lavinia Smith, the virologist.
- And do you know what he says?
- Yes. He said that she's in America.
He said she's in... How could you know?
Please be careful! This is very delicate equipment.
What if she's a spy? What do we do?
- Shoot her?
- Ha! There's something odd about her.
She even tried to tell me you were a spy.
Am I on the right floor?
- Good night.
- Good night, Professor.
- What's that?
- That's my alarm clock.
Oh, Doctor, kindly don't be so patronising.
Now, what is it really?
It's a rhondium sensor. It detects delta particles.
Why do you want to be woken up
when it detects delta particles?
Because I am very fond of delta particles.
- Why do you ask so many questions?
- Because I'm a journalist.
- Are you going to sleep there?
- If you'll allow me to do so.
Good night, Miss Smith.
He has a stout heart, this one, sire. He speaks not a word.
Good. A fair measure for you, Linx.
(HUMMING)
Well, come on, Linx, have at him!
- Ask what you wish.
- Eh?
But you've done nothing.
This is a key. I have unlocked your prisoner's mind.
Question him.
How many men guard Sir Edward's castle?
There are but 10, old men for the most part.
And he plans to attack me with 10 old men?
He sends messages to raise a force against you.
If he succeed, then he will attack.
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
Listen to the fellow! He cannot stop babbling.
Stay, Linx! Have I given you leave?
Each of us has work to do, Irongron. I will be back.
(SNORING)
(PULSING)
Rubeish?
- Rubeish!
- What? Who is it?
Oh, it's all right. Nothing to worry about. Just checking.
- What's happening?
- You're asking questions again.
(PULSE ACCELERATING)
(CRASHING)
- Professor Rubeish?
- Rubeish!
- He's gone!
- Yes.
He was here a moment ago.
He can't have gone far.
He's as blind as a bat without his glasses.
You stay here, Miss Smith. I'm going to check the landing.
- Anybody come out of here just now?
- No.
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING ACCELERATING)
- What were they shooting at?
- Shadows.
Oh, come on, Doctor, stop treating me like a child.
I can't understand why the definition was so low.
Unless he's operating with a very weak
power source at maximum range.
- Yes, of course.
- BRIGADIER: Doctor?
- Doctor?
- Hello!
Look, Doctor, we've had a raid.
Is everyone present on this landing?
No. Professor Rubeish is missing.
Oh, my giddy aunt! The Minister will go spare.
Did you see anything, Doctor?
- Yes.
- What?
Well, I thought I saw a man in armour.
- A man in armour?
- Mmm-hmm.
You mean old-fashioned armour? You mean a ghost?
Oh, I very much doubt it.
- Sorry I can't stop, Brigadier.
- Why? Where are you going?
Well, I've got to get on the trail while it's still warm.
What trail? The chap's just vanished.
No, he hasn't. I just got a fix on him.
There's something very odd indeed going on.
Yes. Well, if I may say so, Doctor,
that is not exactly news to me.
(WHOOSHING)
Well done, old girl. Absolutely on target.
For once.
It's still only a police box.
I must find a telephone.
Sir Edward only has a puny force. He stands within his walls.
If we can only breach them, Bloodaxe.
We could cut Sir Edward's soldiers down
in less time than our rogues spend with their breakfasts.
It's those accursed walls, walls like these.
But with Linx's new weapons...
Excuse me, could you tell me where the nearest telephone...
He flees through the forest. Take him!
After him, you dogs! Through the forest!
Oh, it must be some sort of pageant. I say...
Hey, you there. Hey, what are you doing? Get off!
- Let go of me! Hey!
- How the blazes did she get here?
SARAH: Stop it!
Look, if this is a rag day joke, it's not funny!
- Come on!
- Let me go! I won't tell you...
(TWIG SNAPS)
I won't tell you again!
Look, I'm not amused. Stop it!
(TWIG SNAPS)
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
Make it keen.
I want Sir Edward not to know the moment
when his head is parted from...
(SHOUTING)
- What's this!
- She was found within bowshot, Captain.
Idiots! Why don't you stop this ridiculous pantomime?
She spits fire, eh, Bloodaxe? Come here, girl.
Get lost! Oh! Ow!
- She wears gold, Bloodaxe.
- That hurt, you fool!
You call Irongron a fool?
I'll have the marrow from your bones, my little chicken.
Where are you from?
Look, just pack this up, will you? It's not funny.
I happen to be a reporter, and I've got a big story...
Take her away, Bloodaxe. Throw her in the dungeon.
Why don't you take off that ridiculous gear
and go home to your butcher's shop?
Let go! Look, I warn you.
Any more of this and I'm going straight to the police.
- Stay, Bloodaxe!
- Captain?
Leave her.
That's better.
(SCOFFS) Now, if I could just use your telephone.
(MAN GROANING)
This is the dog that shot at you, Captain!
So you thought to kill Irongron, eh?
Aye, and I would but for her. She drew my aim aside.
You treacherous dog!
- Did Sir Edward send you?
- No.
- You lie!
- I speak the truth!
- If not Sir Edward, who then?
- I don't understand. Where am I?
It was my Lady Eleanor.
Ah, that narrow-hipped vixen.
Bloodaxe, tomorrow we dine at Wessex Castle.
Yes, Captain. And what of the prisoner?
Ere long we shall deal with him sharply.
(LAUGHING)
Sharply, eh? 'Tis richly put.
Aye. That'll be a fine jest, Captain Irongron.
I'm not one of your stuffy Norman nobles.
I like a bit of rough fun.
'Tis true, Captain, you have a merry wit indeed!
Look, please! Now you've had your laugh,
now, you know, just let's stop it and talk sensibly.
I mean, if it's any consolation to you,
you're scaring me out of my wits.
- Perhaps the wench is crazed, Captain.
- Oh, come on. What is this place?
You are in the castle of Irongron, my lady.
Few uninvited guests come here,
and few that do leave alive.
All right. If you insist on playing guessing games...
Now, it's not a village pageant.
It's too elaborate for that.
A film set. No, no lights, no cameras.
Aye, the wench is crazed, right enough.
And pity, she's not un-comely.
I've got it! It's one of those tourist places.
Uh, a medieval castle,
all restored to its original condition
with jolly banquets and buxom serving wenches.
That's it, isn't it?
Mind you, I think you're overdoing the sordid realism a bit.
I mean, I know things were pretty grotty in the Middle Ages,
but, really, you might leave the tourists
a bit of glamorous illusion.
I've never seen such a scurvy...
For pity's sake, cease this babbling, girl!
BLOODAXE: Captain.
Ah, Linx. What of my weapons? Are they ready?
Soon. But I have another weapon to show you.
- For your leave, master, the prisoner?
- Aye, aye.
- What is this?
- Eh?
- Oh, just a girl taken in the forest.
- Girl?
- You have two species on this planet?
- How say you?
The girl is not of your kind, Irongron.
The hair is finer. The thorax of a different construction.
Oh, hell's teeth, have you no girls beyond the stars?
- No women to do the lowly work?
- Ah, I understand.
You have a primary and secondary reproductive cycle.
It is an inefficient system. You should change it.
You what?
In the Sontaran Military Academy,
we have hatchings of a million cadets at each muster parade.
Thus we can sustain enormous casualties on all battlefronts.
You cluck away like a broody old hen.
Wait! This cloth is machine-woven.
The girl is not of your time, Irongron.
Oh, curse the girl! Show me the...
Who? What? How?
Sarah Jane Smith. Reporter.
In a machine. I did not understand it.
- What century?
- Twentieth.
Your civilisation knows nothing
of time-dimensional technology. Explain.
I cannot. It is a machine that
belongs to someone called the Doctor.
- Linx...
- Silence!
This is important. My mission is threatened.
Explain the Doctor.
He is a scientist. He was at the research centre.
He said he was very fond of delta particles.
Ah. Is he here?
Yes. Somewhere. I was hiding in the machine when he left.
It becomes clear.
Linx, what of the weapon?
Very well.
It is here.
Who are you? How do you come into my castle?
Well, speak fellow!
Answer me or lose your head for insolence!
It cannot answer you.
It is just a suit of steel. It is empty.
But it walks!
It walks. And it fights, Irongron. Is it a good weapon?
Does it kill?
It does nothing else and it cannot be killed.
By heavens, Linx, can you make me more of these?
If you wish.
With a few such soldiers as that, I could take the world!
When I have left this dull planet,
it would amuse me to think of it
under the rule of King Irongron.
Very well, provide me with all that I ask for
- and I can make many more of these.
- It's a bargain.
By heavens, Linx, I never thought when I first saw you
that I should come to love you as a brother.
Now, show me how the iron man works.
Wait. The girl creature has gone.
Oh, she'll not get far before one of my guards grabs her tail.
Now, show me. Show me how it fights. Make it walk again.
Sarah? Miss Smith. Come back!
- Stay! Bloodaxe.
- Sire.
- Would you fight for your life, fellow?
- I'll fight any man, my lord.
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
- Then stand against Irongron's champion.
- Who is this?
You'll see some sport now, Bloodaxe. Here, fellow.
Master, this is not fair combat
to pitch knight against bowman.
At this close range, his arrows'll
pierce the armour's weak points.
- Take aim, fellow.
- I am that.
Your freedom if you kill him. Stand back.
Your champion'll have more arrows
in his gizzard than a thistle has spikes.
My lord, look! He still moves!
(MEN LAUGHING)
What fool...
Guard your back, my lord!
BLOODAXE: Captain!
Psst!
By heavens, Bloodaxe, 'tis like a tin tadpole.
You cut off its head and yet it wriggles.
I'll have a word with Linx about this.
(GROWLING)
(MEN LAUGHING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
IRONGRON: Linx? Linx, you mongrel!
I have a bone to pick with you. Come here!
I am occupied, Irongron.
What! Out this minute or I'll burst the door down.
Well? What is it you need to say to me?
Didn't I tell you you might not find my face pleasing?
Aye, and never was truer word spoken.
Are they all so fair of face beyond the stars?
The variety of sentient life forms is infinite.
Do you think your primitive features are pleasing to me?
-Well, what is it you want?
-That accursed iron warrior of yours.
You are pleased with it?
Some knave with a crossbow shot the control from my hand.
The iron man became crazed, tried to kill all of us.
Perhaps the hand control unit itself is a weakness.
I will make you a better warrior, Irongron.
One that'll obey your voice perhaps.
First, help me kill the one I have now.
It still struggles to slay my knaves.
It cannot be killed. It was never alive.
Come, I will de-activate it.
Professor Morrison?
Professor.
Absolute lunacy.
- Rubeish!
- What? Who is it?
It's me. It's the Doctor. Don't you remember?
We were on the same landing at the research centre.
Oh, my dear fellow. So he's got you, too, has he?
No, hardly. Look, Professor,
what's wrong with all these people?
Hypnotised. Can't get a word out of them. Rotten company.
- Well, you seem to be all right.
- Oh, didn't work with me.
- Strong-minded, you see.
- Yes, and very nearly blind.
Oh, nonsense.
Obviously working some sort of ocular device.
Professor, have you any idea where you are?
Some medieval English castle, I suspect.
I've been feeling the carvings on some of these columns.
They're astonishingly well preserved.
Yes, you're in a castle all right,
but do you know the time?
About four in the afternoon.
We haven't had breakfast yet, you know.
Doesn't feed us much. Once a day if we're lucky.
Now, Professor, listen to me.
This may come as a shock to you so steel yourself.
You have been brought back
to the early years of the Middle Ages.
That's interesting.
I've always maintained that the Loop Theory of Time
shouldn't have been so arrogantly dismissed
by Crabshaw and his cronies.
Tell me about it some other time.
We've got to get out of here before Linx comes back.
Not yet, Doctor. This is the opportunity of a lifetime.
There's some most interesting work being done here.
If only I could see it all properly.
Professor, your life is in considerable danger.
I must insist you...
You go if you want to, Doctor. Go on, but leave me alone.
- Professor, don't you understand?
- Stop!
- 教授，你不明白吗？
- You are the one called the Doctor?
- You know who I am?
I have been expecting you. Why did you follow me to this time?
To prevent your interference with the affairs of Earth.
Don't you realise the harm that you'll cause?
This primitive planet and its affairs are of no importance.
That's a typically Sontaran attitude.
Only one thing matters, to complete the repairs to my ship
and return to the glorious war that is my destiny.
Nothing must interfere with that, nothing and nobody.
I vouch for her, my lord.
Without her help, I would not be here.
She looks like one I would trust.
Sit, child. Tell us where you're from.
I can't. It's too difficult to explain.
The manner of her dress is strange,
and the manner of her speech.
There is much strange at Irongron's castle, Sir Edward.
I told you of the knight that fights on
though it should be dead.
And one of the guards told me
there's a man from the stars that lives among them.
A mighty wizard who makes magic weapons.
A man from the stars.
I've heard it said he has the help of devils and magicians.
- It is true, Sir Edward. I have seen it.
- Well, I know who's helping him.
- It's the Doctor.
- The doctor?
Well, that's what he calls himself,
but he's no magician.
- Just some eccentric scientist.
- What does she say?
The words are strange, but I know her meaning.
Who is this doctor? What do you know of him?
Scientists, learned men.
They're being taken from the place I come from,
and I believe that the Doctor is bringing them here
and handing them over to Irongron.
What would Irongron want with these wizards?
To make him magic weapons, my lady.
Irongron thinks only of war and conquest.
Anything that makes Irongron strong can work only to our harm.
With an army of magic knights such as I fought,
Irongron could conquer the whole kingdom.
Who knows what other sorceries
he may soon have at his command?
I'm sure the Doctor's the key to it all.
He was there when one of the scientists was taken.
He has a machine that can travel through time.
Well, it must be him, and somehow we've got to stop him.
If he's Irongron's ally,
he sits safe within Irongron's walls.
There's nought we can do.
Oh, there's always something you can do.
It's just a matter of working out what.
- A brave speech.
- She has the heart of a lion, sire.
I saw her give Irongron the sharp edge of her tongue.
If I had an army of girls such as you,
I might hold this castle forever.
As it is, how can I fight Irongron and this doctor?
All right, I'll tell you how.
Now, the first thing we must do is grab the Doctor
and get him away from Irongron.
And force him to make his magic for me? Aha, good thought.
Aye, but how could it be done?
Oh, what's wrong with you?
All it needs is a sort of commando raid.
You knock out the sentries, rush into the castle,
grab the Doctor, and away.
- You've got soldiers, haven't you?
- A handful.
- 你手头有士兵吧，有吗
- A raid? A bold plan.
- I'll go, Sir Edward.
- 一个小队？这计划很大胆
You resisted well, Doctor.
I could have increased the power,
but I might have killed you.
I need you alive.
A brain of your capacity can be of use to me.
Thank you.
You're not of this planet. How came you to be here?
Oh, I'm just a tourist. I like it here.
- This hole in space?
- You haven't seen it at its best.
It has no military value, no strategic significance.
Once again, a Sontaran philosophy.
I'm Commander Linx, Fifth Sontaran Army Space Fleet.
Ah, yes. Yes, as I thought.
A Sontaran warrior.
So, the perpetual war between the Sontarans and the Rutans
- has spread to this tiny planet, has it?
- Emergency landing.
- 已经扩大到这个小星球了，是吗？
I was on a reconnaissance mission
when I was attacked
by a squadron of Rutan fighters.
You have encountered my race before, Doctor?
Unfortunately.
I'll overlook that insult for the moment.
- What is your native planet?
- Gallifrey. I am a Time Lord.
Ah, yes.
A race of great technical achievement,
but lacking the morale to withstand a determined assault.
- Oh, you think so?
- I'm only a lowly commander, Doctor.
I merely quote from the appreciation
circulated by our military intelligence.
Well, you'd be well advised
never to put that appreciation to the test, Linx.
My only ambition at the moment is to return to my squadron.
You can be of value to me. You can help repair this ship.
You seem to have acquired some help already.
Primitives. I adapted my ship's frequency modulator
and projected myself forward as far as I could.
Unfortunately, I only had the power
to reach the 20th century.
From which you stole the equipment
and the skilled help that you couldn't find here.
Yes.
But the work goes slowly.
Commander Linx, if you will return
these people to their own time,
I might possibly consider helping you.
Do not attempt to bargain with me, Doctor!
Take that seat there by the controls.
Move.
You're interfering with human evolution, Linx.
Don't you realise the damage
that you're going to do to them?
I have no interest in human evolution.
I'm placing you under auto-control, Doctor,
to ensure your complete cooperation.
Human beings must be allowed
to develop at their own pace.
At this period, they're just a few steps away from barbarism.
You will monitor progress rates on
the input panel against the programmer.
Now I must leave you in charge for a time.
You give them breech-loading guns now,
they'll have atomic weapons by the 17th century.
They'll have the capability to destroy their own planet
before they're civilised enough to handle it!
You would do well to concentrate
on the task I have given you, Doctor.
Answer the programmer.
I still say this is no work for women.
I wouldn't have missed this for anything.
Anyway, I'm the only one who knows
what the Doctor looks like.
Come on, this way.
Ah, now these are more to my taste
than your iron man, Linx.
I will still perfect the fighting robot
for your army, Irongron.
We'll take these weapons to the men, Bloodaxe,
and I shall instruct them in their use.
Rubeish! Professor, over here quickly.
Is that you, Doctor? I thought you were going.
- A change of plan. I want your help.
- Are you wearing a hat?
- 计划有变，我需要你的帮助
Behind me you'll find a panel. There's a switch on it.
It's dangerous, overheats the brain.
- Panel... Oh, yes, I've got it.
- Right, turn the switch.
I've always thought that's why judges are so peculiar.
It's those wigs they wear.
No! No! That's the wrong... No, no, man!
Sorry. I do wish I'd brought my glasses.
Yes, so do I. It was the wrong one.
Is this the one?
Yes, that was the one.
Thank you very much indeed, Professor.
- Not at all, Smith.
- Smith. Yes, of course.
Will you excuse me? I've got to go and find a young girl.
I'll see you later, I hope.
Young girl? I should've thought
he was a bit old for that sort of thing.
Oh, well.
Ah, good evening.
Get after him! Call the guards!
(SHOUTING)
Catch him!
Grab him! Grab him!
(SHOUTING)
He who strikes Irongron dies!
Doctor! Up here!
Thank you very much, Miss Smith. A most timely rescue.
This isn't a rescue, Doctor, it's a capture.
Let's get him out of here.
That fellow has the gall of a camel and the cunning of a fox!
You shall have your revenge, Captain.
He'll be with Sir Edward now.
And not even a rat will come out of that castle alive tomorrow.
By the stars, Bloodaxe, I swear I'll chop him up so fine
not even a sparrow will fill its beak at one peck!
One of my workers has disappeared.
Order a search of your castle.
If you've lost one of your dumb, whey-faced ninnies, Linx,
then look for him yourself. My men are at rest.
We march on Sir Edward within the hour.
I insist upon a search, Irongron.
The Doctor is of great value to me.
And while he is at large, he could be dangerous.
The Doctor?
Bother me now, little toad,
and you will feel an axe in your skull!
Master, I heard someone call ''Doctor''
while we were at that fellow's heels.
Is this Doctor a long shank rascal with a mighty nose?
That is how he would appear in human eyes.
Then he is no longer here.
Sir Edward sent raiders to my castle,
captured him.
He has escaped!
- Tell Sir Edward we're back.
- Yes.
- Now...
- You've been getting around, Sarah.
Are you on visiting terms with all the local nobility?
Doctor, let's get a few things straight, shall we?
Oh, dear. I'm afraid you're going to be awfully confused
if you ask me to explain about the Tardis.
- The Tardis?
- Yes, my police box.
You were a stowaway, I imagine.
Yes, but we'll come to that later.
- Now then, why are you helping Irongron?
- My dear girl, I'm not helping him.
- 现在说说，你为什么要帮 Irongron？
Linx is. I'm trying to stop him.
SARAH: Linx?
Yes, perhaps you're lucky enough not to have met him yet.
Nasty, brutish and short just about sums him up.
There was a strange-looking knight with Irongron.
Yes, he'd have looked even stranger
if he hadn't been wearing space armour.
He comes from a planet
where the surface gravity is many times that of Earth.
- A man from the stars?
- Mmm-hmm.
- How do I know you're telling the truth?
- Because I never lie.
Well, hardly ever.
You ever heard of UNIT?
You work for UNIT?
In an advisory capacity, yes.
They asked me to look into this question
of the missing scientists for them.
But I thought you were responsible for that.
My dear girl, I don't go round kidnapping scientists!
No, Linx brought them here to staff his workshop.
Now I've got to find a way of
sending them back to their own time.
- This is the magician?
- Yes. This is the Doctor.
You have done well, Sarah.
How do you do?
It is a pleasure and a privilege
to be in the company of civilised people at last.
A courtly rogue.
Is he willing to change his allegiance
and serve Sir Edward instead of Irongron?
Well, he says he wasn't serving Irongron.
And there is another stranger at the castle,
someone called Linx.
Yes, he's your enemy, I assure you,
not me.
We'd be well advised to join forces against him.
- Does he speak truth?
- I'm not sure.
I suppose I could have been wrong.
That's a generous admission.
Especially coming from one of the fair sex.
Or he could just be changing sides to save his own skin.
These wizards and warlocks were ever a treacherous breed.
We'd best be wary of him.
I shall spare your life
if you cast your spells and incantations
to help me against Irongron, Doctor.
Refuse and you die.
You offer a somewhat restricted choice, Sir Edward.
EDWARD: What is your answer?
My services are at your disposal, sir.
- Such as they are.
- Good.
Serve me straight, Doctor, and I shall reward you well.
Oh, master... Oh, but, master,
Irongron marches here before noon!
We heard this said from his own mouth.
Then we are lost. We cannot stand against them.
- On the contrary, sir, I think we can.
- But how? With a handful of men?
Yes, sir, with just a few men I think
I can persuade Irongron that we have a full garrison.
By the use of your magic?
By creating an illusion, anyway.
Your magic will have to be powerful
indeed to discourage Irongron.
It will be, sir.
- The men are ready, Captain.
- Good.
Though for such an easy conquest as this,
'tis scarce worth strapping on armour!
You and I alone, good Bloodaxe, could take that castle!
Indeed we could, Captain.
With Sir Edward's treasure I shall hire more men,
and with Linx's weapons to arm them,
who shall stand against us?
When does the fighting start, Irongron?
In the time it takes to ride from here to Sir Edward's castle.
- Then I shall come with you.
- What, you?
Ha! Bloodaxe, on my oath,
can you see that on a scaling ladder?
I have an interest in seeing the battle.
Those eyes have a thirst for blood.
Well, find our bold warrior a horse, Bloodaxe.
Come, then!
- Here's a few more for you, Doctor.
- Thank you, Sarah.
Lady Eleanor's got every serving wench
in the castle sewing away like mad.
I told you there'd be plenty of work
for everybody, didn't I?
Oh. Typically masculine arrangement, though.
We do all the dirty work, you get all the fun.
You don't think mixing this singularly noxious compound is fun, do you?
- How's the rest of it going?
- Not bad.
I put Sir Edward in charge of painting the dummies' faces.
He's turned out to be quite an artist.
- Once I'd set him on the right lines.
- Excellent.
- I'm glad I decided to let you stay.
- You decided?
You know, I was never much of a hand
with a paint brush myself.
- No?
- No.
Nor a palette knife for that matter.
I'd like to study under one of the masters one day.
Rembrandt, preferably.
- Rembrandt!
- Mmm-hmm.
Can you... Can you just go anywhere
you like in that Tardis?
Yes, within reason.
Then why are you staying here?
Why don't you go somewhere safer?
Because, my dear Sarah, I've got a job to do.
One that involves the whole future of your species.
Here, hold this will you?
- My species?
- Mmm-hmm.
You're talking as if you weren't human.
Well, the definition of the word ''humanity''
was always rather a complex question, wasn't it?
You know perfectly well what I mean.
Are you or aren't you?
If you mean am I a native of the planet Terra,
the answer is no, I'm not.
- Well, what are you, then?
- Me? I'm a Time Lord.
- A Time Lord?
- Yes, that's right.
And my people are very keen
to stamp out unlicensed time travel.
You can look upon them as
galactic ticket inspectors if you like.
- Galactic ticket inspectors?
- Mmm-hmm.
I could murder a cup of tea. You're serious, aren't you?
About what I do, yes. Not necessarily the way I do it.
That's made them stop and think, anyway.
They've got guns!
No man has fallen, Captain!
- Your weapons do not work, Linx!
- You do not shoot them straight!
Watch.
- LINX: Those figures are dummies.
- Bah, your weapons are useless!
- 那些是假人
They do not move nor fall. They are not living men.
IRONGRON: I smell that fox of a Doctor behind this.
Bring up the scaling ladders!
Here they come, Doctor!
(MEN YELLING)
Away! Away!
Come on, move it!
What was that stuff, Doctor? Some kind of gas?
Gas?
Good heavens, what on earth do you take me for?
No, it was some sort of superior stink bomb
with a few bangs and flashes thrown in for good measure.
It's quite harmless, I assure you, but...
(SNIFFING)
(MEN COUGHING)
Bring me wine! Wine, I say!
To quench the dust from my throat
and the stench from my nostrils.
More, wench, more!
Am I a sparrow to quench my thirst
with a few scant drops?
Ooh, mice!
A few loud noises, a few bad smells
and you scatter like sheep!
It was sorcery, master.
Black devil's work. You said so yourself.
This wizard, the Doctor, he's gone and joined Sir Edward,
and he threw all the fires and the stenches of hell itself at us!
With poltroons like these,
it were ill work to lay siege to a hen coop!
They do but need food and rest to recover their spirits, Captain.
We attack again tomorrow morning.
I will take Sir Edward's castle
or I will see every man of you perish in the attempt!
Chicken-hearted knaves!
Begone from my sight!
Did I not see you yourself leading their retreat, Captain?
Taunt me not, little toad face.
Or by the stars I'll see if the colour
of your blood is red like mortal man's.
You Earth creatures give up too easily.
I doubt if you have the potential
to make a truly military species.
And you, Linx, you claim to like war.
- I haven't seen you doing much this day.
- I came only to observe.
I should have known better than
to look for interest in a struggle of primitives
Threaten me once more and I will destroy you.
Why, you...
Primitives! Childish, squabbling primitives!
It is well I do not need to spend much more time among you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
EDWARD: More wine, Doctor?
No, thank you, no. Oh, well, just perhaps a little.
Those knaves of Irongron's, they ran like rabbits!
Finest sight that ever I saw, Doctor.
And all thanks to you and your wizardry.
Well, we all played our part, Sir Edward.
Now your magic works for us, our troubles are over.
No, not quite, I'm afraid.
The Doctor thinks Irongron's bound to attack again.
And you shall affright the knaves with more of your sorceries.
It won't work indefinitely, I fear.
This time we had the element of surprise.
They won't be frightened off quite so easily again.
Then we've gained a respite. No more.
Actually, the Doctor does have another idea.
Then let us hear your counsel, Doctor.
So far you have served us well.
Well, there's one sure way to prevent Irongron
from capturing your castle.
And that is?
You must capture his.
(SCOFFS)
You advise the impossible, Doctor.
They outnumber us so greatly.
My lady, are you familiar with these herbs and simples?
Ragwort, henbane, love-in-a-mist, fennel, sesame.
Most we have dried in the kitchens.
The rest grow in the woods nearby.
Excellent. I want to brew up a little draught.
You mean to mix a magic potion to slay the dog?
No, not quite. Just something
to calm him down a little.
I should have slain the filthy little toad there and then.
I should have carved him up
into callops on the spot.
Aye, master, it puzzles me
as to why you did not.
Aye, well 'tis a matter of high policy, do you see?
Above your understanding, hmm?
As yet, we still need Linx's aid.
Weapons he has promised me and by the stars,
weapons I shall have.
Wonderful, magical weapons,
that will crumble the castles of those that oppose me into dust.
And then, and only then,
shall Linx die by my hand!
Oh, 'tis a cunning plan, Captain.
Aye, 'tis as well for you dolts that you have me to guide you.
(CHUCKLES)
There's more to war than hard strokes, my good Bloodaxe.
Aye, master.
Yours is indeed a towering intelligence.
Hold, Friar. What business have you here?
We come to beg alms of the good Captain Irongron.
The fame of his charity is spread far and wide.
You will find Captain Irongron in the great hall.
He is indeed a kindly and charitable man
and his temper is most sweet and pleasant.
Pass, Friar.
Heaven will reward you, my son. Come, brother.
(CHUCKLES)
'Tis to be hoped the two friars are fleet of foot,
or the church will have two new martyrs ere long.
(DOOR RATTLING)
What's that?
That's a Sontaran spaceship, to be precise,
and tremendously powerful for its size,
just like its owner.
Here, give me your habit.
- What's wrong with him?
- Deep hypnosis.
Ah, there you are, Doctor! Back again, eh?
- SARAH: Professor Rubeish!
- What?
Oh, it's you!
Doctor, I knew this girl was involved.
We should have reported her as I wanted.
Yes, well, I'm very glad we didn't.
In a few hours, that ship's going to be ready for takeoff.
Yes, he's been working these people at a killing pace.
Come over here.
Look.
No sleep. Practically no food.
They're starting to collapse like flies.
I'm not surprised. He's suffering from near starvation.
We'll have to get them some food, Doctor,
or at least a drink.
- There's no time for that.
- They'll die if we don't.
Sarah, listen to me.
Linx's spaceship is just about ready for takeoff.
And when that happens, there's going
to be the most tremendous explosion.
Everybody in this castle will die.
These are the weapons I have promised you.
Also a good supply of the projectiles that they use.
Oh, my thanks, good toad face... Good Linx.
More weapons from the stars.
I shall complete the repairs of the improved fighting robot
if I have time before I leave.
If you wish to leave, then you would do well to obey me.
Do you threaten me?
I leave when I am ready, and that will be soon.
And will you carry your starship on your back, good toad?
You needed my knaves to bring it here,
you will need them to take it hence.
Evidently you have no understanding
of the forces involved in interstellar travel.
I shall leave when I am ready.
It would be foolish of you to attempt to stop me.
Doctor, what are you doing?
- Trying to break this hypnosis.
- It's very deep.
Narcoleptic condition, eh?
The brain can still receive signals, Professor.
Why can't you just send them as they are?
It's too risky with their minds in this state.
The transition might damage them permanently.
I've never heard so much gobbledegook in me life.
But I expect you know what you're talking about.
- Polka time!
- BOTH: What?
It's the beat. Look, he's beginning to respond.
Hide!
Up!
Get back to work!
Work! What's wrong with you?
Get up or I will kill you!
- Leave him, Linx!
- Ah!
How fortunate that you have returned, Doctor.
My failure to destroy you
was the one thing that marred the pleasure
of my approaching departure from this miserable planet.
Don't you want to know why I've returned?
It is of no interest to me.
I came here to offer you my help.
We're sworn enemies, Doctor. Why should you help me?
Because I want something from you.
If you will let me de-hypnotise people
and send them home
and help me capture Irongron and his men,
then I will assist you in the repairs to your spaceship.
Now, the weapons that you've made for Irongron
you can leave here in the castle.
When it's empty, you can take off,
destroying castle and weapons at the same time.
All right, Commander Linx,
what do you say?
- You wish for my answer, Doctor?
- I do.
Then here it is.
SARAH: No!
The female, too. It seems I am doubly fortunate.
- Get up. Get back to work!
- DOCTOR: Linx.
Can't you see that your prisoners
are physically exhausted?
They've had no sleep and nothing to eat for days.
- They can still work!
- Not for much longer.
LINX: I owe these primitives nothing.
My only concern is to rejoin our glorious struggle for freedom.
DOCTOR: That's such an old tune.
Don't you know there's no such thing
as the super race?
Your Time Lord philosophy is egalitarian twaddle.
It is a weakness.
Every species has its own weakness, Linx.
For instance, you can only be stunned
by a blow on the probic vent,
that small hole at the back of your neck.
LINX: In our case, Doctor, it is a strength,
because it means we must always face our enemies.
Now, to return to the question of your demise.
I think it would be better
if you witnessed first the destruction
of your female companion.
Well done, Rubeish.
- Doctor, are you all right?
- Yes.
Yes. The blast was too brief.
But I wouldn't have been in a few moments.
- Thank you very much, Sarah.
- Oh, pleasure.
Hadn't I better be getting on with the rest of your plan?
- Yes. All right, but be careful.
- You, too, Doctor.
Right. Well, if we can secure our friend here,
we can get on with the job of restoring
his wretched victims.
Will this help?
Rubeish, you're invaluable, my dear chap.
- Bloodaxe.
- Captain.
Fetch me Linx.
Fetch me that scabby-faced stoat from his burrow.
At once, Captain.
Well, that should hold him for a while,
even on this planet.
Why this planet?
Well, in his own environment, he weighs several tons.
Fortunately, his muscles have been designed
for load bearing rather than leverage
Fascinating.
I'd always assumed that creatures
from a high-density planet
would have developed a pressure-balanced physiology.
For example, if you take certain types of seaweed...
BLOODAXE: Linx! Linx!
-Linx?
-DOCTOR: Who speaks?
Captain Irongron commands your presence.
Tell him I'm busy.
Well, come soon or we come and fetch you.
Who is Irongron? Is he a nice chap?
Well, I wouldn't recommend him
for the Royal Society.
All right, Rubeish, you know how
to bring these people round?
- Yes. A simple, repetitive optical...
- Yes, quite so.
- 是，很简单，一直进行光学的...
- I'll leave you to get on with it.
- What do you propose to do?
- 我就把这个事情留给你了
I was going to preset this osmic projector.
Send these people back to their own time.
But now I have to find a way of stalling Irongron.
The robot! Yes, of course.
Thief!
You common scullion, stand aside!
How dare you obstruct me?
I shall have you flogged.
Oh, so, a lady, are you?
- A lady dressed as a serving wench?
- I'm hungry.
- 一位小姐穿得跟个侍女一样？
Please let me go. I've tasted neither
bread nor meat for nearly a month.
No, nor done no work for longer
by the look of you.
All right, my girl, I'll give you bread and cheese,
but you'll have to earn it.
Who are you?
DOCTOR: I am a gift to Captain Irongron
from the one who made me, my master, Commander Linx.
It is indeed the robot, Bloodaxe, though somewhat different in shape.
And I remember, Linx promised
to make me a second iron man,
one that would obey my voice.
But why has Linx sent you?
Why has he not himself obeyed my summons?
My master toils in his workshop to make you more fighting robots.
- He sent me as proof of his goodwill.
- What?
- Now I must return.
- Hold.
I would see something of the mettle of this gift.
- Can you fight, iron man?
- That is my purpose.
Then fight me.
I was programmed to fight for you,
not against you.
- Cease thy gabble and fight.
- You will damage my circuits.
Fight, iron man,
or you'll return to Linx in as
many pieces as did your brother.
(SWORDS CLASHING)
What's that?
Oh, fighting again in the great hall, I'll warrant.
Men were ever like children, fond of noise and brawling.
Get about your work, girl.
Hold!
Hold, I say!
We must slow this iron man's speed a little.
Stick me some crossbow bolts in the creature.
We'll see if it fights as well with
a crossbow bolt or two in its gizzard.
And if that fails,
we'll lop off its head and try again then.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Isn't that a bit unsporting, old man?
I mean, sitting ducks and all that.
This iron man talks like some Norman ninny.
- Lift up your visor.
- I cannot reveal my face, Irongron.
- 抬起你的面具
Why?
Because if I did, it might give you a seizure.
- The wizard!
- Well, I did warn you, didn't I?
Seize him!
No.
The sword is too quick and clean a death for you.
Look at that great spider!
(SCREAMS)
Now listen, all of you.
You've been kidnapped, but you're about to be rescued, I hope.
There's a machine here that'll send you home again.
Unfortunately, I don't know how to work it,
and the chap who does has vanished.
But I expect he'll pop up again.
He usually does.
But the important thing is,
until then, you must carry on working
as if you were still hypnotised.
- Can I ask...
- Morrison, don't start asking a lot of awkward questions
I assure you, I don't know the answers any more than you do.
-IRONGRON: Linx!
Back to work, everyone. Someone's coming.
Linx, you dog!
Where are you hiding?
Oh, there you are, you dragon-eyed toad.
- Who put these bonds on you?
- The Doctor.
I was struck from behind.
- Where is he?
- The Doctor is dying.
What method have you chosen to destroy him?
Thank you, sir, for your charm and old world courtesy.
May I ask the purpose of this tomfoolery?
If you're going to have me shot,
why don't you get on with it?
I would not have your death be in vain, good sorcerer.
I intend that it shall be of some use to me.
Nothing that I do will be of use to you, Irongron.
Oh, nay, Doctor, but you're wrong.
These knaves of mine lack practice with their star weapons.
A living target will give them a chance
to better their aim before tomorrow's battle.
You, shoot!
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
These knaves of mine aim so ill, Doctor,
that you are mayhap safer to stand still.
You, shoot!
The aim improves, Doctor. Be patient.
We shall hit the target all in good time.
I'm in no great hurry, I assure you.
Oh, beshrew me, but I grow fond of this fellow.
Shoot when you please, lads, and a bag of gold
to the one that brings him down.
(GUNS FIRING)
By the stars! This fellow hops around
like a flea on a griddle.
Give me a weapon. I will destroy him.
What? Would you spoil good sport, old toad?
(GUNS FIRING)
Doctor!
Well done, Sarah. Come on.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(IRONGRON SHOUTING)
Sarah, wait.
(DOCTOR WHISTLING)
Do you know, I think that was one of
the most active days that I've had in years.
Well, it's not as if I was a lad any more,
once you're over 200.
So then, Doctor, your plans have miscarried, I fear.
- What will you do now?
- Oh, wait a bit.
Give the potion time to work and then go back.
- Doctor, you can't!
- Sarah, I must.
Rubeish and all those scientists are there.
Linx's spaceship is just about ready for takeoff,
and when that happens, there'll be a tremendous explosion.
All that will be left of that castle
will be a pile of stones.
Irongron's castle is to be destroyed
by sorcery? Then all is well.
There are innocent people in that castle, my lady,
and I don't like the idea of anybody going up in smoke.
Not even Irongron.
If you're going back, then I'm coming with you.
I, too, will come with you if my master permits.
Well, thank you. Thank you both.
I can do with all the help I can get.
Thank you, my friends. Your work is finished.
You may rest now for a time
until the power build-up is complete.
Doctor, I think you'd better get a move on.
- Good evening.
- It's working, Doctor. Look.
Aye, the villains sleep like innocent babes.
Good.
Well, we'll wait a bit to be on the safe side, then we'll go in.
At last, Doctor, there you are.
Something most interesting happening here.
Yes, I see. Where's Linx?
I don't know. He started his spaceship going then cleared off.
Where's the osmic projector?
It was over there on the table.
He put everything back inside the ship.
I'll just have to take it out again, won't I?
Hal, scout around the castle.
See if Irongron and his men are sleeping.
If they are, disarm them and come back here.
What are you going to do, Doctor?
Get the osmic projector.
Fortunately, it's an independent unit.
- Can't you switch this thing off?
- Well, I can try.
Suppose you don't succeed?
Then we've got between five and ten
minutes to get out of here
before we're all blown to kingdom come.
(MAN SNORING)
- Couldn't you shut it down?
- No, the drive system is sealed.
Linx must have taken the activator key.
I managed to get a hold of this, though.
I was lucky to get it out with the drive running.
I think that should do it.
I've got to send them back one at a time.
Get the first one to stand over there,
will you, Rubeish?
Come on, Morrison.
All right, Rubeish, come over here.
I may want you to take over.
Now then, all you have to do is this,
- this and this. Get it?
- Yeah.
Right, here goes.
Right, that ought to surprise them
back at the research centre.
- Next gentleman, please.
- Come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
For the last time, Linx,
let there be no more talk of leaving.
And I tell you for the last time,
I am leaving now.
Our alliance is at an end.
It ends when I say it ends and not before.
You would be well advised to march
from this castle now and capture another.
Soon you will have need of it.
- He threatens us, Captain.
- He does not understand our ways.
Tomorrow, Linx, we smite the enemy, hip and thigh!
But tonight, we feast.
By your dawn, I shall be 700 million miles from here.
Can I be concerned with the fate of primitives?
(ALL LAUGHING)
What did he mean, Captain?
He is a toad.
Who knows what a toad thinks?
Aye, Captain, 'tis truly said.
This stew has made me heavy.
Eh?
That's Linx.
Send the rest of them back.
I'll try and keep him busy.
(SNORING)
Trickery! Sorcery!
- Now you, Professor.
- I really don't think
- I ought to go and leave you.
- Off you go now.
- Now then, this, this and this.
- Well, goodbye and good luck.
It really was the most fascinating experience.
I hope you and the Doctor will be all right.
See you back at research centre.
SARAH: Doctor!
So...
destroy my castle by sorcery, would you, toad face?
Well, Irongron's magic is too strong for you!
Now listen, dog!
In minutes now, this castle
will be destroyed by the sorcery.
If you'd save your miserable skins, then get you gone!
Flee, dogs!
Flee for your life! Come on, waken, you dogs!
And flee! Flee for your lives, you dogs!
Waken! Waken up! Now flee!
Doctor, do get up. We've got to get you out.
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Something's gone wrong.
He must have hit the takeoff button too soon.
Come on, we've got about a minute
to get out of here. Quick! Run!
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING BUILDS)
(BUZZING INTENSIFIES)
Well, you can tell Sir Edward
that his problems are over, Hal.
Irongron, his castle,
his magic weapons and his sorcerer,
they're all destroyed.
Will you not tell him yourself, Doctor?
He will reward you well. We owe you much.
I'm sorry. I'm afraid we must be off.
- Goodbye, Hal.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- Goodbye.
You are truly a great magician, Doctor.
To tell you the truth, Hal, I'm not a magician at all.
I'm not so sure about that.
(WHOOSHING)