Let him go.
Now then - turn off that machine.
I have to report that we have lost the trace.
It was operating only a few moments.
We are not interested in excuses.
Find them! Find them! Find them!
No last words of repentance, Sir Reginald?
No, only that you're making one fundamental mistake...
That is?
A question of mistaken identity.
I am not Sir Reginald Styles.
Is that the best you can do?
But it's true! Sir Reginald...
Sir Reginald is at this moment many thousands of miles away - in Peking, to be precise.
You are lying.
No, I'm not. He flew there yesterday.
I do not believe you.
It's all there in the paper in front of you. Why don't you take a look?
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
It's a trick - kill him now!
If you are not Sir Reginald Styles who are you and what are you doing in his house?
Well, believe it or believe it not, I came here to see you.
We're wasting time, Anat. Here, I'll do it.
Who is in command of this mission?!
We are soldiers, not murderers. Keep guard outside, I'll deal with these two.
I said out!
Now then, answer my question - who are you and what are you doing here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
- Why?
To find out where you came from.
And more to the point - when.
Two soldiers approach.
Hide!
Down there!
Hurry!
Captain Yates, sir, on four.
I can't speak to him now.
He says something very odd is happening at Auderly House.
If you could have a quick word with him, sir?
All right.
Yes, what is it, Yates?
A couple of my men missing, sir, and the Doctor
and Miss Grant - not a sign of them.
Look really, Yates, I've got a major international
crisis on. I really haven't got time for any...
Oh, Lethbridge-Stewart?
Erm, yes, yes, that's right?
Yes, it's the Minister here.
One moment, sir. Listen, Yates, search the grounds
again or report back to me - out!
Yes, Minister?
Right, they're clear of the house. Have you finished?
- Yes.
- We must go.
Quietly!
Oh, that's better.
You know, I've got a good mind to let you
stay like that! So much more peaceful.
In any case, even if I released you,
you'll probably ask me a lot of fool questions!
I've only got one question - who are they?
On the face of it, three rather desperate people.
Well, they're criminals - they must be!
Ah, you're prejudiced.
Well, aren't you? They tried to kill you and me.
That's not in their favour, I'll admit.
You know, we shouldn't really judge 'em
until we find out why they're here.
We are maintaining constant watch, but there is
no sign of any time transference module in operation.
All criminal elements must be tracked down and destroyed.
Well, I am doing everything possible, but...
They will have returned to the time zone
where the first criminal was eliminated.
You will dispatch security forces to search for them.
Of course... at once.
And the new equipment?
The Time Vortex Magnetron is set to the frequency
of the module that was traced.
Anyone using that module will be diverted
in the space-time vortex and attracted here.
But only if that particular module is used?
It is necessary to know the frequency.
But surely no one will use the module?
They must realise that we can trace them...
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
The function of the human is to obey!
Activate the Magnetron!
...to base. Intercept to base.
Do you coordinate? Do you coordinate? Intercept...
No good. There is a massive disturbance in the vortex.
We cannot fail again. This is our last chance.
We must get fresh orders.
The time coordinates are crucial.
We cannot wait for new orders!
Look, why don't I return to the tunnel?
There's better chance of contact there.
Right, Shura. Ask them...
Why ask them anything? Isn't it obvious what we must do?
We wait here and kill Styles.
And if we are detected?
We hold those two as hostages.
We kill them if necessary.
Get alternative orders.
Right./
What do you mean, missing?
Well, there's not a sign of them.
We searched the house and the grounds, sir.
The Doctor, Jo and a couple of my men - vanished.
Now listen, Yates, I've been talking to the Minister.
Styles seems to have pulled it off.
The Chinese have agreed to attend
and the conference is on again.
Oh, when's it fixed for?
Tomorrow night, so you see the spot this puts me in!
Get me Auderly House!
Where is he?
I told you, Anat.
I just don't understand. I mean,
why don't they go back to September 12th
if that's where they want to be -
you know, have another go.
Well, that's the Blinovitch limitation effect.
The what?
On your feet, both of you!
Honestly, sir. You're wasting your time -
he's not there.
Hello? Hello?
Doctor?
Yes?
Lethbridge-Stewart.
Ah.
Is everything all right there?
Yes fine, Brigadier. Yes, things couldn't be better.
Yates and Benton came to look for you.
Said the place was deserted.
Did they? Oh yes, we were probably
down the cellar at the time. /56.8
Old Styles keeps a remarkably
good selection of wines, you know.
Now listen, Doctor, you're sure that
everything is normal down at that house?
Because Styles is coming back there tomorrow night.
Look, I... I don't think that's very wise, Brigadier...
Well, why not if everything's all right?
It is all right, isn't it, Doctor?
Captain Yates was very concerned about you.
Well, you tell Captain Yates not to worry, everything's fine.
And tell old Styles too, and the Prime Minister.
Right.
Oh, and Brigadier?
Yes?
Don't forget to tell it to the marines. Goodbye.
There you are, sir. I said there was something wrong.
I'm going down to that house myself.
Lay on a jeep for me, will you?
I'll meet you there later.
He's coming! Sir Reginald Styles is coming here.
Well that surprises you? Well, I should have thought
with your insight into the future...
oh no, in your case, it'd be the past, wouldn't it?
The conference tomorrow night -
our dates were right after all.
All we have to do is to wait here
until he returns and then...
Right! Drop your guns! If you don't,
I'll smash this to pieces.
Jo, put that thing down.
I've only just got it in working order.
I mean it.
Stupid child! You do not know what you are doing!
Oh yes I do - you're going to let us both out
- or you'll be stranded here for ever.
We don't need that machine. We have another one.
The man who owned that machine is dead.
His body is back in our time zone.
You're... bluffing.
Put it down and don't be silly!
Jo, do as she says.
Drop it... drop it!
Jo! Jo!
Look, can't you do anything?
No, it's too late.
Well, what... what's happened to her?
Disintegrated, dispersed around the time vortex.
If she was lucky.
And if she wasn't?
Re-embodied in the twenty-second century.
Believe me, she would be better off dead.
You may go.
You see, they're really not as terrifying as they look.
What are they?
Ogrons. They're a form of higher anthropoid.
They used to live in scattered communities
on one of the outer planets.
They make very useful servants.
Servants? Well, what do they do?
Oh, we use them as... policemen.
They're very simple, very honest, very loyal.
Do please sit down.
Thank you.
Is this really the... twenty-second century?
Oh, don't worry. We can return you to
your own time, but, er, tell me Miss, erm?
Grant, Jo Grant.
Miss Grant... these three people
who attacked you - what did you make of them?
Well, they were sort of... guerillas, I suppose.
They are cruel and ruthless fanatics.
You know who they are?
Unfortunately, yes. But what you don't know,
is how lucky you are
that they didn't get rid of you straight away.
They tried to kill the Doctor.
He's still with them, is he - this friend of yours?
Yes, they're holding him prisoner.
Then I am afraid he is in very grave danger.
But they've no reason to harm him!
They know he's the wrong man!
You don't know these people!
We have spent years trying to track them down.
If you knew some of the terrifying crimes
they have been capable of!
If anyone stands in their way, they are without mercy.
I can believe it.
However, there is a chance that
I may be able to save your friend.
Could you?!
I can try. There are means but I shall need your help.
Well, how can I help?
Well, first of all, I shall want to know exactly
where you came from... and when.
Well, we were at Sir Reginald Styles' house,
about... fifty miles from London.
Now, you've told me the year,
can you tell me the exact date?
That's easy - it was September the 13th.
Excellent.
Now, you must be tired, you must be hungry.
We do have special guest rooms.
Leave everything to me.
Oh, there is one last question...
these criminals - can you tell me exactly
where they entered your time?
I mean, did they manifest themselves in the house itself?
I don't think so.
Somewhere outside the house - some hiding place?
I don't know for sure, but there's a tunnel
by a canal, not far from the house.
We found that... time machine there.
A tunnel? Thank you.
I'll call you as soon as we have any news.
You see? She trusts me implicitly.
The criminals are using the tunnel as a transfer point.
We will prepare an ambush in the twentieth-century time zone.
We have security forces in the area. With any luck,
they will drive the guerillas straight into our hands.
Anat! Look!
Shoot!
Pull back!
We can get through the library. Come!
Stay where you are! Boaz, get out!
Boaz, come on!
Come on, Boaz, out! Out, out!
How do you do?
Doctor, what on earth's going on?
Thank you, Brigadier, for that timely intervention.
Who is that creature.
Yes, well, I'll explain about him later.
Excuse me, old chap, I'm in a hurry.