Stop! You mustn't kill him!
- Be silent.
- Don't you realise he can help us?
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks.
How can he help us?
He is our contact with the guerrillas.
He has valuable information.
- You have proof of this?
- I know he's working for them.
We will force the truth from him
with the mind analysis machine.
But look at him!
You've practically killed him just
getting a simple admission of identity.
He'll die before
he tells you anything else.
What is your plan?
Let me interrogate him.
Why should you be more successful?
Because I understand human psychology.
I shall be able to gain his confidence.
To put pressure on him through the girl.
By the time I have finished with him,
I shall be able to crush the guerrilla
organisation entirely!
Release him.
Now, the control centre is here.
As far as we know, they're being held
prisoner in this block here.
And how do we get through?
The disused underground railway of the old city.
There's an exit right by this wall.
I know the Doctor
would help you if he could.
I am trying to help him!
I've already saved his life.
Yes, for your own purposes.
Look, if you do not tell me where they operate from,
what their plans are,
then the Daleks will destroy both of you.
I don't doubt it.
Do you value life so little?
On the contrary, I value it enormously.
The Daleks will kill us whatever we tell you.
Not if you cooperate with them.
As you cooperate with them?
Do you really think that makes any difference?
- They can be reasonable!
- Reasonable?
They tolerate you as long as you're useful to them.
I am a senior government official.
You, sir, you, sir, are a traitor!
You're a Quisling!
You do not understand!
We have helped make things better for the others.
We have gained concessions. I have saved lives!
Wouldn't you have helped more
by organising the fight against them?
No one can fight against the Daleks.
That's not what your criminal guerrillas
seem to think, is it?
A handful of fanatics?
Most of them have been killed already.
I assure you, there is nothing
they can do to change things.
- Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
- Anat, look out!
Come! We must reach the control centre, come!
No! Come! Come!
For the last time, I tell you
I haven't got any information.
And quite frankly, even if I had,
I wouldn't give it to you!
- Right, stay where you are!
- Guards!
Guards? You have no guards. They're all dead.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, thank you.
- All the better for seeing you.
- You're coming with us.
No harm must come to these two.
Too much depends on them.
- As for you, my friend...
- Put that gun down!
There's no point in murdering him.
You don't know how much
blood there is on his hands.
Nevertheless, he's not your real enemy.
He's helped the Daleks. He's worked for them!
They would always have found someone.
Now, just leave him.
Right, let's go.
- But how do you know this?
- Oh, there are books.
Even during the wars, people found time
to study, to write about it.
What to you has not yet happened
is to us history.
This history of yours,
it talks about Sir Reginald Styles?
Oh, yeah, he pretended to be working for peace,
but really he just wanted power for himself.
So the conference he called was just a trick?
He managed to lure the world leaders to
a remote country house
and he pretended they needed absolute
quiet if the meeting was to succeed.
But then, there was a devastating explosion...
And Styles was killed with the others.
He must have set a bomb and mistimed the charge.
There were accusations, counter-accusations,
and then the wars began. That was the turning point.
But if this true, Sir Reginald Styles
must be completely round the bend!
Er, so, you went back into our time
to kill Styles before he could carry out his plan?
Right. We've been fighting the Daleks for years.
But it was hopeless.
Eventually we must lose, so we thought,
what else can we do?
We learnt through one of our spies
that the Daleks had succeeded
in creating a time machine.
We even managed to steal a copy of
the plans, and we built one of our own,
so that we could go back into history
to the exact point
where things started to go wrong.
With one action, we could stop them.
Mankind could have a chance
to take a new direction!
But even now, the transfer isn't always stable.
People materialised in your time
and then just faded away.
The ghost that Styles saw?
Somehow, somehow the Daleks
found what we were doing.
And they sent Ogrons back into your time
after us and attacked one of our men.
Well, that must have been the man
that we saw down by the canal tunnel.
You remember, Jo, the one who vanished
from the ambulance?
Yes, we fixed on the tunnel
as a place that was stable in your time and in ours.
We used it as a transfer point.
Well, you know the rest.
Yes, well there's... There's one thing
I don't quite understand and that is
why were you so keen to rescue us?
And believe me, we're grateful, but...
Well, you told us yourself,
you're an old enemy of the Daleks.
- Yes?
- Then you will help us to beat them.
What do you expect me to do?
Well, you can succeed where we've failed, Doctor.
We want you to go back into your
own time and kill Styles.
You're asking me to commit murder!
No! We're asking you to kill one man
and prevent millions more dying.
- That is still murder.
- Isn't it worth it?
- To save the human race from the Daleks?
- Yes, but would it?
We've told you how it happened.
But your history could be wrong, you know.
Now, listen, why don't you
send us back to our time?
We know the future now,
maybe there are other things we can do?
Monia, we're wasting valuable time!
Every minute that goes by...
Doctor, will you help us? It's our only hope.
I still can't believe that Sir Reginald
Styles is a ruthless murderer.
Yes, I agree, Jo.
Vain to the point of arrogance,
a trifle obstinate, perhaps,
but basically a good man.
So, if it happened, how did it happen?
Any of your people
still in our time zone?
- No.
- Well, Shura.
He left just to send a message and we
never saw nor heard from him again.
We assumed he must be dead.
Look, please believe me,
I'm completely with you about the ends.
I only disagree as to the means.
All right. What do you want to know?
This mission of yours to the 20th
century, what did you take with you?
The usual battle gear, radio, disintegrators...
- Any sabotage equipment?
- Only a few charges of Dalekenium.
Dalekenium?
It's a highly effective type of explosive.
We stole the formula from the Daleks.
- Could it destroy a house?
- What are you trying to say, Doctor?
Well, don't you see? This has happened before!
What has?
You went back to change history,
but you didn't change anything,
you became a part of it.
What are you talking about?
If Styles didn't cause that explosion,
somebody else did.
Well, obviously, but who...
Shura!
Isn't that exactly what he would have done?
One last suicidal attempt to carry out his orders?
It's possible, I suppose.
You're trapped in a temporal paradox!
Styles didn't cause that explosion
and start the wars,
you did it yourselves!
You have failed the Daleks.
The Doctor has escaped.
He will be recaptured. I swear it!
He must be found and destroyed.
He will attempt to return to his own time zone.
If those guerrillas are helping
him, they will use the tunnel
and I am setting up an ambush.
If you fail us again,
you will pay with your life.
This is your final chance.
I will go and supervise the operations myself.
Is everything ready?
Security forces have covered the whole tunnel.
Don't worry, they won't escape a second time.
So it has ended as I said it would.
Did I not tell you it was madness
to fight the Daleks?
Is it madness to want to see a world
free from their rule?
- It can't be done.
- Oh, yes it can.
And I can do it. Are you going to stop me?
Go. I will deal with these criminals myself.
I said go!
If only I could be sure.
You spoke of the war,
of its years of suffering and starvation.
Well, I can prevent all that happening, you know.
You saved my life. You could have let them kill me.
- Go, quickly.
- Thank you.
Jo, come here and stand by me.
Sergeant! They're here!
This is Sergeant Benton calling UNIT HQ.
Look, we've found them.
Will you get a Jeep over here pronto?
This way, Doctor.
I am sorry. They were too quick for us.
They escaped in the darkness.
You are lying You have betrayed the Daleks.
No! I told you before,
those security guards
are no match for humans.
You are a traitor to the Daleks.
You must be exterminated!
Who knows? I may have helped to exterminate you!
You have proved yourself worthy
to be the new Controller,
but be warned, the Daleks demand total loyalty
from those who serve them.
Of course.
We must follow them into
the 20th century time zone.
The peace conference must be destroyed.
War must break out.
The Dalek conquest of the planet Earth
must not be reversed!
Look, you're supposed to be in charge of security.
Kindly get on with your job
and leave me to get on with mine.
Brigadier! Brigadier,
get everybody out of this house at once!
Where the devil have you been?
Never mind all that.
Just clear this house immediately!
What's the man talking about?
Do as he says! Look, there isn't much time!
Locate and destroy the peace conference.
Exterminate!
Destroy the human resistance!
Eliminate all humans!
Exterminate!
Brigadier, get this man and all the
delegates out of this area immediately.
Use force if you have to!
Jo, you stay here.
- Sir Reginald, please?
- No, I will not permit it!
Shura!
Get out of here unless you want to die too!
I must kill Styles to prevent the war!
Shura, listen to me.
Styles and all the delegates
are already leaving this house.
You detonate that bomb and you'll be
sacrificing yourself for nothing.
Benton calling UNIT HQ,
we just can't hold them, sir!
Look, Benton, keep them back
as long as you can.
Sir Reginald, this house is under attack
by a hostile force.
You will please consider yourself
under my orders.
- Brigadier, I warn you...
- Now be quiet, sir!
- Captain Yates?
- Sir.
Get Sir Reginald and all the delegates
away from this area at once.
Locate and destroy the peace conference!
Doctor! The Daleks, they're coming into the house!
- Daleks? You're lying!
- No, she's not.
They've come back to make sure that
their version of history isn't changed.
- Is everybody out of the house?
- Yes, everyone but us.
Get out of here. Let them come in!
Leave them to me!
- No, no! You must come with us!
- You don't understand!
That's Dalekenium. It's the only thing
that's effective against the Daleks.
Well, couldn't we set a time fuse?
No, this stuff's too unstable.
There just isn't time.
This is something that I must do myself.
Now, get out!
- Very well.
- Out!
Greyhound to Trap One,
do you read me? Over. Greyhound to...
Tell your men to fall back.
Let the Daleks into the house.
Doctor, are you sure that...
It may not make military sense
but it's the only way.
All right. Brigadier to all units.
Let them pass! I say again, let them pass!
Re-group on the main road, out!
Exterminate!
Eliminate all humans. Exterminate!
The human delegates are inside the house.
Enter and destroy.
- Where are the delegates?
- Where is the man Styles?
They must be found and exterminated!
Oh, no, not this time.
This time it's going to be different!
Well, what happened?
Your conference has been saved, Sir Reginald.
Now it's up to you and your friends
to make sure it's a success.
- You still have a choice.
- Don't worry.
We all know what will happen if we fail.
So do we. We've seen it happen, haven't we, Jo?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)