It's you.
The phantom piper!
No!
No! I'll not go with you!
Do you hear me, piper? No! Leave me!
Leave me. I'll not go with you, do you hear me?
Leave me! No, I'll not go with you!
I'll fight you every inch of the way.
I'll not go with you.
Leave me, piper.
No. Leave me. I'll not go.
Agh!
- Molly, what's happened?
- Oh, Doctor, it was horrible!
- A giant creature like a Cyberman!
- It's all right. Don't be frightened.
- Whatever it was, it's gone now.
- It's the... Doctor, the Cyberman was carrying a patient.
- Cyberman? What are you talking about?
- I'm sure it was.
- I'll not go with you.
- It's OK. It's safe now. Take it easy.
She's right.
There's another one gone.
Sam, Jules, you've got to find these men.
They can't just disappear in a place this size.
Search every square inch, come back until you find them. Now move.
Now, supposing you tell me your story?
What did you see?
I went out to get Jamie some water,
and when I came back,
I saw this giant man or creature or something,
just going out of the door,
carrying one of the patients... like a doll.
- I think it was a Cyberman.
- Forget that part. Then what?
Then nothing.
The door shut, and then you came in.
- What do you know about all this?
- Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
We'll see about that in a minute.
- This thing you saw. What was it like?
- It was enormous, and silver.
- It had holes in its head for eyes, like a robot.
- A robot?
But the Cybermen were all killed
when Mondas blew up.
Stop this Cyberman nonsense! There were Cybermen, every child knows that, but they were destroyed ages ago!
- So we all thought.
- That's enough.
Let's have a little calm thinking.
For the past two weeks,
a complete unknown disease has appeared in the base.
People drop in their tracks
and develop a black pattern on their skin.
Then some of the patients disappear, right?
They can't leave the base without wearing spacesuits,
and there are no spacesuits missing. So where are they?
- I must say, It does sound a little odd.
- More than a little.
I do know one thing - a new disease starts, people disappear, and then you turn up.
- And you think we did it!
- Oh, come on, we haven't done a thing!
Perhaps maybe, I don't know who you are,
what you are, or where you came from,
but you can get off the moon now!
- Well, that suits me fine, the sooner the better!
- No, Ben, we can't go yet.
- Why not? They don't want us here.
- Because there is something evil here. We must stay.
- Evil? Don't be daft!
- Evil is what I meant.
There are some corners of the universe
which have bred the most terrible things.
Things which act against everything
that we believe in. They must be fought.
This disease, for instance. It isn't really
a disease at all, but I can help you with it.
You'll see. I'll find the cause for you.
- Will you, indeed?
- Yes, certainly. I just need to examine a few things. That's all.
- It should be simple.
- Well, I'm not sure.
I'll give you just one Earth-day cycle
to find the cause.
- Earth what?
- 24 hours.
- But that's no time at all.
- It's all you're going to get.
Then you get off the moon,
with this bloke here.
- You can't move him! He's very ill.
- We accept.
Now tell me, you have pathological
equipment here, yes?
Yes. Evans was working on
an extensive research project. It's all in here.
It's quite a small unit. We're not equipped
to deal with a full-scale epidemic.
- Do you think you can manage?
- Yes.
Right. I'll leave you to it.
Don't forget - 24 hours.
- What are you going to do, Doctor?
- We'll start with this one.
- Are you really a medical doctor?
- Yes, I think I was once, Polly.
I think I took a degree once, in Glasgow.
1888, I think. Lister. Hold that for me, will you?
- Oh!
- All right. He's quite unconscious.
It's all right, Jamie. It's all right.
You're going to get better but you must lie still.
What is this place?
Is it the home of the piper?
No, we're on the moon.
You know, the moon up in the sky.
No, I can't be alive.
I've just seen the piper.
The piper! I knew!
Polly! What's happened?
Polly.
Are you all right?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
- Isn't there any clue at all?
- No. It's a complete blank.
All the tests are negative. As far as I can see,
this whole ridiculous place is sterile.
- We'll have to tell Mr Hobson, I suppose.
- I simply don't understand it.
Doctor, it couldn't possibly have
anything to do with Lister, could it?
- Lister?
- Well, I mean, you did say
that you took your degree in Glasgow in 1888.
That's an awfully long time from now, 2070, whatever it is.
Are you suggesting that I'm not confident to carry out these tests?
No, No, I'm just wondering if there was anything
that Joseph Lister didn't know in 1888
- that might help you now.
- Ssh! Somebody's coming!
It's Mr Hobson. Out for blood - ours. Look busy! Quick!
That's the third person
to disappear in the past few hours.
- It's completely illogical.
- Do you mind?
Would you mind standing away from the door
and allowing it to close? The slides. The dust!
It must be you people.
We've got some straight talking to do, you and I.
- Polly. Another boot.
- Do you hear me?
- This is extraordinary. Look here.
- Excuse me, please.
Excuse me. We ARE trying to help you.
- Help? Is that what you call it? You can all get off the moon now.
- No, wait a minute. You said...
- I don't care what I said!
- Ah!
- Have you found something?
- I think perhaps I have.
Yes, I may be onto something,
but I must have some room.
How can I work under these conditions?
Now, please, come along. Outside. I'm trying to work in here!
- Ben, see that they stay outside.
- Did you mean that?
- What?
- You've found something?
Oh, Polly, I only wish I had.
- Coffee? Sugar?
- Hello, Doctor. Thank you.
- It's very hot. Doctor, what about you?
- Thank you, Polly.
Doctor, as I was saying, you've had
your chance. You come up with absolutely  nothing.
Don't touch him!
Let me look.
Charlie and you, Ben,
give us a hand to get him into the medical unit.
Try not to touch his skin.
Don't drink that! It's the sugar!
That's why the disease doesn't affect everyone.
It's the sugar. Not everyone takes it.
Don't touch it.
- What are you doing?
- Just be patient.
Just as I thought.
A large neurotropic virus.
- Like the space plague?
- No.
It's a large infective agent
that only attacks the nerves.
That's why these patients got these lines appear on faces and hands.
It follows the course of the nerves under the skin.
That's _ it well. But how did it get in here?
It is the Cybermen. I believe
they have deliberately infected the base.
My men have searched every square of the base. There's no space to hide a cat, let alone a Cyberman.
Anyhow, how did they get in?
- One moment.
- What is it?
- You say you searched all the base?
- Yes. What of it?
- No chance of anyone hiding anywhere?
- None whatever.
Did your men search in here? Did they?
- There was'nt people in here, so...
- Did they search in here?
- No.
- There's nowhere in here they could hide.
Oh, no!
Back!
Back.