(''DOCTOR WHO'' THEME)
Come here, Jamie.
Look at that.
(JAMIE) Look at the size of that thing, Doctor!
Yes, Jamie. That is a big one.
Just a wee laboratory, eh (?)
Well... Obviously, it's grown.
It's like 20 castles in the sky!
Are you sure this is the right place?
- Of course I am!
- We never get to where you say we will.
I got Victoria to where she wanted to go.
Why does she want to learn graphology?
Will we ever get back to her?
- Of course!
- I'll believe that when I see it!
At the moment, we have other things
to worry about. Look at this!
- I've not seen that before.
- It's not been here before.
It's a teleport control.
You'd think I'd never flown a Tardis solo!
- What does it do?
- It gives the Time Lords dual control.
I shall complain when this is over!
I think we'll dematerialise to avoid
their detection beams and slip in quietly.
- You said they were friendly.
- Probably overwhelmingly so.
Then why do we have to slip in quietly?
The most brilliant scientists in the universe
have assembled here to do research.
I don't want them to know I've arrived.
- Why not?
- They'll all want my autograph.
I just want a quiet word
with Dastari, Head of Projects.
Right, then.
(BOOMING)
Splendid! We've hit conterminous time again.
- We've certainly hit something (!)
- Jamie!
Right.
Follow me.
- Wait!
- What?
We'd better take the recall disk.
- Don't wander off. Stay with me.
- Do I ever?
It has been known. And let me do the talking.
Just stand in the background...
..''And admire your diplomatic skills'' (!)
How dare you?!
How dare you transmat that object
into my kitchens?!
How dare you have the impertinence
to address me like that?
I am Shockeye o' the Quancing Grig!
I'm not interested in the pedigree
of an Androgum. I am a Time Lord!
Oh... My humblest apologies!
I should have realised.
But this one with you?
He is from the planet Earth. A human.
A Tellurian!
I have not seen one of these before!
Is it a gift for Dastari?
A gift?!
Such a soft white skin,
whispering of a tender succulence!
Dastari will not appreciate its qualities.
He has no sensual refinement.
Let me buy it from you.
My companion is not for sale!
No chef in the nine planets would do more
to bring out the flavour of the beast!
You get on with your butchery!
Come along, Jamie.
Ooh...
I can just taste that flesh!
(RUNNING FOOTSTEPS)
Who was that?
Shockeye o' the Quancing Grig.
He's an Androgum.
The Androgums are the servitors here.
- They do the station maintenance.
- You mean a scullion?
Yes, with a high opinion of himself.
Chefs usually have!
- (WHOOSHING)
- It's the Tardis!
Our allies won't care for that!
I said the Group Marshal
could have the Time Lord's machine.
- Will it make any difference?
- Not to me. I have the Kartz-Reimer module.
It shows the Gallifreyans are suspicious.
I was right to lay the plans I did.
- So now we wait.
- Not for long.
Stike is moving.
Already? The calgesic won't have
affected the scientists yet.
It will by the time Stike's forces arrive.
Did they enjoy the meal?
Dastari said you had surpassed yourself!
Oh!
Being unable to taste it, I worried
that it might be over-seasoned!
Shockeye, their last supper would have added
lustre to your reputation...
..except that they won't live to remember it!
I remember it very clearly, Doctor.
You came to our inauguration,
bearing fraternal greetings from Gallifrey.
Yes, that was before I fell from favour.
I'm a bit of an exile these days.
Yes, I heard about that.
But you still act on their instructions?
It's the price I pay for my freedom.
We've had no support from your people.
You can't expect help from the Time Lords.
Their policy is one of strict neutrality.
Nonetheless, they have disappointed
the other Third Zone governments.
Don't chide me. I'm simply a messenger.
- Officially, I'm here unofficially.
- You'll explain that paradox, I know.
I'm a pariah, exiled from Time Lord society.
They can always deny sending me.
Then why have they sent you?
They have been monitoring
the experiments in time travel
of the Professors Kartz and Reimer.
They want them stopped.
I see. How do the Time Lords equate that
with a policy of strict neutrality?
They don't have to.
I have no official existence,
so they can deny sending me.
(LAUGHS)
Typical!
Typical hypocrisy!
- Yes, Chessene?
- Do your guests require refreshment?
- Ah, well...
- No, thank you. We've already eaten.
That was yesterday!
- One meal a day is sufficient.
- You're sure? Thank you, Chessene.
Very good, Professor.
Well, Doctor,
what do you make of our chatelaine?
Was she an Androgum?
She was. Now she's an Androgum TA.
Technologically augmented.
Oh, one of your biological experiments!
I've carried out
nine augmentations on Chessene.
She's at mega genius level now.
I'm very proud of her.
- Proud of her or your own skill?
- Perhaps a little of both.
All that Androgum energy
now functions on a higher plane.
She spends days in the data banks
sucking in knowledge.
- You can't change nature.
- In Chessene's case, I believe I have.
Give a monkey control of its environment
and it will fill the world with bananas!
I expected something
more progressive from you.
- My work has tremendous implications.
- That's why it's dangerous!
Doctor, our races have become tired
and effete. Our seed is thin.
We must hand the baton of progress to others.
If I can raise the Androgums
to a higher plane of consciousness,
there's no limit to what that
boiling energy might achieve!
You could augment an earwig to the point
where it understood nuclear physics.
It would still be a very stupid thing to do.
Identify!
(COMPUTER) The approaching craft
are Sontaran battle cruisers.
Their intention is hostile.
(MAN) Operate the defence!
(COMPUTER) Please complete
your last instructions.
The last instruction is cancelled.
Maintain normal surveillance.
Normal surveillance.
Open all docking bays.
Even if I wanted to, I have no authority to order
Kartz and Reimer to abandon their work.
You have. You sanction every experiment here.
What reason do I give?
That the Time Lords are concerned?
Our monitors have detected ripples
of up to point four on the Bocca scale.
Anything much higher would threaten
the whole fabric of time.
They are well aware of the dangers.
They are responsible scientists.
They're incompetent meddlers!
Aren't you being a little ingenuous?
The Time Lords have a vested interest
in ensuring that others
do not discover their secrets.
I'm sure that's not the case.
Your own machine is no longer in the station.
You didn't want Kartz and Reimer to look at it.
Look, I've a suggestion.
Stop these experiments
while my people study their work.
If Kartz and Reimer are on safe lines,
they'll be allowed to continue.
''Allowed to continue''?
I mean there would be no further objection.
In the first place,
I have no authority to ask Kartz and Reimer
to submit their work for analysis!
In the second place,
the Time Lords have no right
to make this grossly unethical demand.
- That's unmitigated arrogance!
- And that's specious claptrap!
Don't prate to me about ethics!
The balance of the space-time continuum could
be destroyed by your ham-fisted numbskulls!
I don't feel there's anything to be gained
by prolonging this discussion, Doctor.
You have more letters after your name than
anyone I know - enough for two alphabets.
How can you be such a stupid, stubborn,
irrational, objectionable old idiot?
What are you smiling at,
you hairy-legged Highlander?
I'm just admiring your diplomatic skills!
Dastari?
He's got his head doon,
and I can't say I blame him.
- He's drugged!
- He's what?
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
What's that?
I'd have thought a Jacobite
would recognise that sound.
Professor! Agh!
Run, I say. Save yourself!