- Now, you come along with me, sir!
- How dare you?! Let go of me!
- This way!
- No, this way!
- Now, look. You got me into this mess!
- Will you please stop squabbling?
We'll go this way.
(CHESSENE) No!
You'll come this way! We have
some unfinished business to attend to.
My word, what a mess!
I think perhaps, Dastari,
you ought to sack your chatelaine (!)
Shockeye! What has happened here?
It seems that Group Marshal Stike
vaporized his space craft and himself.
I found this.
- So he survived the coronic acid.
- Obviously.
Down to the cellars.
You know the way, I think.
The control box has been moved. Is it damaged?
The briode nebuliser is missing.
Do you mean this?
Why did you remove it?
Because it contains my symbiotic print.
- Return this to the machine.
- How did your imprint get into this?
Stike forced me to prime
and use the machine.
There is a simple way of testing
whether you are still trying to deceive us.
Come, girl.
Now we shall see.
(WHIRRING)
There you are.
Kartz and Reimer's subjects
always vapourised into the time stream.
Peri won't. And she hasn't
any symbiotic nuclei, I can assure you.
(WHIRRING)
Out!
Satisfied?
Dastari, chain these creatures up.
Chain us up? After I've handed you
the secret of time travel on a plate!
Come on, Chessene. Where's your gratitude?
(CHESSENE) Dastari.
Come on.
Ooh, madam, before we leave,
let me cook one of the humans.
Didn't you sate your appetite
sufficiently in the city?
A mere snack. You promised we could
have a human before leaving Earth!
Well, if it would please you.
Take the one in the skirt.
He is the youngest of the jacks.
Thank you, madam!
- Get your hands off me!
- Steady, my beauty!
Oh, there's some juiceful meat
on this one, Chessene!
(JAMIE'S DOCTOR) Jamie!
You might at least say goodbye!
You're almost as clever as I am!
What does he mean?
I presume you've sabotaged
the briode nebuliser?
- Pared the interface.
- Precisely what I would have done.
But it worked, didn't it?
I left a thin membrane
so that it would work once.
- I knew she'd want to test it!
- There's no need to be so smug.
- We've got to rescue Jamie!
- (BOTH) Can you reach that wheelchair?
- I'm not elastic!
- You'll reach it with your feet if you try.
(PERI'S DOCTOR) Good girl!
- What's the idea?
- Push it over towards him.
Why? He's not going anywhere in it!
Come along! That's it!
- What do you think?
- It might work. It's worth a try.
Easy...
Easy does it...
Well done!
- (JAMIE YELLS)
- Never mind me, help him!
The key!
(AGONISED YELL)
- What are you doing?
- Tenderising the meat.
See how the flesh is marbling?
That's the fatty tissue breaking up.
You should kill him first, surely?
It works better on a live animal.
- Aagh!
- It looks very painful.
That's simply a nervous reflex.
I've been butchering all my life.
Primitive creatures don't feel pain
in the way that we would.
(AGONISED YELL)
Now, this is the part, I always say,
where you can tell a butcher from a botcher!
The meat should always have a clean edge.
One of the Time Lords has escaped!
You didn't fasten the manacle!
- I did!
- Don't argue!
It's vital that he be caught and killed!
To kill a Time Lord would destroy
everything we've achieved!
The Gallifreyans have powers
we've not even dreamed of.
Kill him, I tell you!
KILL HIM!
This will only take a few minutes. We could
have the saddle and haunches for supper.
Never mind that now, Shockeye!
I want that Time Lord found!
- Jamie! Can you hear me?
- (JAMIE GROANS)
Jamie! Wake up!
I thought you might return to help the primitive!
Agh!
- Shockeye! The Time Lord!
- I know, madam. I wounded him!
Look!
Then follow his blood trail.
Kill him, Shockeye.
Certainly, madam!
Come along, Peri. It's time we were off.
Chessene wants me to kill you.
Your run is nearly ended, Time Lord!
Give up, Time Lord! You cannot escape
Shockeye o' the Quancing Grig!
(GROANS)
Right! I'll have that Shockeye, so I will!
(DASTARI) I remember it very clearly, Doctor.
There speaks the real Dastari. My old friend!
I ordered you to kill these two.
Why are they still alive?
There's been enough killing,
Chessene, and it's my fault.
I took an Androgum,
a lowly, unthinking creature of instinct,
and tried to set her among the gods!
I put myself among the gods!
I shall liberate my people.
We shall reign over all other beings!
Stop!
(WHIRRING)
Agh!
(PERI) Is she dead?
(DOCTOR) Very.
Molecular disintegration. Horrible!
- That's it, then.
- Except for that Shockeye!
He's been...mothballed (!)
That's a mess! It'll take you quite a while
to put that back together again!
That will not be necessary.
A Stattenheim remote control!
I've always wanted one of those!
Some of us have earned these little privileges!
(WHISTLES)
(WHOOSHING)
- Jamie...
- After you, Doctor.
No, after you, Jamie.
- Goodbye, Peri.
- Bye.
- Doctor.
- Keep an eye on the old gentleman, will you?
Do try to keep out of my way in future
and in past, there's a good fellow.
The time continuum should be
big enough for both of us...just!
I preferred you as an Androgum!
(WHOOSHING)