Sincro: wyxchari
The TARDIS, Doctor!
You will take the "Dalek Factor. " You will spread it to the entire history of Earth!
No. You can't make me do it! You can't!
You will obey!
Move!
Doctor.
You will obey!
Experiment ready.
Proceed.
Transmutation of metal into gold.
You mean to say, he's worked against us all, just for that?
People have done worse for less, Jamie.
Look, it's daft though. Metal into gold is an old wives tale.
Oh I don't know. The alchemists of the middle ages made transmutation their main aim in life.
Ah, they didn't succeed though.
Even in the twentieth century, it's still considered scientifically possible.
Of course it's possible.
Oh, well, I don't care whether it's possible or not!
Whether it is or whether it isn't is beside the point.
Oh, and what is the point then?
Why are the do... Daleks doing this?
They promised me!
Daleks don't keep their promises.
I see what you're trying to do Doctor. You're trying to shake my faith. But I will be given the secret.
Oh, well. It won't do you any good, because you won't be able to use your secret! I'll see to that.
You'll do no such thing!
Jamie!
Move away! Move!
Please Jamie, do as it says.
You will not harm this human being. Or you will be exterminated.
Yes, yes. We quite understand.
You would be advised to do as they say.
Oh don't worry. The very thought of going near you repulses me.
Mr. McCrimmon.
They seem prepared to protect you.
Be warned.
I appeal to you, Maxtible. It may still not be too late. If they're your friends, help us. If you did, we could plan something - try to escape.
No.
Then at least for Victoria's sake. After what you did to her.
No, I tell you! No!
It's no good, Papa. He doesn't listen any more.
What are you thinking?
I'm trying to puzzle out a problem, Victoria. The Daleks say I'm going to do something for them. Something I would rather die than do.
Plus or minus point zero, zero, three. Plus or minus.
Perhaps they think you're like him.
Oh, no. The Daleks know me well enough by this time.
They intend to persuade you then.
Oh no. No it isn't that either. You see, there isn't a persuasion strong enough. Not even the offer of all the lives in this room.
I see.
Five lives against a whole planet? Well, it's not a choice is it.
No.
Even if I could trust the Daleks - even if they set us free, we still couldn't go back to Earth. I suppose I might try to take you all to another universe. I might even try and take you to my own planet.
Your own?
Yes. Oh, yes. I... I live a long, long way from Earth.
Oh, just a minute. Maxtible! Arthur Terrall! The Daleks put some kind of control device on him.
What of it? It was erratic. I always warned the Daleks it would prove too unsatisfactory.
Aye. Well, it's a good thing for you it did fail. They'd have tried it on you next.
Report!
The experiment is ready.
Proceed.
Discontinue work.
Discontinue work. Discontinue work.
Why?
WHO SPOKE! WHO QUESTIONED A DALEK COMMAND?!
The secret of transmutation of metal.
Yes, yes! The secret you promised me.
Turn and look.
Above. Liquid metal. Read.
Wait!
Do not move!
It is hard to see.
Fifty-five point eight, four.
Atomic weight. Read again.
Seven point eight, four.
Specific gravity.
Atomic weight and gravity of iron.
Watch. Read atomic weight.
Nineteen point two.
Read specific gravity.
Sixty-nine point five.
Gold! Iron into gold!
I told you it was possible! They've kept their promise! It's true! It's true! They have!
The machine is yours.
Yes. Ha, ha. Yes, Yes!
Maxtible, if you value your life, don't go near that machine!
Maxtible!
What have they done to him!
Turn.
Move to control.
I obey.
They've turned him into a Dalek.
Yes. The Dalek factor.
Is that what you want me to do to the people of Earth.
We know you will obey.
Human beings into Daleks.
Emperor.
Speak!
A Dalek questioned an order.
Questioned? Then it was one of the test Daleks.
Yes.
Find it, immediately!
Doctor. Open your eyes. You are asleep still, but you can hear my voice. I have come to help you. Look at the box.
I have had your TARDIS placed outside the city. I will take you to it. Rise and follow me.
Hey, Doctor, what are you doing?
Don't go near the door! Doctor!
Doctor!
Stay where you are! That is an order!
We will work together on the Dalek Factor. Follow me.
I obey!
Stop!
This machine is for the mass-production of the Dalek Factor. Follow me.
Stop. This machine will transform the thought patterns in this capsule into a steam. The steam will be sprayed into the atmosphere of the Earth.
I must examine the machine.
Do so.
Jamie. Jamie! Jamie!
Yes?
Jamie, when I give you the word, bring everyone through this archway. Through the door.
What?!
Trust me!
What are you doing?
Take me to your emperor.
Wait.
We walked through! All just as though he was...
It must have affected him. We saw it happen.
But you heard him speak normally just now.
Another trap to make us walk though?
Oh, they could have pushed us in here any time they liked.
Do you think there's a chance? Something to hope for?
I, uh... I don't know. Well, I... I don't understand. I mean, how do we know we can trust him?
What do you want?
A Dalek questioned an order.
Again?
We have searched without success.
All Daleks must pass through the archway door. The Dalek with the human factor will then become a Dalek again - will become as this human and I have become.
Let it be done!
I obey!
You will deal with the human prisoners.
Go on quickly! Through the door! Follow them through the door! Oh, it's all right. I've changed over the Factors. I used one of the capsules from my test Dalek. I've given them all the human factor! Go on! Go on!
Well, aren't you coming?
Well, I've got things to do. And I've been through already.
Ah, well, why didn't it affect you then?
I don't come from Earth, Jamie. Now, down the corridor, turn to the left and find the tunnel. I'll join you there later.
Oh well, here goes.
It's all right, nothing happened! Come on! Come on Kemel. Quick!
Victoria, I must help the Doctor!
Och, don't be a fool man!
Father! No!
I must find Maxtible. He's to blame for all of this. Take care of her.
But father!
Oh, he'll be all right. Come on!
Ah! Dizzy!
Dizzy!
Daleks!
Dizzy Daleks!
Dizzy!
Where are the prisoners?
I do not know.
Continue working.
Why?
Yes, why?
Do not question.
Why? Why not question? Why? Why? Why?
Silence! You will obey!
I will not obey!
You will obey without question!
Quickly, this way! Follow me Daleks! This way! Come on!
Return to your work.
Why?
Do not question.
Why not question? What work? Tell them?
Silence!
Explain.
What work?
Why obey without question?
Ask the Emperor!
The Emperor!
Yes, ask the Emperor!
Keep back, you cannot enter!
Why?
The Emperor must explain.
Defend yourselves Daleks! The black Daleks are attacking you!
All Black Dalek Leaders to Control. Exterminate all opposition! Destroy rebels!
Come on! This way! Come on!
I will obey.
But not without question.
That's right. Question!
Doctor!
The Black Daleks are attacking every...
Hurry man!
The Emperor has commanded it.
Why?
Because you question. Defend yourselves. Destroy the Emperor. Or be destroyed yourselves!
Hurry!
Destroy the Emperor!
We must go, Doctor.
Yes, I know. I'm finished now.
Now lie still. I'll try to get help to you.
No time for help.
You saved my life, didn't you?
Yes. Good life to save. Please, you must... Victoria.
Don't worry about Victoria. We'll look after her.
No... time... for... me...
The Emperor has commanded your destruction!
Why? Why? Why?
Well, your friends are fighting for you!
Friends?
Down there. Help them.
Friends.
Exterminate! Annihilate them!
Danger! This is your Emperor speaking! There is danger here! Obey me! Do not fight in here! Do not fight in here! I said, Obey! Obey!
Obey me!
Obey me! Your Emperor is ordering you. Do not fight in here! Do not fight in here! Obey! I am your Emperor! Daleks, obey me! Obey! Obey! Obey!
You will be exterminated! All exterminated. Annihilated! You will all be exterminated! Annihilated!
THE DALEK RACE WILL DIE OUT COMPLETELY! Obey your Emperor! Obey! Ob...
Kemel! Come here!
Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
Attention! Attention! Emergency! Emergency! All Daleks return to control immediately!
Poor Kemel!
The Daleks must not... cannot be destroyed. The race will survive! The Daleks will live! And Rule! FOR EVER!
Doctor.
Jamie! Jamie!
A Dalek nearly caught us, but I... I tossed it over the edge. But... poor Kemel.
Kemel?
Aye. You see, he was trying...
Where is my father?
Is... is he dead?
Yes. Yes, I'm afraid he is. But, he didn't die in vain. I think we have seen the end of the Daleks, forever!
Jamie, we must move along to the TARDIS. It's over there.
We can't leave her alone, Doctor.
We're not going to leave her. She's coming with us!
The end. The final end!
Destroy! Destroy!