All right, Corporal. Nip back and tell Captain Knight it's all clear up 'ere. And get 'em to get a shift on!
Righto, Staff.
This looks familiar - it's around this corner.
Oh no!
Oh, we can't get to the TARDIS!
No, Victoria, I'm afraid we can't.
What's happened to Chorley, then?
That's what I'm wondering. Did he reach the TARDIS before the fungus, or... or did he not?
You mean to say, he could have got to the TARDIS and already have taken off in it?
I don't know...
Hey, come back, Doctor!
It's alright, Jamie, I'm not going to do anything silly. I...
I just want to try and get a little bit for an analysis.
Oh Jamie, stop him!
It's alright, Victoria.
Has anyone got a box?
I've got my tobacco tin.
Oh, splendid.
But then, it's got tobacco in it.
Never mind.
Eh!... Oh, alright. I only hope you think the sacrifice is worth it!
Hold the tin for me, would you, Evans?
Gone and set it off! Come on, now!
Oh, it's horrible!
Go on, Doctor, get it out!
Hold the tin underneath!
There we are - now back, everyone, quickly!
Hello, Staff. It's alright, it's just Staff Arnold!
One of these days, Evans my lad, you're going to creep up onto someone once too often!
Well, that's life, innit Staff?
Any luck at Holborn?
No - fungus.
Same back there.
Right. I'll tell the Colonel. You lot had better get back to HQ. We'll be along in a few minutes.
Come on, Jamie, I'll just show this bit of fungus to Travers.
Right.
Hey, look at this!
Good Lord! That's Yeti!
You don't think they may still be here?
I hope not!
Oh, Doctor!
D'you reckon they have?
Have what?
Taken him? Like she said?
Yes, I'm very much afraid they have. But why? Why didn't they just kill him? Unless...
Yes?
Well, unless they had a use for him.
Ah, Doctor. What's this I hear about Travers?
'Scuse me, sir, but I think you ought to come to the Ops Room.
Why? What's happening?
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again!
It's like a spider's web, ain't it?
Yes. And we're the flies, alright, but... where is the spider?
Better give the others a hand, Corporal.
Sir.
Doctor. Been thinking about what you were saying earlier,
about someone here in HQ being responsible for all this.
Could it have been Travers?
I doubt it.
Well, after all he has disappeared.
Yes - so has Chorley. I'd say he was a much more likely suspect.
True.
On the other hand, of course, whoever is in league with the Intelligence could still be amongst us here.
That's a fact of which I am uncomfortably aware.
But tell me, Doctor, this Intelligence - exactly what is it?
Well I wish I could give you a precise answer.
Perhaps the best way to describe it is a sort of formless, shapeless thing
floating about in space like a cloud of mist, only... with a mind and will.
What's it after? What's it want?
I wish I knew. The only thing I know for sure is that it brought me here.
Brought you here?
Yes, been wondering how you got here.
Yes, well I... I don't think there's any harm in telling you now.
I...I have a craft, that travels in time and space.
Oh, come now Doctor, you can't expect me to...
This craft of yours, this time-space craft. Could it get us out of here?
Well, yes - but it's at Covent Garden!
What does it look like?
It's a police box.
Oh really, Colonel, surely you're not...
So - if we could rescue that craft, you could take us out?
Yes, yes I could, but I have to stay here and finish Travers' work!
Ah, Doctor. Miss Travers is feeling alright now, and would like to see you right away.
Very good, Jamie. Excuse me, gentlemen, please.
Yes.
Well, I've heard some stories in my time, but that one really takes...
So you don't believe him?
No, of course not, sir! The whole idea is screwy. A police box!
Well whether you think it foolish or not, we are going to rescue that craft.
Oh, but sir! Our job...
Captain Knight. The Army has failed to defeat this menace.
Now the Doctor thinks he might succeed. Personally, I doubt it.
But if we stay here, we're as good as dead.
Therefore I do not intend leaving any escape route unexplored, however... screwy you may think it.
Oh, surely Colonel...
Let's get on with it, shall we, Knight?
Sir.
But... but there must be a chance! If the Doctor says...
No, the soldiers could comb these tunnels for a fortnight and still never find him.
I'm afraid your father's been taken by the Intelligence.
The only way that we can save him is by finding the central control source.
Aye, if he's anywhere, that's where he'll be.
But why? Why him? Why not me, or one of the soldiers, or...
Yes, I know. Tell me, what was your father working
on just before the Yeti broke in, Anne?
Um... oh, we were ready to test the sphere with the control unit
but I don't see what this has to do with anything, Doctor.
But don't you? If he was near to success...
That's why they took him!
Well, it's a possibility, isn't it?
Now Anne, do you feel strong enough to come back to the laboratory?
Yes, yes of course.
Anything we can do?
No, no, you just take it easy, Jamie.
What's the matter?
I've been thinking about what the Doctor said.
Anything we do, the Intelligence always knows!
Aye, but I wouldn't let it worry you. The Doctor will soon find a way out.
I wish I could believe that.
Oh yes. Yes, this seems to be in order, Anne.
My father didn't want it put together until this was in proper order.
Very wise. Let's have a look at this...
Oh yes, yes... My word, this is a splendid piece of work, Anne.
Thank you.
Yes, this should control the sphere, alright, but would it override the commands issued by the Intelligence, I wonder?
No. No, I'm afraid it won't. I just didn't have the time. Do you think we can do it?
Oh, we can do it, if you've got the right bits and pieces.
Hope I'm not disturbing, Doctor, but Staff asked me to give you this.
Where'd you get this?
On the floor, by that young lad Weams, it was.
But this is what brought the Yeti to the explosives store!
It's obviously been reprogrammed as a homing device, and you've given it to me!
Here! You don't think I had anything to do with these Yeti, do you?
Doctor! The other models - they've gone!
Well don't look at me! I didn't want to come down here in the first place!
I shouldn't be down here at all, really. Driver, I am, see.
You'd better have this, before you say I've nicked it.
Thank you.
And I'll have the tin back, when you've finished with it.
Don't look so unhappy - we're all under suspicion, you know, including me.
Hmm!
What's in the tin, Doctor?
It's the fungus from the tunnel. I thought if we examined it, it might give us a clue.
I must get this dismantled. It's like holding a time bomb.
So my party will get above ground and approach Covent Garden by Neal Street. Is that clear?
Now Staff here will be taking the trolley through the tunnel, and will arrive, we hope, at the same time as we do. You picked your two men, Staff?
Yes, sir. Lane and Evans.
Right. Now as soon as we get there, we shall be looking for a police box.
A police box, sir?
Yes, a police box. Now I want that box either out of the station or onto the trolley as quickly as possible. Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
Right. Any questions?
Yes, sir, this, um... police box. Is it important?
Corporal Blake, we'd hardly be going to this trouble if it weren't.
Who's going to look after the civilians, sir?
I'd like you to stay behind and look after them, Captain Knight.
The Doctor's got work to do. Right gentlemen, time to go.
Ah, Doctor.
Oh Jamie, what is it?
The Colonel says to tell you he's on his way.
On his way where?
To rescue the TARDIS!
He's wasting his time.
Well that's what I told him. And I think that man Chorley must be behind...
Now look! Get behind me, both of you, and keep clear. Here we go...
No!
What is it, Doctor?
The tin's empty!... Evans!
Course, really I shouldn't be doing this, you know, Staff.
Not officially on the strength down here, see.
What I am really is a driver, you see...
Don't try to come the old soldier with me, lad!
Who, me?
Yes, you! And when we get in the tunnels, don't you try to skive off,
'cos if you do I'll have you for breakfast. D'you understand?
Trolley's ready, Staff.
Right, come on!
So far, so good. If we don't see any Yeti, we should make Covent Garden in about ten minutes. Come on!
Captain, they've gone, and Evans with them, I think. I can't find him anywhere.
Yes, well we'd better question Evans carefully when he gets back.
Aye, if he gets back.
It's a funny business, Doctor, that fungus disappearing.
Yes, yes I know... Don't worry about that just at the moment.
I've been working on this control box with Miss Travers.
There's a few more things I need - transistors, circuits...
Aren't there any in Stores?
No, not of the right type.
Well in that case, Doctor, I can't help you.
Well - I was wondering... if I could go up to street level...
The mist! Or the Yeti!
There's no mist directly above us here - we'd have to risk the Yeti.
No. No, I'm afraid that's out.
It's terribly important. Please!
It'll only take five minutes.
Alright. I'll get my gear.
Well done, Travers!
The Colonel will be through there at Covent Garden in a few minutes, right?
Do you think they'll be able to load the police box on here, Staff?
Well, if we can get this thing through the fungus stuff -
there's not much of a gradient in this section of the tunnel.
Right, I want one volunteer.
Volunteer? That's a dirty word, that is. Not me!
Lane?
What for, Staff?
Well, if this thing wants some help going through to Covent Garden, I'm going through with it...
Into that stuff?
Have we got those respirators?
Well yeah, here.
I reckon we should be all right in these.
Oh all right, Lane lad. I'll go by meself.
No, 'ang on a sec, Staff. That trolley's heavy, it'll take two of us to shift it.
Good lad. Come on.
You're potty, the pair of you!
Shut up, will you! Do as you're told.
Play that rope out as we go; any sign of trouble whip us out sharpish. Right?
Well, it's your neck.
OK.
Alright then...
Staff? Staff Arnold?...
Look, sir!
In Here! Quick!
Come on, through the gate!
I'm going to find a way out. Split up!
Yetis - three of them, sir!
Grenades!
Right, fire!
Sir, they're smashing down the gate!
We can't hold 'em, sir!
Over the top, all of you!
Grenades!
Through the yard, come on!
Right, bazooka here to cover the others.
Dawson! Langley!
Make for the warehouse!... Murphy!
There it is again, Doctor!
Just one more thing.
For heaven's sake, hurry up!
I just need one more component. I'll look through here.
Doctor! Doctor, look out!
No! No!
And this was in his pocket, you say?
How did he get it? You said it was stolen.
You can't think that he...
No no no, he didn't steal it. The person who did planted it on him.
Hmm!
Eh, don't you try and pin this on me, boyo! Strikes me, anything goes wrong around here and I'm always the one to get the blame.
Alright, alright, let's keep our temper, shall we? The point is, two of these were missing. Now where's the other one?
There. That one shouldn't bother us any more.
Now then, come along, Anne, let's get down to work.
Where did I put those bits and pieces?
I wish I knew who put it in the Captain's pocket.
Well it must have been Chorley.
Well look, he left ages ago.
It doesn't matter. He could still...
Colonel!
Are you alright?
What's happened?
Colonel, what happened?
Gone.
Not all of them?
All of them?
I said so, didn't I? All of them. Evans, what about your party?
Arnold?
Gone, sir.
Captain Knight, too.
Knight! Hopeless.
Can't fight them - it seems... indestructible. Can't fight them!
You were right, Doctor, when you said they were... formless, shapeless... you were right.
Listen... listen, everyone! It's the other Yeti model! It's here! It's somewhere in this room!
That noise, I've been hearing it on and off all day...
Your pockets!
What?
Open your pockets, Colonel! Quickly, quickly, come on!
How... how...
They bring the Yeti!