What are we going to do now, Staff?
The main door should keep the fungus out of the tunnels for a bit. We must warn the others that HQ's had it.
Right.
Well, come on, then.
Oh, oh no, not me.
You're not disobeying an order, are you, Evans?
Now look here, Staff. If we go up there, and this stuff breaks out, we'll be trapped!
Now look, lad, you're scared, that's understandable.
But you've been in the Army long enough to know that orders is orders.
There's four people up there. If we don't warn them, they're for the chop.
So? Four of them's getting the chop - there's no reason to make it six, is there?
I've had enough of your lip for one day. Now come on! Follow me.
Evans! Come back here!
Not on your nelly! Cheerio, Staff!
Right, lad - I'll get you for this!
Anne...
Hey!
Stop! Come back here!
Stop! Anne, I've been thinking. Until we know who else is working for the Intelligence, everyone must be suspect.
Yes?
Well, the fewer people who know this chap's on our side, the better.
Yes... yes, and whoever is the Intelligence is bound to know that you're controlling this Yeti.
Mmm... I know.
You are to remain here for... Do you think a minute will be enough?
What for?
For us to get clear.
Perhaps.
You are to remain here for ninety seconds, and then resume acting on orders from the Intelligence until you are told otherwise. Is that understood?
Right. Switch off, for ninety seconds, starting from... now.
Come on, Anne.
It is them! Come on!
Am I glad to see you! There's fungus at Warren Street.
Yes, I know.
Oh. What are you doing down here, anyway?
Well, as a matter of fact...
I'll tell you another time. Hello, Colonel.
Glad to see you're both safe. Any luck with your gadgets?
No. No, I'm afraid not.
Pity.
Any news of Victoria?
Yes, she's at Piccadilly Station.
Piccadilly?
Is my father there too?
Aye, he's with her.
Are they alright?
Yes.
How do you know?
Ran across Arnold - he saw them.
Arnold?
Arnold! But Evans said - the fungus...
Yes, he went into it, alright, but he came out again somehow.
Says he can't remember what happened.
Well we haven't got any time to find out.
No, time's nearly up.
Yes, your twenty minutes.
Well come on, then.
What are you going to do?
We can't do anything until we get back to Headquarters,
and... then, if we've got time, we'll try and increase the range of the control units. Come on!
What is it, Colonel?
Something up ahead.
We can't go back!
What, fungus, you mean?
Yes.
Is that you, Colonel?
It's Arnold. Hang on, Staff!
Why isn't he in HQ?
Sir - the fungus. It's swamped HQ.
No!
I'm afraid so, sir. The main doors should keep it out of the tunnels for a bit, but...
Where's Evans?
Scarpered, sir.
Our time's up! We're all together - they've come to fetch us!
H... hello! If you... if you're looking for your friend, he went that way...
Look, you don't want me!... I'm not one of them, see?...
Driver, that's what I am... shouldn't be down here at all, really...
Hey, steady on!
Oh, going for a walk, are we? There's lovely.
I'm going to make a break for it, sir.
Think you can?
Well, it's worth a try. On the loose, sir, I might be able to do something. If only you could distract them, sir.
Right, Staff.
I think it wants us to go on, sir.
Right. Here we go.
Wait!... Can't you see, he's fallen over!
Be careful, be careful!
Where are we being taken, Professor?
Oh, to meet the Intelligence, I suppose.
A pyramid!
Yes - but it's different! We... we've never seen one like this before. It's fascinating!
This must be the machine that the Intelligence intends using on the Doctor.
Oh, no no. No, I shouldn't if I was you.
Yes, I think perhaps you're right.
Why didn't you tell me all this before?
Him.
You don't think the Colonel...
Well, you never know, do you?
Which one is ours?
I don't know.
What!
Well unfortunately I've lost track of him.
Oh, that's a great help!
Well, never mind, I... I want you to take this microphone and keep on calling our Yeti to you.
How will I know I've got the right one?
Well, you'll soon know if you haven't got the right one, won't you!
Jamie, I hope you don't suffer from claustrophobia!
Sergeant! Oh, oh thank heavens I found you! I've been wondering down here by myself for... for ages!
Well well well, quite forgotten about you, we had, Mr Chorley!
Tried to get out over the surface, but... there were Yeti everywhere!
And there's this... this fungus, and fog, all around, you see, and... it's hopeless!
Where's the control box?
Hm?
The control box!
It's in my pocket.
Well, why don't you use it on these Yeti? And then maybe we can escape!
Oh, no. I must meet the Intelligence face to face.
Doctor?
What is it?
Been thinking - the Yeti haven't noticed McCrimmon's disappearance yet.
Not that I think he'll be able to achieve anything.
Go on...
Well, I don't really know how to say this, but, um... there's Miss Travers and Victoria to think of, and, er...
You mean, am I going to give myself up?
Yes. Of course, the decision must be yours, and yours alone. But the Intelligence did promise to release Travers and Victoria.
You believe that?
Well, why not?
Hello, we've got company.
Hello, sir!
Evans, where the devil have you been?
Didn't Staff Arnold tell you, sir?
Yes. Sounded very like desertion to me.
Desertion? Me? Oh, good heavens, no!
No, I... I thought I'd try a single-handed and desperate attempt to rescue Professor Travers and the girl!
Isn't Staff Arnold about?
No.
Good!
Listen!...
Now listen, everyone - when the Yeti come for you, don't struggle. Whatever you do, don't resist them!
Don't struggle, he says! He must be joking!
The Doctor will have to give in. There's no other choice!
Aye, aye, time to get fell in!
Thank you!
Father! Oh, father, are you alright?
Yes, I'm alright again... Don't, don't worry, Anne.
Jamie and the Doctor - where are they?
Anne?
Come towards me... Like that, that's it... Come to...
Right now. Raise your right arm.
Raise your right arm!
Oh, what's the use?
Well, there's nothing to be afraid of, dear. Just - just be calm.
Doctor!
The Doctor!
What are they going to do?
Now don't worry, Victoria.
But... I...
Everything's under control. Don't be frightened.
But Doctor, what are they going to do?
Everything is under control. Tell her, Anne, you understand?
Yes... yes, I think so.
Now listen, everyone. Don't do anything foolish! I am perfectly alright.
Yes, he is perfectly alright. Thank you, Doctor, for being so cooperative.
Why don't you show yourself? Who are you?
Silence! You will know soon enough.
Chorley!
Good grief!
But that horrible little man...
You, the Intelligence?
No... no!
No no no, he can't be the Intelligence, he can't! It doesn't make sense!
It isn't me! It isn't me, don't you understand!
I'm not the Intelligence! The Intelligence is him!
It can't be!
Oh. Arnold
No. Merely Arnold's lifeless body in which I have concealed myself.
But let us to work. There will be time for discussion later. In fact, all the time in the world.
Oh... so you weren't going to let us go then, afterwards?
Did you think he would?
The last member of the party. Come and join us!
Oh, Jamie!
Victoria, are you alright?
Your solicitude is touching. Nevertheless, it is wasting time.
Frightened that something might go wrong?
Join the Doctor.
Do what he says, Jamie.
Take him!
Leave him! Leave him be!
I must ensure your complete cooperation, Doctor. Should you prove at all unhelpful, your young friend's neck will be broken.
You gave your word that no one would be harmed. I refuse to submit until you release Jamie!
Alright. Release the boy!
But at the first sign of trouble from you...
Don't worry. I will do what you say.
Good. Into the machine, Doctor.
Soon your mind will be absorbed by the Great Intelligence. You should be very proud, Doctor - your knowledge of the past will help to shape the future of this planet.
Just get on with it, please.
You seem very anxious suddenly.
I just want it over and done with.
Submission is essential. You must understand, Doctor, that without your complete cooperation,
this transference would be of no value. Should you offer any opposition, either physical or mental, I shall be forced to punish you, or rather your friends.
Prepare for a great darkness to cloud your mind.
Attack now! Attack the Yeti!
Stop it! Stop it!
Get Arnold!
No, Jamie, no!
Come on, get the Doctor out!
No, you don't understand, you'll ruin everything! No!
Professor! Anne! Give us some help!
No! No!... No! Leave me be! You don't understand, I've got to stay here!
Well, that's that then, innit?
You blithering Welsh imbecile! Why can't you do what you're told?
Hey, now just a minute, Doctor! If we hadn't pulled you out of that, you'd have been a heap of dust by now.
You're just as bad. I told you to leave it to me! Now you've gone and ruined everything!
Ruined every - How can we! We... we've won, haven't we?
No!
What do you mean, Doctor?
Oh, why didn't they leave it to me? I had crossed those wires on that helmet thing. The Intelligence wouldn't have drained me, I had... would have drained the Intelligence! As it is, all it got was a crossed circuit!
You mean, all we've done is... is cut off its contact with Earth, it's - it's still out there in space somewhere, flying around?
Precisely! Look!
Oh!
Oh, poor fellow!
Do you mean to say that Arnold wasn't the Intelligence?
No. He was just a poor soldier that was taken over. He was probably one of the first to disappear.
You mean it might come back?
Well, it's still around, isn't it? I've failed.
Nonsense, man!
You were marvellous.
Yes. Great victory.
I doubt it.
No - you were a hero, and you know it.
You don't really think so. Do you?
Yes, yes I do.
You've got to face facts, old man. Tomorrow you're going to be a household word, a national figure...
Oh no, oh no!
Yeah! I want you on my television programme, and...
Jamie! Victoria! Come along, it's time we left!
...but the Press Conference, Doctor!
Goodbye!
But Doctor, Doctor, you... you can't go yet, there are a lot of things I want to discuss with you!
I'm sorry, Travers, we have to go.
Where are you going?
Covent Garden! Come along. Come along, Jamie.
Bye!... Bye.
Where's he going?
Huh? Oh, er, back to his TARDIS, I suppose.
You mean this, uh, this time machine thing, it really exists?
Y... well I, er... oh, explain it to him, Anne, will you?
Colonel, I think we'd better check up top, don't you?
Right, Professor. Evans!
Father - father, I...
Now don't you go, Miss Travers, I'd er, I'd like you to explain all about this, this time machine for me.
Oh dear...!
Well, where do we go? Which is the way to Covent Garden?
Oh, don't ask me. I've completely lost my bearings.
All these tunnels look the same to me.
Come on, let's try this way.
Well it doesn't matter, anyway. I mean, there's no danger, is there?
Well, not from the Yeti, no, but who knows, they might suddenly start the trains again! Come on!
Trains?
Oh!
Come on!
There's someone there...
What?
There!
Who's that? Who is it? D'you see who it was?
No. Do you think it could have been...
The Intelligence? If only we could do something!
I'm sure the Doctor will think of something.
No, not this time, Victoria. The Doctor would never risk the chance of the Intelligence harming you.
You mean he'll just give in?
Yes, I'm afraid so. Afraid there's no alternative.
Yes, you're right, Professor. He has no alternative. I am sorry not to be here to welcome you personally, but I am sure you will not be offended. After all, the guest of honour is the Doctor - he, I am sure, will cooperate, as I advise you to do. Any attempt to interfere would be pointless. My Yeti can destroy you so easily.
It's all my fault! If I hadn't tampered with that sphere - people killed, London invaded, all because of my wretched curiosity!
Don't blame yourself, Professor.
Why not? I... I've sacrificed you all! And for what?
My, my, my, we are in a state, aren't we, sir?
Yes... alright... no, I'm fine. I've just been so scared, that's all!
'S alright, sir, nothing to be ashamed of.
Yes.
There's just one thing that puzzles me though, sir.
Oh, what's that?
How you managed to exist all this time - why didn't the Yetis get you?
I'm sorry, what are you suggesting? You're not suggesting that I...
Oh no, sir, I was just wondering, that's all. I think perhaps you'd better come along with me, don't you, sir? Come on, now.