Mr Silverstein?
Yes. Who are you?
Anne Travers. Is my father here?
Yes, he's here.
Come and see him and take him away.
He's a fool. An old fool!
Father?
Father...
Anne...
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
You were supposed to be meeting me.
- Was I?
- At the airport.
What's wrong? You send me a cable
saying you're in grave trouble.
- I fly half the way round the world...
- Trouble? Yes.
A great deal of trouble. It's that thing.
The Yeti?
Mm.
You're a stupid old fool, Julius Silverstein!
ME the fool? You would like me to be the fool
and give you back my Yeti, huh?
You must, man. Don't you understand?
It's dangerous.
For 30 years this stands here in my museum,
and now he tells me it is dangerous!
- I wish I'd never brought it back from Tibet.
- Father, what has happened?
The silly old goat won't listen to me.
I've told him, warned him.
- Damn it, he knows it's a robot!
- But, Father, the Yeti isn't dangerous.
It can't work unless it has a control unit.
But I've done it, Anne!
I HAVE reactivated the control unit.
But, Father, this is wonderful news.
Is it? Yes, I suppose it would be,
except for one thing.
What?
The sphere - it's gone!
It's disappeared! You must let me
have the Yeti back, Julius.
Make him understand, Anne!
I understand.
I buy the Yeti off you 30 years ago.
Now, it is valuable.
You try to scare me, take your Yeti back.
Why? Money!
- You want to rob me!
- I'll buy the thing back if that's what you want!
No, no. It's priceless.
The only one in the world, and it is mine.
- You fool!
- Thief!
- I'm not a thief.
- Swindler!
Stubborn old goat!
- Father!
- Take him away - out of my house!
Perhaps you've made a mistake.
You've put the sphere away
somewhere in your laboratory and forgotten it.
- You've done it before.
- No. I've looked everywhere.
Let's go home and look again, shall we?
You know what you're like.
Yes, but suppose...
Let's go and have a quiet dinner,
and you can tell me all about it.
Then we'll go home and look for the sphere.
Well, all right...
But I warned you, Julius! I warned you!
Get out! Take him away!
Nobody destroys Julius Silverstein's collection!
Nobody!
- Come on, Father.
- The Yeti's mine!
You can't scare me with your mad stories.
Out! Out!
Travers...
It is you? I am not frightened
by your stupid tricks!
Travers! I know it's you.
I'm not a fool!
Agh!
(theme)
(the web of fear)
Some sort of grille.
Don't say you've landed us in a prison!
It could be the dungeons of a castle.
It's so dark.
Ah, steps.
Come along. Be careful.
Yes...
It seems to be a large room.
Tiled walls.
Curved ceiling.
Come on.
The floor seems to end here.
There's a sort of trench. Look.
- Hey, Doctor. Come and look at this.
- What have you found, Victoria?
See for yourself.
"Covent... Garden... "
Yes, of course! It's an underground station.
We're standing on the platform.
- Underground station?
- Underground trains.
- A little after your time, Victoria.
- Is it always as dark as this?
No, it's probably the middle of the night.
Come on. Let's go up top.
- Professor Travers is here, sir.
- Why have I been brought here? Who are you?
- Knight.
- Never heard of you.
Captain Knight. OK, Corporal.
It's no good shouting at me.
- I didn't ask for you.
- Who did, then?
- Your daughter.
- Anne? Just like her mother.
Always interfering in things!
I understood that you'd sent for her to help you.
What do you want me for?
- I don't. I think this is a military matter.
- Well, you haven't had much success so far!
Army What the devil do they know about it?
- The Doctor was wrong!
- It's not night-time. It's broad daylight.
- Just let me get my breath... Those stairs!
- It looks like we're locked in.
- That's strange.
- Doctor...
- Yes?
- Listen.
I can't hear anything.
Oh... It IS quiet. I see what you mean. The
middle of London. There should be some noise.
There's an old man over there. Let's ask him.
Yes, go on.
Excuse me...
Who are you?
- Harold Chorley. London Television.
- What? Television?
- Never watch it. Are you an actor?
- Journalist, actually.
The government decided to only allow one
correspondent down here. The press chose me.
Oh, yeah?
Will you be in charge of the scientific section,
or will your daughter?
Mind your own business!
How long do you think it will take you
to come up with the answer?
- One week? Three, perhaps?
- How the hell should I know?
- Is that working?
- Of course.
It's more than likely
we may not be able to defeat this menace.
The whole of England might be completely
wiped out. There - did you get that?
- What are you doing?
- Just confirming something.
Just as I thought.
There haven't been any trains here for some time.
What's that over there?
It's a power cable.
I wonder what it's doing down here.
In there quickly!
Soldiers? I wonder what they're doing down here.
- Let's go and ask them.
- No. I think we'd better tread carefully.
Let's go and find out what's going on first.
What do you want us to do, Doctor?
You follow the soldiers, but keep out of sight.
I'm going to see where this cable goes to.
Meet back here in a few minutes.
- What's the matter?
- I thought I heard something.
- Getting a bit jumpy, aren't you, Weams?
- It's no wonder, is it, Staff?
- Shall we connect the new drum now, Staff?
- All right, Corporal.
- Good thing we fixed these lights.
- Yeah.
- I can't hear anything.
- Are they still there?
I think they must be moving. Come on.
Agh!
- I told you I heard something, didn't I?
- Yeah.
Come on!
- I'm sorry!
- It was only a cobweb!
- Do you think they heard?
- Hope not. Come on.
Well, well, well, would you believe it?
The Babes in the Wood!
- You're quite sure there was nobody with you?
- How many more times?
That's all right, then.
- Clear to fire, Staff?
- Yes, they were on their own.
Right.
What was all that about?
I suppose there's no harm in telling you.
You two are very lucky.
- We're going to blow up the tunnel.
- What?!
- That's what the cable's for.
- The Doctor!
It's all right. They were on their own.
OK, let's not waste any more time. Off you go.
Agh!
A doctor! Well, if he was anywhere near those explosives when they went up...
Yes sir. Don't you think I should go and have a look, sir? The youngsters said he was following the cable.
Yes, you'd better.
Sir!
Oh, and Staff, take someone with you.
Father?
Hmm...?
The soldiers have found two youngsters in the tunnels. They seem to know a great deal about the Yeti.
Oh?
They know they're robots!
What!
And they know about the control spheres, too.
But they can't have - I mean, the public were never told!
I know.
Hello, hello, Holborn?... This is HQ to Holborn. Can you hear me?... Not a sausage.
There must be someone manning the phone.
OK, Lane, what gives?
Well, it's just firing at the other end, sir.
Firing?
Yes, sir. Listen.
Oh, good grief, no!
Hello, HQ to Holborn?
What happened, Lane?
Well, it was difficult to hear, sir. I think the truck was late getting there...
Then what?
Well they must have got the ammo unloaded, sir, 'cos he says they were jumped when they were moving.
Take O'Brien and a couple of the others.
Sir! Come on, mate.
Here, you're not going out there?
Yes, Mr Chorley. Want to come? Report some action first hand?
Well, I don't think I'd better get in the way. I... er... think I'd better stay here, don't you?
Yes. Yes, I think you better had.
Father?
But it... it can't be...
Why that's... that's over... forty years ago!
What's going on here?
Oh Jamie, don't you recognise him? It's Professor Travers.
So it is! Professor Travers! Here, hasn't he got old!
Huh?
Oh, but we're very pleased to see you, Professor, very pleased.
The time machine... it was all true then?
The TARDIS - I mean aye, of course it's true! Hey, do you know what's happened to the Doctor?
Oh, is he safe?
Isn't he with you?
No, he's in the tunnels. Arnold's gone to look for him. Father, what is going on?
Oh dear, I do hope he's alright. Come on, Jamie, let's go and find out if he's got back yet.
Father!
Eh? Oh, Victoria, try and explain to Anne, will you?
Oh dear!
There hasn't been an explosion, Staff!
Oh, no - well at least, we hope not.
I can see that, lad... Here!
No sign of that Doctor bloke.
No... here, give me a hand with this.
It's our detonator, alright. It's fired, too... 'ere, hang on a minute. All the ammo, Staff. If it's fired, then why didn't...
Yeah, why didn't this tunnel go up?... No damage at all...
Yet something blew up here!
It's obvious, ain't it? It's been got at.
Where's that Doctor? That's what I'd like to know.
Tibet? Tibet? You're joking.
That's where old Travers says they come from. He reckons they're Abominable Snowmen.
Well, he's off his chump, ain't he? How'd they get here in the first place?
Come through the post, don't they?
Nah, seriously. Outer space, that's where they come from. Well that's what I reckon, anyway.
Oh do leave off! You've been reading too many kids' comics, you have!
Alright then, Corp, where do they come from?
It's a foreign power, ain't it? Bacteriological warfare, that's what that stuff is in the tunnels.
What, that fungus stuff?
Yeah. And them Yeti are some sort of new weapon. Well, a sort of robot army.
What, you mean it ain't real then?
Father?
Hmm?
Have you ever seen this TARDIS?
No, no, I can't say I have.
It all sounds a bit far-fetched to me.
You know, I think the Doctor's at the back of all this.
What do you mean?
Doesn't it strike you as odd that on the two occasions you've encountered the Yeti, you've also come across the Doctor?
Well?
Well, it's obvious - he controls them!
Oh, but surely...
What? Oh, tea. Thank you, my dear.
Oh, aren't you having any?
No, I think I'll go and lie down for a bit.
Good idea.
Do you think she heard?
No... in any case, what you say is nonsense, Anne.
I saw the Doctor defeat those robots and save Detsen Monastery.
He wouldn't do that if he was in league with them, now would he?
No, no I suppose not.
Here, Corp, look at this!
What... oh crikey! That's what comes of talking about it!
It's that fungus stuff, it's moving again!
Don't worry!
Can't help it - I feel... responsible somehow.
If only the Doctor would turn up. I'm sure he could help us.
'Scuse me, sir...
Eh, what?
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again. Euston Square's gone.
Come on, let's have a look!
It's on the move again, Weams?
Yes, sir. Kings Cross has gone, and it's moving on to Farringdon.
It's never moved as fast as this before!
Hasn't moved at all the last three weeks, Miss.
What started it up again all of a sudden?
Can't say.
Strange, isn't it, that all this should happen on the very day that your mysterious Doctor friend turns up?
He hasn't turned up.
Precisely. He could have sent those kids in here as spies.
Rubbish! Would Jamie go away and leave Victoria, if he didn't intend coming back again?
Excuse me, sir, but where is the young lady?
Oh, in the Common Room, I suppose.
No she's not, 'cos I went in there when I was looking for you!
What? Well... where is she then?
Jamie? Doctor?... Jamie? Doctor?
Victoria!
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness I found you! Are you alright?
Look, sir, the fungus! It's moving again!
Hope the Captain and Staff Arnold ain't anywhere near that little lot.
Lane? Lane! Fall back, you'll never hold them!
Will nothing stop them?
Come on, back!
We couldn't hold 'em, sir. They're coming, two of 'em! They got O'Brien and Cocksey, nothing stops them!
It's Staff Arnold!
Yeah, come on.
Captain?
Yeti!
They got two of us!
And the ammo detail - they're all gone.
What's the plan then?
I brought a load of explosives down from Holborn. I'm going to blow it - and them with it.
Taking a bit of a risk, aren't you, sir?
Yeah, I know.
Hey, look what's happening!
What are they doing?
Looks like the cobwebs!
Cobwebs or not, I'm going to blow it sky high. Get back!
What's that noise?
The boxes are pulsating!
Get back!
This waiting's getting on my nerves. Why the heck don't they do something?
Steady, lad. We'll know soon enough.
We can't just stand here. Can't we make a run for it?
We wouldn't stand a chance, not with them switched on.
How do you know that?
It's alright, sir. The Professor's vouched for him. Understand he knows a great deal about these robots.
See, you have to find out...
What's that?
What made them do that, I wonder?
Couldn't say, sir. But I don't think we should stay to find out.
Yes, you're right, Staff. Come on, let's get back.
Wait - can we not just see what they're up to?
No! If there's one thing that I've learned, it's never push your luck. Now come on.
Soldier!
Well, there's a sight for sore eyes!
Are you stark raving mad?
Aye, well I always sing when I'm scared, see.
Stand to attention when you're talking to an officer!
Name and serial!
6-0...
Shush!
6-0-1 Evans, sir!
Evans? Anybody know him?
Oh, I'm not one of your lot, sir.
Then what are you doing down here?
Trying to get out, Sarge!
Don't try to be funny with me, lad! How did you get down here in the first place?
Driver on the ammo truck to Holborn. Got jumped, we did - quite a dust up, there was.
Couldn't get past them hairy creatures, see? Been wandering for hours. Lost, I was.
I tried one way, but there seemed to be some sort of cobweb muck moving down the tunnel.
Moving? Are you sure it was moving?
Well of course I'm sure!... sir. Sounds daft, I know,
but it seemed to be following a Yeti that had a kind of pointed glass thing in its hands.
Was it shaped like a pyramid?
Well, I suppose it was, really.
Well that's it! Smash the pyramid, and you put the Intelligence out of action!
What Intelligence?
Whereabouts did you say this happened?
Kings Cross, Staff.
What!
Headquarters, sir - HQ may be in danger!
Yes, we'd better get back as soon as we can. Come on.
No, look...
Now listen to what the officer said, young man. Come on!
Look, I came down here to find the Doctor. I'm not going back till I have!
Now look here...
No, I'm not going! And if I get a chance to smash that pyramid, I will!
That's quite a risk you're taking.
Aye, but it's me that's taking it.
Alright, it's your neck, chum.
Sir!
Yes?
I'd like to volunteer to go with the young gentleman, sir.
Well, you're not one of my lot... alright. Come on, the rest of you.
Monument! Then it's Tower Hill next.
Wait a minute! Did you hear something?
What?
Listen.
Look! The fungus, it's here!
We'd better get out, fast!
- Jamie!  - Doctor! Good to see you!
All right, Corporal. Nip back and tell Captain Knight it's all clear up 'ere. And get 'em to get a shift on!
Righto, Staff.
This looks familiar - it's around this corner.
Oh no!
Oh, we can't get to the TARDIS!
No, Victoria, I'm afraid we can't.
What's happened to Chorley, then?
That's what I'm wondering. Did he reach the TARDIS before the fungus, or... or did he not?
You mean to say, he could have got to the TARDIS and already have taken off in it?
I don't know...
Hey, come back, Doctor!
It's alright, Jamie, I'm not going to do anything silly. I...
I just want to try and get a little bit for an analysis.
Oh Jamie, stop him!
It's alright, Victoria.
Has anyone got a box?
I've got my tobacco tin.
Oh, splendid.
But then, it's got tobacco in it.
Never mind.
Eh!... Oh, alright. I only hope you think the sacrifice is worth it!
Hold the tin for me, would you, Evans?
Gone and set it off! Come on, now!
Oh, it's horrible!
Go on, Doctor, get it out!
Hold the tin underneath!
There we are - now back, everyone, quickly!
Hello, Staff. It's alright, it's just Staff Arnold!
One of these days, Evans my lad, you're going to creep up onto someone once too often!
Well, that's life, innit Staff?
Any luck at Holborn?
No - fungus.
Same back there.
Right. I'll tell the Colonel. You lot had better get back to HQ. We'll be along in a few minutes.
Come on, Jamie, I'll just show this bit of fungus to Travers.
Right.
Hey, look at this!
Good Lord! That's Yeti!
You don't think they may still be here?
I hope not!
Oh, Doctor!
D'you reckon they have?
Have what?
Taken him? Like she said?
Yes, I'm very much afraid they have. But why? Why didn't they just kill him? Unless...
Yes?
Well, unless they had a use for him.
Ah, Doctor. What's this I hear about Travers?
'Scuse me, sir, but I think you ought to come to the Ops Room.
Why? What's happening?
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again!
It's like a spider's web, ain't it?
Yes. And we're the flies, alright, but... where is the spider?
Better give the others a hand, Corporal.
Sir.
Doctor. Been thinking about what you were saying earlier,
about someone here in HQ being responsible for all this.
Could it have been Travers?
I doubt it.
Well, after all he has disappeared.
Yes - so has Chorley. I'd say he was a much more likely suspect.
True.
On the other hand, of course, whoever is in league with the Intelligence could still be amongst us here.
That's a fact of which I am uncomfortably aware.
But tell me, Doctor, this Intelligence - exactly what is it?
Well I wish I could give you a precise answer.
Perhaps the best way to describe it is a sort of formless, shapeless thing
floating about in space like a cloud of mist, only... with a mind and will.
What's it after? What's it want?
I wish I knew. The only thing I know for sure is that it brought me here.
Brought you here?
Yes, been wondering how you got here.
Yes, well I... I don't think there's any harm in telling you now.
I...I have a craft, that travels in time and space.
Oh, come now Doctor, you can't expect me to...
This craft of yours, this time-space craft. Could it get us out of here?
Well, yes - but it's at Covent Garden!
What does it look like?
It's a police box.
Oh really, Colonel, surely you're not...
So - if we could rescue that craft, you could take us out?
Yes, yes I could, but I have to stay here and finish Travers' work!
Ah, Doctor. Miss Travers is feeling alright now, and would like to see you right away.
Very good, Jamie. Excuse me, gentlemen, please.
Yes.
Well, I've heard some stories in my time, but that one really takes...
So you don't believe him?
No, of course not, sir! The whole idea is screwy. A police box!
Well whether you think it foolish or not, we are going to rescue that craft.
Oh, but sir! Our job...
Captain Knight. The Army has failed to defeat this menace.
Now the Doctor thinks he might succeed. Personally, I doubt it.
But if we stay here, we're as good as dead.
Therefore I do not intend leaving any escape route unexplored, however... screwy you may think it.
Oh, surely Colonel...
Let's get on with it, shall we, Knight?
Sir.
But... but there must be a chance! If the Doctor says...
No, the soldiers could comb these tunnels for a fortnight and still never find him.
I'm afraid your father's been taken by the Intelligence.
The only way that we can save him is by finding the central control source.
Aye, if he's anywhere, that's where he'll be.
But why? Why him? Why not me, or one of the soldiers, or...
Yes, I know. Tell me, what was your father working
on just before the Yeti broke in, Anne?
Um... oh, we were ready to test the sphere with the control unit
but I don't see what this has to do with anything, Doctor.
But don't you? If he was near to success...
That's why they took him!
Well, it's a possibility, isn't it?
Now Anne, do you feel strong enough to come back to the laboratory?
Yes, yes of course.
Anything we can do?
No, no, you just take it easy, Jamie.
What's the matter?
I've been thinking about what the Doctor said.
Anything we do, the Intelligence always knows!
Aye, but I wouldn't let it worry you. The Doctor will soon find a way out.
I wish I could believe that.
Oh yes. Yes, this seems to be in order, Anne.
My father didn't want it put together until this was in proper order.
Very wise. Let's have a look at this...
Oh yes, yes... My word, this is a splendid piece of work, Anne.
Thank you.
Yes, this should control the sphere, alright, but would it override the commands issued by the Intelligence, I wonder?
No. No, I'm afraid it won't. I just didn't have the time. Do you think we can do it?
Oh, we can do it, if you've got the right bits and pieces.
Hope I'm not disturbing, Doctor, but Staff asked me to give you this.
Where'd you get this?
On the floor, by that young lad Weams, it was.
But this is what brought the Yeti to the explosives store!
It's obviously been reprogrammed as a homing device, and you've given it to me!
Here! You don't think I had anything to do with these Yeti, do you?
Doctor! The other models - they've gone!
Well don't look at me! I didn't want to come down here in the first place!
I shouldn't be down here at all, really. Driver, I am, see.
You'd better have this, before you say I've nicked it.
Thank you.
And I'll have the tin back, when you've finished with it.
Don't look so unhappy - we're all under suspicion, you know, including me.
Hmm!
What's in the tin, Doctor?
It's the fungus from the tunnel. I thought if we examined it, it might give us a clue.
I must get this dismantled. It's like holding a time bomb.
So my party will get above ground and approach Covent Garden by Neal Street. Is that clear?
Now Staff here will be taking the trolley through the tunnel, and will arrive, we hope, at the same time as we do. You picked your two men, Staff?
Yes, sir. Lane and Evans.
Right. Now as soon as we get there, we shall be looking for a police box.
A police box, sir?
Yes, a police box. Now I want that box either out of the station or onto the trolley as quickly as possible. Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
Right. Any questions?
Yes, sir, this, um... police box. Is it important?
Corporal Blake, we'd hardly be going to this trouble if it weren't.
Who's going to look after the civilians, sir?
I'd like you to stay behind and look after them, Captain Knight.
The Doctor's got work to do. Right gentlemen, time to go.
Ah, Doctor.
Oh Jamie, what is it?
The Colonel says to tell you he's on his way.
On his way where?
To rescue the TARDIS!
He's wasting his time.
Well that's what I told him. And I think that man Chorley must be behind...
Now look! Get behind me, both of you, and keep clear. Here we go...
No!
What is it, Doctor?
The tin's empty!... Evans!
Course, really I shouldn't be doing this, you know, Staff.
Not officially on the strength down here, see.
What I am really is a driver, you see...
Don't try to come the old soldier with me, lad!
Who, me?
Yes, you! And when we get in the tunnels, don't you try to skive off,
'cos if you do I'll have you for breakfast. D'you understand?
Trolley's ready, Staff.
Right, come on!
So far, so good. If we don't see any Yeti, we should make Covent Garden in about ten minutes. Come on!
Captain, they've gone, and Evans with them, I think. I can't find him anywhere.
Yes, well we'd better question Evans carefully when he gets back.
Aye, if he gets back.
It's a funny business, Doctor, that fungus disappearing.
Yes, yes I know... Don't worry about that just at the moment.
I've been working on this control box with Miss Travers.
There's a few more things I need - transistors, circuits...
Aren't there any in Stores?
No, not of the right type.
Well in that case, Doctor, I can't help you.
Well - I was wondering... if I could go up to street level...
The mist! Or the Yeti!
There's no mist directly above us here - we'd have to risk the Yeti.
No. No, I'm afraid that's out.
It's terribly important. Please!
It'll only take five minutes.
Alright. I'll get my gear.
Well done, Travers!
The Colonel will be through there at Covent Garden in a few minutes, right?
Do you think they'll be able to load the police box on here, Staff?
Well, if we can get this thing through the fungus stuff -
there's not much of a gradient in this section of the tunnel.
Right, I want one volunteer.
Volunteer? That's a dirty word, that is. Not me!
Lane?
What for, Staff?
Well, if this thing wants some help going through to Covent Garden, I'm going through with it...
Into that stuff?
Have we got those respirators?
Well yeah, here.
I reckon we should be all right in these.
Oh all right, Lane lad. I'll go by meself.
No, 'ang on a sec, Staff. That trolley's heavy, it'll take two of us to shift it.
Good lad. Come on.
You're potty, the pair of you!
Shut up, will you! Do as you're told.
Play that rope out as we go; any sign of trouble whip us out sharpish. Right?
Well, it's your neck.
OK.
Alright then...
Staff? Staff Arnold?...
Look, sir!
In Here! Quick!
Come on, through the gate!
I'm going to find a way out. Split up!
Yetis - three of them, sir!
Grenades!
Right, fire!
Sir, they're smashing down the gate!
We can't hold 'em, sir!
Over the top, all of you!
Grenades!
Through the yard, come on!
Right, bazooka here to cover the others.
Dawson! Langley!
Make for the warehouse!... Murphy!
There it is again, Doctor!
Just one more thing.
For heaven's sake, hurry up!
I just need one more component. I'll look through here.
Doctor! Doctor, look out!
No! No!
And this was in his pocket, you say?
How did he get it? You said it was stolen.
You can't think that he...
No no no, he didn't steal it. The person who did planted it on him.
Hmm!
Eh, don't you try and pin this on me, boyo! Strikes me, anything goes wrong around here and I'm always the one to get the blame.
Alright, alright, let's keep our temper, shall we? The point is, two of these were missing. Now where's the other one?
There. That one shouldn't bother us any more.
Now then, come along, Anne, let's get down to work.
Where did I put those bits and pieces?
I wish I knew who put it in the Captain's pocket.
Well it must have been Chorley.
Well look, he left ages ago.
It doesn't matter. He could still...
Colonel!
Are you alright?
What's happened?
Colonel, what happened?
Gone.
Not all of them?
All of them?
I said so, didn't I? All of them. Evans, what about your party?
Arnold?
Gone, sir.
Captain Knight, too.
Knight! Hopeless.
Can't fight them - it seems... indestructible. Can't fight them!
You were right, Doctor, when you said they were... formless, shapeless... you were right.
Listen... listen, everyone! It's the other Yeti model! It's here! It's somewhere in this room!
That noise, I've been hearing it on and off all day...
Your pockets!
What?
Open your pockets, Colonel! Quickly, quickly, come on!
How... how...
They bring the Yeti!
Oh no!
I just don't understand what's happening!
Poor Travers!
Silence!
Father!
No, no! No!
But I must...
No, Anne! Don't go near him. Just... just listen to him.
I... am... the Intelligence!
Listen to me! I speak to you with this man's voice
because the time has come for you to understand my purpose.
What's he getting at?
Quiet!
What do you want?
You defeated me in Tibet, Doctor.
Yes.
Now you have fallen into the trap that I have so carefully prepared for you.
What do you want?
You! Your mind will be invaluable to me. Therefore I have invented a machine
that will drain all past knowledge and experience from your mind.
But you'll kill him!
Oh, no. He will survive, his mind unharmed - only empty
You can't - we'll fight!
That will not do. The Doctor must submit willingly.
And if I... if I do submit, what of the others?
Then the others will go free.
And my father too?
Oh, him too. I'm only using his body to communicate with you.
He didn't help you before, then?
Oh, no. I have many other human hands at my command.
And who are they?
Always questioning! Even now, you're seeking to destroy me! I see I shall have to guide your thoughts.
No, Jamie, no!
Cooperate and the child will be unharmed. You have twenty minutes to make up your mind.
Let me go, Doctor!
Jamie, don't be a fool! You don't stand a chance.
Let me go! Victoria!
Let me past, Colonel!
No. The Doctor's right. There've been enough lives wasted.
Please... my wrist... Professor!
Eh! Wait a minute!
What is it, Evans, what's the matter now?
Stand back everyone!
I thought I heard it go!
Yes, well we'd better make sure. Evans - you, myself and McCrimmon will go and search the place. Doctor, you'd better stay behind here and get on with your tinkering.
Professor, please, you're hurting me! My wrist! Professor!
Yes... yes, that should complete the circuit, good... I wonder...
There's only one way to find out.
Yes. Certainly no sound out there.
Shall we chance it, then?
Why not?
Now!
No! Back! No!
Push! Push! Push, hard as you can! Push, get your back to it! Get your back to it!
Fire door - by the stairs - go and unhitch it, and I'll try to hold this. Go on, McCrimmon!
You sure?
Yes, go on! Go on!
Alright, Colonel, come on!
Strange, it's not picking up. The Intelligence must be transmitting... I wonder why it's not working...
Aha! Success! It's going, Anne! Come along.
Oh, oh that's marvellous. I'm sorry I'm being so long - this is such a fiddling job.
Help you in a minute...
There we are. Now then...
Yes, you see, it's homing!
There we are...
Do we go on or turn back?
Let's go on.
Right.
Come on, what are you waiting for?
Hey, wait a minute!
This is Victoria's! We're on the right track!
No, don't shoot!
Is that thing on our side, then?
It is now. Stop!
Were you scared?
Eh? Oh no, no, I mean, I just got up here to get a better aim, that's all. How did you make it stop then?
Simple - I told it to.
Here - ball. Why don't you go back where you come from?
Now, pull the other one.
Oh, show him, Doctor.
Alright, I will. Move forward.
Stop... Move to the left... Stop.
There you are, how about that?
Hey, that's great! Make a smashing toy, that would.
Toy? That's a highly complex piece of equipment.
Oh, is it? Well I don't see how it's going to help us.
But it obeys our commands!
So?
Well, once we get it inside a Yeti, we'll have a powerful ally!
Inside a Yeti?
Yes, certainly. Will you help us?
You must be joking, Go near one of them things? I may be stupid, but I'm not daft...
Oh very well, Anne, I shall have to do it myself.
Oh, I'm coming with you, Doctor.
No no, it's far too dangerous.
There you are, what'd I tell you?
Not another word, I'm coming with you.
Hold it.
Staff Arnold? It can't be, we'd given you up for lost!
Easy, easy...
That's it.
Sorry about this, sir.
What happened?
I don't know. Can't remember. I were pushing the trolley through the fungus, and...
and I blacked out. I thought I were... falling. When I come to, sir, I were in the tunnels...
Where's the Doctor, sir? I met the Professor and the girl back there...
Victoria! Is she alright?
Yeti - guarding them, but... I promised I'd tell the Doctor, sir.
Right. Come on, back to HQ.
I'm going for Victoria.
Really, we'd stand a better chance if we stick together. Go ahead! Come on, Staff.
Doctor's twenty minutes' almost up.
Evans, come out from behind that board.
Oh, it's you, sir.
Where's the Doctor?
Evans!
B-b-but y-y-y-you...
Stop bleating like a Welsh baa-lamb, Evans, and answer the Colonel.
Sir?
Doctor and Miss Travers, where are they?
Gone, sir.
Gone - where?
Warren Street, I think.
Why?
After a Yeti, they said.
Have a look at the board, sir.
Warren Street.
Come on!
No, not you, Staff. Evans, make yourself useful. Get a dressing for the Staff Sergeant's head.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
We're trapped!
Give me the control box, Anne.
The control box...
Yes.
Haven't you got it, Doctor?
What! What... hold the sphere!
Oh Doctor, you must have it!
Yes...
Doctor!
Don't worry, it'll work!... It's got to work!
I know you said it only worked at short range, but for a moment...
Well, don't tell me you were worried? Would you like to hold this for me?
It's alright, it's quite safe.
Nearly out... there.
Right.
Now then - turn round!
Oh, it works! You've done it!
We've done it, you mean! Now then, with my reprogrammed sphere and your control box,
we should be able to work him over quite a distance. And put your arm down!
Now we've got a chance, Anne. Come on!
Oh, mustn't forget him. Come on, Fred, at the double!
Staff! Staff!
What is it?
What is it, Evans?
Go on, Evans lad, get out of it!
What are we going to do now, Staff?
The main door should keep the fungus out of the tunnels for a bit. We must warn the others that HQ's had it.
Right.
Well, come on, then.
Oh, oh no, not me.
You're not disobeying an order, are you, Evans?
Now look here, Staff. If we go up there, and this stuff breaks out, we'll be trapped!
Now look, lad, you're scared, that's understandable.
But you've been in the Army long enough to know that orders is orders.
There's four people up there. If we don't warn them, they're for the chop.
So? Four of them's getting the chop - there's no reason to make it six, is there?
I've had enough of your lip for one day. Now come on! Follow me.
Evans! Come back here!
Not on your nelly! Cheerio, Staff!
Right, lad - I'll get you for this!
Anne...
Hey!
Stop! Come back here!
Stop! Anne, I've been thinking. Until we know who else is working for the Intelligence, everyone must be suspect.
Yes?
Well, the fewer people who know this chap's on our side, the better.
Yes... yes, and whoever is the Intelligence is bound to know that you're controlling this Yeti.
Mmm... I know.
You are to remain here for... Do you think a minute will be enough?
What for?
For us to get clear.
Perhaps.
You are to remain here for ninety seconds, and then resume acting on orders from the Intelligence until you are told otherwise. Is that understood?
Right. Switch off, for ninety seconds, starting from... now.
Come on, Anne.
It is them! Come on!
Am I glad to see you! There's fungus at Warren Street.
Yes, I know.
Oh. What are you doing down here, anyway?
Well, as a matter of fact...
I'll tell you another time. Hello, Colonel.
Glad to see you're both safe. Any luck with your gadgets?
No. No, I'm afraid not.
Pity.
Any news of Victoria?
Yes, she's at Piccadilly Station.
Piccadilly?
Is my father there too?
Aye, he's with her.
Are they alright?
Yes.
How do you know?
Ran across Arnold - he saw them.
Arnold?
Arnold! But Evans said - the fungus...
Yes, he went into it, alright, but he came out again somehow.
Says he can't remember what happened.
Well we haven't got any time to find out.
No, time's nearly up.
Yes, your twenty minutes.
Well come on, then.
What are you going to do?
We can't do anything until we get back to Headquarters,
and... then, if we've got time, we'll try and increase the range of the control units. Come on!
What is it, Colonel?
Something up ahead.
We can't go back!
What, fungus, you mean?
Yes.
Is that you, Colonel?
It's Arnold. Hang on, Staff!
Why isn't he in HQ?
Sir - the fungus. It's swamped HQ.
No!
I'm afraid so, sir. The main doors should keep it out of the tunnels for a bit, but...
Where's Evans?
Scarpered, sir.
Our time's up! We're all together - they've come to fetch us!
H... hello! If you... if you're looking for your friend, he went that way...
Look, you don't want me!... I'm not one of them, see?...
Driver, that's what I am... shouldn't be down here at all, really...
Hey, steady on!
Oh, going for a walk, are we? There's lovely.
I'm going to make a break for it, sir.
Think you can?
Well, it's worth a try. On the loose, sir, I might be able to do something. If only you could distract them, sir.
Right, Staff.
I think it wants us to go on, sir.
Right. Here we go.
Wait!... Can't you see, he's fallen over!
Be careful, be careful!
Where are we being taken, Professor?
Oh, to meet the Intelligence, I suppose.
A pyramid!
Yes - but it's different! We... we've never seen one like this before. It's fascinating!
This must be the machine that the Intelligence intends using on the Doctor.
Oh, no no. No, I shouldn't if I was you.
Yes, I think perhaps you're right.
Why didn't you tell me all this before?
Him.
You don't think the Colonel...
Well, you never know, do you?
Which one is ours?
I don't know.
What!
Well unfortunately I've lost track of him.
Oh, that's a great help!
Well, never mind, I... I want you to take this microphone and keep on calling our Yeti to you.
How will I know I've got the right one?
Well, you'll soon know if you haven't got the right one, won't you!
Jamie, I hope you don't suffer from claustrophobia!
Sergeant! Oh, oh thank heavens I found you! I've been wondering down here by myself for... for ages!
Well well well, quite forgotten about you, we had, Mr Chorley!
Tried to get out over the surface, but... there were Yeti everywhere!
And there's this... this fungus, and fog, all around, you see, and... it's hopeless!
Where's the control box?
Hm?
The control box!
It's in my pocket.
Well, why don't you use it on these Yeti? And then maybe we can escape!
Oh, no. I must meet the Intelligence face to face.
Doctor?
What is it?
Been thinking - the Yeti haven't noticed McCrimmon's disappearance yet.
Not that I think he'll be able to achieve anything.
Go on...
Well, I don't really know how to say this, but, um... there's Miss Travers and Victoria to think of, and, er...
You mean, am I going to give myself up?
Yes. Of course, the decision must be yours, and yours alone. But the Intelligence did promise to release Travers and Victoria.
You believe that?
Well, why not?
Hello, we've got company.
Hello, sir!
Evans, where the devil have you been?
Didn't Staff Arnold tell you, sir?
Yes. Sounded very like desertion to me.
Desertion? Me? Oh, good heavens, no!
No, I... I thought I'd try a single-handed and desperate attempt to rescue Professor Travers and the girl!
Isn't Staff Arnold about?
No.
Good!
Listen!...
Now listen, everyone - when the Yeti come for you, don't struggle. Whatever you do, don't resist them!
Don't struggle, he says! He must be joking!
The Doctor will have to give in. There's no other choice!
Aye, aye, time to get fell in!
Thank you!
Father! Oh, father, are you alright?
Yes, I'm alright again... Don't, don't worry, Anne.
Jamie and the Doctor - where are they?
Anne?
Come towards me... Like that, that's it... Come to...
Right now. Raise your right arm.
Raise your right arm!
Oh, what's the use?
Well, there's nothing to be afraid of, dear. Just - just be calm.
Doctor!
The Doctor!
What are they going to do?
Now don't worry, Victoria.
But... I...
Everything's under control. Don't be frightened.
But Doctor, what are they going to do?
Everything is under control. Tell her, Anne, you understand?
Yes... yes, I think so.
Now listen, everyone. Don't do anything foolish! I am perfectly alright.
Yes, he is perfectly alright. Thank you, Doctor, for being so cooperative.
Why don't you show yourself? Who are you?
Silence! You will know soon enough.
Chorley!
Good grief!
But that horrible little man...
You, the Intelligence?
No... no!
No no no, he can't be the Intelligence, he can't! It doesn't make sense!
It isn't me! It isn't me, don't you understand!
I'm not the Intelligence! The Intelligence is him!
It can't be!
Oh. Arnold
No. Merely Arnold's lifeless body in which I have concealed myself.
But let us to work. There will be time for discussion later. In fact, all the time in the world.
Oh... so you weren't going to let us go then, afterwards?
Did you think he would?
The last member of the party. Come and join us!
Oh, Jamie!
Victoria, are you alright?
Your solicitude is touching. Nevertheless, it is wasting time.
Frightened that something might go wrong?
Join the Doctor.
Do what he says, Jamie.
Take him!
Leave him! Leave him be!
I must ensure your complete cooperation, Doctor. Should you prove at all unhelpful, your young friend's neck will be broken.
You gave your word that no one would be harmed. I refuse to submit until you release Jamie!
Alright. Release the boy!
But at the first sign of trouble from you...
Don't worry. I will do what you say.
Good. Into the machine, Doctor.
Soon your mind will be absorbed by the Great Intelligence. You should be very proud, Doctor - your knowledge of the past will help to shape the future of this planet.
Just get on with it, please.
You seem very anxious suddenly.
I just want it over and done with.
Submission is essential. You must understand, Doctor, that without your complete cooperation,
this transference would be of no value. Should you offer any opposition, either physical or mental, I shall be forced to punish you, or rather your friends.
Prepare for a great darkness to cloud your mind.
Attack now! Attack the Yeti!
Stop it! Stop it!
Get Arnold!
No, Jamie, no!
Come on, get the Doctor out!
No, you don't understand, you'll ruin everything! No!
Professor! Anne! Give us some help!
No! No!... No! Leave me be! You don't understand, I've got to stay here!
Well, that's that then, innit?
You blithering Welsh imbecile! Why can't you do what you're told?
Hey, now just a minute, Doctor! If we hadn't pulled you out of that, you'd have been a heap of dust by now.
You're just as bad. I told you to leave it to me! Now you've gone and ruined everything!
Ruined every - How can we! We... we've won, haven't we?
No!
What do you mean, Doctor?
Oh, why didn't they leave it to me? I had crossed those wires on that helmet thing. The Intelligence wouldn't have drained me, I had... would have drained the Intelligence! As it is, all it got was a crossed circuit!
You mean, all we've done is... is cut off its contact with Earth, it's - it's still out there in space somewhere, flying around?
Precisely! Look!
Oh!
Oh, poor fellow!
Do you mean to say that Arnold wasn't the Intelligence?
No. He was just a poor soldier that was taken over. He was probably one of the first to disappear.
You mean it might come back?
Well, it's still around, isn't it? I've failed.
Nonsense, man!
You were marvellous.
Yes. Great victory.
I doubt it.
No - you were a hero, and you know it.
You don't really think so. Do you?
Yes, yes I do.
You've got to face facts, old man. Tomorrow you're going to be a household word, a national figure...
Oh no, oh no!
Yeah! I want you on my television programme, and...
Jamie! Victoria! Come along, it's time we left!
...but the Press Conference, Doctor!
Goodbye!
But Doctor, Doctor, you... you can't go yet, there are a lot of things I want to discuss with you!
I'm sorry, Travers, we have to go.
Where are you going?
Covent Garden! Come along. Come along, Jamie.
Bye!... Bye.
Where's he going?
Huh? Oh, er, back to his TARDIS, I suppose.
You mean this, uh, this time machine thing, it really exists?
Y... well I, er... oh, explain it to him, Anne, will you?
Colonel, I think we'd better check up top, don't you?
Right, Professor. Evans!
Father - father, I...
Now don't you go, Miss Travers, I'd er, I'd like you to explain all about this, this time machine for me.
Oh dear...!
Well, where do we go? Which is the way to Covent Garden?
Oh, don't ask me. I've completely lost my bearings.
All these tunnels look the same to me.
Come on, let's try this way.
Well it doesn't matter, anyway. I mean, there's no danger, is there?
Well, not from the Yeti, no, but who knows, they might suddenly start the trains again! Come on!
Trains?
Oh!
Come on!
There's someone there...
What?
There!
Who's that? Who is it? D'you see who it was?
No. Do you think it could have been...
The Intelligence? If only we could do something!
I'm sure the Doctor will think of something.
No, not this time, Victoria. The Doctor would never risk the chance of the Intelligence harming you.
You mean he'll just give in?
Yes, I'm afraid so. Afraid there's no alternative.
Yes, you're right, Professor. He has no alternative. I am sorry not to be here to welcome you personally, but I am sure you will not be offended. After all, the guest of honour is the Doctor - he, I am sure, will cooperate, as I advise you to do. Any attempt to interfere would be pointless. My Yeti can destroy you so easily.
It's all my fault! If I hadn't tampered with that sphere - people killed, London invaded, all because of my wretched curiosity!
Don't blame yourself, Professor.
Why not? I... I've sacrificed you all! And for what?
My, my, my, we are in a state, aren't we, sir?
Yes... alright... no, I'm fine. I've just been so scared, that's all!
'S alright, sir, nothing to be ashamed of.
Yes.
There's just one thing that puzzles me though, sir.
Oh, what's that?
How you managed to exist all this time - why didn't the Yetis get you?
I'm sorry, what are you suggesting? You're not suggesting that I...
Oh no, sir, I was just wondering, that's all. I think perhaps you'd better come along with me, don't you, sir? Come on, now.