A doctor! Well, if he was anywhere near those explosives when they went up...
Yes sir. Don't you think I should go and have a look, sir? The youngsters said he was following the cable.
Yes, you'd better.
Sir!
Oh, and Staff, take someone with you.
Father?
Hmm...?
The soldiers have found two youngsters in the tunnels. They seem to know a great deal about the Yeti.
Oh?
They know they're robots!
What!
And they know about the control spheres, too.
But they can't have - I mean, the public were never told!
I know.
Hello, hello, Holborn?... This is HQ to Holborn. Can you hear me?... Not a sausage.
There must be someone manning the phone.
OK, Lane, what gives?
Well, it's just firing at the other end, sir.
Firing?
Yes, sir. Listen.
Oh, good grief, no!
Hello, HQ to Holborn?
What happened, Lane?
Well, it was difficult to hear, sir. I think the truck was late getting there...
Then what?
Well they must have got the ammo unloaded, sir, 'cos he says they were jumped when they were moving.
Take O'Brien and a couple of the others.
Sir! Come on, mate.
Here, you're not going out there?
Yes, Mr Chorley. Want to come? Report some action first hand?
Well, I don't think I'd better get in the way. I... er... think I'd better stay here, don't you?
Yes. Yes, I think you better had.
Father?
But it... it can't be...
Why that's... that's over... forty years ago!
What's going on here?
Oh Jamie, don't you recognise him? It's Professor Travers.
So it is! Professor Travers! Here, hasn't he got old!
Huh?
Oh, but we're very pleased to see you, Professor, very pleased.
The time machine... it was all true then?
The TARDIS - I mean aye, of course it's true! Hey, do you know what's happened to the Doctor?
Oh, is he safe?
Isn't he with you?
No, he's in the tunnels. Arnold's gone to look for him. Father, what is going on?
Oh dear, I do hope he's alright. Come on, Jamie, let's go and find out if he's got back yet.
Father!
Eh? Oh, Victoria, try and explain to Anne, will you?
Oh dear!
There hasn't been an explosion, Staff!
Oh, no - well at least, we hope not.
I can see that, lad... Here!
No sign of that Doctor bloke.
No... here, give me a hand with this.
It's our detonator, alright. It's fired, too... 'ere, hang on a minute. All the ammo, Staff. If it's fired, then why didn't...
Yeah, why didn't this tunnel go up?... No damage at all...
Yet something blew up here!
It's obvious, ain't it? It's been got at.
Where's that Doctor? That's what I'd like to know.
Tibet? Tibet? You're joking.
That's where old Travers says they come from. He reckons they're Abominable Snowmen.
Well, he's off his chump, ain't he? How'd they get here in the first place?
Come through the post, don't they?
Nah, seriously. Outer space, that's where they come from. Well that's what I reckon, anyway.
Oh do leave off! You've been reading too many kids' comics, you have!
Alright then, Corp, where do they come from?
It's a foreign power, ain't it? Bacteriological warfare, that's what that stuff is in the tunnels.
What, that fungus stuff?
Yeah. And them Yeti are some sort of new weapon. Well, a sort of robot army.
What, you mean it ain't real then?
Father?
Hmm?
Have you ever seen this TARDIS?
No, no, I can't say I have.
It all sounds a bit far-fetched to me.
You know, I think the Doctor's at the back of all this.
What do you mean?
Doesn't it strike you as odd that on the two occasions you've encountered the Yeti, you've also come across the Doctor?
Well?
Well, it's obvious - he controls them!
Oh, but surely...
What? Oh, tea. Thank you, my dear.
Oh, aren't you having any?
No, I think I'll go and lie down for a bit.
Good idea.
Do you think she heard?
No... in any case, what you say is nonsense, Anne.
I saw the Doctor defeat those robots and save Detsen Monastery.
He wouldn't do that if he was in league with them, now would he?
No, no I suppose not.
Here, Corp, look at this!
What... oh crikey! That's what comes of talking about it!
It's that fungus stuff, it's moving again!
Don't worry!
Can't help it - I feel... responsible somehow.
If only the Doctor would turn up. I'm sure he could help us.
'Scuse me, sir...
Eh, what?
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again. Euston Square's gone.
Come on, let's have a look!
It's on the move again, Weams?
Yes, sir. Kings Cross has gone, and it's moving on to Farringdon.
It's never moved as fast as this before!
Hasn't moved at all the last three weeks, Miss.
What started it up again all of a sudden?
Can't say.
Strange, isn't it, that all this should happen on the very day that your mysterious Doctor friend turns up?
He hasn't turned up.
Precisely. He could have sent those kids in here as spies.
Rubbish! Would Jamie go away and leave Victoria, if he didn't intend coming back again?
Excuse me, sir, but where is the young lady?
Oh, in the Common Room, I suppose.
No she's not, 'cos I went in there when I was looking for you!
What? Well... where is she then?
Jamie? Doctor?... Jamie? Doctor?
Victoria!
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness I found you! Are you alright?
Look, sir, the fungus! It's moving again!
Hope the Captain and Staff Arnold ain't anywhere near that little lot.
Lane? Lane! Fall back, you'll never hold them!
Will nothing stop them?
Come on, back!
We couldn't hold 'em, sir. They're coming, two of 'em! They got O'Brien and Cocksey, nothing stops them!
It's Staff Arnold!
Yeah, come on.
Captain?
Yeti!
They got two of us!
And the ammo detail - they're all gone.
What's the plan then?
I brought a load of explosives down from Holborn. I'm going to blow it - and them with it.
Taking a bit of a risk, aren't you, sir?
Yeah, I know.
Hey, look what's happening!
What are they doing?
Looks like the cobwebs!
Cobwebs or not, I'm going to blow it sky high. Get back!
What's that noise?
The boxes are pulsating!
Get back!
This waiting's getting on my nerves. Why the heck don't they do something?
Steady, lad. We'll know soon enough.
We can't just stand here. Can't we make a run for it?
We wouldn't stand a chance, not with them switched on.
How do you know that?
It's alright, sir. The Professor's vouched for him. Understand he knows a great deal about these robots.
See, you have to find out...
What's that?
What made them do that, I wonder?
Couldn't say, sir. But I don't think we should stay to find out.
Yes, you're right, Staff. Come on, let's get back.
Wait - can we not just see what they're up to?
No! If there's one thing that I've learned, it's never push your luck. Now come on.
Soldier!
Well, there's a sight for sore eyes!
Are you stark raving mad?
Aye, well I always sing when I'm scared, see.
Stand to attention when you're talking to an officer!
Name and serial!
6-0...
Shush!
6-0-1 Evans, sir!
Evans? Anybody know him?
Oh, I'm not one of your lot, sir.
Then what are you doing down here?
Trying to get out, Sarge!
Don't try to be funny with me, lad! How did you get down here in the first place?
Driver on the ammo truck to Holborn. Got jumped, we did - quite a dust up, there was.
Couldn't get past them hairy creatures, see? Been wandering for hours. Lost, I was.
I tried one way, but there seemed to be some sort of cobweb muck moving down the tunnel.
Moving? Are you sure it was moving?
Well of course I'm sure!... sir. Sounds daft, I know,
but it seemed to be following a Yeti that had a kind of pointed glass thing in its hands.
Was it shaped like a pyramid?
Well, I suppose it was, really.
Well that's it! Smash the pyramid, and you put the Intelligence out of action!
What Intelligence?
Whereabouts did you say this happened?
Kings Cross, Staff.
What!
Headquarters, sir - HQ may be in danger!
Yes, we'd better get back as soon as we can. Come on.
No, look...
Now listen to what the officer said, young man. Come on!
Look, I came down here to find the Doctor. I'm not going back till I have!
Now look here...
No, I'm not going! And if I get a chance to smash that pyramid, I will!
That's quite a risk you're taking.
Aye, but it's me that's taking it.
Alright, it's your neck, chum.
Sir!
Yes?
I'd like to volunteer to go with the young gentleman, sir.
Well, you're not one of my lot... alright. Come on, the rest of you.
Monument! Then it's Tower Hill next.
Wait a minute! Did you hear something?
What?
Listen.
Look! The fungus, it's here!
We'd better get out, fast!
- Jamie!  - Doctor! Good to see you!