Mr Silverstein?
Yes. Who are you?
Anne Travers. Is my father here?
Yes, he's here.
Come and see him and take him away.
He's a fool. An old fool!
Father?
Father...
Anne...
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
You were supposed to be meeting me.
- Was I?
- At the airport.
What's wrong? You send me a cable
saying you're in grave trouble.
- I fly half the way round the world...
- Trouble? Yes.
A great deal of trouble. It's that thing.
The Yeti?
Mm.
You're a stupid old fool, Julius Silverstein!
ME the fool? You would like me to be the fool
and give you back my Yeti, huh?
You must, man. Don't you understand?
It's dangerous.
For 30 years this stands here in my museum,
and now he tells me it is dangerous!
- I wish I'd never brought it back from Tibet.
- Father, what has happened?
The silly old goat won't listen to me.
I've told him, warned him.
- Damn it, he knows it's a robot!
- But, Father, the Yeti isn't dangerous.
It can't work unless it has a control unit.
But I've done it, Anne!
I HAVE reactivated the control unit.
But, Father, this is wonderful news.
Is it? Yes, I suppose it would be,
except for one thing.
What?
The sphere - it's gone!
It's disappeared! You must let me
have the Yeti back, Julius.
Make him understand, Anne!
I understand.
I buy the Yeti off you 30 years ago.
Now, it is valuable.
You try to scare me, take your Yeti back.
Why? Money!
- You want to rob me!
- I'll buy the thing back if that's what you want!
No, no. It's priceless.
The only one in the world, and it is mine.
- You fool!
- Thief!
- I'm not a thief.
- Swindler!
Stubborn old goat!
- Father!
- Take him away - out of my house!
Perhaps you've made a mistake.
You've put the sphere away
somewhere in your laboratory and forgotten it.
- You've done it before.
- No. I've looked everywhere.
Let's go home and look again, shall we?
You know what you're like.
Yes, but suppose...
Let's go and have a quiet dinner,
and you can tell me all about it.
Then we'll go home and look for the sphere.
Well, all right...
But I warned you, Julius! I warned you!
Get out! Take him away!
Nobody destroys Julius Silverstein's collection!
Nobody!
- Come on, Father.
- The Yeti's mine!
You can't scare me with your mad stories.
Out! Out!
Travers...
It is you? I am not frightened
by your stupid tricks!
Travers! I know it's you.
I'm not a fool!
Agh!
(theme)
(the web of fear)
Some sort of grille.
Don't say you've landed us in a prison!
It could be the dungeons of a castle.
It's so dark.
Ah, steps.
Come along. Be careful.
Yes...
It seems to be a large room.
Tiled walls.
Curved ceiling.
Come on.
The floor seems to end here.
There's a sort of trench. Look.
- Hey, Doctor. Come and look at this.
- What have you found, Victoria?
See for yourself.
"Covent... Garden... "
Yes, of course! It's an underground station.
We're standing on the platform.
- Underground station?
- Underground trains.
- A little after your time, Victoria.
- Is it always as dark as this?
No, it's probably the middle of the night.
Come on. Let's go up top.
- Professor Travers is here, sir.
- Why have I been brought here? Who are you?
- Knight.
- Never heard of you.
Captain Knight. OK, Corporal.
It's no good shouting at me.
- I didn't ask for you.
- Who did, then?
- Your daughter.
- Anne? Just like her mother.
Always interfering in things!
I understood that you'd sent for her to help you.
What do you want me for?
- I don't. I think this is a military matter.
- Well, you haven't had much success so far!
Army What the devil do they know about it?
- The Doctor was wrong!
- It's not night-time. It's broad daylight.
- Just let me get my breath... Those stairs!
- It looks like we're locked in.
- That's strange.
- Doctor...
- Yes?
- Listen.
I can't hear anything.
Oh... It IS quiet. I see what you mean. The
middle of London. There should be some noise.
There's an old man over there. Let's ask him.
Yes, go on.
Excuse me...
Who are you?
- Harold Chorley. London Television.
- What? Television?
- Never watch it. Are you an actor?
- Journalist, actually.
The government decided to only allow one
correspondent down here. The press chose me.
Oh, yeah?
Will you be in charge of the scientific section,
or will your daughter?
Mind your own business!
How long do you think it will take you
to come up with the answer?
- One week? Three, perhaps?
- How the hell should I know?
- Is that working?
- Of course.
It's more than likely
we may not be able to defeat this menace.
The whole of England might be completely
wiped out. There - did you get that?
- What are you doing?
- Just confirming something.
Just as I thought.
There haven't been any trains here for some time.
What's that over there?
It's a power cable.
I wonder what it's doing down here.
In there quickly!
Soldiers? I wonder what they're doing down here.
- Let's go and ask them.
- No. I think we'd better tread carefully.
Let's go and find out what's going on first.
What do you want us to do, Doctor?
You follow the soldiers, but keep out of sight.
I'm going to see where this cable goes to.
Meet back here in a few minutes.
- What's the matter?
- I thought I heard something.
- Getting a bit jumpy, aren't you, Weams?
- It's no wonder, is it, Staff?
- Shall we connect the new drum now, Staff?
- All right, Corporal.
- Good thing we fixed these lights.
- Yeah.
- I can't hear anything.
- Are they still there?
I think they must be moving. Come on.
Agh!
- I told you I heard something, didn't I?
- Yeah.
Come on!
- I'm sorry!
- It was only a cobweb!
- Do you think they heard?
- Hope not. Come on.
Well, well, well, would you believe it?
The Babes in the Wood!
- You're quite sure there was nobody with you?
- How many more times?
That's all right, then.
- Clear to fire, Staff?
- Yes, they were on their own.
Right.
What was all that about?
I suppose there's no harm in telling you.
You two are very lucky.
- We're going to blow up the tunnel.
- What?!
- That's what the cable's for.
- The Doctor!
It's all right. They were on their own.
OK, let's not waste any more time. Off you go.
Agh!