- They can't just march in here, can they?
- Not now we know how they got in.
Yes. They tunnelled into the storeroom.
- Come quickly!
- What is it?
MoonbaseI MoonbaseI
- They've got our wavelength. We hear you.
- You are surrounded.
All resistance is useless.
You must open the entry port.
Let me. You're wasting your time. We've
discovered your passageway and blocked it.
- You cannot enter now.
- Resistance is useless.
- Can they get in?
- I'm not stopping to find out.
- Get me Earth as quick as you can.
- Right.
Weather Control Moon calling Earth.
Come in.
Switch it off. We'll never hear anything
through that. Are they jamming it?
- Perhaps.
- They're having a go at the aerial!
Where are you going?
They'll get you in a flash!
- Someone's got to go.
- It's too late. Come and see.
They get us every way, these creatures!
I refuse to believe that!
Everything's got a weak point.
It's just a question
of waiting till it shows up, that's all.
They'll send a relief rocket within 12 hours
if no signals are received from us.
A lot of good that is!
With all the trouble we've had, I'd say
a rocket is on its way - sent off hours ago.
- Rinberg's very quick off the trigger, right?
- I'm sure of it. With my replacement aboard.
- That's wonderful!
- Thanks
I mean we've no need to worry. The Cybermen
can't get in, and help is on its way.
It all sounds too easy.
Watch the flight path between Moon
and Earth. Tell me if you spot anything.
All we have to do is hold on here.
Yes, that's all.
It doesn't depend on us, though.
It depends on what the Cybermen
are hatching up.
If a rocket is on its way,
they're bound to be aware of that already.
EmergencyI
There is a spaceship
approaching from Earth.
It will arrive on the lunar surface
in 15 minutes.
Immediate offensive action must be taken.
They have blocked up our way into the base.
Other methods to gain entry will be tried.
The machine from Earth
must first be destroyed.
There are 14 minutes left.
Understood.
Transmit control signal.
You will listen to me
and follow my instructions.
- Switch on again.
- Without an aerial?
- We can pick up local signals.
- Local? Oh, I see... The Cybermen.
If they have any more words of cheer for us,
we might as well hear them.
Those are your orders.
That is correct, but watch the digital counter.
- How's he shaping?
- Not bad for a beginner...
.. but it will take a long time yet.
At least the Gravitron's stable. I don't know
how they can take it for long in that room.
How's Benson standing up to it?
He's been on for six hours on the trot.
- He says he'll be all right.
- Should he be on it alone?
You're the only other operator who
could replace him, and you're needed here.
- It's tough on him.
- It's tough on all of us...
.. but millions of lives
depend on this weather control unit.
I've brought some coffee to keep us awake.
- Without sugar this time, I hope?
- Of course.
Take some to the Doctor. He's in the Dome.
You will now change
field co-ordinates as instructed.
They've spotted it
on the scanner - the relief ship.
- Where?
- Over here.
- Well?
- I told you they'd be on their way!
- That's a spaceship?
- No, that's the scanner!
It's not far off.
It will be off parking orbit
in six minutes.
- You ought to warn them.
- The Cybermen will be there.
They've got their own warning system
and weapons.
They'll blast the Cybermen and their spaceship
to kingdom come four minutes from now.
Come on!
It seems to move so slowly.
- What are they doing?
- Looks like they've changed direction.
They've changed into an escape orbit.
Follow it.
- It's too fast. I can't keep up with it.
- Keep trying.
- I can't hold it. It's accelerating too fast.
- Look out. You're on the sun.
- That's where it's going.
- The acceleration's gigantic!
- Get R/T contact with the ship.
- It's no good, sir. It's going too fast.
They've had it, I'm afraid.
- The sun...
- Yes.
Will somebody please tell us
what it all means?
The rocket has been deflected
towards the sun. Nothing can save them now.
- Save them? What do you mean?
- From plunging into the sun.
But the sun's millions of miles away.
Once they get into the sun's gravity belt,
they can't change course.
It may take a week but they'll end up there.
What on earth could have caused it?
The rocket was deflected off course,
but why, and how?
Deflected?
- Yes, of course. The Gravitron!
- Have the Cybermen got a gravity weapon?
- No, but we have.
- You don't mean...?
That rocket was deflected into the sun
was from this very room.
I see what you mean.
Of course - the Gravitron.
- Benson must have...
- I said he'd been on duty too long.
If it IS Benson...
It's Evans!
- He was in the medical room.
- The Cybermen have control of them.
- And the other men in there?
- They may not be affected yet.
Barricade the medical room door.
Keep them in there at all costs!
- We haven't passed any of them.
- Maybe only Evans was reactivated.
Well, we'd better keep watch just here.
Let's stick that against the door.
- It won't hold them for long.
- They're not Cybermen. Come on.
Get hold of the other end.
- Hey!
- Behind you!
Quick! Ram him!
Press the locking button.
It won't hold for long.
No.
Get those chairs and we'll block 'em in.
Evans, can you hear me?
Listen, Evans, this is Hobson talking.
Evans, you've got to concentrate.
Your brain has been altered by the Cybermen.
You're being controlled by them.
We've got one or two of those things
as well, you know.
You can't shoot all of us,
so why not come out of there?
What is he doing in there?
Look at the field reactors. We must get
control. He could flood half of Europe
if he keeps the Gravitron
aligned with spring tides.
We'll have to rush him.
Get those weapons out.
Resistance is useless.
All further ships from Earth will be deflected.
Open the air lock to us.
If you do not, we shall destroy the base,
and you will be eliminated.
Can you hear me?
Everything you have said
in the past half-hour has been overheard.
You can hear this, too, then. We're not done
yet, and we'll fight you to the last man.
- You'll never get inside this base!
- We are in it already.
They've punctured the dome!
The oxygen masks.
Everyone take a mask over there!
I hope that we don't lose too much oxygen.
- Can we patch it, do you think?
- We can try.
Give me a hand off with this.
Doctor, I can't breathe.
Thank heavens! I can breathe again.
Oh, no!
- What can we patch it with?
- Nothing.
Wait...
Over there.
Slide it to me but don't let go of it.
We have to do it in one action.
OK. Ready? Now!
Stopped them for the moment.
- I wonder for how long.
- Let's have a look.
Polly! Are you all right?
Yes.
- Where's that air coming from?
- Reserve tanks of oxygen.
- Why couldn't we have had those before?
- And lose all our oxygen?
I see.
- It's so quiet!
- Yes, it is, isn't it?
The Gravitron's stopped!
Quick. Before he comes to. Ben! Jamie!
Joe!
We've barricaded the sick bay,
but it won't hold for ever.
Well done.
Here's another one for you.
- What do we do with him?
- That's your problem.
Just don't let him back here.
I'll become a copper
when I get back to 1966!
Mr Hobson, I've got an idea.
- What do you make of this?
- Made by a laser beam, I think.
- Is there anything the Cybermen haven't got?
- A Gravitron. That's why they want yours.
We'll have to stand guard
with their cyberguns.
Not much use. They're getting
reinforcements. Looks like another spaceship.
Just there.
Another one!
We have brought
reinforcements with other weapons.
You have one chance.
You must open the entry port.
You cannot stop us now.
You will all be completely destroyed.
- What does he mean, other weapons?
- We'll soon find out. I must report this.
I shall count to ten.
If you still stupidly remain silent,
we shall fire.
One...
- They've got another weapon.
- I know. There it is.
Everybody take cover.
Get down, all of you! Doctor!
- Is the Gravitron still switched on?
- Yes.
Then I shall stay here.
.. nine, ten... FireI
Again. Fire.
- What happened?
- It just deflected over the dome.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- The Gravitron deflected it. The force field.
- Yes. And that gives me an idea.
What are they doing now?
They're packing it away.
What will they cook up next?
How far down can this be aimed? Can it be
brought to bear on the surface of the moon?
- I see!
- Well...
- Has it ever been tried?
- No, but we shall try.
- With Evans gone, the Gravitron is all yours.
- Je m'en occupe!
Any further down,
and the field may affect the base.
- What does that matter now?
- You're right.
Get someone to stand by that window
and relay instructions to Benoit.
- He's ready.
- Start moving the probe down.
- That's as far as it will go.
- What?
But it's way over their heads.
There's one chance.
We'll try bringing it down by hand.
- Is this still switched off?
- Yes.
- It won't go.
- All your weight. Once more.
- It's no use. It won't shift.
- Stupid of me. Of course it won't!
The angular cut-out. It's obvious!
There's got to be a safety cut-out
on the angle of the probe.
Otherwise, it might affect the whole base.
That's done it. Stand back. Benoit can do it now.
Switch on!
Well, that's taken care of the Cybermen!
We've got to get this Gravitron
in operation as fast as we can!
- I'm so sorry we damaged it.
- What? Oh, yes...
Nils, rig up a temporary aerial.
Call up Space Control.
Tell Rinberg we'll be operational
in about two hours. It's the best we can do.
We've only two hours to get
the world's weather under control again.
Benoit, take charge of your side.
And, Doctor... What the...
It's just as well.
We've enough madmen here already!
I want to see
your first weather plot in two minutes!
Come on, boys.
Doctor, look.
Could that be them?
Possibly.
And I hope it's the last we see of them.
There we are. In perfect flight.
- Yes, and look what happened last time!
- Just a bumpy landing. It won't happen again.
I know.
- Let's have a look at the Time Scanner.
- The what?
The Time Scanner. Instead of showing where
we are, it gives you a glimpse of the future.
The second sight? Very dangerous.
Nonsense! I haven't used it very much.
It's not very reliable, as you can see.
Doctor...
Look!