Sincro: wyxchari
Stand back, stand back from that door.
You're right! It is them!
Quick! Get out of it!
No!
Remain still.
You devils! You killed him! An unarmed man!
Get up.
See that they remain there.
Yes.
Operational System Two now complete. Operational System Two now complete.
Ready to start Operational System Three
Understood. Operational System Three will now begin.
You are known to us.
And you to me.
Silence.
Who is in command?
I am.
You will be needed.
What have you done with my men?
They will return.
They're not dead?!
No. They are not dead. They are altered.
Altered? What have you done to them?
They are now controlled.
If you do anything to my...
You will do nothing.
This one has not received Neurotrope. Stand back!
Please leave him alone. He's head is hurt. He had an accident.
His head? Then he would be of no value.
The others are ready for conversion.
You will now take us to the control centre.
I'll be damned...
Through here.
You will remain here. If you leave you will be converted like the others.
I don't like that word - "converted. "
Raise your left arm.
Raise your right arm.
Control is excellent.
Transfer that one to the capsule.
It's about time that we heard from those two outside. Let's have a word with them.
All yours, Roger.
Survey party, come in please.
Survey party, come in, we are not receiving you, over.
Can we see the control antenna from here?
No, Roger. It's just around that first block just outside the main port.
So, we have to send somebody outside so get ready...
We have to...
Get back! Get back! These things are lethal!
None will move.
You will remain still. If you move you will be killed.
What are they?! How did they get in!?
Silence! We are Cybermen! You will listen.
But you were all killed!
We are going to take over the Gravitron and use it to destroy the surface of the Earth by changing the weather.
But that will kill everybody on the Earth.
Yes.
You're supposed to be so advanced. Here you are, taking your revenge like children.
Revenge? What is that?
A feeling people have...
Feelings? Yes, we know of this weakness of yours. We are fortunate. We do not posses feelings.
Then why are you here?
To eliminate all dangers.
But you kill every single thing on the Earth!
Yes. All dangers will be eliminated.
Have you no mercy?
It is unnecessary.
Keep watch on them.
Don't rush them!
Operational System Four. Operation System Four. Operational System Four complete. Entry to base now completed.
Entry? How did you get in?
It was very simple. Only stupid Earth brains like yours would have been fooled.
Go on.
Since we couldn't approach direct, we came up under the surface and cut our way in through your store room, contaminating your food supply on the way. A simple hole that's all.
A hole! That explains those sudden air pressure drops we been having.
Clever! Clever! Clever!
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
You seem to be better.
Aye, I feel myself again.
Lie back there!
But I'm better!
Oh, my head.
Well, take it easy, mate.
At least, you know it is not your McCrimmon piper.
It had me worried though, I admit that.
Yeah, those Cybermen have got us all worried mate. We see them in action before.
They must have some weakness.
They have, don't you remember. They can't stand radiation.
But where do we find that here?
There's the Gravitron power pack but that's thermonuclear. None can get near it once its going.
Why not?
Because Duchess, the temperature inside is about four million degrees, that's all.
Well, in my day, they used to sprinkle witches with holy water.
Fat lot of use that would be on them.
Sprinkle... Holy Water... Ben!
Yeah?
What are the Cybermen covered in?
As far as I know, their suit is a metal of some sort.
What about that thing on their chests? You know the part that replaced their heart and lungs.
Some kind of plastic I think.
I thought so. You see, it's simple. Nail vanish remover dissolves nail vanish. Nail vanish is a plastic so we do what Jamie says, we sprinkle them, see?!
No, clear as mud if you ask me.
Anyway, I am going to try an experiment.
Yes, Professor.
Dr. Evans! I thought that they were all dead!
Better if they were by the look of it.
You will leave your places. Go over there.
You will move. Tell the operators in the power unit to come out.
Now.
All right, you can all see what is happening. Come on out, leave the machine and don't try anything.
They will now take over the Gravitron power unit.
Yes.
But you can't send them in their without protected helmets.
Why?
The machine produces very intense sonic fields. Without the helmets, those men will be insane in a few hours!
How many hours?
Twelve possibly.
Then there is no problem.
Why?
Our purpose will be achieved before that.
But what about the men?
They will be disposed of.
Ben?
Yep?
What is nail vanish remover?
Sort of finish, sort of acetone isn't it?
Acetone, of course!
Great, we have some of that.
Now, keep your fingers crossed.
It's works!
But I still don't know what you are on about.
If we can sprinkle some of that on their chest units, it might help to soften them.
I get it! It will clobber their controls or something.
Yes, that's it.
Yeah, but how do we know that acetone will dissolve their sort of plastic?
Hmmm, haven't thought of that.
Just a moment though, if we make up a mixture.
Of all the solvents.
What have we got?!
Belezine, Ether, Alcohol.
We brew up a right little cocktail.
Yes.
Wait a minute, how are we going to throw it at them?
Well, in bottles I suppose. Just a tick though, I got a better idea.
Prepare to align the field rectors.
Main power into projected radius now.
Service pumps to full pressure.
Why have they gone to so such trouble?
What do you mean?
Why didn't they operate the control themselves?
What is happening?
There is loss of control.
Thought so, sonic control. That should be easy.
Funny. Funny. To go to all that trouble to make the men do the work. Why? Do it themselves, easy. They're using the men as tools. Why? Don't know. Yes, I do though. There must be something in here they don't like. Pressure? No, no. Electricity? No. Radiation? Maybe. Grav... Gravity! Now there's a thought. Gravity. Oh yes, Gravity.
Start probe generators. Realign the probe.
Probe field to full power. Now.
They devastate the whole Earth when that field takes hold.
We got to do something.
Earth Control calling Moonbase. Come in please.
Remain still.
Hello Moonbase, come in please.
You will all be silent.
Moonbase, come in please. Hello? Hello? Reading on five centimetre band. Come in. Your last routine signal was not received, over.
We are not receiving you, over. If you hear us and cannot transmit, fire sodium rocket. We will see the flare.
What does that mean?
It is a distress rocket. It injects sodium into space and the sunlight turns the sodium into a solar flare.
What will your Earth do if they do not see the flare?
Well, they'll think...
...we're all dead, they'll do nothing.
Standing by to observe flare. Standing by...
If they don't get our next transmission, they'll send up a relief rocket.
So, get it. This bottle holds the stuff that puts the fire out and this cylinder pushes gas into the bottle so that the stuff comes out here. Now, all we got to do is to undo it...
Poar! Empty it and fill it with Polly cocktail.
I got it all ready here.
Good. What did you put in it?
Let's think... Belezine, Ether, Alcohol, Acetone and Profane.
Blimey, one of them should do it.
Now, we need another one of these.
Right I'll get it.
No, you stay where you are Jamie.
Jamie, youre not well enough.
It's take more than a wee crack on the head to keep a McCrimmon down.
Look mate, we don't want you cracking up on us. I'm sure Polly's very impressed...
Look I said, I'm feeling better. Now, would you like me to prove it to you?
Any time, mate.
Now, come on. Haven't we got enough trouble without you two fighting.
I go.
Come on then.
Not you, Polly. This is men's work.
You'll kill them!
If you will not remain silent you will be put under brain control.
Polly! I thought that I told you to stay behind.
I'm coming with you.
Maybe not, now go back.
I'm coming with you and that's that! You still need someone...
I don't want...
Look! There's no time for that now. If you're coming, come on.
Now look, we only have one chance at this. When I open the door, drop down as low as you can, aim this things... at their chests and squirt like mad. Right?
Right.
Get ready.
Someone is there.
The beam is jammed!
Quick, get their chest things!
Quick, get these things off their heads!
Come on! Quick, there isn't a moment to lose. We got to get the Gravitron down to base level.
What about those poor men?
Shift them off to the medical unit, as quick as you can.
We are not receiving you. We are not receiving you.
They must have failed.
Yes. We must invade now. Prepare the weapons.
Yes.
Before all this, we lost contact with those two men outside.
Well, send somebody else out.
Can't spare anyone. I'll go myself.
Field strength is stable, isn't it?
Yes. Yes, it's all right.
Keep in RT contract and be quick.
Nils?
Yep?
Hook your controls into Joe's channel and keep an eye on Roger when he's outside.
Right.
Hello Base, Hello Base. I've found them. Hmm, At least, I found their suits. They got them, I'm afraid.
Well, there's nothing we can do about that now. You better come inside as quick as you can.
I will.
Sir, sir! There's one of those things outside. He's after Roger Benoit.
You hear that, Roger?
Yes, I did but he must be mistaken. There's none to be seen around here.
No! No!
Did you see that? Those things don't work in the vacuum!
Why can't you squirt it at them, like you did just now?
Because duchess, it would evaporate in the vacuum before it hits them. There, now come on.
Come on, quick.
They're in! That fellow Ben got one of them.
That was Ben?
Now listen everybody. I don't know how many more of these Cybermen there are, but our point of view we are under siege. I'll reckon they will be back in a bit...
Now communications. Charlie, keep trying to get through to Earth. Right?
Right, will do.
The rest of you, lower the armoured doors at all exits. Make up as much of that gubbins that you got, we may need it.
Well done, Ben!
Ground radar?
Ground radar speaking.
Have you got a fix on their ship yet?
Yes, Mr Hobson, we are getting a strong pulse from five four degrees North about three kilometres.
That makes it over the rim.
Mr Hobson, how far can the probe be lowered down?
About thirty degrees.
That's no good.
What do you mean?
Can any other part be lowered?
Well, the main coil lenses can be shifted about without too much trouble but too much trouble...
There's something outside there!
What is it?
It's a long way off.
I'll come.
Oh, it's freezing. Do you think we should have our suits on?
Oh no, it's all right love. Get a gorgeous suntan.
Can't see anything.
Just to the left of the launching area. Around a bit to your left.
Still can't see anything.
No, it's there, look! Reflections from the sun!
You're right. There is something.
It's them! Everybody back inside! Quick!