It's you.
The phantom piper!
No!
No! I'll not go with you!
Do you hear me, piper? No! Leave me!
Leave me. I'll not go with you, do you hear me?
Leave me! No, I'll not go with you!
I'll fight you every inch of the way.
I'll not go with you.
Leave me, piper.
No. Leave me. I'll not go.
Agh!
- What's happened?
- It was horrible!
- A giant creature like a Cyberman!
- It's all right. Don't be frightened.
- It's gone now.
- The Cyberman was carrying a patient.
- Cyberman? What are you talking about?
- I'm sure it was.
It's OK. Take it easy.
She's right.
There's another one gone.
Sam, Jules, you've got to find these men.
They can't just disappear.
Search every square inch
till you find them. Now move.
Now, supposing you tell me your story?
What did you see?
I went out to get Jamie some water,
and when I came back,
I saw this giant man or creature or something,
just going out of the door,
carrying a patient... like a doll.
- I think it was a Cyberman.
- Forget that part. Then what?
Then nothing.
The door shut, and then you came in.
- What do you know about all this?
- Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
We'll see about that in a minute.
- This thing you saw. What was it like?
- It was enormous, and silver.
- It had holes in its head for eyes, like a robot.
- A robot?
But the Cybermen were all killed
when Mondas blew up.
Stop this Cyberman nonsense! There were
Cybermen, but they were destroyed ages ago!
- So we all thought.
- That's enough.
Let's have a little calm thinking.
For the past two weeks,
an unknown disease has appeared in the base.
People drop in their tracks
and develop a black pattern on their skin.
Then patients disappear.
They can't leave the base without spacesuits,
and there are no spacesuits missing.
- It does sound a little odd.
- More than a little.
I do know one thing - a new disease starts,
people disappear, then you turn up.
You think we did it!
We haven't done a thing!
I don't know who you are,
what you are, or where you came from,
but you can get off the moon now!
That suits me fine!
We can't go yet.
- Why not? They don't want us here.
- There is something evil here. We must stay.
- Evil? Don't be daft!
- Evil is what I meant.
There are some corners of the universe
which have bred the most terrible things.
Things which act against everything
that we believe in. They must be fought.
This disease, for instance. It isn't really
a disease at all, but I can help you with it.
You'll see. I'll find the cause for you.
- Will you, indeed?
- Yes. I just need to examine a few things.
- It should be simple.
- Well, I'm not sure.
I'll give you just one Earth-day cycle
to find the cause.
- Earth what?
- 24 hours.
- But that's no time at all.
- It's all you're going to get.
Then you get off the moon,
with this bloke here.
- You can't move him! He's very ill.
- We accept.
Now tell me, you have pathological
equipment here, yes?
Yes. Evans was working on
an extensive research project. It's all in here.
It's quite a small unit. We're not equipped
to deal with a full-scale epidemic.
- Do you think you can manage?
- Yes.
Right. I'll leave you to it.
Don't forget - 24 hours.
- What are you going to do, Doctor?
- We'll start with this one.
- Are you really a medical doctor?
- Yes, I think I was once, Polly.
I think I took a degree once, in Glasgow.
1888, I think. Lister. Hold that for me, will you?
- Oh!
- All right. He's quite unconscious.
- What can we do to help?
- I shall need to examine everything.
Clothes, boots, food, towels, soap -
everything. Will you get them for me, please?
- Have you any idea what it might be?
- No. Not an idea.
But we'll find it out.
I don't understand it. I'm sure
there's a lack of co-ordination somewhere.
- Yes, but where?
- On the indicators. Look!
- It should be steady as a rock.
- The fault must be in the Gravitron.
- Nils, here.
- Yes.
Move the probe. We'll see if the indicators
move the right distance on the map.
- Keep an eye on the probe itself, will you?
- OK.
- All yours.
- Right.
Deflect probe five degrees... now.
Way off. Five degrees should put them
over Iceland. Move the probe back again.
The probe deflects all right.
The fault's here. This could be a disaster
if we can't stabilise the Earth's field.
If we lose that hurricane,
all hell will break loose on Earth.
- I have a wife and family.
- You're not the only one.
Roget, check the potentiometers.
Nils, check the gravitation units.
Shake it up.
We haven't got much time.
- The field is stabilising at 48, Mr Hobson.
- Prepare to move probe.
Check co-ordinates.
We've got to hold that hurricane in the Pacific.
Stand by... Now!
20-degree tilt complete.
The field's not correcting.
- We'll have to increase the reactor power.
- You can't do that. The torus will burn out.
It's all we can do.
International Space Control.
Earth calling Moon Weather Control. Stand by.
This is Moonbase. Come in, please.
- We wish to speak to Mr Hobson.
- Hobson speaking.
- Stand by for the Controller.
- He's actually going to speak to us this time!
Controller Rinberg speaking.
- Is that you, Hobson?
- Yes, Rinberg.
The directional fields are showing
a progressive error.
There are widespread pressure fluctuations
in Atlantic Zone 6.
You must get the Gravitron back into balance.
We're trying to compensate
by realigning the probe.
We have an error in the servos.
Well, there's no sign
of any improvement here.
We've just had a report from Miami, Florida.
30 minutes ago, they were enjoying
clear skies and a heatwave.
Now Hurricane Lucy is right overhead.
- The only thing we can do is shut it down.
- Switch the Gravitron off?
- It's the only chance.
- The collapse of the gravity
would devastate half the globe.
- There'd be storms, hurricanes...
- I overheard your conversation.
It's out of the question.
You're not to shut down the Gravitron
under any circumstances. That's an order.
Perhaps you don't appreciate
how serious the situation already is.
I bet he gets a knighthood
We spent years negotiating methods
of agreement between farmers and landowners.
Now the weather's out of control,
they're after our blood.
I must say, I can't blame them. You've
got to get that thing under control - quickly.
Now please get on with it.
Earth Control over and out.
Well, we've got trouble. Bad trouble.
We haven't got much time.
We're going to run through every circuit,
every field pattern, every nut and bolt
until Charlie boy's running sweet and smooth.
You all know what to do. Let's get on with it.
We'll start on the main tape programme.
It's running now.
Give me the analogue value
on module six, will you?
They look all right.
A at ten millivolts.
B at 15 millivolts.
- C at 26. That fits, doesn't it?
- Yes, they're at normal levels.
Finish checking here, will you?
The answer may be in the control panel.
I'll sing out the binary conversion values.
You check them on readout.
Channel one.
- Eight...
- Right.
- One.
- Mm.
- Three. Four.
- Yeah.
- Six. Eight. Twelve.
All spot-on.
Qu'est-ce que vous fabriquez ici? Vous croyez
que nous sommes en train de nous amuser?
- Come on. Get out of the way!
- Enchanté, monsieur
Now, where were we?
Ah, yes, the fluid servo primers.
I reckon this is probably where the fault is.
- Do you want them all?
- The main tank will do.
- Header one. 45 pounds.
- Yes.
- Header two. 47.
- Three. 42.
- Yes.
Sine values equivalent.
They all fit. Nothing there.
It must be the potentiometer net, then.
It'll take us some time to do that.
We'll need the digital voltmeter.
What the blazes are you doing?
- I'm collecting specimens.
- Specimens?
Oh, yes... Well, get on with it.
We're nearly out of this interferon stuff.
- You'd better ask Mr Hobson where the rest is.
- Right.
It's all right, Jamie. It's all right.
You're going to get better but you must lie still.
What is this place?
Is it the home of the piper?
No, we're on the moon.
You know, the moon up in the sky.
No, I can't be alive.
I've just seen the piper.
The piper! I knew!
Polly! What's happened?
Polly.
Are you all right?
Anything out on the probe servers?
There's a slight discrepancy... in normal limits.
- Check the overall feedback valve.
- That's an idea.
I don't think it's likely to be a mechanical fault.
An air pressure drop again.
Lasts about five seconds.
Something's odd. It's not the pumps.
Has anyone asked permission to leave the base?
No. The compression chamber's empty.
If anybody's been fooling about in there,
I'll tear the hides off them!
- The pressure's up again now, sir.
- Thank heaven.
- I'll check over the control loop monitor.
- You're wasting your time.
Nothing's a waste of time till we trace this fault!
You saw what's happening on Earth.
We can't afford to miss anything. Get on with it!
I've found something.
It's one of the probe control antennae.
- What's wrong with it?
- Two pieces are missing. It's not co-ordinating.
- Missing?
- Meteorites?
Could be. There could be a simpler explanation.
When did these people arrive here?
The end of period 11 in this present lunar day.
- When did the Gravitron start playing up?
- The beginning of period 12.
- When was the last time anyone was outside?
- During period 13.
- Two men realigned a solar mirror.
- That's it!
- I'm not with you.
- It's simple.
Strangers arrive period 11.
- The Gravitron fails period 12.
- I understand, but...
It's time we put that Doctor and his friend
in cold storage.
Just a second. Get two men outside
to look at the antennae, will you?
Joe, tell Jules and Franz
I want them here pretty sharpish.
- What is it?
- Another patient's gone, sir.
What?! Come on!
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
- Isn't there any clue at all?
- No. It's a complete blank.
All the tests are negative. As far as I can see,
this whole ridiculous place is sterile.
- We'll have to tell Mr Hobson, I suppose.
- I simply don't understand it.
Doctor, it couldn't have
anything to do with Lister, could it?
- Lister?
- Well, I mean, you did say
that you took your degree in Glasgow in 1888.
That's an awfully long time from now, 2070.
Are you saying that I'm not confident
to carry out these tests?
No, I just wondered if there was anything
that Joseph Lister didn't know in 1888
- that might help you now.
- Ssh! Somebody's coming!
It's Mr Hobson. Out for blood - ours. Look busy!
That's the third person
to disappear in the past few hours.
- It's completely illogical.
- Do you mind?
Would you mind standing away from the door
and allowing it to close? The slides. The dust!
It must be you people.
We've got some straight talking to do, you and I.
- Polly. Another boot.
- Do you hear me?
- This is extraordinary.
- Excuse me, please.
- Look here...
- Excuse me. We ARE trying to help you.
- Help? You can all get off the moon now.
- You said...
- I don't care what I said!
- Ah!
- Have you found something?
- I think perhaps I have.
Yes, I may be onto something,
but I must have some room.
How can I work under these conditions?
Outside. I'm trying to work in here!
- Ben, see that they stay outside.
- Did you mean that?
- What?
- You've found something?
Oh, Polly, I only wish I had.
Keep them happy with coffee
while I think of something.
All right.
Here, Doctor.
- Completed your examination?
- Yes.
- Have you poked into everything?
- Yes, clothes, boots, food.
- And you've found...
- Absolutely nothing.
Just as I thought, so what I told you still stands.
Ah, coffee. Splendid.
Thank you, Polly.
I think we could all do with a cup!
See how Jules and Franz are getting on.
Right.
Coffee? Sugar?
Thank you.
- It's very hot. Doctor, what about you?
- Thank you, Polly.
Doctor, as I was saying, you've had
your chance and come up with nothing.
Don't touch him!
Let me look.
Charlie and you, Ben,
give us a hand to get him into the medical unit.
Try not to touch his skin.
Don't drink that! It's the sugar!
That's why the disease doesn't affect everyone.
It's the sugar. Not everyone takes it.
Don't touch it.
- What are you doing?
- Just be patient.
Just as I thought.
A large neurotropic virus.
- Like the space plague?
- No.
It's a large infective agent
that only attacks the nerves.
Lines appear on faces and hands where it
follows the course of the nerves under the skin.
How did it get in here?
It is the Cybermen. I believe
they have deliberately infected the base.
We've searched the base. There's no space
to hide a cat, let alone a Cyberman.
Anyhow, how did they get in?
- One moment.
- What is it?
- You say you searched all the base?
- Yes. What of it?
- No chance of anyone hiding anywhere?
- None whatever.
Did your men search in here? Did they?
- People were in here, so...
- Did they search in here?
- No.
- There's nowhere in here they could hide.
Oh, no!
Back!
Back.