Sincro: wyxchari
Oh, splendid! Splendid! You've got a very good band there, Barney.
Thank you, Pilot
Mind you, I don't say you'll come first at the festival, but never say die, hmm, what? Nothing succeeds like success, ha!
"If at first you don't succeed...?"
"... Try, try, try again!"
That's right.
Stop him! Don't let him get out!
What's the matter?
Medok!
Let me go!
Medok! This is very foolish of you Medok. It's for your own good.
Out of my way!
He's far too dangerous to be allowed to escape.
Get after him! You should have stopped him!
What happened, Ola?
He refused treatment in front of my guards, so I dismissed them and he made a dash for it.
Well get after him.
He must not get away!
Hey!
Oh! Oh, Ben! For goodness sake!
Well, what's the big stick for Jamie? Nothing's happened yet.
Have you no sense? Have you forgot what we saw on that time scanner?
Don't, it was horrible.
Aye, well, I'll not being left without nothing to defend ourselves with.
I'm afraid you're wasting your time, Jamie.
Why?
Unless I'm very much mistaken, these creatures are so big they're going to see us long before we see them.
Look out Jamie!
Hang on, mate, I'll get him!
Ben!
Sit on top of him!
What are you doing?_!
Ben, are you all right?
We don't know who you are, strangers, but we are grateful. Medok is one of our last patients in the Colony.
We've done our best for him but he gets worse day by day...
I wasn't informed you were travelling across our territory.
Hurry back to the Colony and tell the Pilot what's happened.
Pilot?
Yes, the Pilot of our colony. No doubt he will want to thank you in person.
Tie him up tighter. Come on, tighter! I don't want any more trouble with him. Come on, I'll show you myself. Get out of...
Er, uh, any good asking where we are?
Well, according to my calculations we're, er, certainly in the future and, er, on a planet very like the Earth.
How do you know?
I don't know. I'm guessing.
My name is Ola. I am the Chief of Police.
That sounds very important.
Oh, it's a very responsible job. I take my instructions from our Control centre. Oh, it all works very well, as you will see. Please follow me.
Oh, thank you.
Ah, not too tight ?it's bad for the blood pressure.
"Run, run, run, run...
Run, run, run, run!
Thank you shift...
Number one!
Pilot, these are the strangers that have helped us.
Very well, Ola. I will look after our guests. You will no doubt wish to take care of poor Medok. You may leave.
Well, our thanks to you and welcome! You are indeed a brave man to tackle someone as disturbed as Medok.
Well, it was nothing. Anyone would have done the same. Well this is gay! Why all the music?
Oh, we regulate our day by music.
Oh.
Yes...
...and now my friends, I suggest you take advantage of our refreshing department.
Oh, lead me to it mate. I'm starving.
Oh, you will eat later. Here we revive the weary body.
Oh.
Keep your eyes skinned.
Why? What's the matter?
Well, they're a weird sort of folk. I don't know that I understand them.
Come along in, my friends, It's just through _ there.
Pilot! Pilot! Control wish you to call them immediately. They wish to welcome our guests.
Oh, but of course.
Switch on please, my dear.
Hey, who's that? He looks smashing.
That's our Controller.
We wish to welcome joyfully the visitors to our colony. We are very grateful to them. They have performed a valuable service. The Colony is to make our guests happy and contented during their stay. Welcome again, friends. Now, back to work, everyone!
Well that's great! I'm really going to enjoy myself.
Splendid! And now my good friends, let me put you into the hands of our supervisor, Barney.
Dear old Barney, everybody calls him.
Well, thank you Pilot.
And I must leave you for... work calls you know, and hard work never hurt anybody.
Till later!
Delighted to see you. Delighted to have you with us. Now you have a complete choice of all our treatments. We have steam baths, beauty treatments, perhaps a massage. You sir, of course, would like your clothes cleaned.
And there's sunlight treatment, moonlight treatment, sparkling and effervescent sprays...
I feel perfectly all right as I am, thank you.
Ah, go on Doctor. Don't be such a drag. It all looks super. Please, may I have a shampoo?
Shampoo, of course, for the young lady.
Thanks very much.
And for the young gentlemen, our very latest treatment in our cubicles over there.
Me? Oh, hey, you're not going to do that to me. I'm no lassie.
It's no good, Jamie, the lassies have got you! And believe me mate, I'm not going to struggle.
And now sir, for you...
Oh, very nice. Very nice indeed. You must certainly be the most beautiful young lady in our Colony and are quite sure to be elected our next beauty president.
Thank you very much.
Oh, not at all. It's all part of our service.
To your liking sir?
Ah, marvellous. Like being at anchor in the Med.
Some protective oils for our guests and a little suntan.
Ha ha! This is the life.
Hey mister, would you call the ladies off? I'm frightened what they might do to me.
But you look charming, sir. Charming.
That's what I'm frightened of.
Please get me out of here! I'm done to a turn!
Clothes reviver.
My clothes don't need reviving!
Oh, while we're about it, sir... and off.
Oh, Doctor. You look gorgeous!
Oh, my shoes!
Oh, they're fantastic. You can see your face in them.
Precisely. Who wants to see their face in a pair of suede shoes?
What's this one?
Oh, that, sir, is our rough and tumble machine, for toning up the muscles.
Exactly what I need!
Full on!
Oh, but no, sir! No!
Turn it off.
Come out of it!
Come out of it, Doctor.
Oh, oh, I feel better. Oh, that's what I need.
Oh, you look smashing. You really do. You look like a prince. Jamie that's super. It really is.
Come on, move back! This prisoner's not to be trusted. He's violent and suffering from delusions.
I'm not the one suffering from delusions, it's you! All of you! You don't know what's happening in this Colony!
Be quiet Medok!
There's only one way to silence me, Ola.
Medok, old fellow, it's Questa. Remember me? What's happened to you?
It's no good. You can't reason with him.
Just a minute. He's an old friend. One of the best.
Ha!
He's as cheerful as any of us. Medok, what's happened to you? What's all this about you seeing things?
I don't see things Questa, you fool! There are things... horrible things... creatures, infesting this camp at night.
That's enough! Have you seen the Pilot?
He's with the strangers. I've no idea where they are.
Back to work! Shift rest is over! No time to be lost! The Colony needs you! Preparation to be made for tonight's reception - a welcome for the strangers!
A reception tonight! A Colony party! Medok, join in with the rest of us, like you used to.
It will be fun for all!
You hear that Medok, fun for all.
All right! Have fun while you can, before they crawl all over you!
That's enough! Right, get back all of you.
There you are. I wondered what had happened to you.
I don't know you. You don't belong here.
Do you belong here?
No, not any more.
We don't talk to him. He sees things. Come on Medok.
Can I help you?
What? Oh, no. No, it's all right, thank you. I... I just thought I'd dropped something, that's all.
Ha! What's _?
Shh, I'm going to set you free.
Just hold still a minute. There we are. One more.
Don't bother to say thank you. Now, tell me something about these things that you see, hmm? Do they, for instance, appear to crawl slowly over the ground?
How do you know?
Oh, just wondered that's all.
Listen!
I don't hear anything.
Someone's coming.
It's all right, I won't let them hurt you.
Get out of my way!
Why don't you listen to me?
I am not being caught!
Stop him! Don't let him escape!
How did he get away? Who's responsible?
What happened?
I... I told him he wouldn't get hurt and he wouldn't believe me.
You mean you let him go?
Well, no, not exactly.
He let the prisoner escape. That is a crime in this Colony. For that, men must work in the pit. Guard!
You can't touch him. He doesn't know your laws!
Er, that's true, Ola. He is a stranger here.
There's something else you're forgetting gentlemen - I set free someone that we caught in the first place.
True - a reasonable point of view, Ola.
Medok is dangerous. He should have never let him go. The Colony will be petrified when they know he's out there in the night.
Well, send your patrol after him. He can't have got far.
He can run you know. He's got legs. He doesn't have to crawl over the ground.
Why did you say that?
Why, no reason. No reason at all.
Anyone who spreads that kind of rumour in this Colony will find himself in the hospital for correction.
Oh... oh, that's where Medok is, is it?
I think, Doctor, you will understand more about Medok if you talk to some of the people who knew him best.
Pilot, I think...
Now take the strangers to the labour centre Ola. See they learn something about us. Please, go with him.
Oh, well thank you.
What is it?
Nothing, come on.
This is your Controller speaking. There is no need for alarm. You may all continue your work and play, confident that the best is being done for you. But our unfortunate companion Medok has been allowed to escape. Emergency Patrols two and three are now searching the Colony and he is sure to be caught before it is dark. Now return to your work and play with fresh heart and renewed energy!
They got that bloke all over the place like a blinking politician.
He is our controller. We are always pleased to see him. He brings us encouragement.
Oh, he's not a politician then!
Number nine shift to stand by. Leader to report to Youth Centre.
Work shift ready to leave.
"We're happy to work,
Happy to play,
That's a nice wee tune Doctor.
Yeah, if you happen to like work.
It's a privilege to work for the Colony.
Shift leader reporting: Shift number nine, all present and correct.
Good. You're the first of the night shift.
Uh, what do ye do then? Farming or fishing?
We work very hard here.
Yes, but what do you do?
We tap and refine gas.
For heating?
No, we use it for many things. The Colony depends on it. It's absolutely essen...
Emergency! Quick, give me that! Come on!
Accident! Stand by, oxygen supply. Take them away. Any other losses?
Two with gas sickness. Come on.
What happened?
Their work. It can't be helped. The work must be done.
Do you hear that, Doctor?
Where's he gone?
Shh! I saw you.
Get out!
Oh, that's not very polite. I was interested in what you were saying.
Who else knows I'm here?
No one. Why should I tell them? Now these creatures - have you seen them clearly? What do they look like?
What has it to do with you?
Well, I'm interested. What do they look like?
All right. If you really want to know. It's hard to say. They move at night, in the dark. And look horrible. Creatures... like giant insects.
With big claws?
Yes, that's it.
You've seen them in the Colony?
Oh yes.
Has anyone else seen them?
A few, but they've lock them up in the correction hospital.
Why do they do that?
Control tells them to. They'll put me back there when they catch me.
And they'll put you back there for helping me.
Doctor! Doctor!
Go on! Quickly! They're looking for you!
Doctor!
But we searched there, I'm sure.
Aye.
Were you looking for me?
Where have you been?
I'm just looking around, that's all.
It's dangerous to go off on your own after dark.
Oh, I'm used to the dark. I like it.
We're confined to rest cubicles at night by order of Control. Anyone who wanders around the Colony at night... may be killed.
Curfew time. All personnel not on duty must retire to quarters.
Do you hear that?
Emergency patrols two and three to remain on duty. Work shifts to remain at their posts until dawn. Visitors to retire for the night to the refreshing department.
That's you. You're confined here.
Here we are, Doctor.
Your young friends are in their rooms over there.
Thank you.
I, er, I hope you sleep well.
Oh, I'm sure I will. Thank you. Goodnight.
Goodnight, Doctor.
It is now dark. No one will go outside into the Colony. A dangerous man is in hiding. Our patrols have orders to shoot on sight. Happy sleep time everybody.
And the same to you!
I'll have a look over there.
It's all right. It's me. Stay where you are.
Why are you back?
Don't move.
Have a look in those new houses they're building.
He's coming! We'll have to get out!
Wait! If he comes in this way, we'll go out the back. If he comes in the back, we'll go out here.
He's coming... to the front of the house.
Over here. I heard something.
All right. Go back.
You can't stay here.
I'll try to create a diversion.
No, they'll kill you!
Do as I tell you.
Thanks.
Go on. Go on.
All right, we'll go through this opening when I give the word.
Right. Now!
No, look. Out there.
I don't see anything.
In that patch of moonlight. I told you I'd seen them!