You may have been on duty all night, Fewsham,
but that's no excuse for this kind of slipping up!
They weren't major hold-ups. Just a few minutes.
- Kelly was going mad back on Earth Control!
- She would!
I'm sorry, Fewsham, but it's my head
in the noose as well, you know!
I know! I'm sorry.
Oh, all right.
All right, go on. You'd better get back to Earth.
(WAILING BEEP)
Now what?!
That's the air locks.
- Who's there?
- No one.
Then how come the air locks are in use?
(MAN SCREAMS IN TERROR)
Phipps! What is it? What's happened?
Come on, man!
(TERRIFIED SCREAM)
Close the door! We've got to keep...
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
Don't move, anybody! Don't do anything!
Harvey, don't!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
The Seeds of Death
(Doctor Who 1963 06x05)
No! I refuse!
(RASPING WHISPER) You will be wise to co-operate at once,
otherwise you will be destroyed!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Well, I suppose that leaves me no alternative.
Don't do it, sir!
(RASPING WHISPER) Silence!
There's a certain element of risk.
(RASPING WHISPER) You are wasting time!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER) What is happening?
I'm afraid there's been a fault.
The circuit's overloaded.
Very unfortunate.
(RASPING WHISPER) You deliberately sabotaged this apparatus!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(JAMIE) Hey! Quite a place, isn't it?
(DOCTOR) Oh, my word!
- Look at the size of this one, Doc!
- Yes!
(ZOE) Oh, Doctor, look!
Doctor, look.
Now, Zoe... (BEEPING)
What's that?
(MAN) Travel Mat is the ultimate form of travel.
Control centre of the present at the moment
is the moon, serving all major cities on Earth.
Travel Mat provides an instantaneous means of public travel,
and transports raw materials and
vital food supplies to all parts of the world.
- (JAMIE) Travel Mat? Sounds like a flying carpet!
- Hush, hush, Jamie, keep silence
Travel Mat supersedes all conventional forms of transports
using the principle of dematerialisation
at the point of departure,
and rematerialisation at the point of arriva
l in special cubicles.
Departure and arrival are almost instantaneous.
Faster than light!
Although The system is still in its early stage,
it is completely automated and
fool-proofed against power failure.
Well, we have our own system, thank you,
only it isn't foolproof!
Jamie, I think that's just a tiny bit...
You saw what happened to your superior.
You would do well to co-operate.
Killing him didn't do you any good.
- Would you do as I ask?
- There is nothing I can do!
- You do not want to die?
- I'm not that good enough a technician!
- It needs an expert!
- But you are second in command here.
- Yes, but...
- You must have certain abilities.
- You must know what needs to be done.
- In theory, yes.
Then you will do it!
He'll only make it worse!
What is their status here?
Maintenance. Second-class technicians.
There's only one person that could really put
all these things right, and she is at Earth Control.
- Without her, it can't be done!
- Who is this specialist?
Miss Kelly, technical co-ordinator.
But there's no way to reach her. T-Mat is not working.
- But you have a video link.
- Yes, but Osgood wrecked that, too!
So, there is no means to communicate with Earth?
No, you've cut us off completely!
In that case, you are useless!
You will all be destroyed!
There's the emergency T-Mat link!
It only operates from here to Earth!
Then you will activate the apparatus...
..at once!
- It's damaged, too!
- The technicians will help repair it.
- We won't help you. Neither will he!
- Then he will die!
No more money, no more facilities.
A life's work abandoned, just like that.
All thanks to T-Mat!
I can understand your sense of bitterness, Professor.
Very short-sighted of the government
to put all their eggs in one basket!
You still haven't told me who you are
and what you're doing here!
(WAILING BLEEP) That's the main door alarm!
What's going on?
Professor Daniel Eldred, well, well, well!
Radnor, come to see how your spies are getting on?
I'm sorry? We've not met.
My name's Radnor. This is Miss Kelly.
Oh, how do you do?
This is Zoe, Jamie, and I'm the Doctor.
Don't pretend you don't know them!
I can assure you I've never met them before in my life.
I see. I find three strangers prowling around in my museum.
and by the merest coincidence,
you turn up on their very heels!
I can assure you I merely wanted a chat
with a very old friend.
Well, you've done without a chat for a good many years.
Old times. Friendships don't die.
Our friendship ended the day
that you walked out of my laboratory
and joined the government administration on T-Mat!
Different men, different careers!
Yes, but you knew which career
would be financed by government funds!
You could have come over with me.
We are friends. You can join us.
Yes, and worked as Miss Kelly's assistant perhaps
You know I respect your work very much,
Professor Eldred.
We would have welcomed you on T-Mat.
I prefer rockets, obsolete as they are!
Not so obsolete as all that, eh?
We don't miss very much, you know.
- So you've been spying on me!
- No, no no, we stopped that a long time ago.
I should think so?
What's wrong with running a private museum?
Nothing, but you're doing rather more than that, aren't you?
Alright, What if I am? It's a free country, isn't it?
What's wrong with having a hobby?
Rather more than a hobby
preparing an ion rocket
for an unauthorised journey into space!
All right, so you know.
What do you intend to do?
- My dear fellow, help you, of course!  - What?
You can make your trip, with full
Government backing.
- as long as it's to the moon.
- Why the moon?
There's a minor fault developed
at T-Mat Control at Moonbase.
- And we had to put it right, quickly.
- I thought T-Mat was infallible!
It will be eventually,
however we have no way of reaching the moon.
Except by out-of-date rocket! Oh, that's perfect!
You need me after all (!)
I thought you'd be taken with the idea,
and a large sum of government funds
wouldn't come amiss, would they?
Now, how soon can you be ready to...blast off?
Well, come on, it's urgent!
Can you give me an approximate ETD?
I could, but I won't.
Why? There are no strings!
I'm just telling you that I refuse!
- Right, that should do it.
- I'll switch on the power.
You fools! When they find out, we'll all be killed!
Moonbase to T-Mat Reception Earth.
Moonbase to Earth.
Emergency! Emergency!
than an out-of-date rocket programme!
- Commander Radnor.
- Excuse me.
Radnor. Emergency message from Moonbase linking through now.
Commander Radnor, Miss Kelly...
..we are in desperate trouble!
Osgood is dead and we are...
Locke! Locke!
Guard!
Kill him!
Stop him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(RASPING WHISPER) Hunt that man!
He must not escape!
Can we not help them? We can use the Tardis!
To go to the moon? We'd probably overshoot
by a few million years!
Yes, or by a few million miles!
I'm afraid the Tardis is not suited to short-range travel.
Still I think we should help them if we can.
- Aye.  - Yes.
- Well, I think I could get your rocket to the moon.  - You?
Yes, I have considerable experience in space travel,
and so have my two companions.
Doctor, that's splendid! Thank you!
- But the rocket is not ready!
- Perhaps you overestimate the difficulty.
How much more work is required?
It needs fuel and a complete computerised check.
- I can order that.
- No! I would not allow it! The risk is too great!
If there was some other way,
- Believe me, I wouldn't even consider such a risk!  - No!
(COMPUTER) Commander Radnor
Radnor. Go ahead.
T-Mat receptions - New York, Moscow, Tokyo -
express great concern over continued hold-up.
Medical shipments and food awaiting
transit to Asiatic centres.
Position desperate in Calcutta. Instructions awaited.
- That's your answer!
- Well, we want to help, as I said!
You don't know what you're doing! It's suicide!
Listen, if this fault lasts much longer,
there's going to be worldwide chaos,
and world population is at stake.
Infallible T-Mat, putting the world in jeopardy!
All right, I admit it.
Now this man has to risk his life
to get you out of trouble!
No, not for me, for thousands of people
all over the world
who will die if we don't take this risk!
I'm sorry, but I've got no alternative.
- Miss Kelly.  - Sir.
I want all technical personnel working on this.
I want that rocket prepared for launching!
Yes, Commander.
We'd be grateful for your help.
If that rocket's to reach the moon safely,
you'll need more than my help...
You'll need a miracle!
(RASPING WHISPER) Continue the search!
He must not escape!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Commander.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
Do you think it's wise letting
these people crew the rocket?
Wise? No, of course it is not wise.
But what's the alternative?
We gave up training astronauts years ago.
- But Who are they?
- Some of Eldred's crazy friends, I imagine,
But the man who calls himeself the Doctor
said he knows this space travel.
- How can you be sure?
He and the girl know more
about space flight than Eldred.
- What about the boy?
- Yes, I'm not sure about him.
(RASPING WHISPER) The emergency link with Earth,
- is it ready yet?
- I've nearly finished.
- Do not make any mistakes!
- I'm not an expert!
- But you will do it?
- Yes!
Commander, I think I should go as crew on the rocket.
Don't be ridiculous, you're too valuable here!
How can T-Mat be repaired if I'm not there?
- What about one of the technicians who was already over there?
- Osgood's dead.
- Yes, well, what about Fewsham?
- He's incapable of doing it! I think I should go!
No! You're the only one who really understands T-Mat.
I can't have you risking your life!
But yet you are perfectly prepared
to allow them to risk theirs!
Don't worry, Miss Kelly we'll be perfectly all right!
But I don't see what good just this emergency link can be.
Even if you had a gigantic army of warriors,
you couldn't send them all to conquer Earth.
(RASPING WHISPER) We do not need an army.
Earth will be ours for the taking...
(HISSING BREATHING) ..very soon!
- Doctor...  - Yes?
Final check on procedure after you land.
Yes, I know. We're to re-establish
video link with the Earth.
That's right.
When we can see what's wrong,
you can do the rest under Miss Kelly's supervision.
Right. We're ready when you are.
12...
10...
nine...eight...seven...
9...8...7...
..six...five...four...three...
..6...5...4...3...
..two...one.
..2...1.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
It's done.
- The emergency link will work now.
- Excellent!
- What are you going to do?
- Do not ask questions!
Activate the link.
- On receive only.
- Receive?
But aren't you going to send...?
Activate the link on receive at once!
- (KELLY) You've double-checked everything?
- Yes, the fault is definitely on Moonbase.
Is it possible for you to effect repairs over video?
Provided the fault is not too major.
And provided they actually get there with the rocket!
- They'll get there
- Why? How do you know?
You can't even be sure
the rocket's still in one piece!
- Miss Kelly!
- What is it, Brent?
We've got through. The emergency T-Mat link
to Moon Control is activating!
Is someone coming through?
No, it's on send.
Moonbase must has managed to make a temporary repair.
It's all we need. Brent, have a full emergency kit waiting.
- I'll join you as soon as possible.
- Yes, Miss Kelly. Standing by.
Where do you think you are going?
If we can send, it's the only thing I can do.
You have no idea what conditions are like up there!
I know all too well what are like down here
Commander, you've stopped me once.
Please don't try it again,
otherwise I shall have to go above your head.
- She's after your job, Julian!
- Miss Kelly!
(TRILLING TONE)
- Thank heavens you've come!
- What happened?
Osgood, it must have been space madness.
He just went berserk! Pretty mad.
It was terrifying.
Osgood? But he'd be the last man, I'd have thought!
- So did we.
- Where are the others?
When Osgood fused the controls,
Locke tried to stop him.
- Osgood killed him.
- This is fantastic!
- What about Phipps?
- He was injured too and I put him under sedation.
- And you?
- There's nothing wrong with me.
You look frightened.
If you'd seen Osgood die, wouldn't you be?
How did he die?
His body's outside.
He just went out.
Without a pressure suit? I see.
Open all control sections and computer links.
Fewsham, what are you doing?
I thought I'd best switch off the emergency link.
- The trouble we've got could easily burn itself out.
- Sensible.
Anyway, it will prevent Commander Radnor
sending up another security guard
to drag me back to Earth!
(RASPING WHISPER) The other human is still free. Find him!
He must not interfere with our plans!
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! Emergency! How do you read me?
Emergency! Emergency! Can you hear me?
Hello, Moonbase! Can you hear ME?
Yes!
Yes, I can hear you loud and clear!
What part of Earth are you speaking from?
(DOCTOR) We're not on the Earth.
We're in a rocket orbiting the moon.
A rocket? But that's impossible!
I can assure you it's not impossible!
What is your emergency?
What's happening on Moonbase?
We've been invaded! Aliens have taken over!
Put that cover back on.
T-Mat back to Earth and report to Commander Radnor.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Stop!
You will remain here!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Doctor, these aliens he described...
- Yes, Ice Warriors!
- What?
Jamie and I have met them before.
They come from the planet Mars.
- What do they want?
- Mars is a dying planet.
- I imagine that they want a new home.
- Why the moon?
- I think it's just a stepping stone.
- What did you say? They're...Ice Warriors?
Yes, you know, Mars is a cold planet
and they've adapted to that.
It's heat they can't stand.
We should just about be coming into range now.
Hello, Moonbase.
(RASPING WHISPER) You will remain here!
That's the lot. The whole system's
completely operational again.
We can now send to any city in the world?
- Yes, anywhere with a T-Mat centre.
- Fewsham, Do you realise what you're doing?!
- I'm trying to save our lives!
- Then what about the lives of the people on Earth?
- We're in no position to argue!
Why do you want control of T-Mat?
If you're going to invade the Earth,
you'll be fighting the armed forces
of the entire world.
You'll never succeed. There'll be too much resistance.
There will be no resistance!
What about us? What will happen to us?
You will remain alive as long as you are useful.
You'll never get any help from me.
When the time comes, you will do
exactly what you are told...
..or die!
Hello?
- Who are you?
- Oh!
- Mr Phipps, I presume?
- Yes, but where did you come from?
From the rocket. We were talking on the radio.
- Thank heavens you've made it. Are the others here too?
- Yeah, They're still in the rocket.
- How many Ice Warriors are there?
- Those creatures you mean?
- Not many, but they're deadly.
- They have their weak points.
Look, they've killed everybody here,
except Fewsham, who's helping them.
I see. Well, there's only one thing for it.
- We shall have to destroy T-Mat.
You will shortly dispatch a cargo
to certain cities on Earth.
Cargo? What sort of cargo?
That's an Ice Warrior.
It's got Miss Kelly, but how...?
Run!
Oh!
Stop!
(RASPING WHISPER) You must be destroyed!
You've got no orders to kill me!
Your leader will want to speak to me!
Humans are our enemies!
But I can be useful to you, like Fewsham!
Your leader will be angry with you
if you kill me! I'm a genius!
(RASPING WHISPER) Genius!
You will come with me!
The prisoner Kelly has escaped.
This human was in the corridors.
Who are you? Where are you from?
I might ask you the same question!
You will find the human Kelly
and bring her back here!
- Who is this man?
- He's not one of the crew.
I don't know this man.
He must have just arrived here.
Impossible - we control T-Mat.
How did you get here?
Our resources are not limited
to T-Mat, you know!
- You arrived by other means? By space craft?
- Rockets haven't been used for years.
Then you are lying!
You have been concealed here all the time.
(DOCTOR) But you can't be sure of that, can you, hmm?
The people of the Earth
may be preparing a whole fleet
of rockets to defend themselves with!
(ICE WARRIOR) No, Earth relies entirely on T-Mat.
There is no defence against our plans.
And what are your plans? Invasion by T-Mat?
There are too few of you to conquer
all the people of the Earth.
(ICE WARRIOR) The Grand Marshall
has ordered the seeds to be prepared!
- You are to receive your instructions.
- Then guard the humans.
If they try to escape, kill them!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Why are you helping them?
I've seen what they can do!
Do you know what is in that container?
All I know is they want me to send
something to Earth by T-Mat.
- I suppose that's what's in it.
- I shall have to look inside,
and you are going to help me!
The Doctor's been captured?
But couldn't you help him?
I'm sorry, but there was nothing we could do.
- We had a job to reach here ourselves.
- Aye. So did we!
Are you sure the Ice Warriors
don't know about this place?
- One of them did find it, but I managed to deal with it.
- How?
I fixed up some kind of a booby trap
to the solar energy power line.
It looks those things are invulnerable!
- No, the Doctor said they can't stand heat.
- That's right!
The heating system of the entire base
is controlled from the Centre.
Now if we can reach those control,
we can turn up the heating.
But how can we get there?
Ice Warriors are patrolling those corridors.
Aye, Yes I know. The maintenance tunnel's over here!
(WHISPERS) All right, Fewsham, now!
I can't! They'll kill us both!
- You've got to help me!
- I can't, I daren't.
Very well, I shall do it by myself.
If I am caught, which is most likely,
we will both get killed.
(RASPING WHISPER) Do not move!
I was ordered to prepare the controls for transmission.
(RASPING WHISPER) Return to where you were!
(FEWSHAM) But this is most important!
If you are trying to escape, I shall destroy you!
I'm not trying to escape!
Go back to where you were!
All right! All right!
Wait!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Open it!
I said, ''Open it''!
What are these things?
They look like seed pods.
(CHOKING COUGH)
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
What's happened to him?
Is he dead?
We can get through it here then.
Turn the heating up, knock the Warriors out
- We can rescue the Doctor.
- And T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
- But I thought that T-Mat's broken down.
- Not any more, I repaired it.
Can we get this cover off?
This part of the base has been disused for ages.
It's rusted. It will take some time.
The Doctor may not have much time.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You will prepare to activate the cubicle
and transmit to London.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING) Obey!
Activate!
(TRILLING HUM)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
Commander Radnor! T-Mat is working.
- Working? Kelly must have got through!
- Splendid!
What is it?
It's alive! The thing's alive!
(COUGHING)
He's dead!
Keep back! It must be that smoke!
(COUGHS)
Guards!
(CHOKING COUGH)
Keep away from here!
Use the air conditioning!
Switch the air conditioning to expel!
(DRONING AND BUZZING)
(RASPING WHISPER) Dispose of him!
- What do you mean?
- You will adjust the T-Mat controls
and suspend him in space...
..between the moon and Earth!
- Is this the right cubicle?
- It had better be!
(FEWSHAM) Please! Please don't make me!
Complete it!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Oh, no!
That's the interior casing.
It comes off easily.
- Is the circuit prepared yet?
- Yes, almost.
- Almost.
- You are wasting time!
- Operate!
- No!
At once!
(TRILLING)
You've killed him!
You've killed him! You've killed him!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER) Prepare to dispatch to London.
Do as I say!
The time has come for your mission.
You understand what you must do?
I understand. (HISSES)
You must succeed at all costs.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Transmit to London!
I need time.
I must reprogramme.
(COMPUTER) Information coming in
on appearance of vegetable blight
attacking parks and gardens
in the metropolises.
(RADNOR) Guards!
(COMPUTER) ..destroying cereals.
(TRILLING BUZZ)
How much longer must I wait here?
(RASPING WHISPER) Do not ask questions!
I need food and rest!
I haven't had any sleep for...
..hours.
(RASPING WHISPER) What are you doing?
I must fix the cubicle.
But you said T-Mat was functioning properly!
I know, but there's something I forgot.
Quick! The heating controls are over there.
Turn the main wheel to full.
Report to Central Control.
The creature is entering the east compound area.
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(RADNOR) What's happened? Report!
Look out, Zoe!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(part4 ends here)
Doctor! Are you all right?
- Yes, I am. I think so.
- Where's Phipps?
He's dead. An Ice Warrior killed him.
How did you manage to escape?
- The other man helped me.
- Fewsham? I thought he was working for them
- He saved my life.
- Doesn't sound much like Fewsham.
He attacked the Ice Warrior.
He's also got T-Mat working again./?
(DOCTOR) Do I gether we can get back to Earth?
- I think so.
- Let's not waste any more time!
(Weather Control Center)
I had to help them or they would have killed me!
All right, Fewsham. There'll be a full inquiry
when we get back to Earth. Tell them.
No more time to waste.
We must T-Mat back to Earth immediately.
But if we all are going, who is going to dispatch us?
There's a way of doing that. Here, this time switch
delays transportation by ten seconds.
- Oh, I see, how genius.
- I'll dispatch you and follow you using the time switch.
Right, so Zoe, Jamie, come along.
I think this could be quite fun!
Fewsham, that time switch was down
on the maintenance report for being inoperable.
We repaired it!
(TRILLING)
In you get, Miss Kelly.
I'll use the time switch.
You better hurry.
Those Ice Warriors will be back any minute.
Do you know, I find T-Mat travel rather disappointing.
There's no sensation at all!
Where have you been?
And what were you being up to all this time?
Where's... Miss Kelly! What's happening up there?
Will someone tell me what's happening down here?!
Who are these people? Is T-Mat working?
Now, please, don't...
Let us just one question at a time!
Doctor, do you know there's been an alien here?
- An Ice Warrior HERE?!
- Jamie, I am not surprised.
They have taken over the whole Moonbase.
- What about the crew?
- All dead except Fewsham.
- You left him there?
- He said he'd follow using the time switch.
He should be back.
What's happening?
I thought so! The time switch is still out of order.
- What? But he said he had repaired it.
- He was lying.
- Why?  - Obviously he's working for them!
Then why did he let us escape?
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
But don't you see, gentlmen?
The invasion of Moonbase,
the taking over of T-Mat, the seed pods,
the arrival of the Ice Warrior,
they're all part of the same plan.
Plan? What plan?
These incidents seem unrelated.
This fungus everywhere,
what's that got to do with it?
I'm not quite sure yet. Have your people
been able to make anything of it?
It's indestructible. We've attacked it
with every possible way, but without success.
Yes, but have you tried to UNDERSTAND it?
You suggest we should psychoanalyse it, Doctor?
I'm merely suggesting that rather than destroy it,
you should find out its composition and purpose.
I have some laboratory equipment
in my workshop. You could use that.
- Good. Then we need a sample.
- No problem about that.
- The gardens are full of the stuff.
- Fine. The let no time to be lost.
I'll get some equipment for you.
Doctor, do be careful. Those pod things are deadly.
Don't worry. I've already had experience.
I'll be careful.
(DOCTOR) Yes... It's organic.
It's alive.
It's definitely a fungus composition.
- Are you sure this is correct?
- As far as I can make out, it is.
A molecule of five atoms...absorbs oxygen.
You know, a complete blanket of this
would reduce the oxygen content
of the Earth's atmosphere drastically.
According to my calculations,
to one twentieth normal.
It would make the Earth's atmosphere
uninhabitable to the human race,
but exactly like the atmosphere of Mars!
Look at that. Even without vegetation
to feed on, it's still active. Oh!
(ELDRED) If that thing explodes here,
the fumes will kill us! Come on, Doctor!
Just a minute. There must be some way of...
- (ELDRED) Come on!
- (DOCTOR) Sulphuric acid!
Hydrochloric acid!
Acetic acid!
(ELDRED) You've done it!
Well, what was it? What did you throw on it?
- You really think it would work?
- Well It could be less effective than Moonbase, of course.
which handles up to two million
microwave channels simultaneously,
the satellite would just take a few thousand.
That would be enough for vital food supplies.
But we can't use normal communications satellites.
They are not programmed for T-Mat.
No. We have to send up a specially programmed one.
That would mean using a rocket, wouldn't it?
I thought no one use them nowadays.
Not manned rockets, but we do send up
satellites for communications.
- How soon can you get one up?
- Well, I don't know. If we're given top priority...
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
There!
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
A communications unit from our ship.
Connect it to the solar batteries!
(DOCTOR) Is Commander Radnor there, please?
- Oh, Zoe, is Radnor there?
- He's in conference with Miss Kelly and Sir James Gregson.
Oh, I see. Zoe. There's the most wonderful news!
We've found a way of destroying the fungus!
- Oh! What is it?
- Water! Ordinary water!
- Oh, Doctor, surely...
- There's no time to explain now.
Apparently, there is a Weather Control Bureau somewhere.
I want you to get in touch with them.
Can't you reach them on the video phone?
No, I've tried. They are not answering,
or it's broken down or something.
- What do you want me to do?
- Get hold of the Weather Control Bureau people
and to make rain, as much rain as possible
over the entire country!
- Well, where is everybody?
- I don't know.
Let's find the main control room. Come on.
So that's why no one answered the video phone.
And look at that!
No, it's no good. They're locked in position.
Our fleet is approaching
the gravitational field of the moon.
- Is all prepared?
- Everything is ready.
I shall guide our ships in on the homing beam signal.
(BEEPING) What the devil's happening?
I don't know... Yes, Moon Control!
The sound, can you turn it up?
Shouldn't we test the directional beam?
- It is not necessary!
- But it's operating on Moonbase power.
I can't guarantee the pulsing rate will be the same.
Very well. Test it!
Commander Radnor, can this be recorded?
- Yes.  - Quickly! Manage it. It's vital!
The transmission coming in
on the video machine would be recorded.
(COMPUTER) Instruction Understood.
Transmission will be recorded.
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(ICE WARRIOR) The device is operating.
Wait a moment!
Um...I must check the connections.
(SIGNAL CONTINUES)
If the power fails, we won't be able
to guide the fleet onto the moon.
There must be no failures!
I realise the importance of that.
If we overshoot the moon,
nothing will stop them from going
straight into an orbit around the sun.
They will not overshoot!
Of course not, but since their fuel
supplies are at a marginal level,
if anything did go wrong,
they'd never be able to regain moon orbit.
This video device is operating!
You have betrayed us!
- Every word has been heard on Earth!
- Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(COMPUTER) Countdown in minus three minutes.
Cancel the launch! We can use that
satellite to mislead the Martian fleet!
Don't you see? Poor Fewsham deliberately
let us overhear their homing signal.
We can imitate that signal
with a homing device in the satellite!
Commander Radnor, top priority message
to satellite launching site!
- Cancel launch! Repeat, Cancel launch!
- (COMPUTER) Message understood.
If we can deflect their armada,
half our battle is won!
- But still, that fungus stuff is everywhere.
- We solved that one with H2O - water!
Water? Well, all we need to do is to make it rain!
It's hopeless, Doctor!
You'll never get that thing going again!
I'm not so sure, Jamie. After all,
it's only the controls that are damaged.
The workings are all right.
If we can bypass the controls...
Have you got your knife on you?
Lend it me, will you? Be careful.
Thank you. There we are.
Now, what have we got here?
Ah, yes... Yes, yes.
Yes, well, it's just a question
of sorting this lot out. That's all.
All is prepared, Grand Marshal.
I shall return to our ship to finalise invasion plans.
Right, now then, Zoe, let's see what happens
when we try to connect these two together.
No, I don't think so somehow!
What about these two?
Ah! That's better! I think I've succeeded /?
in re-establishing one of these rain circuits, Jamie.
Well, it's not raining yet!
Oh, Jamie! Weather Control is a very difficult technology.
You can't expect immediate results.
- Are you sure you're getting it right?
- Yeah, I hope so, Zoe.
Just have to hope for the best. That's all.
I must get on as there's another little job I want to do.
We should have some nice heavy rain before long!
- Ah, there we are!
- Yes, the satellite.
(ELDRED) Isn't that a beautiful sight!
We've finished and installed the homing device.
It's working perfectly.
Doctor, I know we're sending up a false signal,
but aren't some of the Martian ships
bound to follow the right one?
There isn't going to be a right one,
there's going to be only ours, the wrong one,
and that's going to lead the entire Martian fleet
into an orbit round the sun!
- What about Slaar's signal?
- Obviously that has to be stopped.
- But how?
- Well, as soon as that satellite is up
I shall T-Mat myself to the moon
and destroy their homing device.
- They'll kill you on sight!
- No, I don't think so.
I rigged up an interesting device here.
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(KELLY) There it is. It's in orbit.
We're picking up the aliens' homing signal from the moon.
That means their invasion fleet is getting closer.
There's no time to lose.
Are you quite clear? As soon as
I have succeeded destroying their signal,
you must activate our signal in the satellite.
- We'll be ready.
- Right, then I'll be off.
- Doctor, do be careful, won't you?
- Don't worry, Zoe, I will.
- Are you ready, Miss Kelly?
- Doctor, our control of T-Mat hasn't been tested!
Then now's the time to test it!
(TRILLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(SIGNAL GETS LOUDER)
(SIGNAL GETS QUIETER)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(SLAAR) No.
You...
..over there.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
I ordered you to be destroyed!
Well, you weren't very successful, were you?
Destroy that weapon!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
What is your purpose in coming here?
You don't expect me to tell you that, do you?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
The directional beam is still operative.
Yes. I'm afraid you were a little too quick for me.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Are you capable of operating the T-Mat mechanism?
Oh, no. I don't think I...
Well, yes, perhaps I could get the hang of it.
As long as you can be useful to us, you can live,
but this time, there will be no escape.
You will familiarise yourself with the T-Mat controls.
Oh, thank you very much!
You will not touch the controls until I give the order.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
- (KELLY) It's operating perfectly!
- Shoulf we wait till the Doctor got back?
The moon signal has disappeared, hasn't it?
That may be too atmospheric. As all we know
they're transmitting as strongly as ever.
The moon signal was strong enough
before the Doctor left.
- He must have succeeded.
- Then why hasn't he come back?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
When our Warriors arrive,
you will transmit them to Earth
under my direction.
Yes. They haven't arrived yet.
Something still might go wrong.
- Nothing can go wrong now!
- There's many a slip between the cup and the lip.
If anything does go wrong,
you will be the first to die.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
Scan closer!
If they are going to divert,
it should happen any moment now!
They're changing course!
I think you're right!
They're all following the satellite signal!
The Doctor must succeeded!
He must turned off the Martians' signal.
What's happening up there, then?
Why hasn't he come back?
Don't worry, Jamie. A squad of Security guards
armed with flame throwers are on their way here now.
As soon as they get here, we'll T-Mat them to the moon.
- They'll be too late!
- You'll just have to be patient!
I'm sick of being patient! -- Zoe.
- That T-Mat thing, do you know how it works?
- I think so. Why?
- Could you T-Mat me back to the moon?
- Oh, no, Jamie, shouldn't you...
Look, either the Doctor's all right,
in which case we've no reason to worry
or he's in danger and he needs my help!
You have failed us, Slaar!
We shall all die!
We're being pulled into the orbit of the sun!
This is impossible!
The signal! There is no power!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You did this!
Yes. That signal has been going
no further than this control room.
But they were receiving my signal!
Not your signal - ours.
You sent a signal...
..from Earth?
We sent up a satellite.
That signal has sent your fleet into a false orbit!
The heat of the sun will kill them!
You have destroyed our entire fleet!
You tried to destroy an entire world.
Earth will still die!
The fungus will take the oxygen from your atmosphere!
I'm afraid you've failed there, too.
We can destroy the fungus.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Kill him!
DOCTOR!
Jamie! Look out!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
Creag an tuire!
Jamie! The light terminal!
Well done, Jamie!
Oh, goodness me! Jamie, thank you very much!
Now then, we must T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
(THUNDERCLAP)
(COMPUTER) Widespread rainfall throughout the country.
Some flooding but none serious.
Fungus rapidly disappearing.
Weather Control Bureau coming back into operation.
World food shortages partially relieved,
now T-Mats are becoming operational again.
Message to Commander Radnor
from the Security Council of the United Nations -
-  Congratulations.
- All right. Just discontinue report.
So you DID know what you were doing
at the Weather Control Bureau!
Zoe, of course I did.
Well, it took long enough to work!
Well, the rain seems dispose of the fungus well enough.
Now the next thing to do is
to get T-Mat fully operational again.
Yes, when Moon Relay is repaired,
we must check over the equipment .
and build in safeguards. From now on,
T-Mat must be entirely controlled from Earth.
Oh, surely you've learned not to
put all your eggs in one basket!
T-Mat itself is perfectly effective!
You need a secondary transportation system,
a fleet of rockets on permanent stand by!
- There's no need to go to such lengths.
- It's a question of common sense!
I'm sure the Doctor will agree with me! Doctor...
(JAMIE) You didn't have to make it
rain as hard as all that!
Oh, Jamie, some of you is just never satisfied!
What did you rush us back here for?
Oh, you know, questions and explanations
are very difficult. Come on!
- Where are we going now?
- It's no good asking him.
He's no more idea than the man in the moon!
I heard that, Jamie! Come on!