You may have been on duty all night, Fewsham,
but that's no excuse for slipping up!
- They weren't major hold-ups.
- Kelly was going mad on Earth Control!
She would!
It's my head in the noose as well, you know!
I know! I'm sorry.
Oh, all right.
All right, go on. You'd better get back to Earth.
(WAILING BEEP)
Now what?!
It has no air locks.
- Who's there?
- No one.
Then how come the air locks are in use?
(MAN SCREAMS IN TERROR)
Phipps! What's happened?
Come on, man!
(TERRIFIED SCREAM)
Close the door!
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
Don't move, anybody!
Harvey, don't!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
The Seeds of Death
No! I refuse!
(RASPING WHISPER)
You will be wise to co-operate at once,
otherwise you will be destroyed!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Well, I suppose that leaves me
no alternative.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Don't do it, sir!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Silence!
There's a certain element of risk.
(RASPING WHISPER)
You are wasting time!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER)
What is happening?
I'm afraid there's been a fault.
The circuit's overloaded.
Very unfortunate.
(RASPING WHISPER)
You deliberately sabotaged this apparatus!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(JAMIE) Hey! Quite a place, isn't it?
(DOCTOR) Oh, my word!
- Look at the size of this one, Doc!
- Yes!
(ZOE) Oh, Doctor, look!
Doctor, look.
- Now, Zoe...
- (BEEPING)
What's that?
(MAN) Travel Mat is the ultimate form of travel.
Control centre is the moon, serving all major cities on Earth.
Travel Mat is an instantaneous means of travel,
and transports raw materials and food to all parts of the world.
(JAMIE) Travel Mat? Sounds like a flying carpet!
Travel Mat uses the principle of dematerialisation at the point of departure,
and rematerialisation at the point of arrival.
Departure and arrival are almost instantaneous.
Faster than light!
The system is automated and fool-proofed against power failure.
Well, we have our own system, thank you, only it isn't foolproof!
Jamie, I think that's just a tiny bit...
You saw what happened to your superior.
You would do well to co-operate.
Killing him didn't do you any good.
- Would you do as I ask?
- There is nothing I can do!
- You do not want to die?
- I'm not that good enough a technician!
- It needs an expert!
- But you are second in command.
- Yes, but...
- You must have certain abilities.
- You must know what needs to be done.
- In theory, yes.
Then you will do it!
He'll only make it worse!
What is their status here?
Maintenance. Second-class technicians.
- The person you need is at Earth Control.
- Without her, it can't be done!
- Who is this specialist?
- Miss Kelly, technical co-ordinator.
But we can't reach her. T-Mat is not working.
- But you have a video link.
- Osgood wrecked that, too!
So, there is no means to communicate with Earth?
No, you've cut us off completely!
In that case, you are useless!
You will all be destroyed!
There's the emergency T-Mat link!
It only operates from here to Earth!
Then you will activate the apparatus...
..at once!
- It's damaged, too!
- The technicians will help repair it.
- We won't help you. Neither will he!
- Then he will die!
No more money, no more facilities.
A life's work abandoned thanks to T-Mat!
Very short-sighted of the government to put all their eggs in one basket!
You still haven't told me who you are and why you're here!
(WAILING BLEEP)
That's the main door alarm! What's going on?
Professor Daniel Eldred, well, well, well!
Radnor, come to see how your spies are getting on?
I'm sorry? We've not met. My name's Radnor. This is Miss Kelly.
Oh, how do you do?
This is Zoe, Jamie, and I'm the Doctor.
Don't pretend you don't know them!
I can assure you I've never met them before in my life.
I see. I find three strangers prowling around.
and by the merest coincidence, you turn up on their heels!
I merely wanted a chat with a very old friend.
Well, you've done without a chat for a good many years.
Old times. Friendships don't die.
Our friendship ended the day that you walked out of my laboratory to join T-Mat!
Different men, different careers!
Yes, but you knew which career would be financed by government funds!
You could have come over.
Yes, and worked as Miss Kelly's assistant perhaps
You know I respect your work. We would have welcomed you.
I prefer rockets, obsolete as they are!
Not so obsolete as all that, eh? We don't miss very much, you know.
- You've been spying on me!
- No, we stopped that a long time ago.
What's wrong with running a private museum?
Nothing, but you're doing rather more than that
What if I am? What's wrong with having a hobby?
Rather more than a hobby -
preparing an ion rocket
for an unauthorised journey into space!
All right, so you know.
What do you intend to do?
- My dear fellow, help you, of course!
- What?
You can make your trip
- as long as it's to the moon.
- Why the moon?
There's a minor fault developed at T-Mat Control at Moonbase.
- It has to be put right.
- I thought T-Mat was infallible!
It will be eventually, but we are unable to reach the moon.
Except by out-of-date rocket! Oh, that's perfect!
You need me after all (!)
I thought you'd like the idea,
and a large sum of government funds wouldn't come amiss, would they?
Now, how soon can you be ready to...blast off?
Well, come on, it's urgent! Can you give me an approximate ETD?
I could, but I won't.
Why? There are no strings!
I'm just telling you that I refuse!
- Right, that should do it.
- I'll switch on the power.
You fools! When they find out, we'll all be killed!
Moonbase to T-Mat Reception Earth.
Moonbase to Earth.
Emergency! Emergency!
You can't refuse because of an out-of-date rocket programme!
- Commander Radnor.
- Excuse me.
Radnor. Emergency message from Moonbase linking through now.
Commander Radnor, Miss Kelly...
..we are in desperate trouble! Osgood is dead and we are...
Locke! Locke!
Guard!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
- Not again!
- The second Moscow consignment?
They'll think it's deliberate if this goes on.
T-Mat Reception, Earth to moon. Controller Kelly calling.
(COMPUTER) Bombay-Tokyo shipment activated.
Switch your communication links to video.
Bombay sending now. Tokyo receiving now. Dispatch completed.
Osgood's gone too far this time! There'll be trouble!
New York to Moscow delayed, Moonbase clearance awaited.
Stockholm-Washington personnel transportation, Stockholm sending now.
Dispatch completed. Non arrival, shipment of synthetic protein,
New York to Moscow,
Moonbase clearance awaited.
- Brent.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
- Why the delay at Moon Control?
- There's been a mix-up.
- The Moscow shipment's in Canberra.
- Fewsham again, I suppose!
- Take Moscow out of phase.
- Moscow pending. Moonbase clear.
Toronto-Calcutta shipment activated.
Calcutta receiving now.
- Dispatch completed.
- Moscow's ready.
- Report Canberra-Moscow.
- Canberra-Moscow clear.
- Tell them to activate.
- Go ahead.
Canberra sending now. Moscow receiving now. Dispatch completed.
(TRILLING TONE)
- Good morning!
- Morning. Just as well you've arrived!
The sooner you take over from Fewsham on Moon Control the better!
All T-Mat consignments
are five minutes behind schedule.
Fewsham routed a Moscow consignment
through to Canberra.
- He's a lunatic!
- You shouldn't have recommended him
for an assistant controller's job.
Yes, I know now,
but I thought he deserved a break.
He'll do something disastrous one day
and you'll have to answer for it!
- So, I'll work in a synthetics factory!
- It's your career!
So it is! Have you
a T-Mat cubicle ready for me?
- Yes, Number 6.
- See you later.
Prepare lunar cubicle Number 6
for transport to Moon Control.
Ready and waiting.
Activate.
(TRILLING TONE)
It's lucky he got here
before your man arrived.
Yes. He's late.
- Keep a T-Mat cubicle open.
- Right.
Local cubicle two holding open.
- Report Moonbase situation.
- Moonbase clear.
Routine shipments transferring
on automatic control.
Local arrival. Cubicle two activating.
(TRILLING TONE)
Good morning, Brent.
Good morning, Gia. All functioning well?
Of course, Commander Radnor.
In your case, efficiency and charm
go hand in hand!
- I try to run things smoothly.
- Nothing goes wrong while you're on duty!
I don't allow it!
I thought the system was infallible.
- It won't be anything serious.
- I'm glad you think so!
- Brent, is there any obvious damage?
- None reported. All links stable.
- That's only local.
- It's part of the checking process.
- Report on T-Mat breakdown.
- Complete power phase blank.
- The materialisation pulse generator?
- Overloaded. No damage this end.
- Check with Moonbase.
- Primary video link dead.
- Cause?
- Being investigated.
- Are you sure it isn't serious?
- My staff are running a thorough check.
- Until I have the report, I can't answer.
- I want that report soon!
(WHOOSHING)
Doctor, if we've landed, where are we?
That is what I'm trying to find out, Zoe.
(ZOE) A rocket?
(JAMIE) We're just hanging in space!
Well, we can't be!
Let's try and find a star we know.
(DOCTOR GROANS WITH EFFORT)
There we are.
What in heaven's name...?
- What's he up to?
- He's trying to climb aboard.
Just a minute... Just a minute.
(DOCTOR) Oh, this control is...
There we are.
Now that's an ion-jet rocket
of the 21st century, but...but...
..this helmet, if I can...
There we are!
That's not nearly so sophisticated.
It's certainly not later than 1960.
(JAMIE) The letters on his helmet?
(ZOE) C-C-C-P.
(DOCTOR) Of course!
- What?
- Just a minute.
(DOCTOR) Yes, I think that explains it!
(ZOE) Well, Doctor, what is it?
(DOCTOR) It's a flying machine,
designed by a gentleman by the name
of Leonardo da Vinci in about 1500.
- Well, what's it doing up here?!
- Doctor, where are we?
- We're in a museum!
- A what?
A space museum! Look!
There you are. A balloon...
That's a transport plane.
Now, those initials stand for Russia.
That's Gagarin,
the first earthman in space. Look.
Come on, let's have a look round, shall we?
Wait for me!
You will start work at once!
There will be a guard at the door.
When I return...
..you will have the T-Mat link
ready for operation.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Don't be a fool, Fewsham!
If we repair the emergency link,
these creatures can travel to Earth!
- What about us?
- As soon as he gets what he wants,
we'll mean nothing to him!
- If we co-operate, we've got a chance!
- Osgood didn't take it!
Do you think I want to die
like that? I want to live!
(KELLY) Brent, is there
any trace of a reason?
We've double checked.
This end is functioning normally.
Then it must be Moonbase!
We've no way of checking
their apparatus from this end.
- Commander Radnor's at a meeting.
- He'll expect a full report.
There it is.
We've even checked the computer.
(RADNOR) Have you located
the cause of the breakdown?
- This end is clear.
- That isn't what I want to know!
- We cannot trace the fault.
- Miss Kelly!
I have senior government officials
hounding me.
They expect a more informative
answer, and so do I!
There isn't one. The trouble is at Moonbase.
- Why can't you deal with it?
- We can't get there.
We can't even talk to them.
You mean there's no other way
of contacting them?
Only by rocket (!)
That could be our only answer!
(BRENT) The only place you'll find
a rocket is in a museum!
- Exactly!
- Even if one could be made operational,
- no one could control such a project.
- You're wrong. There is one man,
one man alone who can help us now.
For the last time, who are you
and why are you in my private workshop?
Now there really is no need
for all these...these histrionics.
- We are perfectly harmless!
- How did you even get in here?
The usual way. We just materialised.
The T-Mat cubicle didn't give
automatic warnings this time.
(ZOE) That's not our fault, is it?
- Why did you come?
- Well, this is a museum!
The museum is... What on earth's that?
It's a 20th-century police box, isn't it?
Well, yes, in a way.
Well, how did it get in my museum?
(ZOE) You could say
it was a form of spaceship.
We owe this gentleman an apology.
We really are most interested
in the museum, Mr, um...?
Eldred. Professor Eldred.
The museum is closed
to the general public. Please leave.
- Are you in charge of this place?
- I own it! I have the right
- to ask you to leave!
- There's no need to threaten us.
- Trespassers are not welcome!
- We're not trespassers!
- We're very interested!
- Interested in these antiquated machines?
Come for a good laugh, I suppose,
like the rest of them!
Laugh?! You mean people laugh at this?
It's a magnificent exhibition!
- We've had enough souvenir hunters!
- We're not thieves!
We haven't come to take anything!
We genuinely are interested in space travel!
Why, especially a thing like this!
- This is superb!
- (ELDRED) Yes, magnificent!
It was to have been the vehicle
to take man beyond the moon.
- T-Mat put an end to all that!
- You mean this model's been abandoned?
But its speed and stability are
a tremendous advance in rocket design!
Exactly! Here, let me show it to you!
Oh, yes, this is superb. My word!
The real breakthrough was a compact
generator of enormous power!
And these must be the secondary
electrode accelerators.
Yes, you see, it beat the problem
of the neutral caesium ions.
It magnified the G-thrust, too.
Fantastic proportions!
That was awkward!
- What did you do about that?
- I'll show you.
(DOCTOR) What have we got here?
Look at them! They're like a couple of kids!
Yeah, he's almost in love with that rocket!
Well, that's not surprising - I designed it!
I've been in rocketry all my life.
My father engineered
the first lunar passenger module,
and I travelled on the last trip
back to Earth before it finished.
- Before what finished?
- Space travel.
But if the rocket was so good,
why did you stop at the moon?
- Aye, why end there?
- Because of T-Mat.
T-Mat, the ultimate in travel,
with as much sense of adventure
as a synthetic carbohydrates factory!
Surely rockets would still be useful
as an auxiliary means of transport?
Besides, how would man get beyond the moon?
Nobody cares any more about exploring space.
Life's made... Well, it was
made too easy by T-Mat.
I see. So you lost government backing?
The project was abandoned...except by me.
You've got to help me! If we don't
repair it, we'll all be killed!
Maybe we could repair it
and T-Mat back to London?
With that thing guarding the door?
I'll keep on trying.
Maybe there is something we can do.
- What?
- I knew you'd see reason!
- What are you doing?!
- The video link with Earth.
It's not so badly damaged as the T-Mat.
We're supposed to repair the T-Mat link!
Maybe we can get a message through by video.
A guard will see what we're doing!
He'll kill us!
You play your game, we'll play ours.
Stop him!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Hunt that man! He must not escape!
Can we not help them? We can use the Tardis!
To go to the moon? We'd probably
overshoot by a few million years!
Yes, or by a few million miles!
The Tardis is not suited to short-range travel.
Still, we should help them if we can.
- Aye.
- Yes.
- I could get your rocket to the moon.
- You?
Yes, I have considerable experience
in space travel.
That's splendid! Thank you!
- But the rocket is not ready!
- Perhaps you overestimate the difficulty.
How much more work is required?
It needs fuel
and a complete computerised check.
- I can order that.
- No! The risk is too great!
If there was some other way,
- I wouldn't even consider such a risk!
- No!
(COMPUTER) Commander Radnor
Radnor. Go ahead.
T-Mat receptions -
New York, Moscow, Tokyo -
express great concern over continued hold-up.
Medical shipments and food
awaiting transit to Asiatic centres.
Position desperate, Calcutta.
Instructions awaited.
- That's your answer!
- Well, we want to help!
You don't understand! It's suicide!
Listen, if this fault lasts much longer,
there's going to be worldwide chaos,
and world population is at stake.
Infallible T-Mat,
putting the world in jeopardy (?)
All right, I admit it.
Now this man has to risk his life for you!
No, not for me, for thousands
of people all over the world
who will die if we don't take this risk!
I'm sorry but I've got no alternative.
- Miss Kelly.
- Sir.
I want all technical personnel working on this.
I want that rocket prepared for launching!
Yes, Commander.
We'd be grateful for your help.
If that rocket's to reach the moon safely,
you'll need a miracle!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Continue the search!
He must not escape!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Commander.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
Is it wise letting these people crew the rocket?
What's the alternative?
We gave up training astronauts years ago.
- Who are they?
- Eldred's crazy friends, I imagine,
- but the Doctor knows his space travel.
- How can you be sure?
He and the girl know
more about space flight than Eldred.
- What about the boy?
- I'm not sure about him.
(RASPING WHISPER)
The emergency link with Earth,
- is it ready yet?
- I've nearly finished.
- Do not make any mistakes!
- I'm not an expert!
- But you will do it?
- Yes!
Commander, I think I should go
as crew on the rocket.
Don't be ridiculous, you're too valuable here!
How can T-Mat be repaired if I'm not there?
- What about (one of) the technicians (who was already over) there?
- Osgood's dead.
- Yes, well, what about Fewsham?
- He's incapable of doing it! I think I) should go!
No! You're the only one
who really understands T-Mat.
I can't have you risking your life!
But (yet you are perfectly prepared to) allow them to risk theirs!
Don't worry, (Miss Kelly) we'll be perfectly all right!
But I don't see what good
just this emergency link can be.
Even if you had a gigantic army of warriors,
you couldn't send them all to conquer Earth.
(RASPING WHISPER)
We do not need an army.
Earth will be ours for the taking...
(HISSING BREATHING)
..very soon!
- Doctor...
- Yes?
Final check on procedure after you land.
Yes, (I know) we're to re-establish video link with the Earth.
That's right.
When we can see what's wrong,
you can do the rest
under Miss Kelly's supervision.
Right. We're ready when you are.
12...
10...
nine...eight...seven...
..six...five...four...three...
..two...one.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
It's done.
- The emergency link will work now.
- Excellent!
- What are you going to do?
- Do not ask questions!
Activate the link.
- On receive only.
- Receive?
But aren't you going to...?
Activate the link on receive at once!
- (KELLY) You've double-checked?
- Yes, the fault is on Moonbase.
Are you able to effect repairs over video?
the fault is not too major.
- And if they get there with the rocket!
- They'll get there.
You can't even be sure the rocket's still in one piece!
Miss Kelly!
The emergency T-Mat link to Moon Control is activating!
Is someone coming through?
No, it's on send.
Moonbase has managed
to make a temporary repair.
Have a full emergency kit waiting.
- I'll join you as soon as possible.
- Yes, Miss Kelly. Standing by.
Where are you are going?
If we can send, it's the only thing I can do.
You dont know) what conditions are like up there!
I know all too well what are like down here
Commander, you've stopped me once.
Don't try it again, otherwise
I shall have to go above your head.
- She's after your job, Julian!
- Miss Kelly!
(TRILLING TONE)
- Thank heavens you've come!
- What happened?
Osgood, it must have been space madness.
He just went berserk!
Osgood? But he'd be the last man,
I'd have thought!
- So did we.
- Where are the others?
When Osgood fused the controls,
Locke tried to stop him.
- Osgood killed him.
- This is fantastic!
- What about Phipps?
- He's injured and under sedation.
- And you?
- There's nothing wrong with me.
You look frightened.
If you'd seen Osgood die, wouldn't you be?
How did he die?
His body's outside.
He just went out.
Without a pressure suit? I see.
Open all control sections and computer links.
Fewsham, what are you doing?
I'd best switch off the emergency link.
- It could easily burn itself out.
- Sensible.
It will prevent Commander Radnor sending a security guard
to drag me back to Earth!
(RASPING WHISPER)
The other human is still free. Find him!
He must not interfere with our plans!
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! How do you read me?
Emergency! Can you hear me?
(ZOE) It's no use. No contact
at all. Every circuit's dead.
- This is most unfortunate!
- Don't try them again. You'll blow us up!
We don't need a radio.
- We're nearly there.
- I wanted to contact Earth.
There's no need. We can activate
the moon homing beam.
How? We've got no contact
with anyone on the moon.
It's quite simple. It's an automatic device.
Our code radio signals
trigger the homing beam into action.
We automatically lock onto it
until we reach the point in orbit
where we fire retro-rockets to land.
If they've all been cut off,
how can they activate?
It works off a different
power source - solar power.
It's independent of the T-Mat system.
I just hope it works.
If it doesn't, we'll have trouble docking.
It could be quite a crash.
Let's try. I think we're near enough.
- (THREE-TONE SIGNAL)
- That's our activating signal.
- (STEADY BEEP)
- As long as that note is steady,
we're home and dry, no trouble!
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! Emergency! Can you hear me?
Emergency! Can you hear me?
Hello, Earth Control. This is Moonbase.
Can you hear me? Hello, Earth Control...
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
(BEEPING HAS STOPPED)
- The homing beam, it's cut out!
- I'm trying to reactivate it!
- You said it was infallible!
- The solar power source has been damaged.
- That means trouble!
- Yes, it's impossible to land safely.
- You mean we'll crash?
- Or drift endlessly through space.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Guard!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
You allowed them to send a message
back to Earth!
They tricked me! I tried to stop them!
No matter. He will be found and killed.
- What about me?
- Have you repaired the T-Mat link?
- Not yet. It isn't easy!
- But it is possible?
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Yes, only give me time!
- Very well,
but now you know what will happen if you fail!
You will die!
Don't you see this goes far beyond
a petty quarrel over rockets and T-Mat?
Those men are in trouble
and we must help them!
- Find some other way!
- Your rocket is our only hope
of reaching the moon.
- Listen to them.
- I'm listening!
In a way, this is a triumph for your rocket!
- Is it?
- Yes! The government recognises the fact.
Then the government is going to be disappointed!
I don't understand you!
I'll be frank. I played with the idea
of making a space flight,
I even prepared a rocket,
but it was just a dream -
an illusion for a disappointed man.
- So there's nothing?
- The rocket's partially prepared.
- As for an actual lift-off...
- We can do it!
It takes more than enthusiasm
to get a rocket off the ground!
- We have funds, men, equipment...
- What it needs, you haven't got - time!
- We have the best technicians.
- It's nowhere near ready, woman!
The equipment is still unchecked!
- A computer can do that.
- It would still be dangerous!
Daniel...
It was you who created this rocket.
It was your driving force and enthusiasm
that got it off the drawing board.
With you in control, we can't fail to succeed!
That was a long time past.
Now my heart couldn't take
the strain of the G-force.
But your experience and knowledge
aren't useless.
- We need your guidance.
- No!
I told you it's a dream!
I can never go to the moon
and neither can rocket ZA 685!
- Doctor...
- Yes?
- Are you all planning to crew the rocket?
- Oh, aye!
- I hadn't thought about you.
- You're not leaving me behind!
- There can be no excess weight.
- How many does this thing hold?
- It was designed for three men.
- Well, then, I'm going!
The fuel stocks are barely adequate
for a moon journey and return.
- What about other sources?
- New York and Moscow.
- Transit impossible.
- We're only getting TO the moon.
We'll come back by T-Mat, won't we?
It depends what's wrong with it.
The moon has a fuel dump
and a refuelling system on the landing bay.
But that hasn't been used for years!
Neither has the radio homing beam.
Without it, you won't land at all!
In that case, why worry about getting back (?)
The equipment's fully automated
and solar-powered.
- No reason why it shouldn't work.
- I'm sure it will.
- Will you remember all I told you?
- Even if I don't, Zoe has total recall.
- Well, I've written it all down.
- There's no need.
And there's a map of Moonbase, too.
You know how to operate the homing beam?
Don't worry. Your rocket will be in good hands.
(JAMIE) A-hem!
You've only food and water for three days.
- Ignition reserve power.
- (CLICK)
(KELLY) Fully charged.
- Internal atmosphere settings.
- (CLICK)
(ELDRED) All normal.
- (CLICKING)
- Trajectory bearings, orbital lock.
(CLICKING)
Preset registering normal functions.
Lift-off activation check complete.
All readings alpha green.
- Well done! Record time and not a thing wrong!
- So far!
Link programme to telemeter guidance.
Three minutes.
Countdown will begin at T minus 60 seconds.
(RADNOR) This is it.
(KELLY) All functions
are now on computer control preset.
Clear launching site.
Three minutes seem a long time.
Yes. You remember
your take-off briefing, Jamie?
Aye, he's told me
about this G-force stuff. I know!
You don't know about it
until you've experienced it!
(KELLY) Tminus 60 seconds from now.
One minute to go. Hold tight, everyone!
Well, I'm all right. How about you, Jamie?
I keep telling you - I'm fine!
(KELLY) Tminus 50.
Ensure telemeter guidance is operative!
Don't worry! Everything's
been checked and rechecked!
- T minus 40. Technicians, report.
- (BRENT) All areas clear.
Check all systems.
- We have.
- We must make sure!
T minus...30.
(KELLY) 26...
22...
18...
14...
We have lift-off!
(RADNOR) I never thought I'd see
that again - a rocket rising in flight!
Beautiful!
Let's see how they are.
The link is dead!
Something must have gone wrong
on lift-off! Try the second channel.
- Nothing.
- We're out of touch completely?!
What about radio link?
Earth Control to rocket.
How do you read me? Over.
No, nothing but static!
It's only a minor fault, surely?
(KELLY) Earth Control to rocket.
How do you read me?
Don't release the strap until
we have automatic gravity control,
otherwise you'll float away.
- (KELLY) Earth Control to rocket!
- Wait!
Switching to automatic gravity control now!
Try again.
Earth Control to rocket.
(ZOE) Rocket to Earth Control.
Wait a minute, can't you?
Is everything all right?
We've lost our video monitor link.
(DOCTOR) Yes, I think there must be
a fault in one of the circuits.
Doctor? Doctor!
- (ZOE) What is it?
- A circuit's burnt out.
- I'll switch to another one.
- This is worse than the Tardis!
Do you read me, Doctor?!
It sounds as though the entire
communications circuitry has blown out!
Yes. Let's hope that's all that's happened!
Keep trying, Miss Kelly.
Hello, Moonbase! Can you hear me?
Yes!
Yes, I can hear you loud and clear!
What part of Earth are you speaking from?
(DOCTOR) We're in a rocket orbiting the moon.
A rocket? But that's impossible!
I can assure you it's not impossible!
What is your emergency?
What's happening on Moonbase?
We've been invaded! Aliens have taken over!
Put that cover back on.
T-Mat to Earth and report to Commander Radnor.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Stop!
You will remain here!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
These aliens he described...
- Yes, Ice Warriors!
- What?
Jamie and I have met them before.
They come from the planet Mars.
- What do they want?
- Mars is a dying planet.
- They want a new home.
- Why the moon?
- It's a stepping stone.
- They're Ice Warriors?
Yes, you know, Mars is a cold planet
and they've adapted to that.
It's heat they can't stand.
We should just about be coming into range now.
Hello, Moonbase.
(RASPING WHISPER)
You will remain here!
That's the lot. The whole system's
completely operational again.
- We can now send to any city in the world?
- Yes, anywhere with a T-Mat centre.
- Fewsham, Do you realise what you're doing?!
- I'm trying to save our lives!
We're in no position to argue!
Why do you want control of T-Mat?
If you invade the Earth,
you'll fight the armed forces
of the entire world. You'll never succeed.
- There'll be too much resistance.
- There will be no resistance!
What will happen to us?
You will remain alive as long as you are useful.
You'll never get any help from me.
When the time comes, you will do
exactly what you are told...
..or die!
Hello?
- Who are you?
- Oh!
- Mr Phipps, I presume?
- Yes, but where did you come from?
From the rocket. We were talking on the radio.
- Are the others here too?
- Yeah, They're still in the rocket.
- How many Ice Warriors are there?
- Those creatures you mean?
- Not many, but they're deadly.
- They have their weak points.
Look, they've killed everybody here,
except Fewsham, who's helping them.
I see. Well, there's only one thing for it.
- We shall have to destroy T-Mat.
You will shortly dispatch a cargo
to certain cities on Earth.
Cargo? What sort of cargo?
That's an Ice Warrior's. It's got Miss Kelly, but how...?
Run!
Oh!
Stop!
(RASPING WHISPER)
You must be destroyed!
You've got no orders to kill me!
Your leader will want to speak to me!
Humans are our enemies!
But I can be useful to you, like Fewsham!
Your leader will be angry with you
if you kill me! I'm a genius!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Genius!
You will come with me!
The prisoner Kelly has escaped.
This human was in the corridors.
Who are you? Where are you from?
I might ask you the same question!
You will find the human Kelly
and bring her back here!
- Who is this man?
- He's not one of the crew.
He must have just arrived here.
Impossible - we control T-Mat.
How did you get here?
Our resources are not limited
to T-Mat, you know!
- You arrived by space craft?
- Rockets haven't been used for years.
Then you are lying!
You have been concealed here all the time.
(DOCTOR) But you can't be sure
of that, can you, hmm?
The people of the Earth
may be preparing a whole fleet
of rockets to defend themselves with!
(ICE WARRIOR)
No, Earth relies entirely on T-Mat.
There is no defence against our plans.
And what are your plans? Invasion by T-Mat?
There are too few of you to conquer all Earth.
(ICE WARRIOR) The Grand Marshall
has ordered the seeds to be prepared!
- You are to receive your instructions.
- Then guard the humans.
If they try to escape, kill them!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Why are you helping them?
I've seen what they can do!
Do you know what is in that container?
All I know is they want me to send
something to Earth by T-Mat.
- I suppose that's what's in it.
- I shall have to look inside,
and you are going to help me!
- The Doctor's been captured?
- There was nothing we could do.
- We had a job to reach here ourselves.
- Aye. So did we!
Are you sure the Ice Warriors don't know about this place?
One dit but I got him with a booby trap fixed to the solar energy power line.
It looks those things are invulnerable!
- No, the Doctor said they can't stand heat.
- That's right!
The heating controlled from the Centre.
We can turn up the heating.
But how can we get there? Ice Warriors are patrolling those corridors.
Aye, Yes I know. The maintenance tunnel's over here!
(WHISPERS)
All right, Fewsham, now!
I can't! They'll kill us both!
- You've got to help me!
- I can't, I daren't.
Very well, I shall do it by myself.
If I am caught, which is most likely,
we will both get killed.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Do not move!
I was ordered to prepare
the controls for transmission. Ive got to check that everything is in order.
(RASPING WHISPER)
Return to where you were!
(FEWSHAM) But this is most important!
If you are trying to escape, I shall destroy you!
I'm not trying to escape!
Go back to where you were!
All right! All right!
Wait!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Open it!
I said, ''Open it''!
What are these things?
They look like seed pods.
(CHOKING COUGH)
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
What's happened to him?
Is he dead?
We can get through it here then. Turn the heating up, knock the Warriors out
- We can rescue the Doctor.
- And T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
- But T-Mat's broken down.
- I repaired it.
Can we get this cover off?
- This part of the
base has been disused for ages. It's rusted. It will take some time.
The Doctor may not have much time.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You will prepare to activate the cubicle and transmit to London.
Obey!
Activate!
(TRILLING HUM)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
Commander Radnor! T-Mat is working.
- Working? Kelly must have got through!
- Splendid!
What is it?
It's alive!
It's alive! The thing's alive!
(COUGHING)
He's dead!
Keep back! It must be that smoke!
(COUGHS)
Guards!
(CHOKING COUGH)
Keep away from here!
Use the air conditioning!
Switch the air conditioning to expel!
(DRONING AND BUZZING)
(RASPING WHISPER)
Dispose of him!
- What do you mean?
- You will adjust the T-Mat controls
and suspend him in space...
..between the moon and Earth!
- Is this the right cubicle?
- It had better be!
(FEWSHAM) Please! Please don't make me!
Complete it!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Oh, no!
That's the interior casing. It comes off easily.
- Is the circuit prepared yet?
- Yes, almost.
- Almost.
- You are wasting time!
- Operate!
- No!
At once!
(TRILLING)
You've killed him!
You've killed him! You've killed him!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER)
Prepare to dispatch to London.
Do as I say!
The time has come for your mission.
You understand what you must do?
I understand.
(HISSES)
You must succeed at all costs.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Transmit to London!
I need time.
I must reprogramme.
(COMPUTER) Information coming in
on appearance of vegetable blight
attacking parks and gardens
in the metropolises.
(RADNOR) Guards!
(COMPUTER) ..destroying cereals.
(TRILLING BUZZ)
How much longer must I wait here?
(RASPING WHISPER)
Do not ask questions!
I need food and rest!
I haven't had any sleep for...
..hours.
(RASPING WHISPER)
What are you doing?
I must fix the cubicle.
But you said T-Mat was functioning properly!
I know, but there's something I forgot.
Quick! The heating controls are over there.
Turn the main wheel to full.
Report to Central Control.
The creature is entering the east compound area.
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(RADNOR) What's happened? Report!
Look out, Zoe!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(part4 ends here)
Doctor! Are you all right?
- Yes, I am. I think so.
- Where's Phipps?
He's dead. An Ice Warrior killed him.
How did you manage to escape?
- The other man helped me.
- Fewsham? I thought he was working for them?
- He saved my life.
- Doesn't sound much like Fewsham.
- He attacked the Ice Warrior. He's also got T-Mat working again.
- (DOCTOR) Do I gether we can get back to Earth?
- I think so.
- Let's not waste any more time!
(Weather Control Center)
Weather Control Unit
DRY DRY
I had to help them or they would have killed me!
All right, Fewsham. There'll be a full inquiry when we get back to Earth. Tell them.
No more time to waste.
We must T-Mat back to Earth immediately.
- But if we all are going, who is going to dispatch us?
- There's a way of doing that.
Here, this time switch delays
transportation by ten seconds.
Oh, I see, how genius. I'll dispatch you and follow you using the time switch.
Right, so Zoe, Jamie, come along. I think this could be quite fun!
Fewsham, that time switch was down on the maintenance report for being  inoperable.
We repaired it!
(TRILLING)
In you get, Miss Kelly. I'll use the time switch.
You better hurry. Those Ice Warriors will be back any minute.
Do you know, I find T-Mat travel
rather disappointing.
There's no sensation at all!
Where have you been? And what were you being up to all this time?
Where's... Miss Kelly! What's happening up there?
Will someone tell me
what's happening down here?!
Who are these people? Is T-Mat working?
Now, please, don't... Let us just one question at a time!
Doctor, do you know there's been an alien here?
- An Ice Warrior HERE?!
- Jamie, I am not surprised.
They have taken over the whole Moonbase.
- What about the crew?
- All dead except Fewsham.
- You left him there?
- He said he'd follow using the time switch.
He should be back.
What's happening?
I thought so!
The time switch is still out of order.
- What? But he said he had repaired it.
- He was lying.
- Why?
- Obviously he's working for them!
Then why did he let us escape?
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
But don't you see, gentlmen?
The invasion of Moonbase,
the taking over of T-Mat,
the seed pods, the arrival of the Ice Warrior,
they're all part of the same plan.
Plan? What plan?
These incidents seem unrelated.
This fungus everywhere,
what's that got to do with it?
I'm not quite sure yet. Have you people been able to make anything of it?
It's indestructible.
We've attacked it with every possible way, but without success.
Yes, but have you tried to understand it?
You suggest we should psychoanalyse it, Doctor?
I'm merely suggesting that rather than destroy it, you should
find out its composition and purpose.
I have some laboratory equipment
in my workshop. You could use that.
- Good. Then we need a sample.
- No problem about that.
- The gardens are full of the stuff.
- Fine. The let no time to be lost.
I'll get some equipment for you.
Doctor, do be careful. Those pod things are deadly.
Don't worry. I've already had experience. I'll be careful.
(DOCTOR) Yes... It's organic.
It's alive.
It's definitely a fungus composition.
- Are you sure this is correct?
- As far as I can make out, it is.
A molecule of five atoms...absorbs oxygen.
You know,  a complete blanket of this
would reduce the oxygen content
of the Earth's atmosphere drastically.
According to my calculations,
to one twentieth normal.
It would make the Earth's atmosphere
uninhabitable to the human race,
but exactly like the atmosphere of Mars!
Look at that. Even without vegetation
to feed on, it's still active. Oh!
(ELDRED) If that thing explodes here, the fumes will kill us! Come on, Doctor!
Just a minute. There must be some way of...
(ELDRED) Come on!
(DOCTOR) Sulphuric acid!
Hydrochloric acid!
Acetic acid!
(ELDRED) You've done it!
Well, what was it? What did you throw on it?
- You really think it would work?
- Well It could be less effective than Moonbase, of course.
which handles up to two million microwave channels simultaneously,
the satellite would just take a few thousand.
That would be enough for vital food supplies.
But we can't use normal communications satellites.
They are not programmed for T-Mat.
No. We have to send up a specially       programmed one.
That would mean using a rocket, wouldn't it? I thought no one use them nowadays.
Not manned rockets, but we do send up satellites for communications.
- How soon can you get one up?
- Well, I don't know. If we're given top priority...
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
There!
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
A communications unit from our ship.
Connect it to the solar batteries!
(DOCTOR) Is Commander Radnor there, please?
- Oh, Zoe, is Radnor there?
- He's in conference with Miss Kelly and Sir James Gregson.
Oh, I see. Zoe,
there's the most wonderful news!
We've found a way of destroying the fungus!
- Oh! What is it?
- Water! Ordinary water!
- Oh, Doctor, surely...
- There's no time to explain now.
Apparently, there is a Weather Control Bureau somewhere.
I want you to get in touch with them.
Can't you reach them on the video phone?
- No, I've tried. They are not answering, or it's broken down or something.
- What do you want me to do?
- Get hold of the Weather Control Bureau people
and to make rain, as much rain as possible
over the entire country!
- Well, where is everybody?
- I don't know.
Let's find the main control room. Come on.
So that's why no one answered
the video phone.
And look at that!
No, it's no good. They're locked in position.
Our fleet is approaching
the gravitational field of the moon.
- Is all prepared?
- Everything is ready.
I shall guide our ships in
on the homing beam signal.
- (BEEPING)
- What the devil's happening?
I don't know... Yes, Moon Control!
The sound, can you turn it up?
Shouldn't we test the directional beam?
- It is not necessary!
- But it's operating on Moonbase power.
I can't guarantee the pulsing rate
will be the same.
Very well. Test it!
Commander Radnor, can this be recorded?
- Yes.
- Quickly! Manage it. It's vital!
The transmission coming in on the video machine would be recorded.
(COMPUTER) Instruction Understood.
Transmission will be recorded.
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(ICE WARRIOR) The device is operating.
Wait a moment!
Um...I must check the connections.
(SIGNAL CONTINUES)
If the power fails, we won't be able
to guide the fleet onto the moon.
There must be no failures!
I realise the importance of that.
If we overshoot the moon,
nothing will stop them from going
straight into an orbit around the sun.
They will not overshoot!
Of course not, but since their fuel
supplies are at a marginal level,
if anything did go wrong,
they'd never be able to regain moon orbit.
This video device is operating!
You have betrayed us!
- Every word has been heard on Earth!
- Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(COMPUTER) Countdown
in minus three minutes.
Cancel the launch! We can use that
satellite to mislead the Martian fleet!
Don't you see? Poor Fewsham deliberately let us overhear their homing signal.
We can imitate that signal
with a homing device in the satellite!
Commander Radnor, top priority
message to satellite launching site!
- Cancel launch! Repeat, Cancel launch!
- (COMPUTER) Message understood.
If we can deflect their armada,
half our battle is won!
- But still, that fungus stuff is everywhere.
- We solved that one with H2O - water!
Water? Well, all we need to do
is to make it rain!
It's hopeless, Doctor!
You'll never get that thing going again!
I'm not so sure, Jamie. After all, it's only the controls that are damaged.
The workings are all right.
If we can bypass the controls...
Have you got your knife on you?
Lend it me, will you? Be careful.
Thank you. There we are.
Now, what have we got here?
Ah, yes... Yes, yes.
Yes, well, it's just a question
of sorting this lot out. That's all.
All is prepared, Grand Marshal.
I shall return to our ship
to finalise invasion plans.
Right, now then, Zoe, let's see what happens when we try to connect these two together.
No, I don't think so somehow!
What about these two?
Ah! That's better! I think
I've succeeded in re-establishing
one of these rain circuits, Jamie.
Well, it's not raining yet!
Oh, Jamie! Weather Control
is a very difficult technology.
You can't expect immediate results.
- Are you sure you're getting it right?
- Yeah, I hope so, Zoe. Just have to hope for the best. That's all.
I must get on as there's another little job I want to do.
We should have some nice heavy rain before long!
- Ah, there we are!
- Yes, the satellite.
(ELDRED) Isn't that a beautiful sight!
- We've finished and installed the homing device. It's working perfectly.
- Well done.
Doctor, I know we're sending up a false signal,
but aren't some of the Martian ships bound to follow the right one?
There isn't going to be a right one, there's going to be only ours, the wrong one,
and that's going to lead the entire Martian fleet
into an orbit round the sun!
- What about Slaar's signal?
- Obviously that has to be stopped.
- But how?
- Well, as soon as that satellite is up
I shall T-Mat myself to the moon
and destroy their homing device.
- They'll kill you on sight!
- No, I don't think so.
I rigged up an interesting device here.
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(KELLY) There it is. It's in orbit.
We're picking up the aliens'
homing signal from the moon.
That means their invasion fleet is getting closer. There's no time to lose.
Are you quite clear? As soon as I have succeeded destroying their signal,
you must activate our signal in the satellite.
- We'll be ready.
- Right, then I'll be off.
- Doctor, do be careful, won't you?
- Don't worry, Zoe, I will.
- Are you ready, Miss Kelly?
- Doctor, our control of T-Mat hasn't been tested!
Then now's the time to test it!
(TRILLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(SIGNAL GETS LOUDER)
(SIGNAL GETS QUIETER)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(SLAAR) No.
You...
..over there.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
I ordered you to be destroyed!
Well, you weren't very successful, were you?
Destroy that weapon!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
What is your purpose in coming here?
You don't expect me to tell you that, do you?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
The directional beam is still operative.
Yes. I'm afraid you were
a little too quick for me.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Are you capable of operating
the T-Mat mechanism?
Oh, no. I don't think I...
Well, yes, perhaps I could get the hang of it.
As long as you can be useful to us, you can live,
but this time, there will be no escape.
You will familiarise yourself
with the T-Mat controls.
Oh, thank you very much!
You will not touch the controls
until I give the order.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
- (KELLY) It's operating perfectly!
- Shoulf we wait till the Doctor got back?
The moon signal has disappeared, hasn't it?
That may be too atmospheric. As all we know they're transmitting as strongly as ever.
The moon signal was strong enough before the Doctor left.
- He must have succeeded.
- Then why hasn't he come back?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
When our Warriors arrive,
you will transmit them to Earth
under my direction.
Yes. They haven't arrived yet.
Something still might go wrong.
- Nothing can go wrong now!
- There's many a slip between the cup and the lip.
If anything does go wrong,
you will be the first to die.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
Scan closer!
If they are going to divert,
it should happen any moment now!
They're changing course!
I think you're right!
They're all following the satellite signal!
The Doctor must succeeded!
He must turned off the Martians' signal.
What's happening up there, then?
Why hasn't he come back?
Don't worry, Jamie. A squad of Security guards armed with flame throwers are on their way here now.
- As soon as they get here, we'll T-Mat them to the moon.
- They'll be too late!
- You'll just have to be patient!
- I'm sick of being patient!
(WHISPERS) Zoe.
- That T-Mat thing, do you know how it works?
- - I think so. Why?
- Could you T-Mat me back to the moon?
- Oh, no, Jamie, shouldn't you...
Look, Either the Doctor's all right, in which case we've no reason to worry
or he's in danger and he needs my help!
You have failed us, Slaar!
We shall all die!
We're being pulled into the orbit of the sun!
This is impossible!
The signal! There is no power!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You did this!
Yes. That signal has been going
no further than this control room.
But they were receiving my signal!
Not your signal - ours.
You sent a signal...
..from Earth?
We sent up a satellite.
That signal has sent your fleet
into a false orbit!
The heat of the sun will kill them!
You have destroyed our entire fleet!
You tried to destroy an entire world.
Earth will still die!
The fungus will take the oxygen
from your atmosphere!
I'm afraid you've failed there, too.
We can destroy the fungus.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Kill him!
DOCTOR!
Jamie! Look out!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
Creag an tuire!
Jamie! The light terminal!
Well done, Jamie!
Oh, goodness me!
Jamie, thank you very much!
Now then, we must T-Mat ourselves
back to Earth.
(THUNDERCLAP)
(COMPUTER) Widespread rainfall
throughout the country.
Some flooding but none serious.
Fungus rapidly disappearing.
Weather Control Bureau
coming back into operation.
World food shortages partially relieved,
now T-Mats are becoming operational again.
Message to Commander Radnor from the Security Council
of the United Nations -
-  Congratulations.
- All right. Just discontinue report.
So you DID know what you were doing
at the Weather Control Bureau!
Zoe, of course I did.
Well, it took long enough to work!
Well, the rain seems dispose of the fungus well enough.
Now the next thing to do is to get T-Mat fully operational again.
Yes, when Moon Relay is repaired,
we must check over the equipment
and build in safeguards.
From now on, T-Mat must be entirely controlled from Earth.
Oh, surely you've learned not to put all your eggs in one basket!
T-Mat itself is perfectly effective!
You need a secondary transportation system,
a fleet of rockets on permanent stand by!
- There's no need to go to such lengths.
- It's a question of common sense!
I'm sure the Doctor will agree with me! Doctor...
(JAMIE) You didn't have to make it
rain as hard as all that!
Oh, Jamie, some of you is just never satisfied!
- What did you rush us back here for?
- Oh, you know, questions and explanations are very difficult. Come on!
- Where are we going now?
- It's no good asking him.
He's no more idea than the man in the moon!
I heard that, Jamie! Come on!