- You've calculated where we are?
- The instruments are still affected.
But I think it's 1984. London.
- Found it!
- Doctor, where are you going?
The Time Corridor. I want to
find out what all this is about.
Such neglect.
A hundred years ago,
this place would've been bustling.
It might be again, if we find out
who's operating the Time Corridor.
Come on. The trouble with you, Tegen,
is that you have no imagination.
a load of crumbling brickwork!
- Don't come in here. Soldiers!
- What?
- He'll be all right.
- Look at the way he's dressed
He must have come down the Time Corridor.
- You've got to help me.
- What happened?
The Time Corridor's on the next level.
Be careful.
Dark...isn't it?
- Look around.
- I can't see Galloway's body.
Look, Doctor.
Bullets.
- Recently fired.
- Hardly alien.
Why advertise who you are, huh?
Where's Turlough?
Turlough?
Where's he gone?
- Did you hear that?
- No, sir.
I thought I heard voices.
Turlough!
May I help you, gentlemen?
This is private property.
I'm sorry about this, this friend of mine wandered
in here by mistake and we're looking for him.
I haven't seen him.
- What's going on?
- Precisely what I'm trying to find out.
- Who's there?
- Don't harm her, please!
- She's a friend.
- Sorry, Doctor.
- Look!
- What is it?
A Dalek! Take cover!
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
Exterminate! Exterminate!
- Where did they come from?
- The Time Corridor.
- From the ship you were on?
- Must be.
- What do they want?
- I hope we never find out.
Aim for the eyepiece on the dome.
My vision is impaired! I cannot see!
- Quickly!
- I cannot see
I cannot see. Warning! Warning!
My vision is impaired
- Open the door!
- I cannot see. I cannot see
Warning! Emergency!
She's all right. We should get her downstairs.
While you're doing that,
I'd like a hand with the debris outside.
The Dalek sent to the warehouse has been destroyed.
How is that possible?
The Doctor was aided by the Earth soldiers.
Seal the warehouse terminal of the Time Corridor.
- How is she?
- She's sleeping naturally.
- Tea, sir?
- Thank you.
Who discovered these cylinders?
Builders converting the warehouse into flats.
Thought they were unexploded bombs.
- Have you tried to open one?
- Haven't even scratched the casing
You think the Daleks anything to do with this?
It would be an enormous coincidence if they didn't.
Who are you?
- How long is your tour of duty?
- Two years.
Captain normally allows new arrivals to settle in,
before subjecting them to the
tedium of Officer-of-the-Watch.
- What did you do?
- I complained.
Someone should have warned you.
I had every right. Have you seen
the state of the defence system?
- You fear attack?
- That's not the point.
Oh, I wouldn't worry about it. The only ship
we ever see around here is our supply vessel.
I think you may have spoken too soon.
Sensors have picked up a ship in the exclusion zone.
- Inform the captain.
- I wouldn't bother him. Not yet.
It could be anything.
Let the fighters check it out first.
They'll be grateful for the practice!
Checklist completed, all systems functioning.
Raise the force shield.
All troopers to battle stations.
Battle speed!
Fighter leader has made visual contact.
It's a battle cruiser!
Go to red alert. Inform the captain.
Sensors report we're being scanned, sir.
Red alert at once!
We've been hit!
- What's happening?
- Engineering report...
- Damage to the generating plant.
Cruiser's closing in, sir.
I've lost contact with the fighters.
Open fire!
I said open fire!
I can't!
We don't have enough power for the
laser cannon. We're defenceless!
- Cruiser preparing to dock.
- Which airlock?
Three. Maintenance team's working on it.
I want every available man down there.
Block the corridor with anything they can find.
- How long before they dock?
- Three minutes.
- We'd better go down to the airlock.
- Right.
Should we be boarded, destroy the prisoner.
Good luck.
0-3 to HQ? 0-3 to HQ? Over.
- Keep trying.
- You must get reinforcements.
I can't conjure them out of the air.
I need a telephone.
- I'll go. You're needed here.
- It's more than a military matter.
I have to speak to the MOD.
We'll need massive troop involvement.
I'll come with you.
You're the only one who knows
anything about fighting Daleks.
Your duty's here.
Gentlemen, you've saved my life.
I'm Colonel Archer, Bomb Disposal Squad.
I have to make an urgent call.
May I use your radio?
Please.
Thank you.
It's dead.
- Under attack! Withdraw!
- Withdraw! Under attack!
- Regroup! Regroup!
Fools! I told you this would happen,
they'd mine the corridor!
The attack must continue!
Only this time as I planned.
Fire!
Masks down! Masks down!
Move it!
We're finished. It's every man for himself!
Destroy the prisoner.
It's not working!
He is a companion of the Doctor.
He should be destroyed.
He would be better used as bait.
The Doctor is sentimental and emotional.
He will come after the boy.
This will aid the Dalek plan.
Allow the boy to roam freely.
We must get back to the TARDIS.
I have to find the Dalek ship.
I'm not going back there.
They'll kill me.
- I need your help.
- You don't know how much of a coward I am.
You can take this opportunity to show me.
Come along.
Oh! Does nothing work properly?
Try here!
What's that smell?
Activate the exit to the Time Corridor.
We obey.
Exterminate! Exterminate!
- That was gunfire.
- Quickly! We should get out.
Quickly!
There's nothing to worry about.
Right, explosive charges primed.
What is that smell?
- Keep back.
- Help me!
Stay away!
What's happening to me?
No!
Disarmed.
Release Davros.
That's not Colonel Archer.
He gave the Doctor his gun belt,
yet he's wearing one.
- What are you whispering about?
- I was wondering when will the ambulance for Tegen arrive?
- That is in hand.
- The reinforcements?
That is a military matter
and therefore confidential.
I don't think we'll wait for the ambulance.
This warehouse is under martial law.
Attempt to leave and I'll have you shot.
Ninety years I was frozen in that.
Ninety years of mind-numbing boredom.
- You were conscious?
- Every second.
The creatures of Earth have
no stomach for judicial murder.
They prefer to leave you to slowly rot and die.
They call it being humane.
Then you must be equally humane in your revenge.
It is a planet I shall destroy at my leisure.
But first, I must deal with a meddling Time Lord.
- That's been anticipated.
- You have the Doctor?
His capture is imminent.
That's it. I've located the Dalek ship.
I'll drop you off at the warehiuse
when I collect Tegan.
- I'll come with you.
- Good man.
The Doctor's Tardis has been
caught in the Time Corridor.
- Prepare the duplication room.
- I obey.
Turlough?
Foolish boy...Shh!
Quickly! Let's get out of here.
No, Doctor.
This is madness.
The Daleks won't thank you
for capturing me. They'll kill you.
I didn't quite tell the truth.
I serve the Daleks. I'm a Dalek agent.
Exterminate the Doctor!
- Exterm...
- Wait!
He is an enemy of the Daleks.
He must be exterminated.
He must be duplicated first.
Confirm with the Supreme Dalek.
Supreme Dalek confirms the order.
We must take the prisoner
to the duplication chamber.
Proceed.
- Impulsive, aren't they?
- They'd kill anybody,
even if they need them.
How long before it's your turn
Down!
Fire!
Careful.
Uniforms!
Uniforms.
We should leave here at once.
Without Davros, we have no future.
He must be made to believe that we serve him.
The Daleks and the Movellans
were locked in an impasse.
Each time their respective fleets
attempted a stratagem,
it was instantly anticipated and countered
by their opponent's battle computer.
Then the Movellans found the answer.
Sorry, sir.
Quickly, tell me.
They developed a virus
which exclusively attacks the Daleks.
The fleet was destroyed. Those who survived
went to separate parts of the Universe
to avoid the risk of further
infection and to work on a cure.
- Have they succeeded? - Not yet.
What would do you with my duplicate?
- That does no t concern you.
- Oh, I think it does. I'm rather attached to myself.
You will remain silent.
I assume my brain waves are destined for Davros.
You must need his services very badly.
Daleks are the superior being.
We do not require assistance.
Superior? It took you long enough to
ensnare the Tardis in the Time Corridor.
- It was but one trap.
- Hm. Stien was more effective.
- A living, thinking being, not some tin-pot machine.
- Please, Doctor!
Stien is but an extension of Dalek technology.
- What? - He is a duplicate.
He is a product of our genetic engineering.
- Are you all duplicates? - Yes.
Interesting. I wonder
what happened to the real you.
It is vital you complete
your researches as soon as possible.
- I need a sample of the Movellan virus.
- It will be brought to you.
I will also need two Daleks
for experimentation.
That is forbidden.
If I am to find a cure,
I will need living Dalek tissue.
- We must consult the Supreme Dalek.
- Do so! But be quick!
The self-destruct chamber has been invaded.
The hostiles must be exterminated.
There isn't time. Abandon the station.
You should have anticipated this.
The original plan was to snatch Davros and leave.
Nothing must endanger Davros.
The hostiles must be destroyed.
The Daleks must be obeyed!
That's outside! Close the door!
Dalek troopers!
They must have seen us.
Take out that camera.
Build a barricade for protection.
- Have the soldiers been duplicated?
- Yes.
It's so clever. Do tell me how it's done.
- No.
- Thought you wouldn't.
What about Tegan?
- She is our prisoner.
- She's harmless. You must release her.
Show him.
- Why?
- A Doctor with no companions
- would be rather incongruous.
- Why are you doing this?
Your duplicates will return to Gallifrey.
At our command, you will assassinate
members of the High Council.
No!
We have been sent by the Supreme Dalek.
We are to assist in your research.
- I need Dalek tissue, not help.
- You may remove tissue from us.
Excellent.
In no way will my experiment harm.
Releasing locking clamp.
In fact, you will become
considerably invigorated.
Perfect.
Reseal your casings.
Now....
Who do you obey?
We obey Davros. He is our Master!
Excellent.
Now all I require is a sample
of the Movellan virus.
Order a cylinder of Movellan virus
to be transported from Earth.
I obey.
Take the cylinder to Davros.
Perfect.
I have but one more request.
I require your co-operation a little longer.
A spirited but foolish reaction.
He will make an excellent slave.
And so will you.
- Are you ready?
- You ask it as though I have a choice.
Everyone has a ch...oice.
It's in the C-Constitution, 25th Amendment.
- Didn't you go to school?
- Maybe we didn't go to the same school.
- Which school did you go to?
- I-I c-can't remember.
You remember the Amendments!
What was the First? It's important that I know.
And that you remember.
Think! Search the area of
your mind that's been shut off.
Resist before it's too late.
I must cont...inue.
Resist!
I must con...tinue.
Relax, Doctor. Don't fight it.
You'll only cause yourself...pain.
I-I know you you feel.
The pain will pass. Relax.
Quickly!
Recite the Amendments!
- I must do my duty.
- You must resist.
You are destroying my mind.
Stand by.
That's it.
Aaaagh!
- Get them into the Time Corridor.
- Aaagh!
No...! Aaaaaagh!
Into the Time Corridor with her.
The Daleks have secured the station.
It is safe.
Excellent.
- The Doctor has been taken prisoner.
- Better still.
He must be brought to me at once.
Hurry. There is important work to do.
I have waited a long time for this.
- What are you doing?!
- She was about to scream.
It's Tegan. She's a friend.
- Turlough... Who's this?
- Never mind. We must get away. Now
- Not without the Doctor. - He's here?
Look behind you.
I can't stand the confusion in my mind.
Quickly... Release me.
- What about the guards?
- We'll call them in here.
You must secure the Tardis for me.
Take the troopers.
We obey
In here!
Now what? Dalek conditioning
could c-cloud my mind at any time.
- You'll be safe in the Tardis.
- You don't understand. I could kill you.
I'll chance it.
- Doctor!
- Don't just stand there. Come and help.
The Doctor is free.
Your troopers have failed.
And where were your Daleks?
This is Lytton.
Call out my Special Guard.
Doctor, look. We should get out of here.
Quickly!
Lytton grows too arrogant.
His mind resists our control.
He must be exterminated as soon as
it is convenient to the Daleks.
- Lytton.
- Davros has control of two Daleks.
They are in the reception area,
attempting to enter the Doctor's Tardis.
- You must exterminate them.
- At once.
You must also destroy Davros.
He is unreliable. He cannot be trusted.
Go. Release the virus in the Dalek ship.
Davros's Daleks?
Destroy them. The Supreme Dalek's order.
The Tardis is not on this level.
We must search elsewhere.
Now!
Behind you!
Take cover!
We are ready to descend.
Proceed. Everything must be exterminated,
including Lytton and his troopers.
We obey.
Stop
Exterminate
We must find the Tardis.
That is our prime mission.
We must obey Davros.
- What is happening?
- We are being attacked.
The Supreme Dalek wishes us destroyed.
The invading Daleks must be exterminated.
Daleks, to the self-destruct chamber.
A hostile has broken in.
Emergency Emergency
He must be stopped.
We must find the traitors.
The enemy of the Daleks must be destroyed.
We are not traitors.
We serve our creator, Davros.
The Supreme Dalek is your ruler.
He must be obeyed at all times.
- Davros must be honoured.
- He must be exterminated.
Nothing must impede
the true destiny of the Daleks
You must be exterminated. Exterminated
Exterminated
- Doctor!
- Well done.
She's been trying to open the cylinder.
I warned her she could start an epidemic.
The virus attacks only Daleks. Then it will die.
What's happening on the next floor?
Lunch has arrived.
Now for the Daleks.
I did not summon your assistance.
We are here to exterminate you.
- By whose order?
- The Supreme Dalek.
Exterminate me, and you abandon
your lives without purpose.
Join me, and I will
make you rulers of the universe!
Malfunction
- Emergency!
- Malfunction!
Your lives are over!
System failure!
Open the doors.
What is happening? I cannot see.
- I cannot see!  My vision is impaired!
- Emergency
They are dying.
And so are you.
- I cannot see
- Emergency! Emergency!
The Daleks are dead.
Long live the new Daleks!
Oh...!
What is happening?
No...! No!
It cannot be! I...am...not...a...Dalek!
I...cannot...die!
I...am...
DAAAAVROSSSS!
- It's over.
- It was horrible.
The Earth is safe, at least
until the Daleks find an antidote.
Doctor! Look
You have not won, Doctor.
- You won't be able to invade Earth!
- You forget, Doctor.
Daleks do not need to invade.
I have my duplicates.
Some have already been placed in
strategic positions around the planet.
The collapse of Earth society will soon occur.
Your duplicates aren't stable.
The Daleks will triumph.
We cannot fail.
The Daleks' true destiny is to rule the universe.
Hello, boys. Just in time for the fun.
- The Dalek ship has been destroyed.
- How?
- The self-destruct device on the station.
- Davros?
No, no...
Stien, I would think. He must have
finally decided which side he was on.
- Are all the duplicates unstable?
- Oh, yes.
Yes, given time,
they will be free of Dalek control.
- Should we inform Earth's authorities?
- Ah, yes. Yes, indeed. Come along.
I'm not coming with you.
- I beg your pardon?
- I'm tired of it.
- What's the matter?
- A lot of good people died today.
- I'm sick of it.
- You think I want this?
No.
I just don't think I can go on.
- You want to stay on Earth?
- My Aunt Vanessa said,
when I became an air stewardess,
- if you stop enjoying it, give it up.
- Tegan
It's stopped being fun, Doctor!
Goodbye.
Turlough?
I'll miss you both.
- No! No, don't leave, not like this.
- I must. I'm sorry.
Goodbye.
It's, uh, strange.
I left Gallifrey for similar reasons.
I'd grown tired of their lifestyle.
It seems I must mend my ways.
Come on.