Recharge.
(QUARKS HUMMING)
Complete destruction.
Maybe you'll believe in my robots now.
I don't know about robots,
but something was attacking us,
and with pretty sophisticated weapons, too.
Well, whatever it was,
we'd better get out of here fast.
Let's try and move this door.
Unnecessary destruction is wasteful.
Did you inspect it?
All relevant details have been recorded.
See if there are any survivors
and bring them to me.
Alive.
- Come on! Keep it... - Oh!
From your reaction
and your lack of knowledge
of the way of life on Dulkis,
it would seem there is some truth in your story
that you're from another planet.
Of course there's some truth!
Look, it was your people who thought
we were friends of Cully's.
The identity of my son's companions
can now be established,
though what has happened to them
is not quite clear.
But Cully has told you they were murdered.
And I believe him!
(COUNCILLORS MURMURING) Why?
Because I have seen these Dominators!
We were just taken aboard their spacecraft.
Believe me, they're callous, without pity!
(COUNCILLORS MURMURING)
I would be grateful if you could tell me
what occurred on the island.
Oh, look here, we've told you!
We're just wasting time talking
while Zoe's in danger!
Can't we get away?
Oh, we wouldn't stand a chance.
These Quarks are deadly.
- Any idea how they're powered?  - No. Why?
Well, if we knew, we might be able
to put them out of action.
Attack them? Are you out of your mind?
Well, they're only robots.
"Only"?
Do you really think we could destroy one?
It'd be easier if we had a gun of some...
- The laser gun!  - Eh?
Cully, I think we stand a chance.
TOBA: Take them to the others.
QUARK: Move.
I'll set them to work on the drilling site.
Work potential and stamina
to be recorded and sent for analysis.
Agreed. If any of them should escape...
Then you will report the fact to me,
no personal action.
(SHOUTS) Toba!
Command accepted.
Hey, would you look down there?
That's the ruined building. Hello.
What can you see?
- JAMIE: It's Zoe and Cully!
- We've got to get down there!
Jamie, we'll split up
and get round the back of them.
- I'll cut across those cliffs.
- I'll go this way.
- Ready?  - Yes.
Once you're inside, give me time to
get the two Quarks into your line of fire.
Here we go.
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
This one collapsed.
Join the other specimens.
This is foolishness, Cully.
All clear.
Best of luck.
What do you think you're doing?
Zoe's out there!
I know that, you fool,
I was aiming at those Quarks.
QUARK: All specimens stand up!
TOBA: What are you doing?
You were told to keep away from the Quarks.
Oh, but I do.
Whenever I see one, I go away.
But they're all over the island,
where can I go?
Stop! One of them is missing.
The man Cully has escaped.
Has he?
It's no good, Jamie.
We daren't wait any longer.
Something must have happened to the Doctor.
I think you're right.
- TOBA: Cully! - Down!
I told you to stay away from the window.
- Do you think he saw me?
- TOBA: I know you're in there, Cully!
Give me that.
Now you'll see what happens when
the orders of a Dominator are disobeyed!
Quark, destroy!
(WARBLING)
Right. Here goes.
(LASER GUN FIRING)
(WARBLING INCOHERENTLY)
Destroy! Destroy!
(QUARKS WARBLING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
- Let's get out of here.
- CULLY: No! This way.
Stop.
Task completed.