QUARK: On the orders of Dominator Toba,
the building was destroyed,
also the man Cully.
-But Jamie was in that building!
-Silence!
You deliberately disobeyed my order?
My life was threatened
and the Quark destroyed.
Yes, because of your own actions.
Are you suggesting
I should have let him escape?
And where would he have gone?
We are on an island, Toba.
These creatures cannot escape.
Now listen to me carefully,
and this time
you will obey my instructions.
Send these creatures back
to the central bore position.
I want it cleared, ready for drilling.
But the Quarks will do it more quickly.
We must conserve their energy
for drilling purposes.
You know the power levels are low.
Command accepted.