Oh, good heavens!
Look, what's going on? Who are you?
We are Dominators.
Both of you stand by that wall.
- I will not.
- Oh, now, Jamie...
- Oh, no. They're not going to...
- We're meant to be obeyed.
- Not by me, you're not.
- DOCTOR: Jamie!
What... All right, if you insist.
(WARBLING)
Doctor, I can't move. Help me!
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
It is pointless to struggle.
My Quarks have used a molecular force
to bind your bodies to the wall.
What's he going to do with us?
Alien races are occasionally of use to us.
I intend to probe your physiological makeup.
Do what?
- Doctor, can you not do anything?
- Don't struggle, Jamie. Keep still.
Toba. Quarks, attach force units.
- Activate. -(WARBLING)
RAGO: Visor.
Transmatter focus probe.
fixme
Brittle skeletal structure.
Reasonable flexibility.
Certain amount of muscular force,
could be marginally useful.
- Vulnerable, only one heart.
- TOBA: Intelligence?
A simple brain. Signs of recent rapid learning.
Still, somewhat crude.
Shall I prepare the other specimen for scrutiny?
No, they will be identical.
Conserve power.
- TOBA: Are they dangerous?
- No, they are physically inferior.
- So we destroy them?  - No.
- It is possible we may use them.
- What for?
- Workforce.  - We've got the Quarks.
We must conserve their power, you know that.
But why do you want...
Command accepted.
Set up a reaction test.
Test this one.
As soon as your friends return,
they will follow you and Cully
in the second capsule.
Wouldn't it be better
if all four of us went together?
- Travel capsules only take two.
- Number one ready.
There's nothing to be afraid of, you know.
Oh, I'm not frightened.
I'm looking forward to it.
Come on, let's try and stir up
a bit of action in the capital.
You really mustn't believe
Cully's wild tales.
(DOOR HUMMING)
I will dial for the capital, Cully,
if you don't mind.
I see. Frightened I might disappear, eh?
Well, it has been known, hasn't it, Cully?
It'd be a joke if it happened
this time, though, wouldn't it?
And if we are to use these Dulcians as slaves,
there are certain qualities you must look for.
Obedience, strength, sufficient intelligence
to make them of use,
but not so much as to make them dangerous.
Is that clear?
Yes.
Uh, what are they saying?
I think they are arranging
for some sort of test.
- Test? What for?  - I don't know.
I thought I heard them
mention the word "intelligence".
Oh, you mean they're going to
find out how clever we are?
Yes. Or how stupid.
I wonder which is the more important to them?
Well, then, Zoe, what were you doing on the island?
Well, nothing, really, just looking around.
- But didn't you know it was dangerous?
- No. At least not at first.
Oh, Cully, how can your conscience allow you
to expose innocent and foolish people
to such dangers?
- But I didn't take her to the island.
- Oh, nonsense.
I know all about Cully's Adventures Unlimited.
- You know, but why didn't you...
- Well, you weren't doing any harm.
- At least we thought you weren't.
- But it's illegal.
To prosecute would have given you open publicity
and it wouldn't have reflected very well on me, either.
I see. Why can't I be treated as an individual
and not always as the son of the Director?
Now then, young lady, tell me exactly what happened.
Well, I landed with the Doctor and Jamie.
- In Cully's ship, yes?  - Cully?
- Oh, no. We came in the Tardis.
- And what is that?
- It's an advanced craft for travel.
- Goes through time and space.
I think this joke has gone far enough.
There you are, I knew he wouldn't believe it.
But it's true! You can ask the Doctor and Jamie,
they'll be here soon.
What do you hope to gain by this foolishness?
But it's not. I told you when
we spoke on the vision link.
Three people have been killed,
a spacecraft has landed,
radioactivity has disappeared
and there are robots on that island.
Now, I may have a pretty inventive mind,
but I wouldn't have dreamt up
that lot, now, would I?
And no doubt you will confirm all this?
Uh, well, I haven't actually seen
the spacecraft and robots...
Oh, so it seems we only have
your word for it, Cully.
And experience has taught us
how little that can be relied upon.
What's he up to now?
He's arranging some sort of
intelligence test, Jamie.
JAMIE: You mean those wee shapes
in that big box? What for?
Yes, well, we'll have to put
the right shapes into the correct holes,
it's quite simple.
Well, if that's all it is,
a kid of two could do it.
Yes, that's what bothering me.
It's too simple.
You moved.
I'm free. What about you?
- Me, too.  - Come on.
(QUARK BEEPING)
TOBA: Well?
QUARK: Molecular force expended.
Order required.
-Are the specimens to be refused?
-No.
- What are you going to do with us?
- Quiet! Over there.
Sit.
Well, thank you.
Attach force units.
(HUMMING)
Hands. Through there.
Power.
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
That will be repeated at regular intervals
until the puzzle is reassembled.
(WHIMPERING) Oh, no!
Begin.
(GRUNTS)
JAMIE: Hurry up, Doctor.
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
DOCTOR: Oh, my hands!
JAMIE: No, the square bit...
- DOCTOR: What?
- JAMIE: No, not the star,
the square bit in there!
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Detach.
Doctor. Doctor.
Now, where's that...
Here. Take it. Sniff, sniff.
-(DOCTOR COUGHING)
-That's it.
Come away. Come away
from that fearful contraption.
- You all right?  - Yes, I'm all right.
What were you up to? That puzzle was easy.
An unintelligent enemy is far less dangerous
than an intelligent one, Jamie.
- Hey?  - Just act stupid.
- Do you think you can manage that?
- Oh, aye, it's easy...
Attach force units.
You two, over here. Sit!
- Oh, thank you.  - Thank you. Oh.
Power.
Now, get off.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING, DOCTOR YELLING)
- I said, get off. - Oh, but...
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING, BOTH EXCLAIMING)
- Try it round here.  - You're surrounded.
- Well, how do we get off?
- There is a way, find it!
- Test complete?
- TOBA: These creatures are useless.
- Strange.  - You question my report, Navigator Rago?
I find it at variance with what we already know.
- I don't understand.
- The weapons we saw earlier,
could they have been devised by such apparent simpletons?
- You think that there were...
- That we will find out.
Message to fleet leader.
"Materials readily accessible, please proceed to refuel.
"Investigating potential slave labour." Transmit.
(DEVICE BEEPS) Come with me.
- But every time we try and get up...
- Jump!
DOCTOR: Jump?
Jump.
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
A simple circuit completed by your bodies,
you obviously know little of electricity.
Elec... Elec...
Are you such a fool?
You have intelligent eyes.
I will continue the test personally.
- RAGO: I said, what is that?
- Well, it's some sort of gun, isn't it?
- Explain it to me.
- Well, I don't know that I...
- Firepower potential?  - Huh?
- What does it do?  - Oh! Oh, I see.
Well, guns kill people.
- Is that what you wanted to know?  - Fire it.
Well, I don't think...
You have to put something into it first
and it comes out here,
as far as I remember.
You. Fire it.
- Oh, I wouldn't know how...
- Do as Dominator Rago says. Fire it!
(STAMMERING) Well, I'll try. Um...
I think you put a cork
or something in...in there...
Jamie. Jamie, be careful.
- I'll get the hang of it, Doctor.
- Jamie, be careful.
Wait, we don't understand guns on Dulkis.
We haven't used them for hundreds of years.
So,
you don't understand guns.
(EXCLAIMING)
Are you sure?
Yes! It was the clever ones who invented them.
- The clever ones?  - Yes, they...
They lived long ago, you see.
There aren't many of them left.
They stopped us using guns and things.
- There are two distinct types on this planet?
- Yes!
How many of these clever ones are there?
Well, there are not many.
We don't like them much.
- They tell us what to do, you see.  - Good.
I see.
There is nothing to fear from these primitives,
and the others sound as if they're pacifists.
So they are useless.
They have a small labour potential, nothing more.
- Shall I destroy them?
- No, we must conserve power.
- But why do...
- We have nothing to fear from such creatures
It will be a waste of energy to destroy them.
Leave them!
Stay away from us and the Quarks.
- Oh, yes, sir. Thank you very much.
- Yes, Master.
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
- Am I glad that's over.
- Yeah, me, too.
They're a bloodthirsty lot,
these Dominators, aren't they?
Aye. What do you think they're after?
I don't know.
That message they sent.
"Material readily accessible."
Some sort of mineral deposits, do you think?
Then this fleet of theirs would refuel,
land and pick it up. It makes sense.
What do they want the Dulcians
as slaves for? They've got the Quarks.
Aye, nasty little beasties.
Hey, Doctor, they've gone.
We'd better get back to that survey place,
Zoe will be wondering what's happened to us.
I think you're right.
I've got to make them believe me,
before it's too late.
- Well, what are you going to do?
- Get some evidence.
Will you come back to the island with me?
All right. But how do we get past
the council out there?
Through my father's rooms. Come on.
We'll have to steal a travel capsule somehow.
Well, I can manage that all right, but...
- Well, what's the matter?  - Your clothes.
- Not exactly Dulcian, are they?  - So?
We'll attract too much attention.
We'll never get past the capsule managers.
Still, no problem.
We can always fix you up
with some Dulcian garments.
- Where from? - Clothing dispenser unit.
There's one in my father's rooms. Come on.
This will take you direct to the capital, Doctor.
Your young friend Zoe is already there.
And no doubt Director Senex
is awaiting your arrival now.
- Oh, this is splendid. (CHUCKLES)
- Hey, Doctor, what is this?
You know I hate being put in a remote...
Now, perhaps we can get on with our work.
QUARK: Unknown creatures approaching.
-TOBA: Destroy?  - No.
Investigate.
- It's enormous.  - So Cully was telling the truth.
- BALAN: Was he?  - TEEL: But Balan...
Where are the robots?
Inside, perhaps?
But it's empty.
Look, there's a map of the island.
QUARK: Stand still.
But you are not Dulcians!
Where do you think everybody is?
Destroy.
Destroy!
(QUARKS WARBLING)
- Cully, what's happening?  - I don't know.
- ZOE: Oh!  - CULLY: The door. Quick!
Stuck. It's stuck.
We're trapped.
(ZOE SCREAMING)