Hey, Cully, would you look who's here?
Any Quarks?
- CULLY: Yes, one.  - JAMIE: Hmm.
CULLY: No, there's more. Can't quite see,
but I think they're working at something
just outside the building.
JAMIE: Let's have a look.
They don't seem to have harmed anybody.
Well, Balan isn't there.
He's probably working somewhere else.
- Look, Cully...  - What now?
We can't just let them stay up there, can we?
- Well, what can we do?
- Get them down here with us.
- But what about the Quarks?  - Well, we'll...
Here we go again.
- Operate! -(WHIRRING)
- Doctor? - Hmm?
What are they doing?
They're drilling.
Well, yes, I know that, but what for?
Hmm?
I don't think they want to take
anything out of the Earth, Zoe,
rather put something into it.
- Well, what?  - Well, if I'm right...
Oh, no!
(MOUTHING)
(QUARK BLEEPING)
Excuse me...
QUARK: Do not move!
Oh!
(QUARK ALARM BUZZING)
- Right, Cully!  - Quick, follow me!
- Don't just stand there, go on!  - Quick!
Cease drilling!
A Quark is being attacked! Follow!
Quarks, search and destroy!
Quark, where are the prisoners?
QUARK: Out of action.
No recorded data.
They can't be far away. They must be hiding.
Quarks, search and destroy!
Command countermanded!
Why has the drilling stopped again, Toba?
The prisoners have attacked
a Quark and escaped!
And once again you've dropped
everything to hunt them!
I have just completed calculating
the remaining power levels of the Quark force.
Thanks to your foolish actions,
they are dangerously low!
All efforts must now be concentrated
on completing our mission.
And if they attack us again?
The Quark's power must be conserved.
Complete the drilling operation!
Command accepted.
Toba, the primitives will not go unpunished.
Fleet Leader has just confirmed
the Dulcians are unsuitable for slave labour.
They will die with their planet.
Good.
So the sooner we complete the drilling operations,
the sooner they will die.
Quark, follow!
(QUARK BLEEPING)
They've gone.
That was very rash of you, Jamie.
Those Quarks are appallingly dangerous.
Och, they're not so terrible.
You know, we dropped a rock on one earlier.
Hey, where's Balan? Why wasn't he...
He's dead, Cully. The Dominators killed him.
Oh, no! If only we'd managed to get him away, too.
You did your best, Cully.
It's thanks to you and Jamie
that the rest of us are safe.
DOCTOR: I'm afraid not.
Nowhere on the island is safe.
Nowhere on the entire planet, come to that!
You see, we heard the Dominators say
that the Dulcians were unsuitable of slave labour.
- But then they'll leave us in peace!
- Well, no.
They said you'll all die with your planet.
Surely they don't mean to destroy Dulkis completely?
- DOCTOR: I'm afraid they do.
- But why? What do they want?
A large amount of fuel for their invasion fleet.
But we know that there are no minerals worth having,
at least not on this side of the island.
They're not mining for minerals
or any natural fuel source.
But their spaceships use atomic power.
We've established that.
But there was no reactor in that ship of theirs,
only a radiation storage unit.
You remember how when they landed
it sucked up all the radioactive dust
from the island?
Yes. So you're saying
that they store radioactive particles
and then convert that energy into power.
Exactly!
Well, then why are they drilling?
Look, I'll show you.
There are four drill holes
here, here, here and here,
and one drill hole in the centre.
Now, then, they have rockets mounted
in each of these drill holes,
and the centre drill hole is probably
for that atomic seed device.
Oh.
Well, don't you see?
They've chosen this spot because
the crust of the planet is thin.
They're going to fire the rockets through the crust
into the magma, the molten core.
ZOE: Then that will almost certainly
fracture the crust of the planet.
Exactly.
But that will create a volcano.
And if they explode the atomic
seed device in the middle of that...
Yes, that's right, Zoe.
The whole planet will become one vast
molten mass of radioactive material,
the fuel store for their fleet.
Well, we'll just have to stop them, then.
DOCTOR: Oh, Jamie,
it's not as simple as that, is it?
If only I could get hold of
that atomic seed device,
I might be able to defuse it.
Yes, then there'd only be a local
volcanic eruption on the island.
- Yes... - But how can we get to the device?
Yes, that's the problem.
Doctor, I've just had an idea.
Shush a minute, Jamie, I'm trying to think.
- Yes, I know you are, but...  - Oh, Jamie!
Now, listen! Will you listen to me?
Now, there's a dead-easy way
to get that device thing.
- Really?  - Yes, now listen.
You said they were going to drop it
down the centre hole,
the one they're drilling outside here.
- Right?  - DOCTOR: Yes.
Well, it's simple, isn't it?
All we've got to do is dig a tunnel
through from here to the borehole
and catch the seed device thing on its way down!
Oh. Well, it was just an idea.
But Jamie...
It's a brilliant idea!
It's so simple,
only you could have thought of it.
Oh! Hey?
We can get the direction from the periscope.
Just line it up with the drilling site.
Yes, there's only one snag, though.
Could we complete the tunnel in time?
It'd have to be 12 feet long or more.
Well, Cully and I could delay
the Dominators' work up there.
ZOE: How?
Oh, we're getting very good
at destroying Quarks, aren't we?
Yes, certainly seems to stop them working.
DOCTOR: Yes, that's true,
but you've been lucky so far.
If only I could devise some sort of weapon for you.
- Is there anything down here, Cully?
- No, I doubt it.
Nothing but survival rations and medical kit.
Medical kit? Oh!
It's surprising what you can do
with a few simple chemicals and a little ingenuity.
Now, come on, we must dig this tunnel.
- Zoe, give us a direction, will you?  - Right.
On a line from...here.
Right! We start the tunnel there.
Get that bunk away, come on.
That's it, Cully. I'll start with a knife, now...
This line here.
I think you'd better let me start it, Jamie.
How are you going to dig through there
with your sonic screwdriver?
It's a little more than a screwdriver.
Just watch this.
(AMAZED CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
- It's burning straight through!
- Aye, the Doctor's very good.
- Have you finished?  - Yes, just completed.
Good. I shall enjoy destroying
this planet and its creatures.
Get the seed device.
We will delay no longer.
Can you see the borehole yet, Jamie?
JAMIE: The ceiling keeps caving in.
ZOE: They're coming back!
Toba's bringing the seed device.
Oh, dear.
You will recall all Quarks from their positions
and prepare the craft for takeoff.
Command accepted.
I will insert the seed device.
Prime the rockets at perimeter boreholes.
Command accepted.
Very soon we shall see this planet die,
and its creatures with it.
Shall I report to Fleet Leader?
Inform him the Dominator fleet
may approach on its refuelling orbit.
Command accepted. Quarks, follow.
(QUARKS BLEEPING)
Quickly, Doctor!
He's taking the device out of its case now.
Oh, Jamie, he'll be too late!
He's putting it in now.
- It's gone! - DOCTOR: Oh!
JAMIE: Doctor, have you caught it?
- Oh, Doctor!  - He's coming!
JAMIE: Quick, out.
Well?
(LAUGHING)
- Oh, thank goodness!
- We're saved! We're saved, then!
No, not just yet.
I've still got to defuse it
before they explode it.
- Oh! Oh, my word!  - ZOE: What?
Well, it's sealed! It's completely sealed!
I can't possibly undo it!
You mean, all that was for nothing?
We're still going to get blown up?
Yes, I'm afraid so,
unless I can think of some way
of getting it off the planet without a...
Have you thought of something?
Well, there is a way of getting it off the planet
without it doing any harm to any of us at all.
ZOE: Well, how?
Ah! But it's not going to be easy...
What? What are you going to do?
Now, just leave it to me, Jamie, hmm?
You, Zoe go back to the Tardis.
RAGO: Is all prepared?
Yes, just two more Quarks to arrive.
Start takeoff procedure.
Command accepted.
(CAPSULE BEEPING)
Oh, where is he?
The Dominators' ship, it's away!
- Oh!  - Where's the Doctor?
Doctor!
- Hey, where's the bomb thing?
- Oh, did you get rid of it?
- Well, where is it?
- (PANTING) Don't ask so many questions.
- What?  - There's no time.
(EXPLOSIONS)
What's that?
It's the rockets in the other perimeter holes.
Come along, we'd better get inside the Tardis.
There's going to be an...
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Toba!
Doctor, come on, will you?
The whole place is going to blow up!
Oh, it's quite all right, Jamie.
The planet is quite safe.
There's just going to be
a localised volcanic eruption.
It'll only affect the island.
Maybe so, but we happen to be on the island.
Oh, my word! Oh, oh!