(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Is the local radiation completely absorbed?
Yes, its energy's been transferred to our fuel reserves.
- But we need much more.
- Of course. That is why we are here.
With respect, Navigator Rago,
I still consider we should have continued to Epsilon 4.
I decided otherwise, Probationer Toba.
But this planet has never been fully surveyed.
It's suitable for our purpose.
The planetary crust is thin here
and there's an intelligent form of life
suitable for a workforce.
But the natives may not be suitable for slave labour.
Suppose they're hostile?
- If necessary, we shall destroy them.
- Yes, destroy them.
But only if necessary!
Commence work on the preliminary survey.
Command accepted.
(WHOOSHING)
(LAUGHING)
Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
(YAWNING)
- Are you still feeling tired, Doctor?
- Yes, just a little bit weary, Jamie.
It's a very exhausting business
projecting all those mental images, you know.
- You need a good rest, Doctor.
- Yes, we all do. A nice holiday.
Where did you say this place was again?
Well, the scanner screen in the Tardis
showed it as an island of some sort
surrounded by a sea of mist.
Yes, it's an island on Dulkis,
a perfectly splendid planet.
I've heard that one before.
And there won't be any Cybermen or Daleks, will there?
(LAUGHS) No, no, no, of course not.
There's nothing unpleasant on Dulkis.
Quarks, destroy the alien vessel.
(QUARKS BEEPING)
(BUZZING)
Did you say these people were peaceful, Doctor?
(STUTTERING) Oh, yes, Zoe,
the Dulcians are gentle and friendly.
Aye, it sounded like it!
- Did the explosion cause this?
- Oh, no, no, no.
This was caused by an explosion some time ago, Jamie.
Looks like atomic blast damage to me.
Yes, I think you're right, Zoe.
But I don't understand it.
Let's look inside, shall we?
Mind the stuff here.
And you destroyed this travel ship?
You gave me no order to the contrary.
You are a probational navigator.
Your first task is to investigate. Second, assess.
You allowed your instinct for destruction
- to interfere with your primary tasks.
- Not accepted. I did...
How can you assess that which does not exist?
Have you completed your atomic analysis?
Analysis complete.
Atomic energy released on this island 17.2 decades ago.
A long time. Strange that this should be
the only trace of radiation on this planet.
Continue.
Drilling sites have now been located and marked.
Then we will examine them.
Did you check the radiation level
before we left the Tardis?
That's just what I was thinking, Zoe.
I think I did.
- Yes, I'm sure I did.
- Hey, what are you two on about?
Well, I was just thinking.
This place reminds me
of the old atom test islands on Earth.
Yes. Yes, I think you're right, Zoe.
- Test islands?  - For atomic weapons, Jamie.
But why on Dulkis?
They've outlawed war.
No, there must be some other explanation.
Well, I vote we go back to the Tardis
and find somewhere else.
Doctor!
TOBA: This is the eastern drilling site.
- What is that?
- Just a crude, box-like structure.
Shall I summon the Quarks to destroy it?
Why? Will it interfere with the work?
No, but...
Then it would be wasteful to destroy it.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
- Oh, my beautiful coat is all wet.
- Ridiculous.
All this is totally unnecessary, you know.
There's not a trace of contamination on us.
Yes, so I've noticed. It's odd, isn't it?
- What's odd about it?
- Well, the whole island is radioactive.
It has been for 172 years. You must know that.
- Well, it isn't now.  - Of course it is.
- Have you checked?  - TEEL: Well, not yet.
We've only just arrived.
But we're taking the annual readings
during the next few days.
Well, if I were you, I'd take them now.
Oh, my beautiful trousers.
I wasn't aware that anyone else
had permission to work on the island except ourselves.
Tell me exactly what has been happening.
But I was hoping you were going to tell us that.
This is an atom test island, isn't it?
Oh, but of course. Everybody knows that.
Oh, well, we don't.
But atomic weapons on Dulkis?
- I thought war had been abolished here.
- It has.
You seem to know surprisingly little
about your own planet.
Well, that's it, you see.
We've just come in the Tar...
Well, as Jamie was about to say,
we come from a different world, from a different time.
Not from this world? Really, that's very interesting.
I must note that in my daily report.
Well, you don't sound very surprised.
Well, it does explain how you came to
expose yourself to the dangers on this island.
No Dulcian would do such a foolish thing.
Well, what are you doing here, then?
We're part of Educator Balan's
expedition from the university.
But when I was here some time ago,
you were a peaceful race.
- So you've been here before?
- Well, yes.
Ah, I must put that in my...
I'm so sorry. You were saying?
Well, what's happened to you? I thought
aggressive weapons had been abolished.
Oh, indeed they have.
The second council under Director Olvin.
He banned the manufacture of all weapons.
Then what are you doing letting off
atomic devices all over the place?
Oh! Oh, there was only one explosion.
Perhaps my pupil, Kando, should explain.
Let's see how much you remember, my dear.
- Um... Oh, yes.  - The seventh council...
The seventh council under Director Manus
initiated research which lead to
the development of atomic energy.
- The des...
- BALAN: Destructive capabilities.
The destructive capabilities of this
were immediately apparent and...
BALAN: This island...
And this island was used
to test an explosive device,
the results of which can be seen today.
Thereafter, all further research
into this type of energy was prohibited,
and the island kept as both a museum
and warning for future generations.
Oh, well, she certainly does her homework.
I see. Then this is an atomic test site?
Oh, yes. You see, students...
That was really very good, Kando.
Students are brought here
to test the radiation level
and observe the effect on the vegetation.
And of course, to see for themselves
the horrors of atomic destruction.
- So there should be radioactivity here?
- But there isn't.
No. I wonder why?
Explain.
Part of this collection of crude weapons.
Continue.
This one operates on the early laser principle.
Fire mechanism here.
Self-charging power cell. Limited range.
Is this all you notice?
The other weapons are just as simple.
There's nothing here that could threaten us.
- These things are so old that if...
- Precisely. Old.
At last, you casually mention a fact
of major significance.
Has it not occurred to you,
Probationer Toba,
that other weapons
must have been developed since these?
Agreed, Navigator Rago.
DOCTOR: But why do you think
we might be responsible? Thank you.
Well, it is conceivable that your craft, the...
- Tardis.  -...Tardis,
could have attracted the radioactivity
in much the same way as a magnet attracts metal.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, it would have registered.
- Do spacecraft often land in Dulkis?
- As far as I know, you are the first.
I must say, then,
you don't seem the least bit surprised.
We are taught to accept fact,
it being foolish to contemplate fantasy
in the face of reality.
You are here. This is fact.
That you come from another planet I accept,
because I have no other means of proving it.
- TEEL: Not a sign of radiation.
- BALAN: There.
But look what I found.
- Cully, what are you...
- Never mind that now.
We've got to get back to the capital.
Oh, it's impossible.
We haven't even begun our survey yet.
Well, if you don't, you'll be wiped out.
He claims to have seen robots and spacecraft.
- You didn't tell me you brought robots.
- I haven't.
Look, I brought three people here in my ship.
They've been killed by those creatures.
So if you don't...
(LAUGHING)
- ZOE: What's so funny?
- Now, I see. Ajest.
Three people. So you come
from another world, do you, Doctor?
- Hey, I don't think...
- Really, Cully,
you and your friends might at least
have agreed upon the same story.
What? But these aren't my three, you old...
Oh, what's the use?
- JAMIE: What was he talking about?
- I don't know.
Look, I've never seen
this gentleman before in my life.
Cully, you had no right to bring
these people here without permission,
even if you are the son
of the director of the council.
Well, go on, then.
Why don't you call him up?
At least he's not as stupid as you are.
- You say you've seen a spacecraft?
- I've told you, haven't I?
And robots. Well, at least I think
they were robots.
What exactly did this spacecraft look like?
Well, it's large and circular
and a sort of silvery colour.
That means it can't be the Tardis.
Are you sure it wasn't square,
like a large wooden box?
No, no, that's not the spacecraft.
No, the box is where
those aliens have made a sort of mark,
a five-pointed star.
They were examining it just now.
Talking about destroying it.
- What?  - What?
- Jamie, we better go and see.
- Come on.
You're wasting your time.
I prefer to make up my own mind, thank you.
Jamie. Are you coming, Zoe?
- No, I think I'll stay here.  - Right.
- Come on, then.
- We shan't be a minute.
Commence work on preparing the sites
of the outer bore hole.
- At once, Navigator Rago.
- Send this message to Fleet Leader.
"Materials located. Detailed report follows."
Command accepted.
JAMIE: At least they haven't harmed the Tardis.
DOCTOR: That's a relief.
Jamie, come and have a look at this.
It's interesting.
- Look. See. - What?
What's so interesting about that?
Well, I think it must be
some sort of survey mark.
Very likely.
Jamie, look.
- Some sort of tracks.  - So they are.
We'll follow them, shall we?
Oh, look, I think we'd better get back.
Zoe will be wondering what's happening...
Well, this is interesting. Yes.
Obviously an interstellar spaceship
of considerably advanced design.
Oh, no. You're not thinking
what I think you're thinking, are you?
That, I think, Jamie, depends
on what you think I am thinking.
Oh.
- Hey, Doctor. - Stop that, Jamie.
- Doctor. - Jamie, don't do it.
- Doctor, look. Look.  - Oh, my word.
QUARK: Do not move. Do not move.
Next task?
Shall we destroy?