Isn't it beautiful!
- What a wonderful sight!
- Fantastic!
- Get us out of here!
- Don't worry. We're safe in the Tardis.
Are you sure? Has the Tardis
ever been buried in lava before?
- No.
- How can you be sure we'll be all right?
Oh, dear.
- Is something wrong?
- This has happened before.
The fluid links aren't able to take the load. Oh!
(ZOE) Mercury vapour!
Oh, no! If I can't pull this down,
we'll get stuck. That stupid, idiotic...
- The lava's up to the Tardis!
- (ZOE) It's reached the 1,000 danger mark.
There we are.
- Have you done it?
- It's stopped the fluid links from vaporising.
- We shan't suffocate.
- If we don't hurry, we'll be fried by the lava.
- Isn't there any way we can get away?
- Well, there IS an emergency unit, but...
- I can't possibly use that.
- But this IS an emergency!
But it moves the Tardis
out of the time-space dimension, out of reality!
Fine. Reality's getting too hot, anyway!
Oh, all right.
Here we are.
Now, then, which end was...?
Yes...
I can't possibly use this.
We don't know what will happen.
Stop your jabbering and get on with it. Look!
(PULSATING WHINE)