He did it... down there...
This is Salamander. I want a security escort to come to the interrogation room immediately. /38.9
I'm releasing two prisoners. They are to be conducted to the main gates and set free. /45.0
Is that understood? Good.
- Well I hope that works.
- So do I.
What do you want us to do when we get outside?
There are plenty of public phones in the area. Dial double zero one and ask for a man named Forrester.
Eh?
He's my deputy to this area.
Double zero one Forrester.
Tell him where I am and just say "redhead".
Redhead.
Redhead. Is that clear?
Redhead? Is that your wife?
It's our emergency call.
Sorry.
Salamander... Is the, is the pass in order?... Very well, you have my authority.
What's all that about?
We have a visitor.
Giles Kent. What are you doing here?
Oh, I've been looking forward to this meeting. /50.9
You're getting careless. You didn't double lock the doors./53.6
Oh, its all right, I've done it now. /56.0
The only way anybody can get through there is to blast their way through.
How did you get into the Research Centre?
Oh, you know me. There isn't a pass in the world I can't get my hands on if I put my mind to it.
You won't find it so easy getting out.
Really? Well we'll see. I'm not on my own this time. I've got friends here with me. /15.1
And between us we're going to fix you once and for all.
You always were a tiresome man, Kent.
I'm going to be more than tiresome this time. /23.6
You know the biggest mistake you ever made was not killing me when you had the chance.
Oh so you going to kill me huh? How petty. What good do you think that will do?
Hold it! Now don't move quickly, my nerves are a bit shaky at the moment.
We must get in there somehow.
We can't without the emergency key, and Salamander has it in there.
- We could burn our way in.
- Never.
- Why not?
- It's an X-structure alloy, you'd hardly scratch the surface.
We'll have to try it. Get the gear up here. Fast!
Ha ha ha. Never get away with it? Oh, that's good, coming from you.54.5
Don't you realize you're dispensable, and the world is going to get along fine without you from now on. /59.9
The only good idea you ever had in your life was getting rid of me /03.2
and you couldn't even do that properly, could you? Ha ha ha. And now  back and you're finished.
Oh, what's that?
They're breaking down the door.
They don't appear to be having much success.
It's not cutting, sir.
Never mind, keep at it.
You're trapped, aren't you?
You're a fool, Salamander. You don't think I'd forgotten already, do you?
What?
I've been with you too many times in this room in the past, not to know where this leads to.
Your little bolt-hole. Halfway down the tunnel. /42.2
A passage out to the fields and enough explosives down there to stop you
or your thugs following me.
Well that's very interesting Mister Kent. Why didn't you tell me that before?
Oh no, it can't be.
Oh, I'm afraid it is. Oh look. Here's another surprise for you. Look behind you.
Astrid, you've come just in time.
It's too late, Giles, I know everything.
That's him, that's the man who took us down there in the first place.
Giles Kent, we thought you were dead.
Now look, I've never seen these people before in my life.
They told me everything. You and Salamander were in it together...
...You built an atomic shelter, took some people down for an endurance test. The next person they saw was Salamander...
...who told them that an atomic war had started.
You see, Kent...
Oh, be careful, Doctor. He'll kill you.
You kept us down like animals.
Why? Why did you do it to us?
We had to have someone create the natural disasters, didn't we, and we fooled you all!
You didn't fool me, Kent...
You didn't suspect me.
Any man who resorts to murder as eagerly and as rapidly as you must be suspect. /49.1
You didn't just want to expose Salamander, you wanted to kill him and take his place.
And I will! Think you're going to stop me? And these people? /55.6
Now move out of the way, quick! We'll see who'll stop me!
Huh, he's going to try and blow the place up!
Come on then!
No! Don't touch that door, it's red hot.
What do you mean?
Well it's locked. They're trying to burn through from the other side.
Still no good, sir.
Look! Salamander!
Yes. I wonder if he knows Kent's on his way?
You always were a fool, weren't you?
Now wait a minute. They'll be after both of us now.
Oh no they won't.
I tell you, they know!
So what you want me to do, huh? Bury our differences, hmm? /45.0
I didn't need you once, I still don't need you.
Now wait a minute. The place is mined, we know that. We planned it for years, together. /52.5
Between us we can destroy them all, and the evidence. Just you and me, Salamander.
You and me? What use are you to me? You were useful once, but now...
No. No...
Ha ha ha ha. You won't get away from me, Kent. Ha ha ha ha.
Ha ha hah. I told you you could not escape me.
Well if I'm going to die, Salamander, you'll die with me.
No! No!
Aaaaaaa!
Come on Doctor, let's get out of here.
Salamander, Giles, they're dead.
Come along man, quickly.
The people...
People. What people?
The people underground in the deep shelter.
They may have been killed.
I promised Swann I'd get them out.
But that's not your fault. You couldn't have done more.
There's a TV monitor screen in there. There must be a link to the deep shelter.
It's alright! They're alive!
How are you going to get to them?
There's a tunnel from outside. We can get to it outside the Research Station.
But that's probably been destroyed by the explosion.
We'll get to them somehow.
Lookout!
Get me some men. I'll lead them.
Alright. I'll go with you.
Oh good then. That's splendid. I'll come too.
Oh no Doctor. It's far too dangerous. They might mistake you as Salamander.
Oh yes. Ooooh.
- Are you hurt?
- Oh I'm alright.
I'll come with you as far as the gates. Come along, we must go.
I thought you were never coming.
Hey Doctor, are you alright?
Oh there you are Doctor. You do look in a state. Come and sit down.
I told you it wouldn't be long. You, you worry too much.
We shouldn't have left him.
You see, after the explosion, Doctor, we dinna know what to do./07.1
You said to come back here, which we did, but I'm sure we were followed.
Please, can we start straight away?
Me, Doctor? But you said we were never to touch the controls.
Quite right, Jamie. Welcome to the TARDIS.
Thank you. You're doing so well impersonating me, ah, I thought I might return the compliment.
And Giles Kent?
Unfortunately, didn't survive the explosion.
We're going to put you outside, Salamander, no friends, no safety, nothing. /49.5
You'll run, but they'll catch up with you.
No!
And now I'm going to kill you.
No you don't.
Oh, Doctor!
Victoria! Jamie! Hold onto something!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
Jamie! Oh!