Patience, Mister Kent, patience.
Astrid should have been in contact by now.
Can't you contact her?
If I knew where she was.
Oh no, I know she's in the Central European Zone,
But that's a big place.
No, we'll just have to sweat it out and wait.
Astrid, you're back. Switch to scramble.
Scramble? Are we being monitored?
- It's possible.  - Right. Switching now.
Denes dead?
Yes, shot in the back.
Well, it looks as if our friend Salamander's
had a field day, doesn't it?
I'm afraid I haven't done very well.
Don't worry. It's not your fault.
Look, stay put and we'll join you.
The girl Astrid Ferrier,
she was in the Central European Zone.
Was she? Well she's here now. Have you found her?
I think so. One of my men saw someone
answering her description...
...going into Giles Kent's office earlier.
Was she alone?
Yes, sir. But shortly after someone else followed her in.
Well who, man, who?
Leader Salamander's food taster sir, Fariah.
Fariah?
But what are they going to do to Jamie and Victoria?
I don't know.
Hold them in the Central European zone
until Salamander has time to deal with them.
No. You're wrong. Salamander doesn't care for loose ends.
He brought them back with him.
What, to his headquarters, the Research Centre?
Yes. He's going to try to get information from them.
How far will he go to get it?
Very far.
Oh, that's very comforting.
I tell you I know Salamander.
Yes, I... I'm not quite clear
about your part in all this.
You work for Salamander, suddenly
you fall over yourselves to betray him.
I came here for that purpose, yes.
Why?
Because I have every reason to hate Salamander.
He blackmailed me into being his personal servant.
I even had to smile when he told me to.
What sort of blackmail? What had you done?
- Does it really matter?
- Oh, no no no.
Of course not my dear.
Well nobody's perfect, Kent.
But I... I still can't help wondering why...
...why I hadn't tried to expose Salamander?
Well you were in a unique position to do so.
Because without any proof
I'd be wasting my time.
Proof! Proof! Proof!
It always comes back to the same thing.
No one has any evidence against Salamander!
We have some.
Not enough! It's not enough!
Salamander covers up too well.
I have what you want.
But I thought that you said...
No. Not about me. Fedorin.
Fedorin? A public embezzler
who commits suicide?
Salamander engineered nearly every one
of those swindles, and I can prove it.
How?
Fedorin's file.
Is the building surrounded?
A three's in position, Captain.
Just closing up the gaps.
Well you haven't brought me here
on a fool's errand, I hope?
But I'm afraid this... this still isn't evidence,
it's... it's not real evidence.
You mean even this doesn't convince you about Salamander?
Oh, I'm not saying that.
Well then you'll do it? You'll impersonate him?
And of course when they see you with me
they're bound to think you're Salamander.
But I... I still don't know if I can carry it off.
It's the only way to get your friends released.
Yesss...
Of course, there are...
Oh I see, yes of course, there are conditions, aren't there?
You help me, I defeat Salamander?
Now look, you're giving me the biggest opportunity
I'll ever have of ridding the world of this monster.
Either I can convince you one way,
or I'll have to do it another.
What you really want me to do is to kill him, isn't it?
What else do you do when someone is evil?
Private justice, eh? Oh no, no.
I'll expose him, ruin him, have him arrested,
But I won't be his executioner.
No one has that right.
Sometimes it's necessary.
- No.  - Yes, Doctor yes!
Right, we'll move in.
Either you get rid of Salamander,
or we won't lift a finger to help your friends.
Mister Kent, look.
I'd make up my mind quickly if I were you.
- Why?  - Have a look out of the window.
Well, what is it?
What do we do now?
Over here, quick!
Well what's that?
- Through here, the ventilator shaft.
- The files.
- Come on, quick.  - But where did it go?
It doesn't matter, come on.
It's locked.
Now you, Doctor, next.
- Oh what about you?
- Kent! Open the door
Oh no, you're too important.
You go, and Giles.
- I'll follow  - All right.
Very well...
...you leave me no alternative. Break it down.
Get back!
Get away from that door!
Did you get the others?
Not yet, sir.
Now listen to me. It was you,
Astrid Ferrier, Giles Kent...
...and another. Who was the other man?
You'll know soon... soon enough.
I want to know now.
Sir...
Shut up! Well?
You can't threaten me now, Benik.
I can only die once,
and someone's beaten you to it.
Who was the other man?
Sir?
She's dead.
Good.
Fedorin's file. Thank you.
What you mean is you failed.
I always said something should be done about Kent.
You always say. You say things, but you don't think.
You exceeded your authority, Benik.
A woman's been killed.
Resisting arrest.
Maybe. But you can't just take the law into your own hands.
Giles Kent hadn't broken any rules that I know of.
For sure he'd show himself one day,
he was simply building up his resistance group.
Resistance group! The man's a traitor.
These people are rebels.
Bruce, you must find this man who impersonated me.
The dangers are obvious.
He could walk in anywhere at any time
pretending to be me and ruin everything.
You can leave that to me.
How so?
Benik, come with me and I'll go over
the security arrangements with you now.
Do as you're told!
I think you'll find this interesting.
What? The girl Fariah had this?
What can I say?
Yes sir?
The records room is out of bounds.
I am not to be disturbed.
See that the security locks are engaged.
Very well, sir. For how long, sir?
For as long as I say so.
Yes sir.
It seems that Salamander's
locked himself away and can't be got at.
So?
Well, suppose the place caught fire?
It won't.
Don't be foolish!
Look, I can only tell you that
when Salamander works in records,
as he does from time to time, no one is allowed in.
I can understand if it were a... laboratory...
or... a... research room of some sort, but a...
a records room? What sort of records
have you got in there anyway?
What did you want to see him about?
Never mind. I just don't like mysteries.
Salamander's far too important
to lock himself away like this,
anything might happen, a world emergency.
Suppose I had to order you to let me in there?
It wouldn't do any good. When the locks are switched over
they can only be opened from the inside.
I have returned.
Take radiation precautions.
I will make a report about the surface.
He's back!
He's managed to get back again.
Let's hope he's got some good news this time.
Do you think Salamander's found some more food, Swann?
I hope so, otherwise we're finished.
Where's that stock list?
Welcome back, Salamander. Are you all right?
Don't, don't come too near my friend,
I am not yet decontaminated.
I am too weary, totally weary.
You shouldn't have made this trip,
Salamander, you're doing too much.
Someone has to bring back the food
for you, my friend, huh?
You know that the radiation
is slowly killing me, don't you Swann?
You're just doing too much.
I worry about you all the time.
What're you going to do when I am no longer here?
Radiation gets a little more each time, hm?
One day, that needle will stay at maximum radiation.
- Don't say that.  - Why... Mary. Colin.
Huh, it's my big joke, huh?
Just to frighten you a little.
I've got good news for us!
We can return to the surface?
No no no not yet, but I've found another store of food...
Thank goodness!
...And it is undamaged.
Colin, open the last store of wine, huh?
Go on, you help him too, Mary.
You must take it slowly for goodness sake.
I'm all right my friend. I'm just a little dizzy. It's...
It's terrible up there, you know,
Swann, you've no idea.
Right, I am ready.
But I still don't understand what's happened to Fariah.
She went the wrong way. We lost her.
Well we must find her!
You don't seem to realize how vital it is.
Doctor, hold still a moment will you?
Sorry.
There. Look at that, Giles, isn't it amazing?
Salamander to the life.
Yes, it's... it's not bad.
Shh, I think I heard something.
Perhaps it's Fariah.
Stay where you are. I've been looking forward
to meeting you again.