Sincro: wyxchari
Oh, there's nothing like a dip to freshen you up.
Hey, that's a funny looking boat.
It's not a boat, it's a hovercraft.
Eh?
You're right, it is him.
What are we going to do?
A terrifying thing. It's like a sea monster.
Oh, we'll soon get a closer look, it's coming nearer.
Oh yes. Yes.
I don't think I like the look of this. Let's go.
Why, what's the matter?
Come on, run!
Yeah, but...
Don't argue, run.
Over here!
Hurry!
Incredible.
Absolutely incredible.
I'm not a specimen in a glass bowl, you know?
Ah, I'm sorry. Do sit down.
Oh, thank you.
It's just so astonishing. You are Salamander.
Do you see what I mean?
But surely you know how alike you are?
After all, Salamander is a world figure.
Well... well my friends and I, we've been
out of touch... with civilisation for a while.
We're visitors, so to speak, um. On ice shall we say.
I see. Where shall I start?
At the beginning please.
We've been subjected to a number of attacks
because I look like this Salamander of yours.
I'm not surprised. I'll show you why.
I have a video wire of Salamander, addressing
the United Zones Conference on World Food.
And meanwhile, over at the United Zones General Assembly,
from all over the world delegates are flocking in,
eager to hear the latest report from Leader Salamander.
The progress, Mr President, of the Sun Conservation
establishment at Kanowa, in the Australasian Zone...
...is I'm delighted to report highly satisfactory.
But we cannot yet guarantee good summer holidays for all.
However, we have now in orbit the Mark VII Sun Catcher,
and already we have been able to
concentrate the sun's rays into much needed areas.
The great Canadian wheat plains are safe.
And now, Mr President: Ukraine
- the grain field of the planet -
an unfortunate area between Bucava and Kirovograd
devastated by the elements two short years ago.
What have I got to say to you about that?
I can tell you that on both banks of the Dnieper river
the corn is ripening in the sun!
And ten-thousand robot harvesters are moving down
to gather in fifty million tons of flour!
There's nothing there to say he's a bad man.
I quite agree, Victoria.
He seems to be a public benefactor.
uite a speaker too and remarkably handsome,
didn't you think so Jamie?
He's one of the most popular men on the planet.
Many people call him the shopkeeper of the world.
The saviour, in fact, some of them.
Well what's he saved the world from?
Starvation - too many people, too little food.
Until Salamander invented his Sun Store.
Surely you've heard? You must know?
Oh yes, well of course we've heard something.
The Sun Store collects the rays from the sun
and stores them in concentrated form.
Oh, like the ioniser, Doctor?
Yes, a rather different principle I think, Jamie.
Well never mind how it works! What's it for?
Salamander can force-grow three,
sometimes four, crops in one summer.
Well why do these men want to kill him.
I mean, one minute you say he's saving the world, the next...
For his own ends! Step by step he's taking control of this planet.
You have proof of this?
Some, yes. I was once a high official in the World Zone Authority
- Deputy Security Leader for North Africa and Europe
- but Salamander discredited and ruined me
because he realized I was beginning to get suspicious.
But you could be making up stories about Salamander!
Out of revenge.
Yes, I suppose so. Then you can judge for yourself.
You remember Michael Assevski -
he was Controller of the Eastern European Zone?
He was drowned at sea a mile from shore.
Hockingham murdered!
All of them were seen with Salamander,
or a man known as his deputy, shortly before their deaths.
All of them were replaced by men known to be in Salamander's power.
- Known by who?
- By me, Doctor.
Well why don't you tell the authorities, the police or whatever?
Because I'm discredited, don't you see?
Because Salamander is so popular,
and also because the man that took my place,
a man named Donald Bruce,
has since risen to become overall security chief.
Surely there is someone you can take your story to?
Ah yes, Helvig believed me.
So did Assevski, and they're dead.
However, there is one other man,
a man named Alexander Denes,
but none of them will do anything until it's too late!
I'm surprised.
Well if Salamander is everything you say he is,
then why hasn't he tried to...
Dispose of me?
Yes.
Well he has, but he's afraid.
You see, the testimony of a dead man still holds legal weight.
Oh, I see. Well, it seems we have a problem on our hands
whether to believe Mr Kent or not.
Well there is one way that you can find out for yourselves.
Oh, how?
Impersonate Salamander.
Yes I thought that's what we were leading up to.
Well I must admit, Doctor, you do look like him.
Exactly like him.
Yes, there's more to it than that. What about the voice?
Well it's nearly the same pitch, only the accent.
Only the accent! My dear young lady. Oh dear.
Now what was it he said...
We still cannot guarantee good summer holidays for all.
No. Guarantee... no, no, no... guaran... guarantee.
You see, it's very difficult.
Hmm, of course I always was interested in phonetics.
Holidays... summer... summer.
He must have come from Mexico, Quintana Roo or Yucatan or somewhere...
That's incredible, Doctor, he was born at Merida,
state capital of Yucatan.
Yes, there are other very strong influences though.
Oh, I could do it in time. But what if I did it, what then?
You could walk into Salamander's research station at Kanowa,
find out how he's getting control of the separate World Zones,
and then bring out absolute proof.
Yes. I see.
How long did you say it would take you to master Salamander's accent?
I didn't. It would take three weeks, perhaps four.
Well while we've been talking,
the Security Chief I told you about, Donald Bruce,
has since cordoned off this entire area.
He's coming here himself.
Now! I'd say you've got about two minutes, Doctor.
But that's out of the question!
You know what he'll do as soon as he sees you,
a man who resembles Salamander so closely?
Oh that's not fair!
Will you please listen! You'll be under arrest for
impersonation as soon as he sees you. I mean it.
But isn't there another way out of this?
Only one - be Salamander.
But the clothes!
Yes, there are some in here.
A little less eccentric, but do the best you can.
I won't! I can't!
Your friends, Doctor, do you want them to suffer?
Because they will, you know.
No, wait a minute! Why is a man like Bruce coming here?
Don't push me, there isn't time.
You sent for him, didn't you? You tipped him off!
I couldn't miss an opportunity like this,
now please come on.
Giles, for heaven's sake, what have you done?
It's far too risky.
Hello Kent. Doing some recruiting are you?
A bit young for killers, aren't they?
What do you mean?
All right, what do you mean by stepping in here like this?
Anytime, Kent. I've got the right and you know it. Anytime I like.
All right, what do you want?
That's better, you're ex-security,
you know the way it's got to go.
We might as well be nice and civil about it, mightn't we?
That bungalow in Cedar District. In your name, right?
Why?
Do I have to tell you?
There's been an awful nasty mess out there.
Someone has got himself shot in your living room.
- And who are you two?
- Jamie McCrimmon
- And?
- Victoria Waterfield
- What's the matter, can't you speak?
- Don't shout at me.
Oh, very good, the outraged public citizen. Do they know who I am?
Yes they do.
A pity, I like to hear you say it.
Now listen to this, all of you.
One of your men was murdered in a bungalow rented to you.
The remains of two others were found in what was left of a helicopter.
You were in that bungalow at the time.
And there were three other people with you, two youngsters and a man. Right?
Now, there was another man, wasn't there?
So we'll deal with that first? Where is he?
Why hello Bruce, what are you doing here, huh?