You've done very well so far, Fedorin.
It's nothing but a blackmail.
Blackmail? What have I threaten you with? Nothing!
No, but you would if I refused.
Fedorin, I keep on telling you,
this is just a form of comprehensive insurance, hm?
There's nothing for you to worry about.
My dear man, I've done nothing
but praise you ever since we first met.
I said you should be European Controller.
I said I would support you.
You've found out things about me,
lies that would damage me.
On the contrary, I am doing you a good turn.
I am actually suppressing facts about you.
- Lies, I tell you!
- Lies... Truth... Who knows?
But we wouldn't like to put them to the test, would we?
There.
What's this?
Used in the right way, at the right time,
it can dictate your own future
and the future of Alexander Denes.
Poison?
I want you to take a message...
- McCrimmon! What are you doing dressed like this?
- Leader's orders.
Now that you're here, I've got some questions
I want to ask you.
I have better things to do, thank you.
I want to know what Salamander and Giles Kent
were discussing
- when I saw you last time?
- It's not for me to tell you that.
I am concerned of Salamander's safety.
Giles Kent is supposed to be his bitter enemy.
If Salamander wishes you to know that,
I dare say he'll tell you himself.
You'll get no confidential out of me.
Listen. You must go away from here.
Don't get caught up in Salamander's world.
Why? What do you mean?
You sound as if you don't like him.
- Like him? I ...
- Oh, hello there.
Finish writing those menus.
- Did you hear that?
- Aye. Work on her.
I have a feeling she can tell us something about Salamander.
All right. As soon as I can.
What have you been doing?
I managed to slip out
and tell Astrid everything that's happened.
- You might have told me, Jamie!
- There wasn't time.
- She's trying to get Denes away.
- And take him to the Doctor?
- He'd believe Denes.
- Aye, he would.
How can she get in?
Salamander's got guards are everywhere.
She's got friends here.
They're going to arrange passes...
- and the right sort of uniform.
- What sort of uniform?
I don't know. Messenger delivery
or something. Ssh!
Controller Denes has been arrested.
I can't make up my mind whether Fedorin
is to be regarded as a new Controller or not.
The burden of office is heavy, my friend.
I remember when I was...
Alright. They've gone.
Astrid and Giles Kent were quite right.
Salamander IS an evil man.
- I can somehow sense it from all the people here.
- He's bad, all right.
He's had Denes arrested,
and has Fedorin eating out of his hand.
Why should he do that?
Remove the honest man, and put a weaker man in his place
but somehow have a hold on him,
That way Salamander can take over the territory.
I see - when everything's in a turmoil
because of the earthquakes.
Aye, and that's lucky to say the least.
But you don't really believe that Salamander
could cause earthquakes, do you?
I'm certain Salamander's causing the earthquakes, Doctor
and I'm sure your friends Jamie and Victoria
will tell you how bad he really is.
But why make earthquakes?
Years ago, when one country wanted to invade another,
it set about attacking the confidence of that country,
throwing it into confusion, making it weak.
Then it was right for take over.
Now, isn't that exactly what's happening here,
only in a different way?
What you're saying is that Salamander has found a way...
...to harness the natural forces of the Earth.
That's a little difficult to accept.
I'm not saying it's impossible, mind you.
You say it's coming from the research station.
Salamander's research station, eh?
That's what I believe, in spite of...
Ssh! Wait a minute.
In spite of a number of reasons,
he invented the sun-store, a brilliant advance.
He found a way of directing conserved energy
to areas starved of sun.
- What made you suspicious?
- The money he was spending ast the Research Station
The materials involved, the food stores.
It didn't make sense.
- I had all the papers, all the requisition orders.
- But that's valuable evidence!
All destroyed, and new ones appeared...
I was made out to be the criminal!
All by suggestion, of course. I was discredited.
I couldn't do it, Salamander. I couldn't do it.
I stood there with this man's life in my hands.
This powder - I couldn't use it.
I gave you the chance
to become something. Somebody.
- You failed to take it, huh
- There must be some other way.
Of course, my friend. Don't worry.
- What?  - Don't worry.
You try, you fail - so what?
The moon doesn't fall out of the sky!
Come and sit down. Have a drink, huh?
Cheer up. We'll find another way.
I really did try.
Of course you did.
Don't worry.
Forget it, huh?
I have an alternative.
Your health.
I hope you will appreciate this wine.
It's made for me especially in Alaska.
One chance, my friend.
I said one chance!
Some trouble in the kitchens, Leader.
The new man says he's seen
someone in the kitchen gardens.
Very well. Oh, see to that, will you?
Suicide, of course. Such a pity.
- I can't see anything.
- Over there by the trees!
He's armed, too. Get down!
I'm going out there. Stay down here.
When the rest of the guards come,
send them after me.
Yes, all right.
Astrid's going to get you away.
An attempt has been made to rescue this man.
Take him out to the car.
I'm sorry, Janos.
Stop!
After them! Arrest that girl!
Well, we all seem to be here,
except the third member of your escape committee.
- What are you talking about?
- You were seen speaking with a girl in the park.
The one who tried to escape with Denes.
We don't know anything about that.
We don't even know her.
A diversion was caused.
There was no one outside the kitchen.
Of course there was someone, and there was shooting.
Three shots have been fired from this gun.
It's yours, isn't it?
Pretending to save my life was ingenious,
but ingenuity requires a constant stream of new ideas.
Yours seem to have dried up.
I come to the Central Zone.
An attempt is made on my life.
Denes proves to be a traitor.
Fedorin commits suicide because I uncover him.
Do your job, Bruce.
You can see they're all in this.
All right. Take them away.
Take your hands off me!
Salamander, I think you should tell me what's going on.
One minute I see you with this lad McCrimmon,
- you're working together. The next minute...
- I thought he saved my life.
No, I mean before that. In Kent's office.
- What are you talking about?
- Well I saw you there.
But I haven't seen Kent in months.
Yes, you were with Kent, Fariah and the youngsters.
I thought it was so curious,
I spoke to your number two, Benik, about it.
- That's really the reason I came to this zone.
- But I tell you...
I must get back to the research centre.
You will come with me.
It was you!
Or someone... like you?