Hello Bruce, what are you doing here, eh?
I was under the impression
you were in the Central European Zone, Leader.
That's what you were meant to believe.
Why?
I do not care to be questioned by my own security!
Well that's just it. How can I possibly
maintain security when you behave like this?
I'm at least entitled to know your movements.
You have a policeman's mind, Bruce.
That may be! Only a few days ago you questioned me
about this man and his activities.
And we agreed that he was dangerous!
Now, I find you in his office.
Sometimes I like to deal with matters in my own way.
- They're not holding you here?  - Holding me?
Under some threat or other.
No one threatens Salamander!
I still think I deserve an explanation, Leader.
Yes, of course, you shall have it.
But not now. When I return from the Central European Zone.
Very well.
Now what about the dead man found in your bungalow.
He was one of your lot, wasn't he?
Yes. Um, he was trying to protect me.
The other two wanted to kill me.
Now why should they want to do that
to a nice young girl like you?
Well I...
Obviously they thought I was there.
You?
Yes, Bruce, just like you,
a lot of people don't like me.
Don't get clever with me, Kent!
I've a good mind to...
I am prepared to accept his story.
Well I'm not!
That's interesting, but not important.
I accept it! That's all that matters.
It's beginning to look as if these people
are working for you now. Is that right?
You still dare to question me!
They have information! I shall get it!
I will see you on my return. Now leave me!
- McCrimmon, you said?  - Aye
Well you just watch your step, that's all.
I never said a word.
Must be the way you look, Jamie.
You were splendid, Doctor.
Thank you.
That was a dangerous game to play.
It paid off. All right, are you with us?
I don't know where you stand, Mr Kent.
But you and this Salamander are obviously
on opposite sides. That at least is clear.
But which side is good? Which side is bad?
And why should I interfere?
Well you're the only man who can help save the world.
But isn't that what Salamander's trying to do?
Don't you understand? Salamander...
Just a moment. Jamie, you're unusually quiet,
what do you think?
Well to save the world,
aye, well it sounds grand, but...
Oh, we couldn't turn our back
on a challenge like this, Doctor.
Well, at least I know you wouldn't.
We don't know anything about these people.
Astrid saved our lives.
She was wounded because of it.
- Oh but Jamie, you don't think...
- Look, she was...
Look, we're right about Salamander!
It won't take you long to find out for yourselves.
How do you propose we do that?
He'll be well guarded for a start.
We can hardly steal into his study
and go through his papers.
That man, Bruce, said that
he was in the Central European Zone.
It's a long way from Australia.
It's only two hours by rocket.
You could leave almost at once.
- Oh, what then?  - I've had a plan ...
... for infiltrating into Salamander's
inner circle for some time.
Well I could adapt it for your two friends.
I can arrange three travel warrants and visas.
Everything you need.
Just three?
Well one for Astrid, one for you and ah...
- Victoria.  - Of course.
Oh that's very clever of you.
How can you do that?
I thought you said you had no official position?
We have a contact there.
He must be a very important person.
He is. Denes, Controller of the Zone.
Oh, I see. What about me?
I think we better have a look at
Salamander's research station at Kanowa.
Yes. Ah, yes, but from a safe distance of course.
This is dreadful news, Salamander.
I still can't believe it.
Terrible, terrible.
I don't say it will happen.
I say it can happen.
Your Zone is in danger, Denes.
Here, here and here.
We've had no trouble for years in those mountains.
You don't imagine I make it up?
No, no, of course not.
Those volcanoes have been dead
since sixteenth century. Fedorin is right to doubt.
A volcano is a strange thing, my friend.
I tell you the truth.
It's like a man in the hot sun,
sleeping... still... lifeless.
Then boom! He wakes full of energy!
I know volcanoes.
Isn't there a possibility of a...
miscalculation for a few degrees?
I'm never wrong.
Every one of my predictions has been accurate.
Yes. You're record is good. I don't deny that.
You are too kind. Now will you listen to me!
Leader, the communications...
I know! I know! I told you I was not to be disturbed!
Yes, Leader.
No, wait! No, wait, Fariah, ah?
- You like some refreshment, perhaps?
- Thank you.
No, no, not for me.
You're going so soon?
I must consult my scientific advisors.
You still don't believe me?
I believe you sufficiently to want to...
have your information checked.
Before I alarm my people unnecessarily.
Your scientists won't help you.
They don't know. They are amateurs.
No, Salamander, they are not amateurs.
They are very clever men dedicated to their work.
But they are men, capable of human error like anybody else.
Do what you wish.
Captain!
Sir!
Controller Denes is leaving.
Yes, sir.
You will soon see that I am right.
Oh, you will stay, ah? Have a drink.
We have a great deal to talk about, you and I.
Fariah, see to him.
That might be her now. Yes.
Hello, Giles? This is me, Astrid.
Right let‘s have it. What's happening?
Everything's gone fine so far.
And the rocket arrived right on time in Hungary.
And Jamie's got his entrance pass
and has started phase one.
- Do you think the boy can handle it?
- Well I hope so.
My goodness they're a pretty
odd lot though, aren't they?
Well actually the Doctor's with me right now.
Oh, I am sorry. Oh I know...
I'm sure they'll be fine.
What news of Denes? We must keep him posted
as to what is happening.
It's all right, we've contacted
and we've arranged to meet.
Be careful, he's pretty well known.
But what on earth made you
take a job as a food taster?
She was hungry.
Only thing is, now she has all the food she needs,
...she has lost her appetite.
Give me a drink!
You are well protected.
Um.
Very well protected.
Be calm. Sit down, drink your drink.
Ah!
Thank you for calling the guard.
I was wondering what to do about him.
Now don't move for that box!
Not if you value your life.
Now all of you, back over there! That's it.
Not as well protected as you think you are, eh?
Now when I say duck... Duck, get down!
Look at this! What do you do boys, eh?
Read? Sleep? It's a fine thing.
Here we have an attempt to destroy me
and where are you?
It's not so good, boys.
It's not so good. I'm watching you.
Look after him. Better still, get rid of him.
- What's all this about. Eh?
- I heard two men talking.
They said they'd planted a bomb of some kind
in your radio telephone.
I tried to warn them at the gates,
but they wouldn't pay any attention.
So you break in? How you break in?
Well I'm here on holiday with a friend.
She's very pretty, so the guard
didn't see me slip past him.
Why didn't you call out and warn me?
I nearly used the radio telephone several times.
Ah you'd have had me shot, most like.
Why do you risk your skin to save me?
Well without you
the Earth hasn't much of a chance, has it?
You like to work for me, eh? You like that?
Oh no, you don't have to do that.
I mean, you owe me nothing.
You're quite right, boy.
And I'm on holiday.
You won't find what I pay you disappointing.
Aye, there's my girlfriend too though.
Oh we might be able to find something for her.
Eh Fariah?
Yes, your chef could use an assistant.
See to it. What do you say, eh?
Well I'll give it a go.
But I'll say this though,
your security system's rotten.
There'll have to be changes.
Oh what a boy, ah?
Fariah, see he gets some proper uniform
instead of this skirt.
And bring him and his girlfriend to see me.
Come along then.
What an extraordinary young man.
I prize loyalty very highly, my friend.
And I repay it very generously.
Like I do the girl Fariah, eh.
I used to love to do this sort of thing when I was a boy.
I'm sorry. It was the safest place I could think of.
Oh, it's all right. I'm still fit enough.
Thank you for getting me the necessary documents.
Have you been successful?
So far. Salamander's swallowed it.
I thought he would.
The boy's very confident.
The girl, not so much.
See, the point is that I'm near enough
to him to pick out something.
This was the first time I met Salamander.
I must say that you were right about him, Astrid.
We must get rid of him. He must be stopped.
He will be stopped!
I'm returning to Giles Kent.
Can you wait till we can take action?
Oh, with a bit of luck, yes.
Fedorin, would he betray you in some way?
I'm trying to think of some reason why he should.
But these are all lies, Salamander. Lies, I assure you.
So you say.
What are you going to do? My family... my friends.
My dear man. My dear Fedorin.
You don't suppose I intend to
make your swindling public, eh?
This is... this just an insurance, um.
Sit down, forget it.
I tell you what I'm going to do for you.
What?
You are going to replace Denes
as controller of this Zone.
But, don't say anything.
I'll know you'll accept.
What do you want?
I'll tell you. There will be disaster in this Zone.
I cannot stop the disaster,
but I can come to the aid of this Zone
when it's happened.
And take over? I see.
- The Zone would be yours!
- Oh ours, Fedorin, ours.
It's a partnership I'm offering you.
Either you have half of everything, or you have nothing.
But there's Alexander Denes.
Oh yes, the popular, well beloved Denes.
- What a pity.  - Pity?
Oh didn't I tell you, Denes is going to die.
Mysteriously... an assassin... terrible.
I can't do that! You can't ask me!
I think I can ask you to do anything I want.
My predictions are accurate!
The entire Eperjes-Tokaj Ranges are in eruption!
Fedorin, come and look. It's very pretty.
The history of Hungary is about to be rewritten!
Salamander.
What are you doing here, Bruce?
I had a report there was trouble here,
an attempt on your life.
It was nothing. Come and look.
Terrible. Those poor people.
Salamander! What have you done?
I warned you!
You couldn't have known!
You've done this somehow yourself!
The man is mad! Worse still he is incompetent!
I warned this man that this zone
was in danger of natural disaster...
...and he did nothing!
Issued no cautions to the public.
You deliberately allowed your people to suffer and die!
You're a traitor!
You're a traitor! You contrived this for your own ends.
Bruce, I order you to arrest this man.
But this is nonsense. Fedorin, you were here.
You know this is nonsense.
Denes you are too naive.
At your trial, Fedorin will be
the chief witness against you!