Sincro: wyxchari
What the...?
Day of the Daleks
(Whopix fan edit)
Doctor, why don't you take a break?
It's maddening, you know. So nearly there.
If I could only cut out their override
on the dematerialisation circuit.
Let me see those figures.
Doctor?
I thought the TARDIS was working again.
What gave you that idea?
Oh, being dragged off to an alien planet
five hundred years in the future, for example.
Oh, you know - all that business
with the miners and the colonists.
My dear Jo, the TARDIS was being operated then under
remote control by the High Council of the Time Lords.
Well, if it worked for them...
I don't want it to work for them.
I want it to work for me.
No-one's going to turn me into
an interplanetary puppet.
Yes, of course. Why didn't I think of that before?
Yes, of course. I remember now.
Look, don't worry, my dear. I know you're alarmed but you needn't be.
Yes, well I think that should do it. Why on Earth I never realised that...
Oh no! What are you doing here?
Well, I'm not here. Don't worry.
Well, that is, in a sense, er, I am here,
but, erm, you are not there.
Er... yes, well, it's a bit difficult
to explain really.
This won't do at all!
We can't have two of us running about.
Yes, well don't worry. It will all sor...
Doctor! What happened?
Well, it's a very complicated thing - time - Jo.
Once you've begun tampering with it,
the oddest things start happening.
But there was another you and another... me.
Well, where've they gone?
Back into their own time stream, of course.
Or do I mean forward?
But, Doctor, I don't understand...
Look, Jo. Don't worry about it. It was a freak
affect. It's very unlikely to happen again.
Hold that and give me those papers.
Ah, Doctor. Glad you're still here.
I need your help.
Sorry, Brigadier. I'm busy.
Yeah, so am I, Doctor, so am I. Now then,
you've heard of Sir Reginald Styles?
No, can't say that I have.
Well isn't he the chief representative at the UN?
That's right - key figure at the latest
summit conference.
My dear chap, I'm a scientist. Not a politician.
You know, Doctor, if you... didn't spend so much time
tinkering around with this wretched contraption,
you'd realise just how bad
the international situation's become.
Humans are always squabbling over something, Brigadier.
Yes, well, this particular squabble looks like
ending up in a third world war.
The Chinese delegation have refused to attend.
Without them, the conference can't even begin.
Now Styles is flying to Peking in a few hours.
There's just a chance that he can persuade them to change their minds.
All right, Brigadier. So what's his problem?
Well, he was working late last night,
down at Auderly...
Where's that?
Auderly, Miss Grant, is a Government owned country house
about fifty miles north of London where the conference is due to be held.
Oh.
He suddenly started behaving... rather oddly.
Seemed to think that someone was trying to assassinate him.
Any idea who?
Some sort of "ghost" apparently.
He said somebody attacked him and vanished.
And you're absolutely certain that he used the word "ghost"?
Oh yes. But afterwards he...
Miss Paget! What's going on here?!
These people are from UNIT, sir.
Who asked them to come here?
I did - because of what happened yesterday.
Nothing happened yesterday.
There seems to have been some sort of incident,
Sir Reginald?
Nothing of any importance.
Well, if you could tell us what happened?
I was working late. I must have dropped off.
Freak gust of wind, blew some papers off my desk,
I woke up rather confused,
I was picking up the papers when Miss Paget came in.
But you did mention ghosts.
Did I? Must have been having a nightmare.
But the French windows were shut. I closed them before I went to bed.
Then I must have opened them!
Did you, er, did you also make
those marks on the floor over there?
Muddy feet, Sir Reginald. Someone was in here, you know.
Are you accusing me of lying, sir?!
Sir Reginald, you've obviously been under considerable
strain recently. Were you feeling at all unwell last night?
I felt, and feel, perfectly well.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I've a lot to do.
I'm due at the airport in an hour.
You've no objection to my men searching the grounds?
None at all. Though I really don't know
what you hope to find.
Sergeant!
Ah, he's in a bad way, poor chap.
You'd better get him to the hospital.
Captain Yates...
Right away, sir.
This is a new one on me.
What do you make of it, Doctor?
I'm not sure...
Sir?
What've you got there, Benton?
No idea, sir.
It was hidden about fifty feet inside the tunnel.
Have you seen this before?
Really Brigadier! What sort of games are you playing?
It's not a game, sir. It's our duty to protect you!
I don't need your protection!
Sir Reginald, we've just found a very severely
injured man down by the canal tunnel.
Oh really? And what did he look like?
Thirty-fiveish, average build. He was wearing
a sort of guerilla combat suit.
And carrying that gun.
I am very sorry, gentlemen, but I have rather more important
things on my mind at the moment. If you'll excuse me?
I've arranged an escort to take you to the airport, sir.
Thank you, but it shouldn't be necessary.
I'm sorry, sir, but I think it will!
Oh, if you insist.
I'd like to get that gun down to the laboratory
and run a few tests on it.
Well, basically it's a form of ultra-sonic disintegrator.
You mean a ray gun?
That's right, Jo, I mean a ray gun.
Only it's far more sophisticated than any weapon
yet invented on Earth. Now take a look at this.
Quite an effective little weapon, eh?
Doctor, you say this wasn't made on Earth.
Do you mean it comes from another planet?
Well that was my theory at first, yes.
But the metallurgical analysis shows that the,
er, iron constituent is very much of this world.
In fact, it was mined not very far from here - North Wales.
How do you explain that?
Do you believe in ghosts, Brigadier?
Let's be serious, Doctor.
I am.
Oh, come along, Doctor, come along.
Oh, my mistake. I was forgetting
the unimaginative nature of the military mind.
But we saw a couple of "Amicus Seperatus"
a few moments ago, didn't we, Jo?
Did we?
Yes, here in this laboratory.
Oh, you mean when we...
Mind you, they were manifestations
of a much more benevolent kind.
None of your clanking chains and chilly fingers!
But ghosts, none the less.
That was because you were playing around
with the time mechanism on the TARDIS, wasn't it?
Still can't get it to work, eh?
Well, I can't get this thing to work, either.
But this is a form of, er, of time machine of a very crude kind.
How do you know?
Come over here. Look at this.
Now what do you think that is?
Ooh, it's a... mini-dematerialisation circuit.
Top of the class, Jo.
Now then, pop this in here, like that.
Now, as far as I can gather,
when you push this button, it should...
Good grief! It's working!
Sir?
What is it?
Time transmitter in operation, sir.
Twentieth Century Zone.
Can you fix the space-time coordinates?
Do be careful, Doctor!
All right, Jo, all right.
Well?
No good, sir. There was a transference,
I think, but the machine's cut out completely.
Continue scanning - and next time
you had better be more efficient!
Report!
Yes, I see. All right, sergeant.  You'd better
report back to Captain Yates. Goodbye.
That was Benton. He was in the ambulance
with the man we found.
Well?
Well according to him, that man just...
vanished, faded away - like a ghost.
Oh no!
Well, Doctor, what now?
Well, everything that happens seems to
centre round Styles' house.
Obviously.
And whoever tried to harm him will probably try again.
Jo, how would you like to spend the night
in a haunted house?
Wake up, Jo.
It's all right. It's morning.
Nothing's happened?
No, nothing at all.
Jo! Jo!
Please! Turn that machine off
- or they'll kill all of us! Please!
Sir?
Yes?
We've picked up that time transmitter again.
You're sure?
Yes, sir. Same frequency, same time...
time zone. Much stronger now.
Right. I want the exact space-time co-ordinates
so whatever happens, don't lose it!
What is your report?
We have a fix on the time transfer device.
It is operating again in the twentieth century
time zone and it must be them.
You have obtained the space-time co-ordinates?
We're trying now. The trace is much stronger
this time. There is every chance...
You must not fail!
Security forces are standing by. If we do get
the co-ordinates, what are your instructions?
Whoever is operating the time machine
is an enemy of the Daleks.
All enemies of the Daleks must be destroyed!
Exterminate them!
Let him go.
Now then - turn off that machine.
I have to report that we have lost the trace.
It was operating only a few moments.
We are not interested in excuses.
Find them! Find them! Find them!
No last words of repentance, Sir Reginald?
No, only that you're making one fundamental mistake...
That is?
A question of mistaken identity.
I am not Sir Reginald Styles.
Is that the best you can do?
But it's true! Sir Reginald...
Sir Reginald is at this moment many thousands of miles away - in Peking, to be precise.
You are lying.
No, I'm not. He flew there yesterday.
I do not believe you.
It's all there in the paper in front of you. Why don't you take a look?
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
It's a trick - kill him now!
If you are not Sir Reginald Styles who are you and what are you doing in his house?
Well, believe it or believe it not, I came here to see you.
We're wasting time, Anat. Here, I'll do it.
Who is in command of this mission?!
We are soldiers, not murderers. Keep guard outside, I'll deal with these two.
I said out!
Now then, answer my question - who are you and what are you doing here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
- Why?
To find out where you came from.
And more to the point - when.
Two soldiers approach.
Hide!
Down there!
Hurry!
Captain Yates, sir, on four.
I can't speak to him now.
He says something very odd is happening at Auderly House.
If you could have a quick word with him, sir?
All right.
Yes, what is it, Yates?
A couple of my men missing, sir, and the Doctor
and Miss Grant - not a sign of them.
Look really, Yates, I've got a major international
crisis on. I really haven't got time for any...
Oh, Lethbridge-Stewart?
Erm, yes, yes, that's right?
Yes, it's the Minister here.
One moment, sir. Listen, Yates, search the grounds
again or report back to me - out!
Yes, Minister?
Right, they're clear of the house. Have you finished?
- Yes.
- We must go.
Quietly!
Oh, that's better.
You know, I've got a good mind to let you
stay like that! So much more peaceful.
In any case, even if I released you,
you'll probably ask me a lot of fool questions!
I've only got one question - who are they?
On the face of it, three rather desperate people.
Well, they're criminals - they must be!
Ah, you're prejudiced.
Well, aren't you? They tried to kill you and me.
That's not in their favour, I'll admit.
You know, we shouldn't really judge 'em
until we find out why they're here.
We are maintaining constant watch, but there is
no sign of any time transference module in operation.
All criminal elements must be tracked down and destroyed.
Well, I am doing everything possible, but...
They will have returned to the time zone
where the first criminal was eliminated.
You will dispatch security forces to search for them.
Of course... at once.
And the new equipment?
The Time Vortex Magnetron is set to the frequency
of the module that was traced.
Anyone using that module will be diverted
in the space-time vortex and attracted here.
But only if that particular module is used?
It is necessary to know the frequency.
But surely no one will use the module?
They must realise that we can trace them...
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
The function of the human is to obey!
Activate the Magnetron!
...to base. Intercept to base.
Do you coordinate? Do you coordinate? Intercept...
No good. There is a massive disturbance in the vortex.
We cannot fail again. This is our last chance.
We must get fresh orders.
The time coordinates are crucial.
We cannot wait for new orders!
Look, why don't I return to the tunnel?
There's better chance of contact there.
Right, Shura. Ask them...
Why ask them anything? Isn't it obvious what we must do?
We wait here and kill Styles.
And if we are detected?
We hold those two as hostages.
We kill them if necessary.
Get alternative orders.
Right.
What do you mean, missing?
Well, there's not a sign of them.
We searched the house and the grounds, sir.
The Doctor, Jo and a couple of my men - vanished.
Now listen, Yates, I've been talking to the Minister.
Styles seems to have pulled it off.
The Chinese have agreed to attend
and the conference is on again.
Oh, when's it fixed for?
Tomorrow night, so you see the spot this puts me in!
Get me Auderly House!
Where is he?
I told you, Anat.
I just don't understand. I mean,
why don't they go back to September 12th
if that's where they want to be -
you know, have another go.
Well, that's the Blinovitch limitation effect.
The what?
On your feet, both of you!
Honestly, sir. You're wasting your time -
he's not there.
Hello? Hello?
Doctor?
Yes?
Lethbridge-Stewart.
Ah.
Is everything all right there?
Yes fine, Brigadier. Yes, things couldn't be better.
Yates and Benton came to look for you.
Said the place was deserted.
Did they? Oh yes, we were probably
down the cellar at the time.
Old Styles keeps a remarkably
good selection of wines, you know.
Now listen, Doctor, you're sure that
everything is normal down at that house?
Because Styles is coming back there tomorrow night.
Look, I... I don't think that's very wise, Brigadier...
Well, why not if everything's all right?
It is all right, isn't it, Doctor?
Captain Yates was very concerned about you.
Well, you tell Captain Yates not to worry, everything's fine.
And tell old Styles too, and the Prime Minister.
Right.
Oh, and Brigadier?
Yes?
Don't forget to tell it to the marines. Goodbye.
There you are, sir. I said there was something wrong.
I'm going down to that house myself.
Lay on a jeep for me, will you?
I'll meet you there later.
He's coming! Sir Reginald Styles is coming here.
Well that surprises you? Well, I should have thought
with your insight into the future...
oh no, in your case, it'd be the past, wouldn't it?
The conference tomorrow night -
our dates were right after all.
All we have to do is to wait here
until he returns and then...
Right! Drop your guns! If you don't,
I'll smash this to pieces.
Jo, put that thing down.
I've only just got it in working order.
I mean it.
Stupid child! You do not know what you are doing!
Oh yes I do - you're going to let us both out
- or you'll be stranded here for ever.
We don't need that machine. We have another one.
The man who owned that machine is dead.
His body is back in our time zone.
You're... bluffing.
Put it down and don't be silly!
Jo, do as she says.
Drop it... drop it!
Jo! Jo!
Look, can't you do anything?
No, it's too late.
Well, what... what's happened to her?
Disintegrated, dispersed around the time vortex.
If she was lucky.
And if she wasn't?
Re-embodied in the twenty-second century.
Believe me, she would be better off dead.
You may go.
You see, they're really not as terrifying as they look.
What are they?
Ogrons. They're a form of higher anthropoid.
They used to live in scattered communities
on one of the outer planets.
They make very useful servants.
Servants? Well, what do they do?
Oh, we use them as... policemen.
They're very simple, very honest, very loyal.
Do please sit down.
Thank you.
Is this really the... twenty-second century?
Oh, don't worry. We can return you to
your own time, but, er, tell me Miss, erm?
Grant, Jo Grant.
Miss Grant... these three people
who attacked you - what did you make of them?
Well, they were sort of... guerillas, I suppose.
They are cruel and ruthless fanatics.
You know who they are?
Unfortunately, yes. But what you don't know,
is how lucky you are
that they didn't get rid of you straight away.
They tried to kill the Doctor.
He's still with them, is he - this friend of yours?
Yes, they're holding him prisoner.
Then I am afraid he is in very grave danger.
But they've no reason to harm him!
They know he's the wrong man!
You don't know these people!
We have spent years trying to track them down.
If you knew some of the terrifying crimes
they have been capable of!
If anyone stands in their way, they are without mercy.
I can believe it.
However, there is a chance that
I may be able to save your friend.
Could you?!
I can try. There are means but I shall need your help.
Well, how can I help?
Well, first of all, I shall want to know exactly
where you came from... and when.
Well, we were at Sir Reginald Styles' house,
about... fifty miles from London.
Now, you've told me the year,
can you tell me the exact date?
That's easy - it was September the 13th.
Excellent.
Now, you must be tired, you must be hungry.
We do have special guest rooms.
Leave everything to me.
Oh, there is one last question...
these criminals - can you tell me exactly
where they entered your time?
I mean, did they manifest themselves in the house itself?
I don't think so.
Somewhere outside the house - some hiding place?
I don't know for sure, but there's a tunnel
by a canal, not far from the house.
We found that... time machine there.
A tunnel? Thank you.
I'll call you as soon as we have any news.
You see? She trusts me implicitly.
The criminals are using the tunnel as a transfer point.
We will prepare an ambush in the twentieth-century time zone.
We have security forces in the area. With any luck,
they will drive the guerillas straight into our hands.
Anat! Look!
Shoot!
Pull back!
We can get through the library. Come!
Stay where you are! Boaz, get out!
Boaz, come on!
Come on, Boaz, out! Out, out!
How do you do?
Doctor, what on earth's going on?
Thank you, Brigadier, for that timely intervention.
Who is that creature.
Yes, well, I'll explain about him later.
Excuse me, old chap, I'm in a hurry.
Get back! Get back!
Please! Wait! I've got to talk to you!
Keep away!
Exterminate!
_ or you'll be caught in the time field!
We warned you.
Yes, yes, so you did.
This may come as a shock to you, but you've just
travelled two hundred years through time.
Thank you. But I'm probably more familiar
with the concept of time travel than you are.
Now wait a minute. Before the time transference,
I saw a Dalek.
You know of the Daleks?
Indeed I do. I know them only too well.
They've been my bitterest enemy for many years.
Then you're a fool to have let yourself be brought here!
Look, I came here in order to find Miss Jo Grant.
I told you, she's probably dead.
But as long as there's a chance...
Come on, Anat.
Wait a minute - what is my best way of finding her?
That's your problem.
We can't just leave him!
I can - come!
Run, Doctor - run!
Report!
The security guards have combed the tunnels.
They've found nothing.
You have failed the Daleks! You will be punished!
The fault is not mine! Your security guards let them get away.
- Those creatures are useless!
- They are loyal to the Daleks.
As loyal as they are stupid!
They will never be a match for human guerillas.
No one can succeed who opposes the Daleks.
For every guerilla cell that you destroy,
another one springs up.
They have stolen your time machines and copied them.
They steal your weapons, your explosives.
These criminals will be exterminated.
The Daleks will destroy them.
If only you would let me
recruit more human security guards...
Humans are treacherous and unreliable!
Not all humans. I have served you faithfully.
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
Obey without question!
Very well. There was one... curious thing.
The girl referred to a companion in her own time zone.
She called him... "the Doctor".
Doctor?! Did you say "Doctor"?!
He appears to have got through to our time.
He was seen by the guards.
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks!
He must be found at once and exterminated!
Don't gloss over it, Anat, we failed!
We had no choice once our plan was known to them.
If you'd listened to me, we still could have done what was needed.
We did all we could!
Monia, our orders were to eliminate Styles, right?
Yes, but you failed.
We could have succeeded.
Then why didn't you?
He wasn't there! Security guards found us.
But Anat went soft.
Be quiet.
The trouble with you, Boaz is...
Both of you! We have to think now.
The situation is different.
As I see it, it's exactly the same -
we still have a job to do.
No. There may be other ways.
I've had a report from one of our contacts.
A girl has been captured.
They're holding her prisoner at the control centre.
The same girl - the one who operated
the time module at Styles' house?
It fits your description.
Well, at least she's alive.
In the hands of the Daleks? She won't live long.
Can she tell them anything?
Nothing of importance.
Have they picked up that Doctor yet?
Not yet. It's only a matter of time.
Move! Move! Come along there, you scum!
Move! Come along there, move! Move! Go on!
Well?
Been captured. Taken for processing.
We must rescue him.
Rescue him? Are you mad?! From there?
I say we must!
Suicide.
Are you afraid?
Me? Of course I am. I'm not a fool.
What is he to us?
We have fresh information from
one of our contacts at control centre.
He is the sworn enemy of the Daleks.
He is the one man they're afraid of - don't you see?
It's our only hope. If we don't act quickly,
it may be too late.
You are the Doctor! You are an enemy of the Daleks!
Now you are in our power! You will be exterminated!
You will be exterminated! You will be exterminated!
Stop! You mustn't kill him!
- Be silent.
- Don't you realise he can help us?
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks.
How can he help us?
He is our contact with the guerrillas.
He has valuable information.
- You have proof of this?
- I know he's working for them.
We will force the truth from him
with the mind analysis machine.
But look at him!
You've practically killed him just
getting a simple admission of identity.
He'll die before
he tells you anything else.
What is your plan?
Let me interrogate him.
Why should you be more successful?
Because I understand human psychology.
I shall be able to gain his confidence.
To put pressure on him through the girl.
By the time I have finished with him,
I shall be able to crush the guerrilla
organisation entirely!
Release him.
Now, the control centre is here.
As far as we know, they're being held
prisoner in this block here.
And how do we get through?
The disused underground railway of the old city.
There's an exit right by this wall.
I know the Doctor
would help you if he could.
I am trying to help him!
I've already saved his life.
Yes, for your own purposes.
Look, if you do not tell me where they operate from,
what their plans are,
then the Daleks will destroy both of you.
I don't doubt it.
Do you value life so little?
On the contrary, I value it enormously.
The Daleks will kill us whatever we tell you.
Not if you cooperate with them.
As you cooperate with them?
Do you really think that makes any difference?
- They can be reasonable!
- Reasonable?
They tolerate you as long as you're useful to them.
I am a senior government official.
You, sir, you, sir, are a traitor!
You're a Quisling!
You do not understand!
We have helped make things better for the others.
We have gained concessions. I have saved lives!
Wouldn't you have helped more
by organising the fight against them?
No one can fight against the Daleks.
That's not what your criminal guerrillas
seem to think, is it?
A handful of fanatics?
Most of them have been killed already.
I assure you, there is nothing
they can do to change things.
- Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
- Anat, look out!
Come! We must reach the control centre, come!
No! Come! Come!
For the last time, I tell you
I haven't got any information.
And quite frankly, even if I had,
I wouldn't give it to you!
- Right, stay where you are!
- Guards!
Guards? You have no guards. They're all dead.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, thank you.
- All the better for seeing you.
- You're coming with us.
No harm must come to these two.
Too much depends on them.
- As for you, my friend...
- Put that gun down!
There's no point in murdering him.
You don't know how much
blood there is on his hands.
Nevertheless, he's not your real enemy.
He's helped the Daleks. He's worked for them!
They would always have found someone.
Now, just leave him.
Right, let's go.
- But how do you know this?
- Oh, there are books.
Even during the wars, people found time
to study, to write about it.
What to you has not yet happened
is to us history.
This history of yours,
it talks about Sir Reginald Styles?
Oh, yeah, he pretended to be working for peace,
but really he just wanted power for himself.
So the conference he called was just a trick?
He managed to lure the world leaders to
a remote country house
and he pretended they needed absolute
quiet if the meeting was to succeed.
But then, there was a devastating explosion...
And Styles was killed with the others.
He must have set a bomb and mistimed the charge.
There were accusations, counter-accusations,
and then the wars began. That was the turning point.
But if this true, Sir Reginald Styles
must be completely round the bend!
Er, so, you went back into our time
to kill Styles before he could carry out his plan?
Right. We've been fighting the Daleks for years.
But it was hopeless.
Eventually we must lose, so we thought,
what else can we do?
We learnt through one of our spies
that the Daleks had succeeded
in creating a time machine.
We even managed to steal a copy of
the plans, and we built one of our own,
so that we could go back into history
to the exact point
where things started to go wrong.
With one action, we could stop them.
Mankind could have a chance
to take a new direction!
But even now, the transfer isn't always stable.
People materialised in your time
and then just faded away.
The ghost that Styles saw?
Somehow, somehow the Daleks
found what we were doing.
And they sent Ogrons back into your time
after us and attacked one of our men.
Well, that must have been the man
that we saw down by the canal tunnel.
You remember, Jo, the one who vanished
from the ambulance?
Yes, we fixed on the tunnel
as a place that was stable in your time and in ours.
We used it as a transfer point.
Well, you know the rest.
Yes, well there's... There's one thing
I don't quite understand and that is
why were you so keen to rescue us?
And believe me, we're grateful, but...
Well, you told us yourself,
you're an old enemy of the Daleks.
- Yes?
- Then you will help us to beat them.
What do you expect me to do?
Well, you can succeed where we've failed, Doctor.
We want you to go back into your
own time and kill Styles.
You're asking me to commit murder!
No! We're asking you to kill one man
and prevent millions more dying.
- That is still murder.
- Isn't it worth it?
- To save the human race from the Daleks?
- Yes, but would it?
We've told you how it happened.
But your history could be wrong, you know.
Now, listen, why don't you
send us back to our time?
We know the future now,
maybe there are other things we can do?
Monia, we're wasting valuable time!
Every minute that goes by...
Doctor, will you help us? It's our only hope.
I still can't believe that Sir Reginald
Styles is a ruthless murderer.
Yes, I agree, Jo.
Vain to the point of arrogance,
a trifle obstinate, perhaps,
but basically a good man.
So, if it happened, how did it happen?
Any of your people
still in our time zone?
- No.
- Well, Shura.
He left just to send a message and we
never saw nor heard from him again.
We assumed he must be dead.
Look, please believe me,
I'm completely with you about the ends.
I only disagree as to the means.
All right. What do you want to know?
This mission of yours to the 20th
century, what did you take with you?
The usual battle gear, radio, disintegrators...
- Any sabotage equipment?
- Only a few charges of Dalekenium.
Dalekenium?
It's a highly effective type of explosive.
We stole the formula from the Daleks.
- Could it destroy a house?
- What are you trying to say, Doctor?
Well, don't you see? This has happened before!
What has?
You went back to change history,
but you didn't change anything,
you became a part of it.
What are you talking about?
If Styles didn't cause that explosion,
somebody else did.
Well, obviously, but who...
Shura!
Isn't that exactly what he would have done?
One last suicidal attempt to carry out his orders?
It's possible, I suppose.
You're trapped in a temporal paradox!
Styles didn't cause that explosion
and start the wars,
you did it yourselves!
You have failed the Daleks.
The Doctor has escaped.
He will be recaptured. I swear it!
He must be found and destroyed.
He will attempt to return to his own time zone.
If those guerrillas are helping
him, they will use the tunnel
and I am setting up an ambush.
If you fail us again,
you will pay with your life.
This is your final chance.
I will go and supervise the operations myself.
Is everything ready?
Security forces have covered the whole tunnel.
Don't worry, they won't escape a second time.
So it has ended as I said it would.
Did I not tell you it was madness
to fight the Daleks?
Is it madness to want to see a world
free from their rule?
- It can't be done.
- Oh, yes it can.
And I can do it. Are you going to stop me?
Go. I will deal with these criminals myself.
I said go!
If only I could be sure.
You spoke of the war,
of its years of suffering and starvation.
Well, I can prevent all that happening, you know.
You saved my life. You could have let them kill me.
- Go, quickly.
- Thank you.
Jo, come here and stand by me.
Sergeant! They're here!
This is Sergeant Benton calling UNIT HQ.
Look, we've found them.
Will you get a Jeep over here pronto?
This way, Doctor.
I am sorry. They were too quick for us.
They escaped in the darkness.
You are lying You have betrayed the Daleks.
No! I told you before,
those security guards
are no match for humans.
You are a traitor to the Daleks.
You must be exterminated!
Who knows? I may have helped to exterminate you!
You have proved yourself worthy
to be the new Controller,
but be warned, the Daleks demand total loyalty
from those who serve them.
Of course.
We must follow them into
the 20th century time zone.
The peace conference must be destroyed.
War must break out.
The Dalek conquest of the planet Earth
must not be reversed!
Look, you're supposed to be in charge of security.
Kindly get on with your job
and leave me to get on with mine.
Brigadier! Brigadier,
get everybody out of this house at once!
Where the devil have you been?
Never mind all that.
Just clear this house immediately!
What's the man talking about?
Do as he says! Look, there isn't much time!
Locate and destroy the peace conference.
Exterminate!
Destroy the human resistance!
Eliminate all humans!
Exterminate!
Brigadier, get this man and all the
delegates out of this area immediately.
Use force if you have to!
Jo, you stay here.
- Sir Reginald, please?
- No, I will not permit it!
Shura!
Get out of here unless you want to die too!
I must kill Styles to prevent the war!
Shura, listen to me.
Styles and all the delegates
are already leaving this house.
You detonate that bomb and you'll be
sacrificing yourself for nothing.
Benton calling UNIT HQ,
we just can't hold them, sir!
Look, Benton, keep them back
as long as you can.
Sir Reginald, this house is under attack
by a hostile force.
You will please consider yourself
under my orders.
- Brigadier, I warn you...
- Now be quiet, sir!
- Captain Yates?
- Sir.
Get Sir Reginald and all the delegates
away from this area at once.
Locate and destroy the peace conference!
Doctor! The Daleks, they're coming into the house!
- Daleks? You're lying!
- No, she's not.
They've come back to make sure that
their version of history isn't changed.
- Is everybody out of the house?
- Yes, everyone but us.
Get out of here. Let them come in!
Leave them to me!
- No, no! You must come with us!
- You don't understand!
That's Dalekenium. It's the only thing
that's effective against the Daleks.
Well, couldn't we set a time fuse?
No, this stuff's too unstable.
There just isn't time.
This is something that I must do myself.
Now, get out!
- Very well.
- Out!
Greyhound to Trap One,
do you read me? Over. Greyhound to...
Tell your men to fall back.
Let the Daleks into the house.
Doctor, are you sure that...
It may not make military sense
but it's the only way.
All right. Brigadier to all units.
Let them pass! I say again, let them pass!
Re-group on the main road, out!
Exterminate!
Eliminate all humans. Exterminate!
The human delegates are inside the house.
Enter and destroy.
- Where are the delegates?
- Where is the man Styles?
They must be found and exterminated!
Oh, no, not this time.
This time it's going to be different!
Well, what happened?
Your conference has been saved, Sir Reginald.
Now it's up to you and your friends
to make sure it's a success.
- You still have a choice.
- Don't worry.
We all know what will happen if we fail.
So do we. We've seen it happen, haven't we, Jo?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)