(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963)
The Dominators
(Whopix fan edit)
(Based on English subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
Is the local radiation completely absorbed?
Yes, its energy's been transferred to our fuel reserves.
- But we need much more.
- Of course. That is why we are here.
With respect, Navigator Rago,
I still consider we should have continued to Epsilon 4.
I decided otherwise, Probationer Toba.
But this planet has never been fully surveyed.
It's suitable for our purpose.
The planetary crust is thin here
and there's an intelligent form of life
suitable for a workforce.
But the natives may not be suitable for slave labour.
Suppose they're hostile?
- If necessary, we shall destroy them.
- Yes, destroy them.
But only if necessary!
Commence work on the preliminary survey.
Command accepted.
(WHOOSHING)
(LAUGHING)
Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
(YAWNING)
- Are you still feeling tired, Doctor?
- Yes, just a little bit weary, Jamie.
It's a very exhausting business
projecting all those mental images, you know.
- You need a good rest, Doctor.
- Yes, we all do. A nice holiday.
Where did you say this place was again?
Well, the scanner screen in the Tardis
showed it as an island of some sort
surrounded by a sea of mist.
Yes, it's an island on Dulkis,
a perfectly splendid planet.
I've heard that one before.
And there won't be any Cybermen or Daleks, will there?
(LAUGHS) No, no, no, of course not.
There's nothing unpleasant on Dulkis.
Quarks, destroy the alien vessel.
(QUARKS BEEPING)
(BUZZING)
Did you say these people were peaceful, Doctor?
(STUTTERING) Oh, yes, Zoe,
the Dulcians are gentle and friendly.
Aye, it sounded like it!
- Did the explosion cause this?
- Oh, no, no, no.
This was caused by an explosion some time ago, Jamie.
Looks like atomic blast damage to me.
Yes, I think you're right, Zoe.
But I don't understand it.
Let's look inside, shall we?
Mind the stuff here.
And you destroyed this travel ship?
You gave me no order to the contrary.
You are a probational navigator.
Your first task is to investigate. Second, assess.
You allowed your instinct for destruction
- to interfere with your primary tasks.
- Not accepted. I did...
How can you assess that which does not exist?
Have you completed your atomic analysis?
Analysis complete.
Atomic energy released on this island 17.2 decades ago.
A long time. Strange that this should be
the only trace of radiation on this planet.
Continue.
Drilling sites have now been located and marked.
Then we will examine them.
Did you check the radiation level
before we left the Tardis?
That's just what I was thinking, Zoe.
I think I did.
- Yes, I'm sure I did.
- Hey, what are you two on about?
Well, I was just thinking.
This place reminds me
of the old atom test islands on Earth.
Yes. Yes, I think you're right, Zoe.
- Test islands?  - For atomic weapons, Jamie.
But why on Dulkis?
They've outlawed war.
No, there must be some other explanation.
Well, I vote we go back to the Tardis
and find somewhere else.
Doctor!
TOBA: This is the eastern drilling site.
- What is that?
- Just a crude, box-like structure.
Shall I summon the Quarks to destroy it?
Why? Will it interfere with the work?
No, but...
Then it would be wasteful to destroy it.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
- Oh, my beautiful coat is all wet.
- Ridiculous.
All this is totally unnecessary, you know.
There's not a trace of contamination on us.
Yes, so I've noticed. It's odd, isn't it?
- What's odd about it?
- Well, the whole island is radioactive.
It has been for 172 years. You must know that.
- Well, it isn't now.  - Of course it is.
- Have you checked?  - TEEL: Well, not yet.
We've only just arrived.
But we're taking the annual readings
during the next few days.
Well, if I were you, I'd take them now.
Oh, my beautiful trousers.
I wasn't aware that anyone else
had permission to work on the island except ourselves.
Tell me exactly what has been happening.
But I was hoping you were going to tell us that.
This is an atom test island, isn't it?
Oh, but of course. Everybody knows that.
Oh, well, we don't.
But atomic weapons on Dulkis?
- I thought war had been abolished here.
- It has.
You seem to know surprisingly little
about your own planet.
Well, that's it, you see.
We've just come in the Tar...
Well, as Jamie was about to say,
we come from a different world, from a different time.
Not from this world? Really, that's very interesting.
I must note that in my daily report.
Well, you don't sound very surprised.
Well, it does explain how you came to
expose yourself to the dangers on this island.
No Dulcian would do such a foolish thing.
Well, what are you doing here, then?
We're part of Educator Balan's
expedition from the university.
But when I was here some time ago,
you were a peaceful race.
- So you've been here before?
- Well, yes.
Ah, I must put that in my...
I'm so sorry. You were saying?
Well, what's happened to you? I thought
aggressive weapons had been abolished.
Oh, indeed they have.
The second council under Director Olvin.
He banned the manufacture of all weapons.
Then what are you doing letting off
atomic devices all over the place?
Oh! Oh, there was only one explosion.
Perhaps my pupil, Kando, should explain.
Let's see how much you remember, my dear.
- Um... Oh, yes.  - The seventh council...
The seventh council under Director Manus
initiated research which lead to
the development of atomic energy.
- The des...
- BALAN: Destructive capabilities.
The destructive capabilities of this
were immediately apparent and...
BALAN: This island...
And this island was used
to test an explosive device,
the results of which can be seen today.
Thereafter, all further research
into this type of energy was prohibited,
and the island kept as both a museum
and warning for future generations.
Oh, well, she certainly does her homework.
I see. Then this is an atomic test site?
Oh, yes. You see, students...
That was really very good, Kando.
Students are brought here
to test the radiation level
and observe the effect on the vegetation.
And of course, to see for themselves
the horrors of atomic destruction.
- So there should be radioactivity here?
- But there isn't.
No. I wonder why?
Explain.
Part of this collection of crude weapons.
Continue.
This one operates on the early laser principle.
Fire mechanism here.
Self-charging power cell. Limited range.
Is this all you notice?
The other weapons are just as simple.
There's nothing here that could threaten us.
- These things are so old that if...
- Precisely. Old.
At last, you casually mention a fact
of major significance.
Has it not occurred to you,
Probationer Toba,
that other weapons
must have been developed since these?
Agreed, Navigator Rago.
DOCTOR: But why do you think
we might be responsible? Thank you.
Well, it is conceivable that your craft, the...
- Tardis.  -...Tardis,
could have attracted the radioactivity
in much the same way as a magnet attracts metal.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, it would have registered.
- Do spacecraft often land in Dulkis?
- As far as I know, you are the first.
I must say, then,
you don't seem the least bit surprised.
We are taught to accept fact,
it being foolish to contemplate fantasy
in the face of reality.
You are here. This is fact.
That you come from another planet I accept,
because I have no other means of proving it.
- TEEL: Not a sign of radiation.
- BALAN: There.
But look what I found.
- Cully, what are you...
- Never mind that now.
We've got to get back to the capital.
Oh, it's impossible.
We haven't even begun our survey yet.
Well, if you don't, you'll be wiped out.
He claims to have seen robots and spacecraft.
- You didn't tell me you brought robots.
- I haven't.
Look, I brought three people here in my ship.
They've been killed by those creatures.
So if you don't...
(LAUGHING)
- ZOE: What's so funny?
- Now, I see. Ajest.
Three people. So you come
from another world, do you, Doctor?
- Hey, I don't think...
- Really, Cully,
you and your friends might at least
have agreed upon the same story.
What? But these aren't my three, you old...
Oh, what's the use?
- JAMIE: What was he talking about?
- I don't know.
Look, I've never seen
this gentleman before in my life.
Cully, you had no right to bring
these people here without permission,
even if you are the son
of the director of the council.
Well, go on, then.
Why don't you call him up?
At least he's not as stupid as you are.
- You say you've seen a spacecraft?
- I've told you, haven't I?
And robots. Well, at least I think
they were robots.
What exactly did this spacecraft look like?
Well, it's large and circular
and a sort of silvery colour.
That means it can't be the Tardis.
Are you sure it wasn't square,
like a large wooden box?
No, no, that's not the spacecraft.
No, the box is where
those aliens have made a sort of mark,
a five-pointed star.
They were examining it just now.
Talking about destroying it.
- What?  - What?
- Jamie, we better go and see.
- Come on.
You're wasting your time.
I prefer to make up my own mind, thank you.
Jamie. Are you coming, Zoe?
- No, I think I'll stay here.  - Right.
- Come on, then.
- We shan't be a minute.
Commence work on preparing the sites
of the outer bore hole.
- At once, Navigator Rago.
- Send this message to Fleet Leader.
"Materials located. Detailed report follows."
Command accepted.
JAMIE: At least they haven't harmed the Tardis.
DOCTOR: That's a relief.
Jamie, come and have a look at this.
It's interesting.
- Look. See. - What?
What's so interesting about that?
Well, I think it must be
some sort of survey mark.
Very likely.
Jamie, look.
- Some sort of tracks.  - So they are.
We'll follow them, shall we?
Oh, look, I think we'd better get back.
Zoe will be wondering what's happening...
Well, this is interesting. Yes.
Obviously an interstellar spaceship
of considerably advanced design.
Oh, no. You're not thinking
what I think you're thinking, are you?
That, I think, Jamie, depends
on what you think I am thinking.
Oh.
- Hey, Doctor. - Stop that, Jamie.
- Doctor. - Jamie, don't do it.
- Doctor, look. Look.  - Oh, my word.
QUARK: Do not move. Do not move.
Next task?
Shall we destroy?
Oh, good heavens!
Look, what's going on? Who are you?
We are Dominators.
Both of you stand by that wall.
- I will not.
- Oh, now, Jamie...
- Oh, no. They're not going to...
- We're meant to be obeyed.
- Not by me, you're not.
- DOCTOR: Jamie!
What... All right, if you insist.
(WARBLING)
Doctor, I can't move. Help me!
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
It is pointless to struggle.
My Quarks have used a molecular force
to bind your bodies to the wall.
What's he going to do with us?
Alien races are occasionally of use to us.
I intend to probe your physiological makeup.
Do what?
- Doctor, can you not do anything?
- Don't struggle, Jamie. Keep still.
Toba. Quarks, attach force units.
- Activate. -(WARBLING)
RAGO: Visor.
Transmatter focus probe.
fixme
Brittle skeletal structure.
Reasonable flexibility.
Certain amount of muscular force,
could be marginally useful.
- Vulnerable, only one heart.
- TOBA: Intelligence?
A simple brain. Signs of recent rapid learning.
Still, somewhat crude.
Shall I prepare the other specimen for scrutiny?
No, they will be identical.
Conserve power.
- TOBA: Are they dangerous?
- No, they are physically inferior.
- So we destroy them?  - No.
- It is possible we may use them.
- What for?
- Workforce.  - We've got the Quarks.
We must conserve their power, you know that.
But why do you want...
Command accepted.
Set up a reaction test.
Test this one.
As soon as your friends return,
they will follow you and Cully
in the second capsule.
Wouldn't it be better
if all four of us went together?
- Travel capsules only take two.
- Number one ready.
There's nothing to be afraid of, you know.
Oh, I'm not frightened.
I'm looking forward to it.
Come on, let's try and stir up
a bit of action in the capital.
You really mustn't believe
Cully's wild tales.
(DOOR HUMMING)
I will dial for the capital, Cully,
if you don't mind.
I see. Frightened I might disappear, eh?
Well, it has been known, hasn't it, Cully?
It'd be a joke if it happened
this time, though, wouldn't it?
And if we are to use these Dulcians as slaves,
there are certain qualities you must look for.
Obedience, strength, sufficient intelligence
to make them of use,
but not so much as to make them dangerous.
Is that clear?
Yes.
Uh, what are they saying?
I think they are arranging
for some sort of test.
- Test? What for?  - I don't know.
I thought I heard them
mention the word "intelligence".
Oh, you mean they're going to
find out how clever we are?
Yes. Or how stupid.
I wonder which is the more important to them?
Well, then, Zoe, what were you doing on the island?
Well, nothing, really, just looking around.
- But didn't you know it was dangerous?
- No. At least not at first.
Oh, Cully, how can your conscience allow you
to expose innocent and foolish people
to such dangers?
- But I didn't take her to the island.
- Oh, nonsense.
I know all about Cully's Adventures Unlimited.
- You know, but why didn't you...
- Well, you weren't doing any harm.
- At least we thought you weren't.
- But it's illegal.
To prosecute would have given you open publicity
and it wouldn't have reflected very well on me, either.
I see. Why can't I be treated as an individual
and not always as the son of the Director?
Now then, young lady, tell me exactly what happened.
Well, I landed with the Doctor and Jamie.
- In Cully's ship, yes?  - Cully?
- Oh, no. We came in the Tardis.
- And what is that?
- It's an advanced craft for travel.
- Goes through time and space.
I think this joke has gone far enough.
There you are, I knew he wouldn't believe it.
But it's true! You can ask the Doctor and Jamie,
they'll be here soon.
What do you hope to gain by this foolishness?
But it's not. I told you when
we spoke on the vision link.
Three people have been killed,
a spacecraft has landed,
radioactivity has disappeared
and there are robots on that island.
Now, I may have a pretty inventive mind,
but I wouldn't have dreamt up
that lot, now, would I?
And no doubt you will confirm all this?
Uh, well, I haven't actually seen
the spacecraft and robots...
Oh, so it seems we only have
your word for it, Cully.
And experience has taught us
how little that can be relied upon.
What's he up to now?
He's arranging some sort of
intelligence test, Jamie.
JAMIE: You mean those wee shapes
in that big box? What for?
Yes, well, we'll have to put
the right shapes into the correct holes,
it's quite simple.
Well, if that's all it is,
a kid of two could do it.
Yes, that's what bothering me.
It's too simple.
You moved.
I'm free. What about you?
- Me, too.  - Come on.
(QUARK BEEPING)
TOBA: Well?
QUARK: Molecular force expended.
Order required.
-Are the specimens to be refused?
-No.
- What are you going to do with us?
- Quiet! Over there.
Sit.
Well, thank you.
Attach force units.
(HUMMING)
Hands. Through there.
Power.
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
That will be repeated at regular intervals
until the puzzle is reassembled.
(WHIMPERING) Oh, no!
Begin.
(GRUNTS)
JAMIE: Hurry up, Doctor.
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
DOCTOR: Oh, my hands!
JAMIE: No, the square bit...
- DOCTOR: What?
- JAMIE: No, not the star,
the square bit in there!
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Detach.
Doctor. Doctor.
Now, where's that...
Here. Take it. Sniff, sniff.
-(DOCTOR COUGHING)
-That's it.
Come away. Come away
from that fearful contraption.
- You all right?  - Yes, I'm all right.
What were you up to? That puzzle was easy.
An unintelligent enemy is far less dangerous
than an intelligent one, Jamie.
- Hey?  - Just act stupid.
- Do you think you can manage that?
- Oh, aye, it's easy...
Attach force units.
You two, over here. Sit!
- Oh, thank you.  - Thank you. Oh.
Power.
Now, get off.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING, DOCTOR YELLING)
- I said, get off. - Oh, but...
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING, BOTH EXCLAIMING)
- Try it round here.  - You're surrounded.
- Well, how do we get off?
- There is a way, find it!
- Test complete?
- TOBA: These creatures are useless.
- Strange.  - You question my report, Navigator Rago?
I find it at variance with what we already know.
- I don't understand.
- The weapons we saw earlier,
could they have been devised by such apparent simpletons?
- You think that there were...
- That we will find out.
Message to fleet leader.
"Materials readily accessible, please proceed to refuel.
"Investigating potential slave labour." Transmit.
(DEVICE BEEPS) Come with me.
- But every time we try and get up...
- Jump!
DOCTOR: Jump?
Jump.
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
A simple circuit completed by your bodies,
you obviously know little of electricity.
Elec... Elec...
Are you such a fool?
You have intelligent eyes.
I will continue the test personally.
- RAGO: I said, what is that?
- Well, it's some sort of gun, isn't it?
- Explain it to me.
- Well, I don't know that I...
- Firepower potential?  - Huh?
- What does it do?  - Oh! Oh, I see.
Well, guns kill people.
- Is that what you wanted to know?  - Fire it.
Well, I don't think...
You have to put something into it first
and it comes out here,
as far as I remember.
You. Fire it.
- Oh, I wouldn't know how...
- Do as Dominator Rago says. Fire it!
(STAMMERING) Well, I'll try. Um...
I think you put a cork
or something in...in there...
Jamie. Jamie, be careful.
- I'll get the hang of it, Doctor.
- Jamie, be careful.
Wait, we don't understand guns on Dulkis.
We haven't used them for hundreds of years.
So,
you don't understand guns.
(EXCLAIMING)
Are you sure?
Yes! It was the clever ones who invented them.
- The clever ones?  - Yes, they...
They lived long ago, you see.
There aren't many of them left.
They stopped us using guns and things.
- There are two distinct types on this planet?
- Yes!
How many of these clever ones are there?
Well, there are not many.
We don't like them much.
- They tell us what to do, you see.  - Good.
I see.
There is nothing to fear from these primitives,
and the others sound as if they're pacifists.
So they are useless.
They have a small labour potential, nothing more.
- Shall I destroy them?
- No, we must conserve power.
- But why do...
- We have nothing to fear from such creatures
It will be a waste of energy to destroy them.
Leave them!
Stay away from us and the Quarks.
- Oh, yes, sir. Thank you very much.
- Yes, Master.
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
- Am I glad that's over.
- Yeah, me, too.
They're a bloodthirsty lot,
these Dominators, aren't they?
Aye. What do you think they're after?
I don't know.
That message they sent.
"Material readily accessible."
Some sort of mineral deposits, do you think?
Then this fleet of theirs would refuel,
land and pick it up. It makes sense.
What do they want the Dulcians
as slaves for? They've got the Quarks.
Aye, nasty little beasties.
Hey, Doctor, they've gone.
We'd better get back to that survey place,
Zoe will be wondering what's happened to us.
I think you're right.
I've got to make them believe me,
before it's too late.
- Well, what are you going to do?
- Get some evidence.
Will you come back to the island with me?
All right. But how do we get past
the council out there?
Through my father's rooms. Come on.
We'll have to steal a travel capsule somehow.
Well, I can manage that all right, but...
- Well, what's the matter?  - Your clothes.
- Not exactly Dulcian, are they?  - So?
We'll attract too much attention.
We'll never get past the capsule managers.
Still, no problem.
We can always fix you up
with some Dulcian garments.
- Where from? - Clothing dispenser unit.
There's one in my father's rooms. Come on.
This will take you direct to the capital, Doctor.
Your young friend Zoe is already there.
And no doubt Director Senex
is awaiting your arrival now.
- Oh, this is splendid. (CHUCKLES)
- Hey, Doctor, what is this?
You know I hate being put in a remote...
Now, perhaps we can get on with our work.
QUARK: Unknown creatures approaching.
-TOBA: Destroy?  - No.
Investigate.
- It's enormous.  - So Cully was telling the truth.
- BALAN: Was he?  - TEEL: But Balan...
Where are the robots?
Inside, perhaps?
But it's empty.
Look, there's a map of the island.
QUARK: Stand still.
But you are not Dulcians!
Where do you think everybody is?
Destroy.
Destroy!
(QUARKS WARBLING)
- Cully, what's happening?  - I don't know.
- ZOE: Oh!  - CULLY: The door. Quick!
Stuck. It's stuck.
We're trapped.
Recharge.
(QUARKS HUMMING)
Complete destruction.
Maybe you'll believe in my robots now.
I don't know about robots,
but something was attacking us,
and with pretty sophisticated weapons, too.
Well, whatever it was,
we'd better get out of here fast.
Let's try and move this door.
Unnecessary destruction is wasteful.
Did you inspect it?
All relevant details have been recorded.
See if there are any survivors
and bring them to me.
Alive.
- Come on! Keep it... - Oh!
From your reaction
and your lack of knowledge
of the way of life on Dulkis,
it would seem there is some truth in your story
that you're from another planet.
Of course there's some truth!
Look, it was your people who thought
we were friends of Cully's.
The identity of my son's companions
can now be established,
though what has happened to them
is not quite clear.
But Cully has told you they were murdered.
And I believe him!
(COUNCILLORS MURMURING) Why?
Because I have seen these Dominators!
We were just taken aboard their spacecraft.
Believe me, they're callous, without pity!
(COUNCILLORS MURMURING)
I would be grateful if you could tell me
what occurred on the island.
Oh, look here, we've told you!
We're just wasting time talking
while Zoe's in danger!
Can't we get away?
Oh, we wouldn't stand a chance.
These Quarks are deadly.
- Any idea how they're powered?  - No. Why?
Well, if we knew, we might be able
to put them out of action.
Attack them? Are you out of your mind?
Well, they're only robots.
"Only"?
Do you really think we could destroy one?
It'd be easier if we had a gun of some...
- The laser gun!  - Eh?
Cully, I think we stand a chance.
TOBA: Take them to the others.
QUARK: Move.
I'll set them to work on the drilling site.
Work potential and stamina
to be recorded and sent for analysis.
Agreed. If any of them should escape...
Then you will report the fact to me,
no personal action.
(SHOUTS) Toba!
Command accepted.
Hey, would you look down there?
That's the ruined building. Hello.
What can you see?
- JAMIE: It's Zoe and Cully!
- We've got to get down there!
Jamie, we'll split up
and get round the back of them.
- I'll cut across those cliffs.
- I'll go this way.
- Ready?  - Yes.
Once you're inside, give me time to
get the two Quarks into your line of fire.
Here we go.
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
This one collapsed.
Join the other specimens.
This is foolishness, Cully.
All clear.
Best of luck.
What do you think you're doing?
Zoe's out there!
I know that, you fool,
I was aiming at those Quarks.
QUARK: All specimens stand up!
TOBA: What are you doing?
You were told to keep away from the Quarks.
Oh, but I do.
Whenever I see one, I go away.
But they're all over the island,
where can I go?
Stop! One of them is missing.
The man Cully has escaped.
Has he?
It's no good, Jamie.
We daren't wait any longer.
Something must have happened to the Doctor.
I think you're right.
- TOBA: Cully! - Down!
I told you to stay away from the window.
- Do you think he saw me?
- TOBA: I know you're in there, Cully!
Give me that.
Now you'll see what happens when
the orders of a Dominator are disobeyed!
Quark, destroy!
(WARBLING)
Right. Here goes.
(LASER GUN FIRING)
(WARBLING INCOHERENTLY)
Destroy! Destroy!
(QUARKS WARBLING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
- Let's get out of here.
- CULLY: No! This way.
Stop.
QUARK: On the orders of Dominator Toba,
the building was destroyed,
also the man Cully.
- But Jamie was in that building!
- Silence!
You deliberately disobeyed my order?
My life was threatened
and the Quark destroyed.
Yes, because of your own actions.
Are you suggesting
I should have let him escape?
And where would he have gone?
We are on an island, Toba.
These creatures cannot escape.
Now listen to me carefully,
and this time you will obey my instructions.
Send these creatures back
to the central bore position.
I want it cleared, ready for drilling.
But the Quarks will do it more quickly.
We must conserve their energy
for drilling purposes.
You know the power levels are low.
Hey, Cully, would you look who's here?
Any Quarks?
- CULLY: Yes, one.  - JAMIE: Hmm.
CULLY: No, there's more. Can't quite see,
but I think they're working at something
just outside the building.
JAMIE: Let's have a look.
They don't seem to have harmed anybody.
Well, Balan isn't there.
He's probably working somewhere else.
- Look, Cully...  - What now?
We can't just let them stay up there, can we?
- Well, what can we do?
- Get them down here with us.
- But what about the Quarks?  - Well, we'll...
Here we go again.
- Operate! -(WHIRRING)
- Doctor? - Hmm?
What are they doing?
They're drilling.
Well, yes, I know that, but what for?
Hmm?
I don't think they want to take
anything out of the Earth, Zoe,
rather put something into it.
- Well, what?  - Well, if I'm right...
Oh, no!
(MOUTHING)
(QUARK BLEEPING)
Excuse me...
QUARK: Do not move!
Oh!
(QUARK ALARM BUZZING)
- Right, Cully!  - Quick, follow me!
- Don't just stand there, go on!  - Quick!
Cease drilling!
A Quark is being attacked! Follow!
Quarks, search and destroy!
Quark, where are the prisoners?
QUARK: Out of action.
No recorded data.
They can't be far away. They must be hiding.
Quarks, search and destroy!
Command countermanded!
Why has the drilling stopped again, Toba?
The prisoners have attacked
a Quark and escaped!
And once again you've dropped
everything to hunt them!
I have just completed calculating
the remaining power levels of the Quark force.
Thanks to your foolish actions,
they are dangerously low!
All efforts must now be concentrated
on completing our mission.
And if they attack us again?
The Quark's power must be conserved.
Complete the drilling operation!
Command accepted.
Toba, the primitives will not go unpunished.
Fleet Leader has just confirmed
the Dulcians are unsuitable for slave labour.
They will die with their planet.
Good.
So the sooner we complete the drilling operations,
the sooner they will die.
Quark, follow!
(QUARK BLEEPING)
They've gone.
That was very rash of you, Jamie.
Those Quarks are appallingly dangerous.
Och, they're not so terrible.
You know, we dropped a rock on one earlier.
Hey, where's Balan? Why wasn't he...
He's dead, Cully. The Dominators killed him.
Oh, no! If only we'd managed to get him away, too.
You did your best, Cully.
It's thanks to you and Jamie
that the rest of us are safe.
DOCTOR: I'm afraid not.
Nowhere on the island is safe.
Nowhere on the entire planet, come to that!
You see, we heard the Dominators say
that the Dulcians were unsuitable of slave labour.
- But then they'll leave us in peace!
- Well, no.
They said you'll all die with your planet.
Surely they don't mean to destroy Dulkis completely?
- DOCTOR: I'm afraid they do.
- But why? What do they want?
A large amount of fuel for their invasion fleet.
But we know that there are no minerals worth having,
at least not on this side of the island.
They're not mining for minerals
or any natural fuel source.
But their spaceships use atomic power.
We've established that.
But there was no reactor in that ship of theirs,
only a radiation storage unit.
You remember how when they landed
it sucked up all the radioactive dust
from the island?
Yes. So you're saying
that they store radioactive particles
and then convert that energy into power.
Exactly!
Well, then why are they drilling?
Look, I'll show you.
There are four drill holes
here, here, here and here,
and one drill hole in the centre.
Now, then, they have rockets mounted
in each of these drill holes,
and the centre drill hole is probably
for that atomic seed device.
Oh.
Well, don't you see?
They've chosen this spot because
the crust of the planet is thin.
They're going to fire the rockets through the crust
into the magma, the molten core.
ZOE: Then that will almost certainly
fracture the crust of the planet.
Exactly.
But that will create a volcano.
And if they explode the atomic
seed device in the middle of that...
Yes, that's right, Zoe.
The whole planet will become one vast
molten mass of radioactive material,
the fuel store for their fleet.
Well, we'll just have to stop them, then.
DOCTOR: Oh, Jamie,
it's not as simple as that, is it?
If only I could get hold of
that atomic seed device,
I might be able to defuse it.
Yes, then there'd only be a local
volcanic eruption on the island.
- Yes... - But how can we get to the device?
Yes, that's the problem.
Doctor, I've just had an idea.
Shush a minute, Jamie, I'm trying to think.
- Yes, I know you are, but...  - Oh, Jamie!
Now, listen! Will you listen to me?
Now, there's a dead-easy way
to get that device thing.
- Really?  - Yes, now listen.
You said they were going to drop it
down the centre hole,
the one they're drilling outside here.
- Right?  - DOCTOR: Yes.
Well, it's simple, isn't it?
All we've got to do is dig a tunnel
through from here to the borehole
and catch the seed device thing on its way down!
Oh. Well, it was just an idea.
But Jamie...
It's a brilliant idea!
It's so simple,
only you could have thought of it.
Oh! Hey?
We can get the direction from the periscope.
Just line it up with the drilling site.
Yes, there's only one snag, though.
Could we complete the tunnel in time?
It'd have to be 12 feet long or more.
Well, Cully and I could delay
the Dominators' work up there.
ZOE: How?
Oh, we're getting very good
at destroying Quarks, aren't we?
Yes, certainly seems to stop them working.
DOCTOR: Yes, that's true,
but you've been lucky so far.
If only I could devise some sort of weapon for you.
- Is there anything down here, Cully?
- No, I doubt it.
Nothing but survival rations and medical kit.
Medical kit? Oh!
It's surprising what you can do
with a few simple chemicals and a little ingenuity.
Now, come on, we must dig this tunnel.
- Zoe, give us a direction, will you?  - Right.
On a line from...here.
Right! We start the tunnel there.
Get that bunk away, come on.
That's it, Cully. I'll start with a knife, now...
This line here.
I think you'd better let me start it, Jamie.
How are you going to dig through there
with your sonic screwdriver?
It's a little more than a screwdriver.
Just watch this.
(AMAZED CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
- It's burning straight through!
- Aye, the Doctor's very good.
- Have you finished?  - Yes, just completed.
Good. I shall enjoy destroying
this planet and its creatures.
Get the seed device.
We will delay no longer.
Can you see the borehole yet, Jamie?
JAMIE: The ceiling keeps caving in.
ZOE: They're coming back!
Toba's bringing the seed device.
Oh, dear.
You will recall all Quarks from their positions
and prepare the craft for takeoff.
Command accepted.
I will insert the seed device.
Prime the rockets at perimeter boreholes.
Command accepted.
Very soon we shall see this planet die,
and its creatures with it.
Shall I report to Fleet Leader?
Inform him the Dominator fleet
may approach on its refuelling orbit.
Command accepted. Quarks, follow.
(QUARKS BLEEPING)
Quickly, Doctor!
He's taking the device out of its case now.
Oh, Jamie, he'll be too late!
He's putting it in now.
- It's gone! - DOCTOR: Oh!
JAMIE: Doctor, have you caught it?
- Oh, Doctor!  - He's coming!
JAMIE: Quick, out.
Well?
(LAUGHING)
- Oh, thank goodness!
- We're saved! We're saved, then!
No, not just yet.
I've still got to defuse it
before they explode it.
- Oh! Oh, my word!  - ZOE: What?
Well, it's sealed! It's completely sealed!
I can't possibly undo it!
You mean, all that was for nothing?
We're still going to get blown up?
Yes, I'm afraid so,
unless I can think of some way
of getting it off the planet without a...
Have you thought of something?
Well, there is a way of getting it off the planet
without it doing any harm to any of us at all.
ZOE: Well, how?
Ah! But it's not going to be easy...
What? What are you going to do?
Now, just leave it to me, Jamie, hmm?
You, Zoe go back to the Tardis.
RAGO: Is all prepared?
Yes, just two more Quarks to arrive.
Start takeoff procedure.
Command accepted.
(CAPSULE BEEPING)
Oh, where is he?
The Dominators' ship, it's away!
- Oh!  - Where's the Doctor?
Doctor!
- Hey, where's the bomb thing?
- Oh, did you get rid of it?
- Well, where is it?
- (PANTING) Don't ask so many questions.
- What?  - There's no time.
(EXPLOSIONS)
What's that?
It's the rockets in the other perimeter holes.
Come along, we'd better get inside the Tardis.
There's going to be an...
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Toba!
Doctor, come on, will you?
The whole place is going to blow up!
Oh, it's quite all right, Jamie.
The planet is quite safe.
There's just going to be
a localised volcanic eruption.
It'll only affect the island.
Maybe so, but we happen to be on the island.
Isn't it beautiful!
- Oh, my word. What a wonderful sight!
- Fantastic!
Listen, will you two stop gaping at that
and get us out of here.
Don't worry, Jamie. We're safe in the Tardis.
Are you sure? Has the Tardis
ever been buried in lava before?
- No.
- How can you be so sure we're going to be all right?
Oh, dear.
- Is something wrong?
- This has happened before.
The fluid links aren't able to take the load. Oh!
(ZOE) Mercury vapour!
Oh! This darn thing's stuck! Of all the stupid, idiotic!
- Doctor, The lava's up to the Tardis!
- (ZOE) Doctor
If only I could unstick this stupid, idiotic...
There we are.
Have you done it? Are we on our way?
It's stopped the fluid links from vaporising.
We shan't suffocate.
If we don't hurry, we'll be fried by the lava.
- Isn't there any way we can get away?
- Well, there IS an emergency unit, but...
- I can't possibly use that.
- But this IS an emergency!
But it moves the Tardis out of the
time-space dimension, out of reality!
Fine. Reality's getting too hot, anyway!
Oh, all right.
Here we are.
Now, then, which end was...?
Yes...
I can't possibly use this.
We don't know what will happen.