Oh no!
I just don't understand what's happening!
Poor Travers!
Silence!
Father!
No, no! No!
But I must...
No, Anne! Don't go near him. Just... just listen to him.
I... am... the Intelligence!
Listen to me! I speak to you with this man's voice
because the time has come for you to understand my purpose.
What's he getting at?
Quiet!
What do you want?
You defeated me in Tibet, Doctor.
Yes.
Now you have fallen into the trap that I have so carefully prepared for you.
What do you want?
You! Your mind will be invaluable to me. Therefore I have invented a machine
that will drain all past knowledge and experience from your mind.
But you'll kill him!
Oh, no. He will survive, his mind unharmed - only empty
You can't - we'll fight!
That will not do. The Doctor must submit willingly.
And if I... if I do submit, what of the others?
Then the others will go free.
And my father too?
Oh, him too. I'm only using his body to communicate with you.
He didn't help you before, then?
Oh, no. I have many other human hands at my command.
And who are they?
Always questioning! Even now, you're seeking to destroy me! I see I shall have to guide your thoughts.
No, Jamie, no!
Cooperate and the child will be unharmed. You have twenty minutes to make up your mind.
Let me go, Doctor!
Jamie, don't be a fool! You don't stand a chance.
Let me go! Victoria!
Let me past, Colonel!
No. The Doctor's right. There've been enough lives wasted.
Please... my wrist... Professor!
Eh! Wait a minute!
What is it, Evans, what's the matter now?
Stand back everyone!
I thought I heard it go!
Yes, well we'd better make sure. Evans - you, myself and McCrimmon will go and search the place. Doctor, you'd better stay behind here and get on with your tinkering.
Professor, please, you're hurting me! My wrist! Professor!
Yes... yes, that should complete the circuit, good... I wonder...
There's only one way to find out.
Yes. Certainly no sound out there.
Shall we chance it, then?
Why not?
Now!
No! Back! No!
Push! Push! Push, hard as you can! Push, get your back to it! Get your back to it!
Fire door - by the stairs - go and unhitch it, and I'll try to hold this. Go on, McCrimmon!
You sure?
Yes, go on! Go on!
Alright, Colonel, come on!
Strange, it's not picking up. The Intelligence must be transmitting... I wonder why it's not working...
Aha! Success! It's going, Anne! Come along.
Oh, oh that's marvellous. I'm sorry I'm being so long - this is such a fiddling job.
Help you in a minute...
There we are. Now then...
Yes, you see, it's homing!
There we are...
Do we go on or turn back?
Let's go on.
Right.
Come on, what are you waiting for?
Hey, wait a minute!
This is Victoria's! We're on the right track!
No, don't shoot!
Is that thing on our side, then?
It is now. Stop!
Were you scared?
Eh? Oh no, no, I mean, I just got up here to get a better aim, that's all. How did you make it stop then?
Simple - I told it to.
Here - ball. Why don't you go back where you come from?
Now, pull the other one.
Oh, show him, Doctor.
Alright, I will. Move forward.
Stop... Move to the left... Stop.
There you are, how about that?
Hey, that's great! Make a smashing toy, that would.
Toy? That's a highly complex piece of equipment.
Oh, is it? Well I don't see how it's going to help us.
But it obeys our commands!
So?
Well, once we get it inside a Yeti, we'll have a powerful ally!
Inside a Yeti?
Yes, certainly. Will you help us?
You must be joking, Go near one of them things? I may be stupid, but I'm not daft...
Oh very well, Anne, I shall have to do it myself.
Oh, I'm coming with you, Doctor.
No no, it's far too dangerous.
There you are, what'd I tell you?
Not another word, I'm coming with you.
Hold it.
Staff Arnold? It can't be, we'd given you up for lost!
Easy, easy...
That's it.
Sorry about this, sir.
What happened?
I don't know. Can't remember. I were pushing the trolley through the fungus, and...
and I blacked out. I thought I were... falling. When I come to, sir, I were in the tunnels...
Where's the Doctor, sir? I met the Professor and the girl back there...
Victoria! Is she alright?
Yeti - guarding them, but... I promised I'd tell the Doctor, sir.
Right. Come on, back to HQ.
I'm going for Victoria.
Really, we'd stand a better chance if we stick together. Go ahead! Come on, Staff.
Doctor's twenty minutes' almost up.
Evans, come out from behind that board.
Oh, it's you, sir.
Where's the Doctor?
Evans!
B-b-but y-y-y-you...
Stop bleating like a Welsh baa-lamb, Evans, and answer the Colonel.
Sir?
Doctor and Miss Travers, where are they?
Gone, sir.
Gone - where?
Warren Street, I think.
Why?
After a Yeti, they said.
Have a look at the board, sir.
Warren Street.
Come on!
No, not you, Staff. Evans, make yourself useful. Get a dressing for the Staff Sergeant's head.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
We're trapped!
Give me the control box, Anne.
The control box...
Yes.
Haven't you got it, Doctor?
What! What... hold the sphere!
Oh Doctor, you must have it!
Yes...
Doctor!
Don't worry, it'll work!... It's got to work!
I know you said it only worked at short range, but for a moment...
Well, don't tell me you were worried? Would you like to hold this for me?
It's alright, it's quite safe.
Nearly out... there.
Right.
Now then - turn round!
Oh, it works! You've done it!
We've done it, you mean! Now then, with my reprogrammed sphere and your control box,
we should be able to work him over quite a distance. And put your arm down!
Now we've got a chance, Anne. Come on!
Oh, mustn't forget him. Come on, Fred, at the double!
Staff! Staff!
What is it?
What is it, Evans?
Go on, Evans lad, get out of it!