Doctor Who 1963 S05E04
The Enemy of the World
(Whopix fan edit)
(Sincro: bamanzi)
Oh, there's nothing like a dip to freshen you up.
Hey, that's a funny looking boat.
It's not a boat, it's a hovercraft.
Eh?
You're right, it is him.
What are we going to do?
A terrifying thing. It's like a sea monster.
Oh, we'll soon get a closer look, it's coming nearer.
Oh yes. Yes.
I don't think I like the look of this. Let's go.
- Why, what's the matter?  - Come on, run!
- Yeah, but...  - Don't argue, run.
Over here!
Hurry!
Incredible.
Absolutely incredible.
I'm not a specimen in a glass bowl, you know?
Ah, I'm sorry. Do sit down.
Oh, thank you.
It's just so astonishing. You are Salamander.
Do you see what I mean?
But surely you know how alike you are?
After all, Salamander is a world figure.
Well... well my friends and I, we..
we've been out of touch...
with civilisation for a while.
We're visitors, so to speak, um.
On ice shall we say.
I see. Where shall I start?
At the beginning please.
We've been subjected to a number of attacks
because I look like this Salamander of yours.
I'm not surprised. I'll show you why.
I have a video wire of Salamander,
addressing the United Zones Conference on World Food.
And meanwhile, over at the United Zones General Assembly,
from all over the world delegates are flocking in,
eager to hear the latest report from Leader Salamander.
The progress, Mr President, of the Sun Conservation
establishment at Kanowa, in the Australasian Zone is...
...I'm delighted to report highly satisfactory.
But we cannot yet guarantee good summer holidays for all.
However, we have now in orbit the Mark VII Sun Catcher...
and already we have been able to
concentrate the sun's rays into much needed areas.
The great Canadian wheat plains are safe.
And now, Mr President: Ukraine - the grain field of the planet -
an unfortunate area between Bucava and Kirovograd
devastated by the elements two short years ago.
What have I got to say to you about that?
I can tell you that on both banks of the Dnieper river
the corn is ripening in the sun!
And ten-thousand robot harvesters are moving down
to gather in fifty million tons of flour!
There's nothing there to say he's a bad man.
I quite agree, Victoria.
He seems to be a public benefactor.
Quite a speaker too and remarkably handsome,
didn't you think so Jamie?
He's one of the most popular men on the planet.
Many people call him the shopkeeper of the world.
The saviour, in fact, some of them.
Well what's he saved the world from?
Starvation - too many people, too little food.
Until Salamander invented his Sun Store.
Surely you've heard? You must know?
Oh yes, well of course we've heard something.
The Sun Store collects the rays from the sun
and stores them in concentrated form.
Oh, like the ioniser, Doctor?
Yes, a rather different principle I think, Jamie.
Well never mind how it works! What's it for?
Salamander can force-grow three,
sometimes four, crops in one summer.
Well why do these men want to kill him.
I mean, one minute you say he's saving the world, the next...
For his own ends! Step by step
he's taking control of this planet.
You have proof of this?
Some, yes. I was once a high official
in the World Zone Authority
Deputy Security Leader for North Africa and Europe,
but Salamander discredited and ruined me
because he realized I was beginning to get suspicious.
But you could be making up stories about Salamander!
Out of revenge.
Yes, I suppose so. Then you can judge for yourself.
You remember Michael Assevski -
he was Controller of the Eastern European Zone?
He was drowned at sea a mile from shore.
(s/Shockingly/Hockingham,/) murdered!
All of them were seen with Salamander,
or a man known as his deputy
shortly before their deaths.
All of them were replaced by men
known to be in Salamander's power.
- Known by who?   - By me, Doctor.
Well why don't you tell the authorities,
the police or whatever?
Because I'm discredited, don't you see?
Because Salamander is so popular,
and also because the man that took my place,
a man named Donald Bruce...
...has since risen to become overall security chief.
Surely there is someone you can take your story to?
Ah yes, Helvig believed me.
So did Assevski, and they're dead.
However, there is one other man,
a man named Alexander Denes,
but none of them will do anything until it's too late!
I'm surprised.
Well if Salamander is everything you say he is,
then why hasn't he tried to...
- Dispose of me?  - Yes
Well he has, but he's afraid.
You see, the testimony of a dead man
still holds legal weight.
Oh, I see. Well, it seems we have a problem on our hands...
...whether to believe Mr Kent or not.
Well there is one way that you can find out for yourselves.
Oh, how?
Impersonate Salamander.
Yes I thought that's what we were leading up to.
Well I must admit, Doctor, you do look like him.
Exactly like him.
Yes, there's more to it than that. What about the voice?
Well it's nearly the same pitch, only the accent.
Only the accent! My dear young lady.
Oh dear. Now what was it he said...
We still cannot guarantee good summer holidays for all.
No. Guarantee... no, no, no... guaran... guarantee.
You see, it's very difficult.
Hmm, of course I always was interested in phonetics
Holidays... summer... summer.
He must have come from Mexico,
Quintana Roo or Yucatan or somewhere...
That's incredible, Doctor, he was born at Merida,
state capital of Yucatan.
Yes, there are other very strong influences though.
Oh, I could do it in time.
But what if I did it, what then?
You could walk into Salamander's research station at Kanowa,
find out how he's getting control of the separate
World Zones, and then bring out absolute proof.
Yes. I see.
How long did you say it would take you
to master Salamander's accent?
I didn't. It would take three weeks, perhaps four.
Well while we've been talking,
the Security Chief I told you about,
Donald Bruce, has since cordoned off this entire area.
He's coming here himself...Now!
I'd say you've got about two minutes, Doctor.
But that's out of the question!
You know what he'll do as soon as he sees you,/?
a man who resembles Salamander so closely?
- Oh that's not fair!
- Will you please listen!
You'll be under arrest for impersonation
as soon as he sees you. I mean it.
But isn't there another way out of this?
Only one - be Salamander.
But the clothes!
Yes, there are some in here.
A little less eccentric, but do the best you can.
I won't! I can't!
Your friends, Doctor, do you want them to suffer?
Because they will, you know.
No, wait a minute! Why is a man like Bruce coming here?
Don't push me, there isn't time.
You sent for him, didn't you? You tipped him off!
I couldn't miss an opportunity like this,
now please come on.
Giles, for heaven's sake, what have you done?
It's far too risky.
Hello Kent. Doing some recruiting are you?
A bit young for killers, aren't they?
What do you mean?
All right, what do you mean by stepping in here like this?
Anytime, Kent. I've got the right and you know it.
Anytime I like.
All right, what do you want?
That's better, you're ex-security,
you know the way it's got to go.
We might as well be nice and civil about it, mightn't we?
That bungalow in Cedar District. In your name, right?
Why?
Do I have to tell you?
There's been an awful nasty mess out there.
Someone has got himself shot in your living room.
- And who are you two?  - Jamie McCrimmon
- And?  - Victoria Waterfield
- What's the matter, can't you speak?
- Don't shout at me.
Oh, very good, the outraged public citizen.
- Do they know who I am?
- Yes they do.
A pity, I like to hear you say it.
Now listen to this, all of you.
One of your men was murdered in a bungalow rented to you.
The remains of two others were found
in what was left of a helicopter.
You were in that bungalow at the time.
And there were three other people with you,
two youngsters and a man. Right?
Now, there was another man, wasn't there?
So we'll deal with that first? Where is he?
Why hello Bruce, what are you doing here, huh?
I was under the impression
you were in the Central European Zone, Leader.
That's what you were meant to believe.
Why?
I do not care to be questioned by my own security!
Well that's just it. How can I possibly
maintain security when you behave like this?
I'm at least entitled to know your movements.
You have a policeman's mind, Bruce.
That may be! Only a few days ago you questioned me
about this man and his activities.
And we agreed that he was dangerous!
Now, I find you in his office.
Sometimes I like to deal with matters in my own way.
- They're not holding you here?  - Holding me?
Under some threat or other.
No one threatens Salamander!
I still think I deserve an explanation, Leader.
Yes, of course, you shall have it.
But not now. When I return from the Central European Zone.
Very well.
Now what about the dead man found in your bungalow.
He was one of your lot, wasn't he?
Yes. Um, he was trying to protect me.
The other two wanted to kill me.
Now why should they want to do that
to a nice young girl like you?
Well I...
Obviously they thought I was there.
You?
Yes, Bruce, just like you,
a lot of people don't like me.
Don't get clever with me, Kent!
I've a good mind to...
I am prepared to accept his story.
Well I'm not!
That's interesting, but not important.
I accept it! That's all that matters.
It's beginning to look as if these people
are working for you now. Is that right?
You still dare to question me!
They have information! I shall get it!
I will see you on my return. Now leave me!
- McCrimmon, you said?  - Aye
Well you just watch your step, that's all.
I never said a word.
Must be the way you look, Jamie.
You were splendid, Doctor.
Thank you.
That was a dangerous game to play.
It paid off. All right, are you with us?
I don't know where you stand, Mr Kent.
But you and this Salamander are obviously
on opposite sides. That at least is clear.
But which side is good? Which side is bad?
And why should I interfere?
Well you're the only man who can help save the world.
But isn't that what Salamander's trying to do?
Don't you understand? Salamander...
Just a moment. Jamie, you're unusually quiet,
what do you think?
Well to save the world,
aye, well it sounds grand, but...
Oh, we couldn't turn our back
on a challenge like this, Doctor.
Well, at least I know you wouldn't.
We don't know anything about these people.
Astrid saved our lives.
She was wounded because of it.
- Oh but Jamie, you don't think...
- Look, she was...
Look, we're right about Salamander!
It won't take you long to find out for yourselves.
How do you propose we do that?
He'll be well guarded for a start.
We can hardly steal into his study
and go through his papers.
That man, Bruce, said that
he was in the Central European Zone.
It's a long way from Australia.
It's only two hours by rocket.
You could leave almost at once.
- Oh, what then?  - I've had a plan ...
... for infiltrating into Salamander's
inner circle for some time.
Well I could adapt it for your two friends.
I can arrange three travel warrants and visas.
Everything you need.
Just three?
Well one for Astrid, one for you and ah...
- Victoria.  - Of course.
Oh that's very clever of you.
How can you do that?
I thought you said you had no official position?
We have a contact there.
He must be a very important person.
He is. Denes, Controller of the Zone.
Oh, I see. What about me?
I think we better have a look at
Salamander's research station at Kanowa.
Yes. Ah, yes, but from a safe distance of course.
This is dreadful news, Salamander.
I still can't believe it.
Terrible, terrible.
I don't say it will happen.
I say it can happen.
Your Zone is in danger, Denes.
Here, here and here.
We've had no trouble for years in those mountains.
You don't imagine I make it up?
No, no, of course not.
Those volcanoes have been dead
since sixteenth century. Fedorin is right to doubt.
A volcano is a strange thing, my friend.
I tell you the truth.
It's like a man in the hot sun,
sleeping... still... lifeless.
Then boom! He wakes full of energy!
I know volcanoes.
Isn't there a possibility of a...
miscalculation for a few degrees?
I'm never wrong.
Every one of my predictions has been accurate.
Yes. You're record is good. I don't deny that.
You are too kind. Now will you listen to me!
Leader, the communications...
I know! I know! I told you I was not to be disturbed!
Yes, Leader.
No, wait! No, wait, Fariah, ah?
- You like some refreshment, perhaps?
- Thank you.
No, no, not for me.
You're going so soon?
I must consult my scientific advisors.
You still don't believe me?
I believe you sufficiently to want to...
have your information checked.
Before I alarm my people unnecessarily.
Your scientists won't help you.
They don't know. They are amateurs.
No, Salamander, they are not amateurs.
They are very clever men dedicated to their work.
But they are men, capable of human error like anybody else.
Do what you wish.
Captain!
Sir!
Controller Denes is leaving.
Yes, sir.
You will soon see that I am right.
Oh, you will stay, ah? Have a drink.
We have a great deal to talk about, you and I.
Fariah, see to him.
That might be her now. Yes.
Hello, Giles? This is me, Astrid.
Right let‘s have it. What's happening?
Everything's gone fine so far.
And the rocket arrived right on time in Hungary.
And Jamie's got his entrance pass
and has started phase one.
- Do you think the boy can handle it?
- Well I hope so.
My goodness they're a pretty
odd lot though, aren't they?
Well actually the Doctor's with me right now.
Oh, I am sorry. Oh I know...
I'm sure they'll be fine.
What news of Denes? We must keep him posted
as to what is happening.
It's all right, we've contacted
and we've arranged to meet.
Be careful, he's pretty well known.
But what on earth made you
take a job as a food taster?
She was hungry.
Only thing is, now she has all the food she needs,
...she has lost her appetite.
Give me a drink!
You are well protected.
Um.
Very well protected.
Be calm. Sit down, drink your drink.
Ah!
Thank you for calling the guard.
I was wondering what to do about him.
Now don't move for that box!
Not if you value your life.
Now all of you, back over there! That's it.
Not as well protected as you think you are, eh?
Now when I say duck... Duck, get down!
Look at this! What do you do boys, eh?
Read? Sleep? It's a fine thing.
Here we have an attempt to destroy me
and where are you?
It's not so good, boys.
It's not so good. I'm watching you.
Look after him. Better still, get rid of him.
- What's all this about. Eh?
- I heard two men talking.
They said they'd planted a bomb of some kind
in your radio telephone.
I tried to warn them at the gates,
but they wouldn't pay any attention.
So you break in? How you break in?
Well I'm here on holiday with a friend.
She's very pretty, so the guard
didn't see me slip past him.
Why didn't you call out and warn me?
I nearly used the radio telephone several times.
Ah you'd have had me shot, most like.
Why do you risk your skin to save me?
Well without you
the Earth hasn't much of a chance, has it?
You like to work for me, eh? You like that?
Oh no, you don't have to do that.
I mean, you owe me nothing.
You're quite right, boy.
And I'm on holiday.
You won't find what I pay you disappointing.
Aye, there's my girlfriend too though.
Oh we might be able to find something for her.
Eh Fariah?
Yes, your chef could use an assistant.
See to it. What do you say, eh?
Well I'll give it a go.
But I'll say this though,
your security system's rotten.
There'll have to be changes.
Oh what a boy, ah?
Fariah, see he gets some proper uniform
instead of this skirt.
And bring him and his girlfriend to see me.
Come along then.
What an extraordinary young man.
I prize loyalty very highly, my friend.
And I repay it very generously.
Like I do the girl Fariah, eh.
I used to love to do this sort of thing when I was a boy.
I'm sorry. It was the safest place I could think of.
Oh, it's all right. I'm still fit enough.
Thank you for getting me the necessary documents.
Have you been successful?
So far. Salamander's swallowed it.
I thought he would.
The boy's very confident.
The girl, not so much.
See, the point is that I'm near enough
to him to pick out something.
This was the first time I met Salamander.
I must say that you were right about him, Astrid.
We must get rid of him. He must be stopped.
He will be stopped!
I'm returning to Giles Kent.
Can you wait till we can take action?
Oh, with a bit of luck, yes.
Fedorin, would he betray you in some way?
I'm trying to think of some reason why he should.
But these are all lies, Salamander. Lies, I assure you.
So you say.
What are you going to do? My family... my friends.
My dear man. My dear Fedorin.
You don't suppose I intend to
make your swindling public, eh?
This is... this just an insurance, um.
Sit down, forget it.
I tell you what I'm going to do for you.
What?
You are going to replace Denes
as controller of this Zone.
But, don't say anything.
I'll know you'll accept.
What do you want?
I'll tell you. There will be disaster in this Zone.
I cannot stop the disaster,
but I can come to the aid of this Zone
when it's happened.
And take over? I see.
- The Zone would be yours!
- Oh ours, Fedorin, ours.
It's a partnership I'm offering you.
Either you have half of everything, or you have nothing.
But there's Alexander Denes.
Oh yes, the popular, well beloved Denes.
- What a pity.  - Pity?
Oh didn't I tell you, Denes is going to die.
Mysteriously... an assassin... terrible.
I can't do that! You can't ask me!
I think I can ask you to do anything I want.
My predictions are accurate!
The entire Eperjes-Tokaj Ranges are in eruption!
Fedorin, come and look. It's very pretty.
The history of Hungary is about to be rewritten!
Salamander.
What are you doing here, Bruce?
I had a report there was trouble here,
an attempt on your life.
It was nothing. Come and look.
Terrible. Those poor people.
Salamander! What have you done?
I warned you!
You couldn't have known!
You've done this somehow yourself!
The man is mad! Worse still he is incompetent!
I warned this man that this zone
was in danger of natural disaster...
...and he did nothing!
Issued no cautions to the public.
You deliberately allowed your people to suffer and die!
You're a traitor!
You're a traitor! You contrived this for your own ends.
Bruce, I order you to arrest this man.
But this is nonsense. Fedorin, you were here.
You know this is nonsense.
Denes you are too naive.
At your trial, Fedorin will be
the chief witness against you!
You've done very well so far, Fedorin.
It's nothing but a blackmail.
Blackmail? What have I threaten you with? Nothing!
No, but you would if I refused.
Fedorin, I keep on telling you,
this is just a form of comprehensive insurance, hm?
There's nothing for you to worry about.
My dear man, I've done nothing
but praise you ever since we first met.
I said you should be European Controller.
I said I would support you.
You've found out things about me,
lies that would damage me.
On the contrary, I am doing you a good turn.
I am actually suppressing facts about you.
- Lies, I tell you!
- Lies... Truth... Who knows?
But we wouldn't like to put them to the test, would we?
There.
What's this?
Used in the right way, at the right time,
it can dictate your own future
and the future of Alexander Denes.
Poison?
I want you to take a message...
- McCrimmon! What are you doing dressed like this?
- Leader's orders.
Now that you're here, I've got some questions
I want to ask you.
I have better things to do, thank you.
I want to know what Salamander and Giles Kent
were discussing
- when I saw you last time?
- It's not for me to tell you that.
I am concerned of Salamander's safety.
Giles Kent is supposed to be his bitter enemy.
If Salamander wishes you to know that,
I dare say he'll tell you himself.
You'll get no confidential out of me.
Listen. You must go away from here.
Don't get caught up in Salamander's world.
Why? What do you mean?
You sound as if you don't like him.
- Like him? I ...
- Oh, hello there.
Finish writing those menus.
- Did you hear that?
- Aye. Work on her.
I have a feeling she can tell us something about Salamander.
All right. As soon as I can.
What have you been doing?
I managed to slip out
and tell Astrid everything that's happened.
- You might have told me, Jamie!
- There wasn't time.
- She's trying to get Denes away.
- And take him to the Doctor?
- He'd believe Denes.
- Aye, he would.
How can she get in?
Salamander's got guards are everywhere.
She's got friends here.
They're going to arrange passes...
- and the right sort of uniform.
- What sort of uniform?
I don't know. Messenger delivery
or something. Ssh!
Controller Denes has been arrested.
I can't make up my mind whether Fedorin
is to be regarded as a new Controller or not.
The burden of office is heavy, my friend.
I remember when I was...
Alright. They've gone.
Astrid and Giles Kent were quite right.
Salamander IS an evil man.
- I can somehow sense it from all the people here.
- He's bad, all right.
He's had Denes arrested,
and has Fedorin eating out of his hand.
Why should he do that?
Remove the honest man, and put a weaker man in his place
but somehow have a hold on him,
That way Salamander can take over the territory.
I see - when everything's in a turmoil
because of the earthquakes.
Aye, and that's lucky to say the least.
But you don't really believe that Salamander
could cause earthquakes, do you?
I'm certain Salamander's causing the earthquakes, Doctor
and I'm sure your friends Jamie and Victoria
will tell you how bad he really is.
But why make earthquakes?
Years ago, when one country wanted to invade another,
it set about attacking the confidence of that country,
throwing it into confusion, making it weak.
Then it was right for take over.
Now, isn't that exactly what's happening here,
only in a different way?
What you're saying is that Salamander has found a way...
...to harness the natural forces of the Earth.
That's a little difficult to accept.
I'm not saying it's impossible, mind you.
You say it's coming from the research station.
Salamander's research station, eh?
That's what I believe, in spite of...
Ssh! Wait a minute.
In spite of a number of reasons,
he invented the sun-store, a brilliant advance.
He found a way of directing conserved energy
to areas starved of sun.
- What made you suspicious?
- The money he was spending ast the Research Station
The materials involved, the food stores.
It didn't make sense.
- I had all the papers, all the requisition orders.
- But that's valuable evidence!
All destroyed, and new ones appeared...
I was made out to be the criminal!
All by suggestion, of course. I was discredited.
I couldn't do it, Salamander. I couldn't do it.
I stood there with this man's life in my hands.
This powder - I couldn't use it.
I gave you the chance
to become something. Somebody.
- You failed to take it, huh
- There must be some other way.
Of course, my friend. Don't worry.
- What?  - Don't worry.
You try, you fail - so what?
The moon doesn't fall out of the sky!
Come and sit down. Have a drink, huh?
Cheer up. We'll find another way.
I really did try.
Of course you did.
Don't worry.
Forget it, huh?
I have an alternative.
Your health.
I hope you will appreciate this wine.
It's made for me especially in Alaska.
One chance, my friend.
I said one chance!
Some trouble in the kitchens, Leader.
The new man says he's seen
someone in the kitchen gardens.
Very well. Oh, see to that, will you?
Suicide, of course. Such a pity.
- I can't see anything.
- Over there by the trees!
He's armed, too. Get down!
I'm going out there. Stay down here.
When the rest of the guards come,
send them after me.
Yes, all right.
Astrid's going to get you away.
An attempt has been made to rescue this man.
Take him out to the car.
I'm sorry, Janos.
Stop!
After them! Arrest that girl!
Well, we all seem to be here,
except the third member of your escape committee.
- What are you talking about?
- You were seen speaking with a girl in the park.
The one who tried to escape with Denes.
We don't know anything about that.
We don't even know her.
A diversion was caused.
There was no one outside the kitchen.
Of course there was someone, and there was shooting.
Three shots have been fired from this gun.
It's yours, isn't it?
Pretending to save my life was ingenious,
but ingenuity requires a constant stream of new ideas.
Yours seem to have dried up.
I come to the Central Zone.
An attempt is made on my life.
Denes proves to be a traitor.
Fedorin commits suicide because I uncover him.
Do your job, Bruce.
You can see they're all in this.
All right. Take them away.
Take your hands off me!
Salamander, I think you should tell me what's going on.
One minute I see you with this lad McCrimmon,
- you're working together. The next minute...
- I thought he saved my life.
No, I mean before that. In Kent's office.
- What are you talking about?
- Well I saw you there.
But I haven't seen Kent in months.
Yes, you were with Kent, Fariah and the youngsters.
I thought it was so curious,
I spoke to your number two, Benik, about it.
- That's really the reason I came to this zone.
- But I tell you...
I must get back to the research centre.
You will come with me.
It was you!
Or someone... like you?
Patience, Mister Kent, patience.
Astrid should have been in contact by now.
Can't you contact her?
If I knew where she was.
Oh no, I know she's in the Central European Zone,
But that's a big place.
No, we'll just have to sweat it out and wait.
Astrid, you're back. Switch to scramble.
Scramble? Are we being monitored?
- It's possible.  - Right. Switching now.
Denes dead?
Yes, shot in the back.
Well, it looks as if our friend Salamander's
had a field day, doesn't it?
I'm afraid I haven't done very well.
Don't worry. It's not your fault.
Look, stay put and we'll join you.
The girl Astrid Ferrier,
she was in the Central European Zone.
Was she? Well she's here now. Have you found her?
I think so. One of my men saw someone
answering her description...
...going into Giles Kent's office earlier.
Was she alone?
Yes, sir. But shortly after someone else followed her in.
Well who, man, who?
Leader Salamander's food taster sir, Fariah.
Fariah?
But what are they going to do to Jamie and Victoria?
I don't know.
Hold them in the Central European zone
until Salamander has time to deal with them.
No. You're wrong. Salamander doesn't care for loose ends.
He brought them back with him.
What, to his headquarters, the Research Centre?
Yes. He's going to try to get information from them.
How far will he go to get it?
Very far.
Oh, that's very comforting.
I tell you I know Salamander.
Yes, I... I'm not quite clear
about your part in all this.
You work for Salamander, suddenly
you fall over yourselves to betray him.
I came here for that purpose, yes.
Why?
Because I have every reason to hate Salamander.
He blackmailed me into being his personal servant.
I even had to smile when he told me to.
What sort of blackmail? What had you done?
- Does it really matter?
- Oh, no no no.
Of course not my dear.
Well nobody's perfect, Kent.
But I... I still can't help wondering why...
...why I hadn't tried to expose Salamander?
Well you were in a unique position to do so.
Because without any proof
I'd be wasting my time.
Proof! Proof! Proof!
It always comes back to the same thing.
No one has any evidence against Salamander!
We have some.
Not enough! It's not enough!
Salamander covers up too well.
I have what you want.
But I thought that you said...
No. Not about me. Fedorin.
Fedorin? A public embezzler
who commits suicide?
Salamander engineered nearly every one
of those swindles, and I can prove it.
How?
Fedorin's file.
Is the building surrounded?
A three's in position, Captain.
Just closing up the gaps.
Well you haven't brought me here
on a fool's errand, I hope?
But I'm afraid this... this still isn't evidence,
it's... it's not real evidence.
You mean even this doesn't convince you about Salamander?
Oh, I'm not saying that.
Well then you'll do it? You'll impersonate him?
And of course when they see you with me
they're bound to think you're Salamander.
But I... I still don't know if I can carry it off.
It's the only way to get your friends released.
Yesss...
Of course, there are...
Oh I see, yes of course, there are conditions, aren't there?
You help me, I defeat Salamander?
Now look, you're giving me the biggest opportunity
I'll ever have of ridding the world of this monster.
Either I can convince you one way,
or I'll have to do it another.
What you really want me to do is to kill him, isn't it?
What else do you do when someone is evil?
Private justice, eh? Oh no, no.
I'll expose him, ruin him, have him arrested,
But I won't be his executioner.
No one has that right.
Sometimes it's necessary.
- No.  - Yes, Doctor yes!
Right, we'll move in.
Either you get rid of Salamander,
or we won't lift a finger to help your friends.
Mister Kent, look.
I'd make up my mind quickly if I were you.
- Why?  - Have a look out of the window.
Well, what is it?
What do we do now?
Over here, quick!
Well what's that?
- Through here, the ventilator shaft.
- The files.
- Come on, quick.  - But where did it go?
It doesn't matter, come on.
It's locked.
Now you, Doctor, next.
- Oh what about you?
- Kent! Open the door
Oh no, you're too important.
You go, and Giles.
- I'll follow  - All right.
Very well...
...you leave me no alternative. Break it down.
Get back!
Get away from that door!
Did you get the others?
Not yet, sir.
Now listen to me. It was you,
Astrid Ferrier, Giles Kent...
...and another. Who was the other man?
You'll know soon... soon enough.
I want to know now.
Sir...
Shut up! Well?
You can't threaten me now, Benik.
I can only die once,
and someone's beaten you to it.
Who was the other man?
Sir?
She's dead.
Good.
Fedorin's file. Thank you.
What you mean is you failed.
I always said something should be done about Kent.
You always say. You say things, but you don't think.
You exceeded your authority, Benik.
A woman's been killed.
Resisting arrest.
Maybe. But you can't just take the law into your own hands.
Giles Kent hadn't broken any rules that I know of.
For sure he'd show himself one day,
he was simply building up his resistance group.
Resistance group! The man's a traitor.
These people are rebels.
Bruce, you must find this man who impersonated me.
The dangers are obvious.
He could walk in anywhere at any time
pretending to be me and ruin everything.
You can leave that to me.
How so?
Benik, come with me and I'll go over
the security arrangements with you now.
Do as you're told!
I think you'll find this interesting.
What? The girl Fariah had this?
What can I say?
Yes sir?
The records room is out of bounds.
I am not to be disturbed.
See that the security locks are engaged.
Very well, sir. For how long, sir?
For as long as I say so.
Yes sir.
It seems that Salamander's
locked himself away and can't be got at.
So?
Well, suppose the place caught fire?
It won't.
Don't be foolish!
Look, I can only tell you that
when Salamander works in records,
as he does from time to time, no one is allowed in.
I can understand if it were a... laboratory...
or... a... research room of some sort, but a...
a records room? What sort of records
have you got in there anyway?
What did you want to see him about?
Never mind. I just don't like mysteries.
Salamander's far too important
to lock himself away like this,
anything might happen, a world emergency.
Suppose I had to order you to let me in there?
It wouldn't do any good. When the locks are switched over
they can only be opened from the inside.
I have returned.
Take radiation precautions.
I will make a report about the surface.
He's back!
He's managed to get back again.
Let's hope he's got some good news this time.
Do you think Salamander's found some more food, Swann?
I hope so, otherwise we're finished.
Where's that stock list?
Welcome back, Salamander. Are you all right?
Don't, don't come too near my friend,
I am not yet decontaminated.
I am too weary, totally weary.
You shouldn't have made this trip,
Salamander, you're doing too much.
Someone has to bring back the food
for you, my friend, huh?
You know that the radiation
is slowly killing me, don't you Swann?
You're just doing too much.
I worry about you all the time.
What're you going to do when I am no longer here?
Radiation gets a little more each time, hm?
One day, that needle will stay at maximum radiation.
- Don't say that.  - Why... Mary. Colin.
Huh, it's my big joke, huh?
Just to frighten you a little.
I've got good news for us!
We can return to the surface?
No no no not yet, but I've found another store of food...
Thank goodness!
...And it is undamaged.
Colin, open the last store of wine, huh?
Go on, you help him too, Mary.
You must take it slowly for goodness sake.
I'm all right my friend. I'm just a little dizzy. It's...
It's terrible up there, you know,
Swann, you've no idea.
Right, I am ready.
But I still don't understand what's happened to Fariah.
She went the wrong way. We lost her.
Well we must find her!
You don't seem to realize how vital it is.
Doctor, hold still a moment will you?
Sorry.
There. Look at that, Giles, isn't it amazing?
Salamander to the life.
Yes, it's... it's not bad.
Shh, I think I heard something.
Perhaps it's Fariah.
Stay where you are. I've been looking forward
to meeting you again.
Over there... No, not you.
Sit down, all of you.
Incredible. You fooled me the first time we met,
but now, even Salamander himself
would think he was looking in a mirror.
Why? You want this man to impersonate Salamander, why?
How much are they paying you?
I beg your pardon?
They want you to assassinate Salamander,
don't they? Take his place?
That's ridiculous! I couldn't possibly do that.
But you were preparing to impersonate him, weren't you?
Well well, yes.
Alright then, why?
Because Salamander holds my two friends prisoner
and I was going to attempt to rescue them.
And at the same time get evidence
that would expose Salamander...
...as a traitor, blackmailer and murderer!
Quite an ambitious plan.
How do you know such evidence exists?
It exists in Salamander's records.
Oh, yes, I know why you want Salamander out of the way.
You hate him because he exposed
your profitable sideline of misusing public money.
Oh, it was Salamander who was misusing the money.
And I was dismissed from my post and
the evidence against Salamander concealed.
So you say. But you've no evidence at all
against Salamander, have you?
I tell you the evidence is in Salamander's records.
And I'm expected to take that from you?
We do hold evidence...
that Salamander isn't quite
so pure and white as he's painted.
No? What?
A file, containing certain information
about a gentleman called Fedorin.
Salamander was going to
use this evidence against Fedorin.
Blackmail him into submission.
after he'd got rid of Denes, that is.
And so gain control of another zone.
Where is this file?
Fariah has it, Salamander's food taster.
Fariah? But she's dead.
Dead? But how?
She was shot by one of Benik's guards, escaping arrest.
Escaping arrest? Benik had her killed,
because she had evidence against Salamander.
And Benik will return the file to Salamander.
We must get to the Research Station.
You're not going anywhere or doing anything.
As far as I'm concerned, this story you've told me
could be a pack of lies...
to cover your attempt to assassinate Salamander.
Now I'm not saying I'm altogether satisfied with
Salamander or his organisation,
but I'll investigate in my own way.
Meanwhile Salamander will have found a way to cover himself,
and also a way of disposing of you.
You're digging your own grave, Bruce.
That's my affair. And I do things my own way.
And I do things my way.
Really, as Head of Security,
you should have more reliable guards.
- Leader Salamander?
- Still inside, sir.
Let me know the moment the doors are opened.
Yes sir.
So you've brought them?
Good. Any trouble?
No, a light drug saw to that.
Let me know the moment they wake up.
Yes sir.
I'm looking forward to questioning them.
I have the feeling they're going to be stubborn.
So much more interesting when our prisoners are stubborn.
You're only making trouble for yourself.
Killing me won't get you anywhere.
We have to get to the Research Station,
and you're not going to stop us.
But you're completely surrounded.
You don't really believe I came here
with just one guard, do you?
You'd be very silly to try and fight your way out.
I'd give you about... thirty seconds to live if you try.
Alright Bruce, we might have just thirty seconds
but you'd have exactly half that time, if you were lucky!
Please, Mister Kent!
You're forgetting one very important thing.
- What?  - Me.
Without me you haven't got an earthly chance
of getting in that control centre.
So?
I told you before,
I will not have anything to do with violence!
And what about your two friends?
Are you going to leave them
to the tender mercies of Salamander?
No I am not. May I?
- What?  - Please? Just trust me.
Now then, I think you agree that
at this moment your life is in my hands.
What are you doing?
Hold it.
It's alright, Mister Bruce isn't going
to shoot anyone, are you?
Why? Why'd you do that?
Because I think I know what sort of man you are
- honest and reasonable.
Go on.
I gave you back that gun because I trust you.
Now I want you to trust me.
You must be a complete fool, or very clever.
Well I'm afraid you will have to
make up your mind to that right away.
What do you hope to gain from this gesture?
Your confidence.
Do you believe Kent's accusations against Salamander?
I think there's reasonable doubt about
Salamander's personal integrity,
but there's only one way to get proof.
By getting into Salamander's Research Station?
Yes. And my two young friends may have some information.
And if there isn't any evidence?
Then you'll be perfectly free to arrest us
and put us in prison, won't you?
Alright, I'll do it, on one condition.
And what's that?
That you and I go alone,
Kent and the girl stay here as hostages.
No wait a minute, I must go with him.
No, Kent, you stay here.
I must be mad to trust you.
I only hope your impersonation of Salamander fools Benik.
If it doesn't, we're in dead trouble.
Here, take this. Keep those two in the caravan.
Oh, and, um, watch the girl. Come on.
Ah, how we getting on here, huh?
Ah, all this? That's a good haul.
Stand by to make your report, Swann.
Reaching full power here, Swann.
Salamander, I must see you.
Not now, we are too busy.
This is urgent.
Oh very well.
Now what's the matter, huh?
What's this? What is this?
What?
Newspaper. It's a piece of newspaper.
So?
Well go on, look at it. Read it. Last year's date.
Look at the bit of headline there. THERE!
Control yourself, Swann. You'll go mad.
"Holiday Liner Sinks"!
You say there's a global war. Radiation everywhere.
How can there be holiday liners? Tell me how!
You've lied to us, haven't you? HAVEN'T YOU?
In a way, Swann, yes. I had to.
Had to? What do you mean had to?
Well it's true that... that the war is over,
but have you any idea what happens to people
who've been involved in a nuclear war? HAVE YOU?
Course I haven't, I've been down here.
Those who are lucky enough to escape the annihilation
have their bodies eaten away by radiation poisoning.
They're deformed in mind and body.
But this, this, this newspaper?
They have a kind of society,
but it's... it's evil! Corrupt!
You don't think I could expose you to that sort of thing?
Think of Mary and the other women.
You could have told me, at least.
I decided not to.
You should have told me.
I thought it was best.
And what about the natural disasters
we've been organising?
The volcanoes, earthquakes?
Swann, they're not fit to live.
You're murdering them, killing them off!
I want you and the others
to inherit the Earth, make a new world.
Yes, I know all about that,
but not at the price of wholesale murder!
It's not murder! If you could see
you would understand. It's an act of mercy.
There must be some other way.
NO!
I won't take your word any more.
I want to see for myself.
You, you, you'd be horrified.
Maybe.
The radiation would kill you!
I'll chance that.
Very well. But, but promise me one thing,
you won't tell the others.
Why shouldn't I?
Because I am right and you are wrong!
You, you wouldn't want to,
you wouldn't want to hurt them like that, huh?
And if you're lying,
and I want to tell when I get back...?
How can I stop you?
You'd better, ah, tell them you're coming with me.
Say er, say you've persuaded me.
Swann, trust me, don't go ahead with this huh?
I have to.
Where are we?
You're in the Australasian zone.
I had you brought here especially.
Why?
So that Salamander could ask you some questions.
For all the answers he's gonna get
he might as well have left us there.
Stand up when you talk to me!
You'll get nowhere by shouting.
On the contrary. I'm going to get everything
I want from you two.
We'll not tell you a thing.
That's good. I like that.
- What?  - Spirit. Resistance.
You've got plenty of both, haven't you, boy?
Well I wonder how long you'll last.
Five minutes?
No, a little longer, maybe? Ten, perhaps?
- What do you mean?
- Come now, you don't think...
...I'm just going to sit here
and ask questions, do you?
You must have been a nasty little boy.
Oh I was. But I had a very enjoyable childhood.
Ha ha hah. Yes, I thought so.
Spirit, plenty of spirit.
Oh, we're going to enjoy ourselves, aren't we? Now then...
I... I thought you were going to take us to see Salamander?
Yes I will. But he'd expect me to do my little best first.
You lay a finger on her, I'll kill you.
Will you? How? Ha ha ha.
No. I think the time's come for you
to answer my questions, don't you?
Come here, girl!
If you don't, I shall have to shoot one of you.
Oh, not a mortal wound. In the leg, perhaps?
Better go. Don't worry.
There. That's better.
Oh, such pretty hair, don't you think?
Alright, leave her alone. What do want to know?
Quite a lot. And you're going to
tell me everything. Aren't you?
- Aaah!  - All right, yes!
Who's behind you? Is it Giles Kent?
Oh, so they're here, eh?
Salamander, I, I thought you were in Records?
Have they told you anything yet?
Not yet.
Very well. Bruce and I will take over.
You may go, and er,
take your little puppy dog with you, hm?
Now...
We can't tell you anything.
Of course not. We know everything.
We know about Giles Kent,
we know about the girl called Astrid,
and we know about your friend the Doctor.
I don't believe you.
A childish plan to impersonate me.
Yes the truth, isn't it?
Ah but he didn't agree to it.
But you two were sent to
the Central European zone to stir up trouble.
If you want to know the truth,
Giles Kent told us a story and we weren't sure.
Before the Doctor could do anything
we had to come here
and find out what person you were like.
Yeah, and we found that out right enough.
You see Bruce, they just terrorists.
Not very big fry, either.
All this nonsense about proof against me.
If you're doing so much good for the world,
why are you so afraid for your own life?
Aye, and why do you have so many enemies?
- Personal guards?
- Your own food taster?
And why destroy the one man
people trusted, Alexander Denes?
- Aye.  - What do you mean, destroy?
One of your men shot him.
Trying to escape?
He shot him deliberately.
Aye. And that girl Fariah,
well she was close to Salamander,
she'd speak against him, I know she would.
Fariah is dead.
Dead?
You've had her murdered too, have you?
- Why you...
- Oh, Victoria! Don't hit me!
You wouldn't hit your old friend the Doctor, would you?
I wouldn't leave you in the tender mercy of Salamander.
You're the Doctor?
You don't believe me? Oh. Huh.
Only, you made me leave it in the TARDIS.
- It is him!  - Oh, Doctor!
"Tardis"? "Tardis", what's that?
Well, it's a little place that we three have in common.
You must admit they thought
I was Salamander to begin with.
Yes. I concede that. But there's still no proof.
No, but there's enough doubt in your mind...
to make you go on asking questions, isn't there?
That's why we came here.
Wait. What happens up there?
Oh, it ends in a ruined building.
This is where I bring the stores,
- uh, you would be safer here.
- Safer?
Yes, the radiation.
I don't think it filters down here.
I still want to see the surface.
You will, you will.
I should have insisted on going with him.
Bruce should have taken me.
You know he doesn't trust you.
He wouldn't trust his own grandmother.
Oh, never mind, Giles. We've come a long way.
Months ago, well a few weeks ago even,
nobody would have even listened to you.
Oh, maybe.
There's no maybe about it.
Yeah perhaps you're right.
Bruce listens to us at last.
He's even prepared to ask questions, that's fine, but...
I know Salamander.
He'd talk his way out of the quicksand.
Well what else can we do,
the guard's still outside?
I must get into the Research Centre.
I've got to make sure that Bruce
understands the evidence, understands it, Astrid.
Don't you realize, he mightn't know
what he's looking for. I know.
But we can't attack the guard.
It would only make matters worse.
Not if I was to give Bruce real evidence.
Giles, how long would it take you
to get to the Research Station?
Well just a few minutes, I've got a pass.
It's just a matter of getting there.
Alright, I think I can help you.
I'll draw the guard off and leave you alone.
You think you can do it?
Yes, I think so.
But I thought you said we weren't going to attack the guard?
Oh, we're not going to attack the guard,
but there is going to be an attack. A fatal one.
Where does this lead?
It goes on up and comes out in a field.
What about radiation?
Here it's almost negligible.
You mean you could have brought others here from below?
I don't understand you.
Don't you realise what a break
it would be for them,
just moving away from that underground tomb once in a while?
You seem to forget, Swann,
I've brought people up here before!
There's always an element of risk!
I still want to have a look at these people
you say are living on the surface.
Where does that lead?
Oh, that's a dead end.
It's a place I sometimes rest.
It's very hard work, you know, bringing all the...
Yes, I know that.
This way, then?
You, you sure you... won't change your mind, huh?
What's going on here?
He's been shot. Through the window.
Alright, stand back.
He's finished.
Better get a doctor anyway, just in case.
Hey! Come back!
Hellllp! Somebody help me.
Heeellllp! Help... Somebody help me...
Who did this to you?
A man named... Salamander.
Salamander?
He did it... down there...
This is Salamander.
I want a security escort to come
to the interrogation room immediately.
I'm releasing two prisoners.
They are to be conducted to the main gates and set free.
Is that understood? Good.
- Well I hope that works.
- So do I.
What do you want us to do when we get outside?
There are plenty of public phones in the area.
Dial double zero one and ask for a man named Forrester.
- Eh?  - He's my deputy to this area.
Double zero one Forrester.
Tell him where I am and just say "redhead".
Redhead.
Redhead. Is that clear?
Redhead? Is that your wife?
It's our emergency call.
Sorry.
Salamander... Is the, is the pass in order?
Very well, you have my authority.
What's all that about?
We have a visitor.
Giles Kent. What are you doing here?
Oh, I've been looking forward to this meeting.
You're getting careless.
You didn't double lock the doors.
Oh, its all right, I've done it now.
The only way anybody can get through there
is to blast their way through.
- How did you get into the Research Centre?
- Oh, you know me.
There isn't a pass in the world
I can't get my hands on, if I put my mind to it.
You won't find it so easy getting out.
Really? Well we'll see.
I'm not on my own this time.
I've got friends here with me.
And between us we're going to fix you once and for all.
You always were a tiresome man, Kent.
I'm going to be more than tiresome this time.
You know the biggest mistake you ever made...
was not killing me when you had the chance.
Oh so you going to kill me huh? How petty.
What good do you think that will do?
Hold it! Now don't move quickly,
my nerves are a bit shaky at the moment.
We must get in there somehow.
We can't without the emergency key,
and Salamander has it in there.
- We could burn our way in.  - Never.
- Why not?
- It's an X-structure alloy, you'd hardly scratch the surface.
We'll have to try it. Get the gear up here. Fast!
Ha ha ha. Never get away with it?
Oh, that's good, coming from you.
Don't you realize you're dispensable,
and the world is going to get along fine
without you from now on.
The only good idea you ever had in your life
was getting rid of me...
and you couldn't even do that properly, could you?
Ha ha ha. And now I'm back and you're finished.
Oh, what's that?
They're breaking down the door.
They don't appear to be having much success.
It's not cutting, sir.
Never mind, keep at it.
You're trapped, aren't you?
You're a fool, Salamander.
You don't think I'd forgotten already, do you?
What?
I've been with you too many times in this room in the past,
not to know where this leads to.
Your little bolt-hole.
Halfway down the tunnel.
A passage out to the fields...
and enough explosives down there
to stop you or your thugs following me.
Well that's very interesting Mister Kent.
Why didn't you tell me that before?
- Oh no, it can't be.  - Oh, I'm afraid it is.
Oh look. Here's another surprise for you. Look behind you.
Astrid, you've come just in time.
It's too late, Giles, I know everything.
That's him, that's the man
who took us down there in the first place.
Giles Kent, we thought you were dead.
Now look, I've never seen these people before in my life.
They told me everything.
You and Salamander were in it together...
...You built an atomic shelter,
took some people down for an endurance test.
The next person they saw was Salamander...
...who told them that an atomic war had started.
You see, Kent...
Oh, be careful, Doctor. He'll kill you.
You kept us down like animals.
Why? Why did you do it to us?
We had to have someone create
the natural disasters, didn't we,
and we fooled you all!
You didn't fool me, Kent...
You didn't suspect me.
Any man who resorts to murder as eagerly
and as rapidly as you must be suspect.
You didn't just want to expose Salamander,
you wanted to kill him and take his place.
And I will! Think you're going to stop me?
And these people?
Now move out of the way, quick!
We'll see who'll stop me!
Stop him, Stop him!
He's going to try and blow the place up!
Come on then!
No! Don't touch that door, it's red hot.
What do you mean?
Well it's locked.
They're trying to burn through from the other side.
Still no good, sir.
Look! Salamander!
Yes. I wonder if he knows Kent's on his way?
You always were a fool, weren't you?
Now wait a minute.
They'll be after both of us now.
Oh no they won't.
I tell you, they know!
So what you want me to do, huh?
Bury our differences, hmm?
I didn't need you once, I still don't need you.
Now wait a minute.
The place is mined, we know that.
We planned it for years, together.
Between us we can destroy them all, and the evidence.
Just you and me, Salamander.
You and me? What use are you to me?
You were useful once, but now...
No. No...
Ha ha ha ha. You won't get away
from me, Kent. Ha ha ha ha.
Ha ha hah. I told you you could not escape me.
Well if I'm going to die, Salamander,
you'll die with me.
No! No!
Aaaaaaa!
Come on Doctor,
we're going to get you out of here.
Oh, look, Salamander, Giles, they're dead.
We'll be dead too if we don't get out of here.
The people...
People. What people?
The people underground in the deep shelter.
They may have been killed.
I promised Swann I'd get them out.
But that's not your fault.
You couldn't have done more.
There's a TV monitor screen in there.
There must be a link to the deep shelter.
It's alright! They're alive!
How are you going to get to them?
There's a tunnel from outside.
We can get to it outside the Research Station.
But that's probably been destroyed by the explosion.
We'll get to them somehow.
Lookout!
Get me some men. I'll lead them.
Alright. I'll go with you.
Oh good then. That's splendid. I'll come too.
Oh no Doctor. It's far too dangerous.
They might mistake you as Salamander.
Oh yes. Ooooh.
- Are you hurt?  - Oh I'm alright.
I'll come with you as far as the gates.
Come along, we must go.
I thought you were never coming.
Hey Doctor, are you alright?
Oh there you are Doctor.
You do look in a state. Come and sit down.
I told you it wouldn't be long.
You, you worry too much.
We shouldn't have left him.
You see, after the explosion, Doctor,
we dinna know what to do.
You said to come back here, which we did,
but I'm sure we were followed.
Please, can we start straight away?
Me, Doctor? But you said we were never to touch the controls.
Quite right, Jamie. Welcome to the TARDIS.
Thank you. You're doing so well impersonating me, ah,
I thought I might return the compliment.
And Giles Kent?
Unfortunately, didn't survive the explosion.
We're going to put you outside, Salamander,
no friends, no safety, nothing.
You'll run, but they'll catch up with you.
No!
And now I'm going to kill you.
No you don't.
Oh, Doctor!
Victoria! Jamie! Hold onto something!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
Jamie! Oh!