Stop him!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Hunt that man! He must not escape!
Can we not help them? We can use the Tardis!
To go to the moon? We'd probably
overshoot by a few million years!
Yes, or by a few million miles!
The Tardis is not suited to short-range travel.
Still, we should help them if we can.
- Aye.
- Yes.
- I could get your rocket to the moon.
- You?
Yes, I have considerable experience
in space travel.
That's splendid! Thank you!
- But the rocket is not ready!
- Perhaps you overestimate the difficulty.
How much more work is required?
It needs fuel
and a complete computerised check.
- I can order that.
- No! The risk is too great!
If there was some other way,
- I wouldn't even consider such a risk!
- No!
(COMPUTER) Commander Radnor
Radnor. Go ahead.
T-Mat receptions -
New York, Moscow, Tokyo -
express great concern over continued hold-up.
Medical shipments and food
awaiting transit to Asiatic centres.
Position desperate, Calcutta.
Instructions awaited.
- That's your answer!
- Well, we want to help!
You don't understand! It's suicide!
Listen, if this fault lasts much longer,
there's going to be worldwide chaos,
and world population is at stake.
Infallible T-Mat,
putting the world in jeopardy (?)
All right, I admit it.
Now this man has to risk his life for you!
No, not for me, for thousands
of people all over the world
who will die if we don't take this risk!
I'm sorry but I've got no alternative.
- Miss Kelly.
- Sir.
I want all technical personnel working on this.
I want that rocket prepared for launching!
Yes, Commander.
We'd be grateful for your help.
If that rocket's to reach the moon safely,
you'll need a miracle!
(RASPING WHISPER)
Continue the search!
He must not escape!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Commander.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
Is it wise letting these people crew the rocket?
What's the alternative?
We gave up training astronauts years ago.
- Who are they?
- Eldred's crazy friends, I imagine,
- but the Doctor knows his space travel.
- How can you be sure?
He and the girl know
more about space flight than Eldred.
- What about the boy?
- I'm not sure about him.
(RASPING WHISPER)
The emergency link with Earth,
- is it ready yet?
- I've nearly finished.
- Do not make any mistakes!
- I'm not an expert!
- But you will do it?
- Yes!
Commander, I think I should go
as crew on the rocket.
Don't be ridiculous, you're too valuable here!
How can T-Mat be repaired if I'm not there?
- What about (one of) the technicians (who was already over) there?
- Osgood's dead.
- Yes, well, what about Fewsham?
- He's incapable of doing it! I think I) should go!
No! You're the only one
who really understands T-Mat.
I can't have you risking your life!
But (yet you are perfectly prepared to) allow them to risk theirs!
Don't worry, (Miss Kelly) we'll be perfectly all right!
But I don't see what good
just this emergency link can be.
Even if you had a gigantic army of warriors,
you couldn't send them all to conquer Earth.
(RASPING WHISPER)
We do not need an army.
Earth will be ours for the taking...
(HISSING BREATHING)
..very soon!
- Doctor...
- Yes?
Final check on procedure after you land.
Yes, (I know) we're to re-establish video link with the Earth.
That's right.
When we can see what's wrong,
you can do the rest
under Miss Kelly's supervision.
Right. We're ready when you are.
12...
10...
nine...eight...seven...
..six...five...four...three...
..two...one.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
It's done.
- The emergency link will work now.
- Excellent!
- What are you going to do?
- Do not ask questions!
Activate the link.
- On receive only.
- Receive?
But aren't you going to...?
Activate the link on receive at once!
- (KELLY) You've double-checked?
- Yes, the fault is on Moonbase.
Are you able to effect repairs over video?
the fault is not too major.
- And if they get there with the rocket!
- They'll get there.
You can't even be sure the rocket's still in one piece!
Miss Kelly!
The emergency T-Mat link to Moon Control is activating!
Is someone coming through?
No, it's on send.
Moonbase has managed
to make a temporary repair.
Have a full emergency kit waiting.
- I'll join you as soon as possible.
- Yes, Miss Kelly. Standing by.
Where are you are going?
If we can send, it's the only thing I can do.
You dont know) what conditions are like up there!
I know all too well what are like down here
Commander, you've stopped me once.
Don't try it again, otherwise
I shall have to go above your head.
- She's after your job, Julian!
- Miss Kelly!
(TRILLING TONE)
- Thank heavens you've come!
- What happened?
Osgood, it must have been space madness.
He just went berserk!
Osgood? But he'd be the last man,
I'd have thought!
- So did we.
- Where are the others?
When Osgood fused the controls,
Locke tried to stop him.
- Osgood killed him.
- This is fantastic!
- What about Phipps?
- He's injured and under sedation.
- And you?
- There's nothing wrong with me.
You look frightened.
If you'd seen Osgood die, wouldn't you be?
How did he die?
His body's outside.
He just went out.
Without a pressure suit? I see.
Open all control sections and computer links.
Fewsham, what are you doing?
I'd best switch off the emergency link.
- It could easily burn itself out.
- Sensible.
It will prevent Commander Radnor sending a security guard
to drag me back to Earth!
(RASPING WHISPER)
The other human is still free. Find him!
He must not interfere with our plans!
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! How do you read me?
Emergency! Can you hear me?
(ZOE) It's no use. No contact
at all. Every circuit's dead.
- This is most unfortunate!
- Don't try them again. You'll blow us up!
We don't need a radio.
- We're nearly there.
- I wanted to contact Earth.
There's no need. We can activate
the moon homing beam.
How? We've got no contact
with anyone on the moon.
It's quite simple. It's an automatic device.
Our code radio signals
trigger the homing beam into action.
We automatically lock onto it
until we reach the point in orbit
where we fire retro-rockets to land.
If they've all been cut off,
how can they activate?
It works off a different
power source - solar power.
It's independent of the T-Mat system.
I just hope it works.
If it doesn't, we'll have trouble docking.
It could be quite a crash.
Let's try. I think we're near enough.
- (THREE-TONE SIGNAL)
- That's our activating signal.
- (STEADY BEEP)
- As long as that note is steady,
we're home and dry, no trouble!
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! Emergency! Can you hear me?
Emergency! Can you hear me?
Hello, Earth Control. This is Moonbase.
Can you hear me? Hello, Earth Control...
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
(BEEPING HAS STOPPED)
- The homing beam, it's cut out!
- I'm trying to reactivate it!
- You said it was infallible!
- The solar power source has been damaged.
- That means trouble!
- Yes, it's impossible to land safely.
- You mean we'll crash?
- Or drift endlessly through space.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Guard!
Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
You allowed them to send a message
back to Earth!
They tricked me! I tried to stop them!
No matter. He will be found and killed.
- What about me?
- Have you repaired the T-Mat link?
- Not yet. It isn't easy!
- But it is possible?
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Yes, only give me time!
- Very well,
but now you know what will happen if you fail!
You will die!
Don't you see this goes far beyond
a petty quarrel over rockets and T-Mat?
Those men are in trouble
and we must help them!
- Find some other way!
- Your rocket is our only hope
of reaching the moon.
- Listen to them.
- I'm listening!
In a way, this is a triumph for your rocket!
- Is it?
- Yes! The government recognises the fact.
Then the government is going to be disappointed!
I don't understand you!
I'll be frank. I played with the idea
of making a space flight,
I even prepared a rocket,
but it was just a dream -
an illusion for a disappointed man.
- So there's nothing?
- The rocket's partially prepared.
- As for an actual lift-off...
- We can do it!
It takes more than enthusiasm
to get a rocket off the ground!
- We have funds, men, equipment...
- What it needs, you haven't got - time!
- We have the best technicians.
- It's nowhere near ready, woman!
The equipment is still unchecked!
- A computer can do that.
- It would still be dangerous!
Daniel...
It was you who created this rocket.
It was your driving force and enthusiasm
that got it off the drawing board.
With you in control, we can't fail to succeed!
That was a long time past.
Now my heart couldn't take
the strain of the G-force.
But your experience and knowledge
aren't useless.
- We need your guidance.
- No!
I told you it's a dream!
I can never go to the moon
and neither can rocket ZA 685!
- Doctor...
- Yes?
- Are you all planning to crew the rocket?
- Oh, aye!
- I hadn't thought about you.
- You're not leaving me behind!
- There can be no excess weight.
- How many does this thing hold?
- It was designed for three men.
- Well, then, I'm going!
The fuel stocks are barely adequate
for a moon journey and return.
- What about other sources?
- New York and Moscow.
- Transit impossible.
- We're only getting TO the moon.
We'll come back by T-Mat, won't we?
It depends what's wrong with it.
The moon has a fuel dump
and a refuelling system on the landing bay.
But that hasn't been used for years!
Neither has the radio homing beam.
Without it, you won't land at all!
In that case, why worry about getting back (?)
The equipment's fully automated
and solar-powered.
- No reason why it shouldn't work.
- I'm sure it will.
- Will you remember all I told you?
- Even if I don't, Zoe has total recall.
- Well, I've written it all down.
- There's no need.
And there's a map of Moonbase, too.
You know how to operate the homing beam?
Don't worry. Your rocket will be in good hands.
(JAMIE) A-hem!
You've only food and water for three days.
- Ignition reserve power.
- (CLICK)
(KELLY) Fully charged.
- Internal atmosphere settings.
- (CLICK)
(ELDRED) All normal.
- (CLICKING)
- Trajectory bearings, orbital lock.
(CLICKING)
Preset registering normal functions.
Lift-off activation check complete.
All readings alpha green.
- Well done! Record time and not a thing wrong!
- So far!
Link programme to telemeter guidance.
Three minutes.
Countdown will begin at T minus 60 seconds.
(RADNOR) This is it.
(KELLY) All functions
are now on computer control preset.
Clear launching site.
Three minutes seem a long time.
Yes. You remember
your take-off briefing, Jamie?
Aye, he's told me
about this G-force stuff. I know!
You don't know about it
until you've experienced it!
(KELLY) Tminus 60 seconds from now.
One minute to go. Hold tight, everyone!
Well, I'm all right. How about you, Jamie?
I keep telling you - I'm fine!
(KELLY) Tminus 50.
Ensure telemeter guidance is operative!
Don't worry! Everything's
been checked and rechecked!
- T minus 40. Technicians, report.
- (BRENT) All areas clear.
Check all systems.
- We have.
- We must make sure!
T minus...30.
(KELLY) 26...
22...
18...
14...
We have lift-off!
(RADNOR) I never thought I'd see
that again - a rocket rising in flight!
Beautiful!
Let's see how they are.
The link is dead!
Something must have gone wrong
on lift-off! Try the second channel.
- Nothing.
- We're out of touch completely?!
What about radio link?
Earth Control to rocket.
How do you read me? Over.
No, nothing but static!
It's only a minor fault, surely?
(KELLY) Earth Control to rocket.
How do you read me?
Don't release the strap until
we have automatic gravity control,
otherwise you'll float away.
- (KELLY) Earth Control to rocket!
- Wait!
Switching to automatic gravity control now!
Try again.
Earth Control to rocket.
(ZOE) Rocket to Earth Control.
Wait a minute, can't you?
Is everything all right?
We've lost our video monitor link.
(DOCTOR) Yes, I think there must be
a fault in one of the circuits.
Doctor? Doctor!
- (ZOE) What is it?
- A circuit's burnt out.
- I'll switch to another one.
- This is worse than the Tardis!
Do you read me, Doctor?!
It sounds as though the entire
communications circuitry has blown out!
Yes. Let's hope that's all that's happened!
Keep trying, Miss Kelly.