It's alive! The thing's alive!
(COUGHING)
He's dead!
Keep back! It must be that smoke!
(COUGHS)
Guards!
(CHOKING COUGH)
Keep away from here!
Use the air conditioning!
Switch the air conditioning to expel!
(DRONING AND BUZZING)
(RASPING WHISPER)
Dispose of him!
- What do you mean?
- You will adjust the T-Mat controls
and suspend him in space...
..between the moon and Earth!
- Is this the right cubicle?
- It had better be!
(FEWSHAM) Please! Please don't make me!
Complete it!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Oh, no!
That's the interior casing. It comes off easily.
- Is the circuit prepared yet?
- Yes, almost.
- Almost.
- You are wasting time!
- Operate!
- No!
At once!
(TRILLING)
You've killed him!
You've killed him! You've killed him!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER)
Prepare to dispatch to London.
Do as I say!
The time has come for your mission.
You understand what you must do?
I understand.
(HISSES)
You must succeed at all costs.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Transmit to London!
I need time.
I must reprogramme.
(COMPUTER) Information coming in
on appearance of vegetable blight
attacking parks and gardens
in the metropolises.
(RADNOR) Guards!
(COMPUTER) ..destroying cereals.
(TRILLING BUZZ)
How much longer must I wait here?
(RASPING WHISPER)
Do not ask questions!
I need food and rest!
I haven't had any sleep for...
..hours.
(RASPING WHISPER)
What are you doing?
I must fix the cubicle.
But you said T-Mat was functioning properly!
I know, but there's something I forgot.
Quick! The heating controls are over there.
Turn the main wheel to full.
Report to Central Control.
The creature is entering the east compound area.
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(RADNOR) What's happened? Report!
Look out, Zoe!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(part4 ends here)