Doctor! Are you all right?
- Yes, I am. I think so.
- Where's Phipps?
He's dead. An Ice Warrior killed him.
How did you manage to escape?
- The other man helped me.
- Fewsham? I thought he was working for them?
- He saved my life.
- Doesn't sound much like Fewsham.
- He attacked the Ice Warrior. He's also got T-Mat working again.
- (DOCTOR) Do I gether we can get back to Earth?
- I think so.
- Let's not waste any more time!
(Weather Control Center)
Weather Control Unit
DRY DRY
I had to help them or they would have killed me!
All right, Fewsham. There'll be a full inquiry when we get back to Earth. Tell them.
No more time to waste.
We must T-Mat back to Earth immediately.
- But if we all are going, who is going to dispatch us?
- There's a way of doing that.
Here, this time switch delays
transportation by ten seconds.
Oh, I see, how genius. I'll dispatch you and follow you using the time switch.
Right, so Zoe, Jamie, come along. I think this could be quite fun!
Fewsham, that time switch was down on the maintenance report for being  inoperable.
We repaired it!
(TRILLING)
In you get, Miss Kelly. I'll use the time switch.
You better hurry. Those Ice Warriors will be back any minute.
Do you know, I find T-Mat travel
rather disappointing.
There's no sensation at all!
Where have you been? And what were you being up to all this time?
Where's... Miss Kelly! What's happening up there?
Will someone tell me
what's happening down here?!
Who are these people? Is T-Mat working?
Now, please, don't... Let us just one question at a time!
Doctor, do you know there's been an alien here?
- An Ice Warrior HERE?!
- Jamie, I am not surprised.
They have taken over the whole Moonbase.
- What about the crew?
- All dead except Fewsham.
- You left him there?
- He said he'd follow using the time switch.
He should be back.
What's happening?
I thought so!
The time switch is still out of order.
- What? But he said he had repaired it.
- He was lying.
- Why?
- Obviously he's working for them!
Then why did he let us escape?
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
But don't you see, gentlmen?
The invasion of Moonbase,
the taking over of T-Mat,
the seed pods, the arrival of the Ice Warrior,
they're all part of the same plan.
Plan? What plan?
These incidents seem unrelated.
This fungus everywhere,
what's that got to do with it?
I'm not quite sure yet. Have you people been able to make anything of it?
It's indestructible.
We've attacked it with every possible way, but without success.
Yes, but have you tried to understand it?
You suggest we should psychoanalyse it, Doctor?
I'm merely suggesting that rather than destroy it, you should
find out its composition and purpose.
I have some laboratory equipment
in my workshop. You could use that.
- Good. Then we need a sample.
- No problem about that.
- The gardens are full of the stuff.
- Fine. The let no time to be lost.
I'll get some equipment for you.
Doctor, do be careful. Those pod things are deadly.
Don't worry. I've already had experience. I'll be careful.
(DOCTOR) Yes... It's organic.
It's alive.
It's definitely a fungus composition.
- Are you sure this is correct?
- As far as I can make out, it is.
A molecule of five atoms...absorbs oxygen.
You know,  a complete blanket of this
would reduce the oxygen content
of the Earth's atmosphere drastically.
According to my calculations,
to one twentieth normal.
It would make the Earth's atmosphere
uninhabitable to the human race,
but exactly like the atmosphere of Mars!
Look at that. Even without vegetation
to feed on, it's still active. Oh!
(ELDRED) If that thing explodes here, the fumes will kill us! Come on, Doctor!
Just a minute. There must be some way of...
(ELDRED) Come on!
(DOCTOR) Sulphuric acid!
Hydrochloric acid!
Acetic acid!
(ELDRED) You've done it!
Well, what was it? What did you throw on it?
- You really think it would work?
- Well It could be less effective than Moonbase, of course.
which handles up to two million microwave channels simultaneously,
the satellite would just take a few thousand.
That would be enough for vital food supplies.
But we can't use normal communications satellites.
They are not programmed for T-Mat.
No. We have to send up a specially       programmed one.
That would mean using a rocket, wouldn't it? I thought no one use them nowadays.
Not manned rockets, but we do send up satellites for communications.
- How soon can you get one up?
- Well, I don't know. If we're given top priority...
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
There!
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
A communications unit from our ship.
Connect it to the solar batteries!
(DOCTOR) Is Commander Radnor there, please?
- Oh, Zoe, is Radnor there?
- He's in conference with Miss Kelly and Sir James Gregson.
Oh, I see. Zoe,
there's the most wonderful news!
We've found a way of destroying the fungus!
- Oh! What is it?
- Water! Ordinary water!
- Oh, Doctor, surely...
- There's no time to explain now.
Apparently, there is a Weather Control Bureau somewhere.
I want you to get in touch with them.
Can't you reach them on the video phone?
- No, I've tried. They are not answering, or it's broken down or something.
- What do you want me to do?
- Get hold of the Weather Control Bureau people
and to make rain, as much rain as possible
over the entire country!
- Well, where is everybody?
- I don't know.
Let's find the main control room. Come on.
So that's why no one answered
the video phone.
And look at that!
No, it's no good. They're locked in position.
Our fleet is approaching
the gravitational field of the moon.
- Is all prepared?
- Everything is ready.
I shall guide our ships in
on the homing beam signal.
- (BEEPING)
- What the devil's happening?
I don't know... Yes, Moon Control!
The sound, can you turn it up?
Shouldn't we test the directional beam?
- It is not necessary!
- But it's operating on Moonbase power.
I can't guarantee the pulsing rate
will be the same.
Very well. Test it!
Commander Radnor, can this be recorded?
- Yes.
- Quickly! Manage it. It's vital!
The transmission coming in on the video machine would be recorded.
(COMPUTER) Instruction Understood.
Transmission will be recorded.
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(ICE WARRIOR) The device is operating.
Wait a moment!
Um...I must check the connections.
(SIGNAL CONTINUES)
If the power fails, we won't be able
to guide the fleet onto the moon.
There must be no failures!
I realise the importance of that.
If we overshoot the moon,
nothing will stop them from going
straight into an orbit around the sun.
They will not overshoot!
Of course not, but since their fuel
supplies are at a marginal level,
if anything did go wrong,
they'd never be able to regain moon orbit.
This video device is operating!
You have betrayed us!
- Every word has been heard on Earth!
- Kill him!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(COMPUTER) Countdown
in minus three minutes.
Cancel the launch! We can use that
satellite to mislead the Martian fleet!
Don't you see? Poor Fewsham deliberately let us overhear their homing signal.
We can imitate that signal
with a homing device in the satellite!
Commander Radnor, top priority
message to satellite launching site!
- Cancel launch! Repeat, Cancel launch!
- (COMPUTER) Message understood.
If we can deflect their armada,
half our battle is won!
- But still, that fungus stuff is everywhere.
- We solved that one with H2O - water!
Water? Well, all we need to do
is to make it rain!