It's hopeless, Doctor!
You'll never get that thing going again!
I'm not so sure, Jamie. After all, it's only the controls that are damaged.
The workings are all right.
If we can bypass the controls...
Have you got your knife on you?
Lend it me, will you? Be careful.
Thank you. There we are.
Now, what have we got here?
Ah, yes... Yes, yes.
Yes, well, it's just a question
of sorting this lot out. That's all.
All is prepared, Grand Marshal.
I shall return to our ship
to finalise invasion plans.
Right, now then, Zoe, let's see what happens when we try to connect these two together.
No, I don't think so somehow!
What about these two?
Ah! That's better! I think
I've succeeded in re-establishing
one of these rain circuits, Jamie.
Well, it's not raining yet!
Oh, Jamie! Weather Control
is a very difficult technology.
You can't expect immediate results.
- Are you sure you're getting it right?
- Yeah, I hope so, Zoe. Just have to hope for the best. That's all.
I must get on as there's another little job I want to do.
We should have some nice heavy rain before long!
- Ah, there we are!
- Yes, the satellite.
(ELDRED) Isn't that a beautiful sight!
- We've finished and installed the homing device. It's working perfectly.
- Well done.
Doctor, I know we're sending up a false signal,
but aren't some of the Martian ships bound to follow the right one?
There isn't going to be a right one, there's going to be only ours, the wrong one,
and that's going to lead the entire Martian fleet
into an orbit round the sun!
- What about Slaar's signal?
- Obviously that has to be stopped.
- But how?
- Well, as soon as that satellite is up
I shall T-Mat myself to the moon
and destroy their homing device.
- They'll kill you on sight!
- No, I don't think so.
I rigged up an interesting device here.
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(KELLY) There it is. It's in orbit.
We're picking up the aliens'
homing signal from the moon.
That means their invasion fleet is getting closer. There's no time to lose.
Are you quite clear? As soon as I have succeeded destroying their signal,
you must activate our signal in the satellite.
- We'll be ready.
- Right, then I'll be off.
- Doctor, do be careful, won't you?
- Don't worry, Zoe, I will.
- Are you ready, Miss Kelly?
- Doctor, our control of T-Mat hasn't been tested!
Then now's the time to test it!
(TRILLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(SIGNAL GETS LOUDER)
(SIGNAL GETS QUIETER)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(SLAAR) No.
You...
..over there.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
I ordered you to be destroyed!
Well, you weren't very successful, were you?
Destroy that weapon!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
What is your purpose in coming here?
You don't expect me to tell you that, do you?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
The directional beam is still operative.
Yes. I'm afraid you were
a little too quick for me.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Are you capable of operating
the T-Mat mechanism?
Oh, no. I don't think I...
Well, yes, perhaps I could get the hang of it.
As long as you can be useful to us, you can live,
but this time, there will be no escape.
You will familiarise yourself
with the T-Mat controls.
Oh, thank you very much!
You will not touch the controls
until I give the order.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
- (KELLY) It's operating perfectly!
- Shoulf we wait till the Doctor got back?
The moon signal has disappeared, hasn't it?
That may be too atmospheric. As all we know they're transmitting as strongly as ever.
The moon signal was strong enough before the Doctor left.
- He must have succeeded.
- Then why hasn't he come back?
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
When our Warriors arrive,
you will transmit them to Earth
under my direction.
Yes. They haven't arrived yet.
Something still might go wrong.
- Nothing can go wrong now!
- There's many a slip between the cup and the lip.
If anything does go wrong,
you will be the first to die.
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
Scan closer!
If they are going to divert,
it should happen any moment now!
They're changing course!
I think you're right!
They're all following the satellite signal!
The Doctor must succeeded!
He must turned off the Martians' signal.
What's happening up there, then?
Why hasn't he come back?
Don't worry, Jamie. A squad of Security guards armed with flame throwers are on their way here now.
- As soon as they get here, we'll T-Mat them to the moon.
- They'll be too late!
- You'll just have to be patient!
- I'm sick of being patient!
(WHISPERS) Zoe.
- That T-Mat thing, do you know how it works?
- - I think so. Why?
- Could you T-Mat me back to the moon?
- Oh, no, Jamie, shouldn't you...
Look, Either the Doctor's all right, in which case we've no reason to worry
or he's in danger and he needs my help!
You have failed us, Slaar!
We shall all die!
We're being pulled into the orbit of the sun!
This is impossible!
The signal! There is no power!
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You did this!
Yes. That signal has been going
no further than this control room.
But they were receiving my signal!
Not your signal - ours.
You sent a signal...
..from Earth?
We sent up a satellite.
That signal has sent your fleet
into a false orbit!
The heat of the sun will kill them!
You have destroyed our entire fleet!
You tried to destroy an entire world.
Earth will still die!
The fungus will take the oxygen
from your atmosphere!
I'm afraid you've failed there, too.
We can destroy the fungus.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Kill him!
DOCTOR!
Jamie! Look out!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
Creag an tuire!
Jamie! The light terminal!
Well done, Jamie!
Oh, goodness me!
Jamie, thank you very much!
Now then, we must T-Mat ourselves
back to Earth.
(THUNDERCLAP)
(COMPUTER) Widespread rainfall
throughout the country.
Some flooding but none serious.
Fungus rapidly disappearing.
Weather Control Bureau
coming back into operation.
World food shortages partially relieved,
now T-Mats are becoming operational again.
Message to Commander Radnor from the Security Council
of the United Nations -
-  Congratulations.
- All right. Just discontinue report.
So you DID know what you were doing
at the Weather Control Bureau!
Zoe, of course I did.
Well, it took long enough to work!
Well, the rain seems dispose of the fungus well enough.
Now the next thing to do is to get T-Mat fully operational again.
Yes, when Moon Relay is repaired,
we must check over the equipment
and build in safeguards.
From now on, T-Mat must be entirely controlled from Earth.
Oh, surely you've learned not to put all your eggs in one basket!
T-Mat itself is perfectly effective!
You need a secondary transportation system,
a fleet of rockets on permanent stand by!
- There's no need to go to such lengths.
- It's a question of common sense!
I'm sure the Doctor will agree with me! Doctor...
(JAMIE) You didn't have to make it
rain as hard as all that!
Oh, Jamie, some of you is just never satisfied!
- What did you rush us back here for?
- Oh, you know, questions and explanations are very difficult. Come on!
- Where are we going now?
- It's no good asking him.
He's no more idea than the man in the moon!
I heard that, Jamie! Come on!